Maybe I would like to use this word. They are astray in the sense that they are also deviated.
I think the word astray can also mean they deviated from the right path, when they were on it at one time.
And Verse 16 says so. They have chosen straying instead of guidance. The choice is theirs.
But some people have been astray from the beginning. They were never on the path.
They never came to the right path.
So, as Karim and I were talking the other night, they had no path in the beginning; they had no direction.
But the righteous had a direction.
These traitors, once upon a time, were given that sense of direction, but they chose to deviate and so on.
That's all I want to say. I've taken so much of your time.
I guess one thing more.
I want to summarize what Behrouz said, and then add a verse that we want to confirm.
But Behrouz is saying that there are the believers, the righteous, and then the disbelievers, and the hypocrites.
But he says that the hypocrites are also disbelievers. Yes, they are.
The hypocrites are disbelievers in the set of the unbelievers.
And I think we will crown this idea by looking at page 65, at the bottom, page 65 at the bottom, at verse 140.
God has revealed to you in the scripture that if you hear the revelations of God being rejected and ridiculed,
you shall not sit with them unless they engage in a different subject; otherwise you will be as guilty as they are.
Alright, and then the last part says, God will gather the hypocrites together with the disbelievers in Hell.
So both the disbelievers and the hypocrites are together.
They come to have an evil reward.
On verse 16, I was going to show a really strong parallelism.
Okay, it says, "They have chosen straying instead of guidance, and thus their trade never prospers, nor are they guided."
And if you go to Surah 22, verse 11 and 12, that's on page 226.
And there is the one who worships God conditionally.
If something good happens to him, he is content.
But when a tribulation afflicts him, he reverts.
Thus he loses both this life and the Hereafter.
Such is the real loss. He idolizes besides God what neither harms nor benefits him; this is the far straying.
To me, that's an expansion on that verse, very strongly.
It's, um, because it's conditional worshiping; that's when they were on the path and then...
and they left Him as betrayers.
Such a person really doesn't believe.
Yeah.
He believes only if something good is going on with him.
And it also says here in Verse 16 that their trade never prospers.
Well, it says here they lose both this life and the Hereafter.
If we go back to Chapter 1, then the theme would be... see, what we would have in that...
...is an emphasis on a Hebrew word.
Excuse me.
Mustaqim would be a Hebrew word
for this interpretation, which I will discuss.
Now,
Verse 9,
contains the number 17,
we said the number 19,
and now the number 17
shows up.
So we have, in Verse 9,
the
number 19 from the Arabic.
the number 19, which is the code of the Quran, and we have the number 17.
Now the number 17 is the number of Bani Israel.
So the idea of the 17 and 19 together would be very consistent with the idea of having
Arabic words and Hebrew words together.
Now, probably, on the front, on page 361, yes, there's the Iranian calendar, the Bahá'í
calendar, that has 19 months...
361?
Yeah, 19 months of 19 days, that's the Bahá'í calendar.
So you have people who say they believe, but the faith has not entered their hearts.
So I think that in the third category, hypocrisy, in Surah 2, it's a no-joke description of people.
So apparently the Quran has more concern with hypocrisy than with everybody else.
So that shows the disease of hypocrisy is very important, it's a critical, it's a
critical condition, and the spirit of the Quran is to give the remedy for this affliction.
This is also very easy to perceive because you can imagine a person coming to you and
saying, I am a disbeliever, I don't believe in this.
And a person coming to you and saying, I'm a believer, I agree with you, I believe 100%,
when that person really is not a believer.
So we can see the deceit and the danger of hypocrisy.
I look at it in terms of a self-mechanism.
So you get an error.
So we did a lengthy analysis of the error
in order to have all the possible error recovery devices.
An engineer would design the self-mechanism.
First must have a sensor to find out the error,
and then a correction device.
I think the Quran is a self-maintaining device for the believer.
Okay, let's go on to verse 20, that also deals with the hypocrites.
The light of faith. Verse 20 says,
The lightning is so bright, it almost blinds them.
Whenever it lights for them, they move forward.
And when it turns dark, they stand still.
And if God willed, He could have taken away their hearing and their eyesight.
God is omnipotent. And we have a footnote here that says,
He does not imply gender in the Arabic language.
God Almighty is neither male nor female.
This is why Arabic was chosen for the final scripture.
Ok, this has to do with the word 'He'.
But the parable of the lightning is that the hypocrites
actually sit with the believers, and they claim to be believers, so they are
getting the light of the Quran. And whenever they follow that light, they move forward,
but when they ignore it, they are in total darkness, they cannot move, they stand still. Then we go to
verse 21, O people, you shall worship your Lord who created you, and those before you,
that you may attain salvation. He is the one who made the earth habitable for you.
He is the one who constructed the sky. He sends down water from the sky to produce
fruit for your sustenance. Therefore you shall not set up idols besides God, now that you know.
If you have any doubt regarding what we revealed to our servant, then
produce one surah like it, and call upon your witnesses besides God,
if you are truthful. And the challenge here to produce a surah
is not simply a literary challenge.
Because there were people who wrote pieces of literature that are excellent,
Shakespeare, and even Arabic,
or even some Arabic literature giants who claim that they can write better than the Quran.
literature-wise. And I agree with them. They actually did magnificent writing.
But the challenge here has to do with the mathematical structure of the Quran, not just the
literature. And that will really nullify their claims. I mean, what can you say to a person
who says, I can write better than Quran? That's his opinion, and he will find a lot of
people who would agree with him, but the mathematical structure cannot be duplicated.
Joseph had 11 brothers, and he saw in his dream 11 stars.
This is not the only one.
Then we come to some very important teachings in the Quran, starting at verse 24,
where heaven and hell are allegorically described.
Now, they are allegorically described because we cannot...
Somebody preaching over there?
Heaven and hell are allegorically described because we cannot imagine
the beauty of Heaven, or the reality of Heaven, there is absolutely no way you can imagine Heaven for real.
That's why in Surah 32 we're told that you have no idea how much joy and happiness are waiting for you in Heaven.
Nobody among the believers has any idea how much joy and happiness are in Heaven.
It's just indescribable.
So God describes them in terms that we can understand here.
That is, fruits, food, things that we enjoy in this life.
And then verse 24 says, if you fail to do this, and most certainly you will fail,
that is to duplicate the Quran, its mathematical structure and writings.
If you fail to do this, and most certainly you will fail, then beware of the hellfire
whose fuel is people and rocks. It awaits the disbelievers. And give good news to those
who believe and work righteousness, that they have deserved gardens with flowing
streams. This is the first description of Heaven and Hell. When given a fruit therein, they
would say, this is what was given to us before. They will be given the same kind.
They will have pure spouses therein, and they abide therein forever.
God does not shy away from citing any kind of example, from a mosquito and higher.
So you see, this will give you an idea that the description of Heaven in the Quran, compared to the real Heaven,
is like the mosquito compared to you.
Size-wise, complexity-wise, and of course goal-wise.
I mean, you don't go around stinging people.
Those who believe know that it is the truth from their Lord.
While the disbelievers would say,
What does God mean by such an allegory?
He misleads many thereby, and guides many thereby.
But He never misleads except the wicked. And this verse started a whole bunch of
discussions that went on for centuries, literally, that God misleads. This question was being
discussed over many centuries. But see the end of the verse here, it says
but He never misleads except the wicked. So the person is already wicked, the person
The person already made the decision that he doesn't want to have anything to do with God.
So God says, okay, I'm going to help you. You don't want anything to do with me, I'm going to mislead you.
And God misleads that person.
All the circumstances will work out against the guidance of a person who doesn't want to have anything to do with God.
So, the decision has to be made first.
Either you make a decision, you want to believe in God, or the person makes a decision that
he or she doesn't want to have anything to do with God.
Then based on this, God actually guides or misleads.
If you decide that you want to believe in God, then all the circumstances around you
He will work out to guide you.
He then will direct you in that direction.
God takes over.
All you need is to make a decision.
That's why
sometimes people
want a solution to their health problem
or financial problem
or
any kind of problem,
and there's always one solution.
One, only one solution,
that is to go to God.
Be with God. Be with God. That's the only thing.
That will solve all the problems.
Any kind of problem you can think of.
There was a whole bunch of problems in the Middle Ages.
One kept dying, and the other one,
for some reason or other,
what do you do then?
Yeah.
Yeah. Any kind of problem, whether it is health, or finance, or marital, or social,
all you need is to make one decision. That will solve all the problems.
But you have to have that confidence. You cannot do it through calculation.
Where will the money come from?
If I believe in God and just put all my trust in Him, where would the money come from?
God says it will come whence you never expect.
And if you expect it, the trust is not correct.
But it will come. Your problem will be over.
Over.
And the misleader is the devil.
But the reason for the wrong decision
is the mental immaturity.
The people who are not mature, who are not of age,
if they make the wrong decision, they will not be penalized.
They will be...
Children?
Yes.
They're not supposed to make a decision yet.
But they will make it.
They will make it when they grow up.
So there are people who are not capable of making a decision, and if they make a mistake, they can't...
God knows that. I mean, the person who is mentally retarded, and is incapable of making decisions, that person goes straight to heaven.
Because of his luck. That's the luckiest person.
Reagan goes to heaven.
What?
Who?
Reagan.
Reagan?
Well, if he is, if he believes in God, yes.
Are we at 27?
The definition of the wicked.
The wicked that are misled by God.
The wicked who violate God's covenant after
pledging to keep it,
sever what God has ordered to be joined,
and corrupt the earth.
These are the losers. Then we come to a very important verse, two deaths and two lives.
How could you disbelieve in God when you were dead, and He gave you life? Then He
will put you to death, then bring you back to life; to Him is your ultimate return.
Do you see the two deaths and two lives?
Do you know what death feels like?
You tried it before, you were dead.
Remember the 3 million years you were dead?
You were dead for 3 million years, or more.
And that's exactly how death will feel like.
So if there were 3 million years to the Day of Resurrection, that's how long it will feel
to you.
I mean, exactly the way it felt to you in your first death.
You can think of all the human beings as the total human population, past, present and
future.
They exist in one of three stages.
Death before birth, then life on Earth,
and then the state of Barzakh.
Or, and then the other stages, being the
life from birth to death, and then the
second death.
And when the last person, or the last few
people die, then comes the resurrection.
You can see the two deaths and two lives.
We were dead, now we are alive, we are going to die, and then we get up again, for the
eternal life.
Real life.
And this is repeated in the Quran.
But death, of course, is a big mystery to most people, but not to Muslims.
Muslims know exactly what death feels like.
Most people who don't read the Quran, they don't realize that before this life, they were
dead.
Are you asking a question?
Okay, when you come and write in this Masjid,
I will give you a five dollar little penny.
That's an offer, that's an offer.
Can I?
I just want to make a very simple reflection on
on the divine Quranic miracle, and what I will say is new to most of you.
Anyhow, a little reminder is not so bad.
It's very interesting, see, 27 stops on a kind of subject, and 28 is a new one.
Although related, naturally.
On the fifth verse of Surah 2, God says that the righteous, those who follow the guidance,
and they are the winners.
Now in Arabic, Muflihun.
Right?
Now don't forget the word here.
This is for you.
Muflihun, the verb is F, three letters, F, L, H.
F, L, H.
And Muflih means one, Muflihun, many.
Now, at the end of 27, the hypocrite and the disbeliever, these are the losers.
See, this is a kind of craftsmanship, right?
Now, what I was going to mention is that for my dear brothers and sisters,
when Wali makes the adhan, or Ustad makes the adhan,
in the adhan is a phrase they say which is very beautiful. They say,
Hayya 'ala al-Falah, Hayya 'ala al-Falah.
The Falah is the same, F-L-H.
Come to, come and join the winning team.
Isn't that right?
When one hears Hayya 'ala al-Falah, come to the winning team.
And the Quran says they are those who observe the Salat, prayers.
These are the winners.
So the Mu'azzin is telling us, come to pray,
come to the winning team, the Falah.
And this is the same word used by the Quran.
The righteous are the winners.
The adhan is telling us, forget everything now and join the winning team.
It's a very simple observation, but I think it means a lot. Even our adhan, the call to prayer, is really an attempt to join the winning team.
And that's all I want to say. I want the adhan to be more meaningful for us, in relation to the Quran.
Well, at this time I'm going to make an announcement, and that is mostly mentioning the birthdays of three people.
Today is Maryam's birthday, tomorrow is Inga's birthday, and yesterday was mine.
So, what can I say to celebrate the birthday, when we have with us here kids who
think like us?
I hope I'm not taking too much time.
I don't want to let my life come to an end.
You are.
Did you touch the third rail?
No, I'm not.
Don't let them, don't let them bug you.
He likes to tease.
27. Those who violate God's covenant after pledging to keep it.
I think this can mean two things, historically.
Historically, it might mean, it might refer to those hypocrites who made a pledge with God regarding the coming of the Prophet to Medina and so on.
But that's historical.
For the more general aspect, it might have a reference to that verse, "Alastu bi Rabbikum?"
I can't find it.
That's coming up.
Oh, that?
Surah 7.
Yeah.
100.
143.
Surah 7.
142.
143.
I'm sorry.
133.
100.
Yeah.
133.
7, 113.
You want to...
Am I not your Lord?
No, that's 143.
That's 143.
Or 172.
No, excuse me.
You want to say,
"Am I not your Lord?"
That's the verse.
172.
I think that verse 27 of Surah 2 might be related to verse 172 of Surah 7, page 116.
This is the original covenant when Allah asked the descendants of Adam,
"Am I not your Lord?"
And mankind says,
"Yes." That is a covenant.
They admit that Allah is
the Lord. And therefore
this means a system of
relations and certainly
obligations on the part of mankind towards
Allah. But Allah promises
revelation. And yes,
back to Surah
Baqarah, these are people
who have entered into
God's covenant. All of us have
entered a covenant with Allah.
It's part of our nature, part of our mental, biological, physical, spiritual makeup to accept Allah as our Lord.
Or an instinct. It's a religious instinct and inclination on the part of man.
This is the covenant. And those who break the covenant go against their very nature.
Because they go against the instinct.
against the nature of the bird.
People who don't believe in God, they go against their instinct.
You can imagine if a bird refused to sit on its egg.
The bird lays the egg, then it sits on the egg; it's just instinct.
And if they refused to sit on the egg, the whole species would have become extinct.
Have you looked at verse 172 of Surah 7?
Do you realize now that you made a covenant with God?
Each one of us made a covenant with God, that He is our Lord.
And those who break this covenant, they're the ones who bring corruption to the earth.
They don't care about the Day of Accountability, for verse 172 says,
lest you say on the Day of Resurrection, "We never knew about this."
But these people who bring corruption on earth are those who think they don't have to account to anyone.
They bring mischief. They are no different from those birds that refuse to sit on their eggs.
They are defying their own nature. That's all.
Before we go to Inga, can I ask the mothers to make sure the kids are quiet?
And if your kids are making noise, contributing to the distraction, just take them out of the room.
Can you turn that off, please?
As soon as we're quiet, we can go to our next reader.
Sister, you were going to read for us, is that right?
How far did you get in this Surah?
Twenty-nine to thirty-nine.
Okay.
Do you want me to read all of it?
Yes, please.
Give us your reflections.
We'll see how much ESP you have.
I'm ready for it.
He is the One who created for you everything on earth.
Then He turned to the heaven and perfected seven heavens.
He is fully aware of all things.
And your Lord said to the angels, "I am placing a representative on earth."
They said, "Will You place on it one who will spread corruption and shed blood, while we praise Your glory and sanctify You?"
He said, "I know what you do not know."
He taught Adam all the names, then presented them to the angels, saying, "Tell me the names of these, if you are truthful."
They said, "Glory be to You, we have no knowledge except what You have taught us. You are indeed the All-Knowing, the All-Wise."
He said, "O Adam, tell them their names." And when he told them their names, He said,
"Did I not tell you that I know the secrets of the heavens and the earth, and I know what you reveal and what you conceal?"
And when We said to the angels, "Prostrate before Adam," they prostrated, except for Iblis. He refused and was arrogant.
And We said, "O Adam, dwell, you and your wife, in Paradise and eat from it generously, but do not approach this tree, lest you be among the transgressors."
But Satan caused them to slip, and got them expelled from where they were. We said, "Go down, as enemies to one another. On earth you will have a dwelling place and a provision for a time."
Then Adam received from his Lord words, and He redeemed him.
We said, "Go down from it, all of you. When guidance comes to you from Me, those who follow My guidance will have no fear, nor will they grieve.
As for those who disbelieve and reject Our revelations, they will be the dwellers of the Fire; they will abide therein forever."
Thank you for watching.
The seven heavens are the structure of the universe.
One of the...
Our immediate universe includes a hundred billion galaxies and a hundred billion stars.
It has distances of billions of light years.
All this incredible vastness is only part of the lowest and smallest heaven.
Six more larger heavens surround our lowermost, small heaven.
and they said, "We glorify You, praise You, and sanctify You, so why place on it one who will shed blood and cause corruption?"
The verse 2:29 is showing us what we can't even imagine.
The seven heavens... And how many Gods are there?
Seven heavens, and how many homes?
Seven heavens, and how many houses?
Seven universes, and how many houses?
One God.
You are reading the Quran now.
We are reading the Quran.
Okay.
They are asking or inquiring because they already praise God.
I don't know if that means they think they can go to Earth too, and see if they can die
or what.
How do they know that man is going to be bad?
I'm going to give you something to think about.
You notice in the first sentence, God told the angels He's placing a representative. Where?
On Earth.
This is before creation of Adam, right?
Yes.
Before Adam.
because he doesn't go to earth unless he breaks God's law.
And this is before he was created.
Yeah, so this is why God put them in heaven,
in paradise, put Adam and Eve in paradise.
But before He created them, He said to the angels,
on earth. But God knew that they would break
His law, and they would deserve to be kicked out of heaven, and sent
sent down to earth, and the angels concluded from this, that this creature is going to break God's law.
So they said, "Why do You create a creature who will break God's law,
while we are praising and glorifying You all the time?"
So God said, "I know what you do not know."
Which is what?
Right, what?
Right.
So, what did they protest?
Protest of creating Adam?
No, no.
They are saying to Allah,
"We hold You sacred."
"Hold You sacred" means whatever You say, we obey.
This is their bay'ah.
This is, in other words, what the angels said:
"We are doing everything that you expect us to do.
We carry out the orders."
I'm sorry, Inga, but I...
I guess I would have assumed that
the souls had already been created.
Right.
Right, you're right.
That's right.
Okay now, if you take the whole Quran in totality, what Inge is asking is,
God is telling the angels, who is making the noise there?
Keep him apart or something to make him quiet.
Get that bottle out from next to Erol.
So Inge is saying, where are the souls of the human beings at that time?
We are told in surah 40, in surah 18, that God did not let the angels witness our creation, the creation of our souls.
God created the souls of you and me and everybody, but the angels did not witness that.
But at the appropriate moment, God told the angels, "I am going to place a representative on earth."
And they said, they concluded from this, that this creature will break God's law and will deserve to be kicked out of heaven and sent down to earth.
So they said, why create a creature who will break your law?
And God said, "I know what you do not know."
What God knew, as we saw in this expression here,
do you remember? Do you get it?
Let's see what verse, what verse is that?
Yeah, the end of verse 30.
His answer at the end is what? "I know what you do not know."
And what God knew was that one of the, one of the big angels...
Who's grunting?
What God knew was that one of the archangels was thinking rebellious ideas.
And God wanted to expose that one angel.
Now the angels, the angels don't know that.
The angels don't know that Satan is rebelling.
God knew what the angels did not know.
And one purpose, the first purpose of creating Adam
was to expose Satan.
As we see later on.
Do you want to go on, Inge?
May I just say something?
Inge raised the question.
It's indeed a bid on the part of the angels to become the representative, did you not
suggest it?
No, you mentioned the word, "representative."
And then I wanted to know why they would do that, you know, this thing of wanting to
supplant him for God.
Many people, many persons have interpreted this verse to mean that the angels are saying
to God, "Why put people who shed blood?"
I think they were making a deal, the angels wanted to be the representatives.
Some people have asked this question, and I've heard it, and it's very curious that Inge suggested that, no?
I wanted to ask, were they offering that, or was it something to do with jealousy?
Well, rather than the jealousy.
It's a simple question. It's a simple question.
Why create a creature who will defy and revolt?
We do not do that.
It's an excellent question. If I said I knew what it is...
But isn't this a deal on the part of the angels, that they're asking for something in exchange?
They're already much higher.
It's a very interesting question.
They do not want to be lower.
When God said "representative on earth," that's a terrible demotion.
And that's exactly what tipped off the angels as to the nature of the human being.
Shedding blood, corrupting the earth, not praising God when he should be praised.
And the evidence was all around us.
It is because there are those names, when people look at angels, some names that you are aware of.
I just talked about this thing a couple of times before, and I'm not comfortable with it.
I don't...
Well, how, let me put it this way.
Who was it that was presented to the angels?
Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam, Adam.
Right. Did you watch the funeral of Princess Grace?
Well, we did. It was here on the TV, right?
So there's an event going on, on the other side of the globe,
that we're watching live here.
Everything that's happening over there, we're watching it here.
And how do you think the angels feel about this invention of the TV?
Now this is the kind of thing that God taught us.
When a person is sitting in Washington D.C., I was sitting in Tucson.
That's quite an event.
Now, so, this is the kind of knowledge that amazed the angels.
This was meant by the names.
In other words, God gave a human being knowledge.
How do you think the angels feel about a 747 flying, a huge city, floating in the air?
Did you ride a 747?
Did you ride a 747 plane?
When you ride it, you look inside and you just wonder how is this steel, this thing
built of steel, and aluminum, etc., etc., and carpets, and engines, and so forth, is up
floating in the air.
And when you sit at the, you go to the other end of the plane and look inside, it's a whole
like a floating city.
And the human being did that, and the angels watching in amazement.
So this is the, this is the knowledge that God gave to the human being.
Inventing the TV, the video recorder, the airplane, that's what's meant by the names.
So that really explains what you wanted to say.
Right.
Thank you.
Question over there?
Yes.
What did he make the soul out of?
Yes, that's the question in Surah 17.
That you find out in a different dimension.
That's the answer.
The soul is in a different dimension.
But the soul is part of God, by the way.
Great, good. The soul is a small part of God, which is why when you do things that have to do with God, your soul grows.
What this soul looks like, what it is made of, you will find out in the day of resurrection.
Now that's not symmetrical, is it? Okay, go ahead.
Okay, so that was the first purpose of creating the human being, is to expose Satan.
Because God made him up out of clay, of lowly material.
And Satan was very, very arrogant and rebellious.
So God told the angels, this is what God knew, that the angels would not disobey.
Alright.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Give me your question again.
When Satan was cast out, was any other angel cast out with him or not?
He was just cast out, and we are not told of any other.
God has made a deal with him for a time.
What does the Bible say? I think the Bible mentions other angels who work with him.
What's the question again?
The question is, was Satan cast out alone or did he have entities with him?
Fallen entities.
In the Bible, not in the Torah, not in the Psalms, but in other parts of the Bible, a big group went with him.
It doesn't matter though, that's the...
When I was wondering what it was like back then, was Satan tempted by Satan?
Yeah.
I was wondering what, you know...
We were not, we were not with Adam at the time either.
We didn't exist. We are descendants of Adam, but we didn't exist then, I mean our bodies.
Descendants means they came from him, not that all descendants were with him.
But I can't think of any place in Quran where it mentions any other angels.
Iblis was just cast out by himself.
Yes.
I thought it was said that Adam was made from clay,
and angels from light,
and the jinn were made from fire?
They were made out of the fire.
The angels were made out of fire, not made out of light.
The definition of jinn, the definition of jinn is a hidden angel.
So the angel, when the angel rebels, becomes a jinn.
When Satan became a jinn, he was an angel.
Some of the old sheikhs decided that Satan was not an angel; I think it's lack of knowledge
of the Arabic language. This happens only in Persia and Pakistan, where they refute
that Satan was an angel.
But if you look, do you have a copy of the Quran there?
If you look at this, verse 34, it says,
And We said to the angels,
fall prostrate before Adam. So, it's certain.
If Satan were not an angel, he would not be required to
prostrate. He, therefore, broke God's law.
Because God told the angels to prostrate.
Right? There is absolutely no question that Satan was one of them.
I've heard all of these stories, but they don't mean anything.
What?
When I was listening to a scholar, for instance, I heard an old statement saying he was blind.
It's a hadith. The Quran doesn't say that he was blind.
But it says that these additions are made in contrast.
Right.
The jinn were made of fire, so since a jinn was an angel initially, then I suppose
the angels were made of fire.
We have the same theory.
But there's no difference between fire and light.
Anyway, the angels made of light is a hadith.
The ruh.
What's the question?
Now, there is the second question.
What word?
The word that we see, the word that is pure.
And what does He say?
When We said to the angels, "Bow down to Adam,"
they bowed down, except Iblis.
He said, "Shall I bow down to one whom You created from clay?"
So what I understand from this is that Adam was only created in a form.
It's his bodily form there.
So they could see the clay form of his body.
But later on it says that when he ate from the tree, his body became visible to them.
So it sounds like...
Do you see a soul?
No.
The soul is ruh. The ruh is not visible. But you are now in the dimension where the body is visible to you.
You are not in the dimension of the ruh, the soul. This is why you don't see it.
So, before eating from the tree, they were in the dimension of the soul, where the body is invisible to them.
And as soon as they broke God's law, they went down to the dimension where the body is visible to them.
You cannot be in there, in both of them.
Yes, it's very clear in the Quran that when they ate from the tree, their bodies became
visible to them.
But the angels could see, of course, they have to see both of them.
And they are God's helpers.
They are supposed to have access to any body.
Other questions?
First, I think we're going into it too far.
This idea of the names, maybe we should spend some more time on it.
Basically, we compare it with the...
We're not studying the Bible of the Jews and Christians,
but I think if we go deeper, we might learn something, maybe.
For example, one difference is this.
In the Bible of the Jews and Christians, it does not say that God taught Adam.
There, Adam, on his own accord, began to give names to the animals and the plants.
This is already one difference.
In the Quran, Allah teaches Adam the names, whatever these names are.
But in the Bible of the Jews, Adam is on his own.
There's no suggestion that Allah teaches Adam.
It's Adam who goes to the garden and he starts to name the things that God created.
I think this is very important.
Because the way Moses Maimonides, who is the greatest Jewish philosopher,
describes how Adam is naming animals and plants,
you would think that Adam was a professor of botany and zoology.
And I would think that Adam would have bigger things to worry about.
So, many Muslims in their tafsir, guided by the readings of the Jewish Bible,
and to demonstrate to other Muslims that they know something else beyond the Quran,
Theologians began to teach us that what Allah taught Adam were the names of animals and plants.
So this time, it's Allah who becomes the professor of botany and zoology.
Now, it seems there is something in the names which the angels do not know, or maybe cannot know.
But they can know some.
Now, this is very interesting, there have been many interpretations about this, of many kinds, some tolerant and some indulgent.
There is a standard teaching among some Sufi writers, that these names refer to the names of Allah.
Now, first of all, I think among the Arabs, knowing a name is more than knowing a name,
like, say, sir.
No.
As Ustaz is saying, a name refers to more than the name of someone, it refers to knowledge,
which I accept.
You mentioned it.
And most people who have made commentary will agree that these names refer to knowledge.
Knowledge. Some say knowledge of abstraction. That is the intelligence of man. He can go
from the concrete to the abstract. He can go and rationalize or reason, we say.
In other words, he can know logic. But I am very much inclined to accept the hints of
the Sufis when they say that Allah taught Adam the names of His qualities.
Now this is knowledge of the highest form. And the angels cannot know all. For example,
Allah, one of the names of Allah is, He is One who gives death. Now angels, it seems,
don't know what is death.
Death.
Allah who willed
it.
But Adam can understand
eventually the meaning of death.
Another thing.
An angel, as philosophers
argue, cannot understand
the meaning of
patience or the care of children.
You know.
Because they don't have children.
So when Allah tells us to be patient,
we understand that. If Allah helps us, we understand Allah if He tells us to be patient.
This is a quality which Allah helps us develop. But the angels cannot have this.
In other words, the angels belonging to another dimension and not having a physical body like us
cannot exemplify some of the virtues which Allah already wants us to demonstrate.
And I think many of these names of Allah, like for example Al-Musawwir, and also Allah
is Al-Muhyi, He who gives life.
In some ways we do give life with the help of Allah.
When we have children, we are in some ways creating, naturally with the help of Allah,
we are creating lives.
And I do not think angels understand that.
They cannot know this thing.
Be careful now, don't make them angry.
No, because I cannot see them.
They're watching you now.
I'm talking to you because I cannot show you with my eyes.
So, maybe I'll be borne out with my eyes.
Watch what you say about the angels because you don't want to make them angry.
And so, the way I look at it is that I agree that these names refer to knowledge, and I
would just like to submit for your thinking, for you to develop on your own, or reject,
that maybe these names are a special form of knowledge.
They refer to those special qualities of Allah which He gave us the ability to exercise when
He, as we just mentioned, gave part of himself to us as a soul.
He breathed unto us something of his spirit.
That is our soul.
And this gives us the capacity to understand certain things.
And the angels can never know this.
It seems to me, therefore, that in our test in life, you need a body.
And you need the combination of this body with part of ourselves, which really is Allah's,
to exercise certain things in order to arrive at certain knowledge.
And this is what Allah has given us.
And that's why He has sent us to a material world,
because only we can interact in this material world with our bodies
and exemplify certain potentialities.
And the angels cannot, by virtue of their nature.
Yes, they can. They can?
They carried the throne of Sheba from...
from... they are very physical.
They can... I mean, they are... actually, they're solid in nature.
Well, they can do many things, but some they cannot. For example...
See, what I'm saying is they are very physical.
They are not... a lot of people think of angels as spirits
who can go through this wall. They can't...
They can tear it down, but they are very physical.
No, I agree with you. They are forces. They can do.
But I cannot imagine an angel having a toothache and telling Allah, Allah strengthen me with my patience to tolerate this toothache.
Certain cases.
Not all.
Because the idea here is that angels need to know certain things.
The only problem with the names of Allah is that the next verse says that God showed these things to the angels.
And said, tell me the names of these.
So they are objects.
They are the names of objects.
They are not just names; they are theories.
Yes, but verse 32 suggests that the angels know some of the names.
In 32, they say, we have no knowledge except what you already have taught us.
So angels know.
Yes, but what I'm saying is, God showed the angels something, objects,
and said, give me the names of these.
He presented them to the angels and asked them, give me the names of these.
So there is something being presented, and the angels asked to give the names of these things.
Yeah, but the angels do not seem to know.
Right, they didn't.
They didn't know.
Is there a reference to what things were shown? Like arms and feet, or people, or animals?
No, that's just an object.
It could be qualities.
How do you show a quality?
How can you show clemency?
Yes, you cannot see clemency, but you can see the effect on material things.
No, but you cannot present clemency in some way and say, what is this?
For example, on a hot day we need rain.
This is something physical, but we can say it is an expression of the quality of Allah or nothing.
It's not the quality of Allah.
Or punishment.
Or punishment, in this case maybe.
Because Allah, also one of His names, He punishes.
He is severe in punishment. Anyhow, this is a form of knowledge, for reflection.
Very good point.
But I don't want to go deeper or elaborate on it.
It's just for some who would like to...
It's really very simple.
We are at verse 34.
And this is a very good point.
The names can be anything.
Let's go back to our lesson, because it's hard to get the other details.
Okay, thirty-five.
Adam lived with his wife in paradise, and eat from it freely as you please, but do not approach this one tree, or you will fall into transgression.
studying the names of what he knows is going to happen.
The names of what he knows is going to happen.
Then Satan made them slip, and taught him to turn from his religion.
Go down as enemies to each other.
And that 'each other' refers to the devil and mankind,
or at least Adam and his wife.
And on earth will be your habitation and a provision for a while, not condemning them there forever.
Then Adam received from his Lord words, and He redeemed him.
Now, he's redeemed, but God then told him that this offense that you did is forgiven, period.
But if the ultimate objective was to send Adam and all his descendants to earth,
in order to show Satan and the angels,
what this creature was, who would worship God without ever seeing Him?
That's the second objective of our being here today.
As far as we're concerned, we are here to worship God,
to discover that God is the only Master.
It's really what 2:138 is all about.
We said, "Go down from there, all of you."
And when guidance comes to you from Me,
those who follow My guidance,
they will have no fear, nor will they grieve.
Although mankind was placed on Earth,
they're not forgotten,
they're not just left.
And we'll have the opportunity
to share some stories,
some of them,
along with a lot of people.
We'll go back.
And those who disbelieve and reject Our revelations, they are the dwellers of hell; they will abide in it forever.
There is an ocean here of Quranic revelations.
The test is frequently in the world.
It's rare that we take a step back and do those through God's will.
It's a failure if we don't take a step back and do those through the light of God's revelation.