Talking now of 76, right?
Right.
It seems to be very clear that when these, when they are by themselves, these enemies of Islam, right?
They say to each other, do you tell them of God's revelations to you and thus provide them support for the argument?
In other words, they are withholding information.
Right.
And this would be, for just a moment I have to try to...
Isn't this also connected with 42, or the same chapter, verse 42?
Yes.
Do not confound the truth with falsehood, nor shall you conceal the truth knowingly.
It is very clear that the, because he's talking to the children of Israel,
it seems that the children of Israel, knowingly, were trying to withhold
information from others.
No, from us, from the Muslims.
Yeah, from the others, non-Jews.
Right.
Yeah, I understand.
Well, first, the first to talk to the Muslims.
Yeah.
The first one who is hearing the Quran.
No, this is what I was trying to mention this morning.
That one...
Verse 75, do you, Muslims, expect them,
This is what I am trying to mention this morning, that one defect of some of the Jews, is that
they considered these revelations for themselves, alone, they were making it national, and...
But you or I may say something that is true, just from the Quran, and there is a quote for it in the Bible.
For example, there will come a prophet after Moses from his brethren who will
give us all truth, and we see this in their Bible, but they want to hide that. They don't want to give
you any support. Yeah, because they are taking these revelations only for sectarian purposes.
And if I may also, with permission also, look at their selfishness, even on
from verse 80, where others have pointed this, that they consider themselves so much of a
special group of people that even they, hell is not eternal for them.
They say, we will not suffer in hell except for a few days.
So even there they consider themselves privileged, they were a chosen people and so on.
We are God's beloved.
Yeah, so on.
And yet, your title, next one says,
the children of Israel rebel.
Terrible.
Ok, we're going to pray at 8 to 7 tonight,
and then we're going to eat first.
We're at 77.
Do they not realize that God knows everything
they conceal and everything they declare? Among them are illiterates who do not know the
Scriptures, except through hearsay and conjecture. Therefore, woe to those who distort the
Scriptures with their own hands, then say, this is from God, seeking to achieve gain.
Woe to them for distorting the Scriptures, and woe to them for their earnings only.
There are lots of people who rely, who receive the Scriptures through other people, and
And this portion of the Bible, or the Quran, or the divine teachings is a trap for the misled.
What about those people who have no access or cannot read or write?
Are they misled?
Well, no, they are not misled.
The whole thing is complete. We should look at,
but most will get
the punishment,
the retribution for those who defraud.
the truth.
For all the sins,
can we now just go to the next verse?
Because they are connected.
It's a continuation of our theme.
Because the question is
whether
these things come from God.
They say,
"We will not suffer in Hell
except for a few days."
Say, "Did you take such a promise
from God? In other words, is it found in your scripture? For God never breaks His covenant.
So, because they say this is from God, you know, 79, they're saying this is from God.
And in 80, God says, "Well, this thing that you're claiming, that you will not suffer in Hell except
for a few days, is this found in the scripture? God never breaks His
promise. Or
do you say about God what
you do not know?" You ascribe
something to Him. I think
it's from 79, no? Yes.
Indeed, anyone
who works evil and becomes
surrounded by sin,
these have deserved Hell.
They will abide therein forever.
This becomes the argument.
There is no such thing as temporary Hell.
But I must note
an article of faith of the Mahdi
believers.
The Ahmadiyya movement in Islam is a case in point, which is very important.
And if you read their translation, in the book by the Ahmadiyya, you will note that the word is manipulated here.
Forever. You will never see it.
You will see it only when it applies to Heaven, but not when it applies to Hell.
And it is also...
Even though the Arabic word in 81 and 82 is identical, their translations are not identical.
May I also add, may I add that after the Quran says this, after the Quran is blaming these Jews for saying this,
it is very clear, the Quran is saying that these Jews who say this are wrong. And there are many
Muslims, not only the Ahmadiyyas, who are falling into the very same presumption as
these Jews whom the Quran is condemning, because they say that the Prophet will intercede for them.
And therefore, the Prophet will snatch them out of Hell.
So they do the very, they say the very same thing which the Quran here condemns.
done by Jews.
And they said, "The fire will not touch us,
except for a limited number of days."
It can be... It can be...
Say to them,
Yeah.
They say the fire will not touch us except for a number of days.
Say, "Have you taken a promise from Allah?
Then Allah will never break His promise.
Or do you say about Allah what you do not know?"
Indeed.
Oh.
Whoever earns evil, and is encompassed by his sin;
those are the companions of the fire, wherein they will abide eternally.
And those who believe and do righteous works,
those are the companions of Paradise; they will abide in it eternally.
Yeah, but they skip these verses.
And when they are very successful, when you ask them about it,
what do they think of them? They say, you know, this world is enough.
it's forever. Fiha Khalidun.
Khalidun, Khalidun. Khalidun forever.
It's the same thing also with the translation of Muhammad Ali, I think.
Yeah, but he has a side note on that.
Really?
Yeah, because they split.
There are two, the Rabwah group, this is the Rabwah group, and the Lahori group.
The Lahori group has been coming closer to the orthodox.
And this group has been declared by law as a separate sect, not Islamic.
You see, Aisha said, "He sat down and my father was standing up."
He sat down, he said.
But, with wearing shoes.
Yeah, with wearing shoes.
Yeah, I am losing my shoes at the masjid,
and searching for them afterwards.
I'm worried about the shoes.
That's what we know.
For a moment, I was confused by these things.
I was worried that somebody might
take my shoes at least.
That bothers me, because I would be...
The crowd from the Jumu'ah prayer room took so much time to get me out of the place. I used to be there from time to time.
Yeah.
Sometimes we would use these covers.
They go missing, and you could steal them.
Yes.
And now, again, if they look better, you know.
They have to be right where it has to be.
Now, `amma`, that is consistent with, what did we say, chapter 3, no?
You know, something that is difficult to hear.
Don't make trouble for me.
You give me time.
If you don't agree, you can stop the tape.
It's difficult.
You don't need anything else from me.
That's right.
Nine times saying,
why did you kill your prophets?
Six say prophets, three say messengers.
Very interesting, no?
And three times,
why did you kill your messengers?
No, no, messengers, three times.
Why did you kill your prophets?
I think this distinction is important.
So not only did they kill prophets,
but they have killed Rasul.
It's terrible, right? It's terrible.
Now, going on, they also say—they're starting to argue, right?
They said, God has enjoined on us that we should not believe any messenger unless he brings us an offering
consumed by a holocaust.
Say it. Say it.
Listen to this.
Exactly the thing you're asking.
You can find out.
You see what you are now asking.
Now, what they're asking is something extraordinary, right?
A holocaust. A miracle, like a miracle.
But they killed them.
Why? Why did you kill them?
Now, I am on to the difficult... the difficult nine.
In truth, we know, the Jews killed their own people.
We have been given a hard theory, I mean, a hard belief.
And it's a theory.
And now, I want to confirm why it is just referred to as an incident.
And the conclusion is, I think they have killed Moses.
Do you know that Freud has written a book, Moses and Monotheism,
trying to show psychoanalytically that the Jews did kill Moses, and that's where the guilt comes from?
Now, I've discussed this with ulama, the ulama have told me, why does the Quran not specifically say it?
I said, when this revelation is recited to the Jews, it doesn't have to be explicit; the Jews know.
Do you know that the scholar Sellin mentioned that there is a suspicion in the book of Hosea that the tribe of Ephraim,
Yeah, one of the sons of Joseph is responsible for the killing of the prophet among the Jews?
No.
This was pointed out 100 years ago by a scholar, by the name of Sellin.
100 years ago a Protestant scholar showed that there is a tradition among the Jews that they killed Moses.
End of 1920 when the theory was born.
It is time to recover something that the Quran already suggested.
It's amazing.
I believe in this.
The Jews don't unite.
They have a history of disobeying and disrespecting Moses.
Even now.
But according to Freud, the reason why they killed Moses was because he was not only very tough, but in the long run they recognized that he was an Egyptian.
In other words, Moses was a prophet for the Jews, but, ethnically, he was an Egyptian.
Well, according to Freud, at least that's his view.
Oh, I see, I see.
Well, he grew up as an Egyptian in the house of Pharaoh.
But he was a Hebrew, one hundred percent.
But I tell you, what is a Hebrew?
One hundred percent loving your father?
That is a very interesting Freudian idea.
How a psychologist tries to prove something.
And he's quoting a Protestant.
But if Freud knows what we're talking about, he would put his head in the corner.
Because this is very interesting.
I don't know which is the worse evil, disrespecting the prophet or idolization
of the prophet. I don't know which is the... I think the idolization is the worst.
And yet by all logic, I'm not, I didn't mean to interrupt, I didn't want to take time.
In general, the Jews have more of a tendency than the Christians to be like you.
Because, you know, the Christians are so wrapped up with Jesus, that Jesus becomes an idol; they make him a god.
But the Jews do not accept that.
That's what I'm saying. I'm saying that it is worse to idolize a man.
I think Satan made a mistake.
I mean, Satan worked on having the Jews kill their prophets and messengers.
This backfired.
A higher proportion of Jews worship God.
God. Yeah. Without idolizing the prophets and messengers. And he didn't like that. So
he tried. Yeah. He got the other extreme, the Christians. That's right. And then when
he came to the Muslims, he did exactly what he did to the Christians, but in a concealed
way. He's improving himself. I mean, he got the Jews to kill the prophets, kill the messengers,
No, it's through experience.
desecrate them and disrespect them.
And this made them...
It's very beautiful, huh?
Yeah, it's very beautiful.
And this made them worship God.
And he said, I don't want that.
Let's make them idolize the Prophet.
I was reading another book.
I think I want to show it to you.
Because the author of the book is Jewish.
Yeah.
They killed Jeremiah.
He said they killed Jeremiah.
Oh, yeah.
They were running from Babylonia to Egypt.
And this Prophet was stopping them.
They killed...
not Isaiah.
and Ezekiel
and all the other
most of them.
I know Jeremiah,
because I read
in his book,
and it's very
interesting
because
how they threw
the ropes.
It's almost
an illusion.
They threw
his rope.
He was weaker
than Moses.
He took advantage
of that.
Now the secret is that the Jews are terribly afraid of it.
Because it's telling them so many things.
In fact, it says in one of the verses that this Quran tells the Children of Israel most of these things.
And they know it. And they know it as they know their own children.
Oh, it says that it tells the Children of Israel many of the things wherein they dispute.
Are you familiar with that verse?
Yes, yes, I've read it many, many times.
So it specifically says what you just said now.
It's amazing that Barakat was quoting it the other day.
I wrote an essay on this, and I showed it to some Arabs.
One of them was a Syrian minister on sanitation.
He liked the essay.
Very short essay.
The other one was racist.
And he said, put it in summary.
So that's what he told me.
And as for what Professor Mahmoud said is that the Jews killed Moses and Harun.
Do you believe it or not? You know what Khalaf said?
Yeah.
He said, those Jews are capable of anything, I believe it.
Yeah, yeah.
But it's racist too.
Yeah.
In these times, you must realize there are many of them who are really righteous from among the Jews.
But the Quran says a few of them, you know what I mean?
Yeah.
A few of them.
A few of them, I don't know, it seems to me that it's the same proportion in total.
A few of the Jews, a few among the Christians, a few among the Muslims, will make it.
Some of them are righteous, and some of them are wrong too.
What do you want in Arabic?
So, what do you want?
Well, minhum ummatun qaimah wa kathirun.
Minhum, minhum.
Minhum ummatun qaimah wa kathirun minhum sa'a ma kanu ya'malun.
I don't know if you know the story, but the story of Samuel, the prophet, he was the...
And Samuel is the one that they went to, you know.
They asked their prophet for a king.
But like, it's not the same thing.
No.
Some of them, they didn't want to fight until they had a commander.
So Saul was appointed.
Yeah.
They didn't know who did it.
There is another one also about the holy cow.
says they know.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, the whole
surah is named after that story.
There's got to be
a lot of stuff in there.
We just
went too fast over it tonight.
We really didn't.
He didn't have any deadlines to meet.
Yeah.
It's okay.
So that's one thing I was wondering if there's...
if the relationship, the minimum relationship to why they were seeking that special heifer,
the heifer, which was yellow...
But they're all yellow.
God was not referring to a specific heifer.
He just went along with their demands.
But...
Well, I know there were many of them.
Just to pick out any one that satisfies this description.
Not too old and not too young.
It was never worked.
It has a bright color, pleasing to the beholders, and there isn't any blemish in it.
There are lots of them.
They are hiding something. These people don't want to do it because they are hiding something.
They are just complicating things, like you said.
But they also don't want to push it too far.
Right, that too. Symbolic.
Yeah, because the truth comes out.
At the end of the day, God revealed what you tried to conceal.
That's about the miracle though.
In 71 it says, now you've brought the truth.
So they slaughtered it, though they almost did not do it.
Did the man revive after that, to say who was the killer?
Probably simultaneously.
Was it a murder in conjunction with not wanting to slay that cow?
Well, there didn't have to be a connection with the cow, initially.
The cow then... God said to strike the victim with part of the cow.
And that was the way of resurrecting the flesh.
So those were the days when God was performing these visible miracles, you know, and
then in Surah 17, God stopped that because it didn't do any good anyway.
And to think they saw all the miracles, Moses split the sea in front of them, they
crossed it, they had manna and quails, they had springs gushing in front of them, and all this,
then they worshipped the calf, you know.
So in Surah 17, God stopped doing these miracles because they didn't do any good anyway.
The same story is true for Muhammad, because the Quran says, "We don't do this anymore."
Yeah.
What does it say?
Fantastic blessing or a terrible curse?
And the same is true with the Quran.
Look at, look how Israel is repeating the whole scandal. What a scandal this is.
This doesn't make sense. Of course it makes sense in light of the Quran, but I mean on the physical level it doesn't make sense at all.
This is now the second time.
Israel, today, is the second time.
The first time was probably Hitler or the Babylonians... well, no, I don't think it would be Babylonian
because I mean they had already been kicked out of Israel, out of the territory,
by the Romans before the Quran came down, and in the way you've translated, the two times are in the future.
Yeah, so it would have to be after, still coming up. Well, what I was wondering is if...
if the Arab invasion thing was early on, like around 1948, when they were fighting with the
Arabs in that land, or they were fighting back and forth, I don't know.
What was happening then, was...
the Arabs were tasked to attack them in that land.
The invasion from Egypt in 1967 didn't actually get into Israeli soil.
Even their armies didn't come into Israel, so they didn't invade them in their homeland.
That's right. They had to be bound by religion, by belief.
They had to be the people of God that we have here in this world.
The Germans, they, you know, they did it because God commanded them to enter their country.
I mean, that's, you know, God made a situation to send them in; that the people that are
vain don't ask God for leave.
They may leave their belief for certain parties, all kinds of things.
But they're still servants of God, anyway.
Yeah.
Unwitting, unwitting servants of God.
Yeah, but they've already done that.
Right.
I know they were fighting with the Arabs.
I hope we have this understood better now.
You know, it's common, though.
People do fight in the Mideast.
When they have a big group of people, they fight.
They fight with the Jews.
They don't shy from death.
They're a very heavy-duty people.
I know that.
But they're talking.
They're not going to take that kind of thing.
They're going to press among the Jews.
Yeah.
Who is going to have weight with them?
And they are going to get the Jews.
They have no...
They are the ones...
They are the ones who disbelieve in Ar-Rahman.
But they'll be the very ones who...
Then they will be in distress.
It's an oppressed people.
Again and again, they do.
And the Copts are oppressed.
And they're supporting this, or that.
But that's what they do.
They've got to come through.
This is for you too.
I mean, you know what happened to my wife?
They have to take away everything.
Everything, yeah.
Only the upper teeth?
All of the upper ones.
Not the lower ones.
And even that is the next part.
So, the operation is on.
You know, she was in a concentration camp there.
Yeah, and all of these lack of vitamins and so on, she was a young girl.
She seemed to be positive.
So, what happened is that, those dates that she gave,
she only gave, for me to eat.
Because she could not eat.
But I could chew them.
She liked it very much.
My mother is 88 years old, my mother, she has perfect teeth, except for two missing.
But they're all her own teeth.
And my father, my father has all his teeth.
Those are leaves?
Yeah.
Yeah, you see, you make a tea of it.
All of them.
All of them stayed in.
Not even a filling.
Really?
Yeah.
`Alaykum as-salam.
How about you people?
Are they good?
Yeah.
I was asking.
Do you know Molokhia?
I don't know.
I thought it was a strictly different thing.
No.
Yeah.
I know what the leaves should look like.
They are like this.
Yeah.
Plain green.
This grows in our country.
Wow.
Very nice.
It's very green.
It's very common.
I brought seeds with me from Egypt.
Alaikum assalam.
What's the verse, Maryam?
Two, one.
Okay, we'll start at 62. Yeah, you're right, 62.
Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
Verse 62 is subtitled, Minimum Requirement for Salvation.
And this is one of the most important verses and verities in Quran, yeah.
Yes. 2:87.
This is a very important doctrine in Islam.
So people will come to you and ask, can a Christian make it to Jannah?
Can a Jew make it to Jannah?
Can a person who converted from Christianity to Judaism,
Judaism to Islam, or Islam to Christianity,
can this person make it to Jannah?
Very good question. Are the Muslims the only people who will make it to heaven?
So, the answer is in this verse. Those who believe, those who are Jewish, the Christians,
and the converts, any of them who believe in God and the Last Day, and live a righteous life,
shall receive their recompense from their Lord, have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
So I hope you add this part of the verse in its sense. They shall receive the
recompense from their Lord and they have nothing to fear nor will they grieve. If
you join any other religion in the past or in the future and they tell you that
these are the only people who will go to heaven, you will take off, just flee, because they are wrong.
What this verse is telling us, that anybody who believes in God, the Creator of this universe, the ruler of this universe,
and believes in the Day of Judgment, accountability, resurrection, and lives a righteous life,
that person has attained the minimum requirement of salvation and will go to heaven.
Whether he is Jewish, or Christian, or Muslim, or Buddhist, or anything. Yes.
Well, then they don't believe in God?
But they do.
No.
No, you must believe in God.
I used to be a Catholic, okay? And I used to, well, I'm sorry, but as a Catholic, I was so, you know, I really believed that, you know, what we say. But I was always told, you know, "Listen to this, God is good."
Right, so you don't believe, you didn't believe in God. You believed in a false God.
I believed that there was something else too.
No, no, no. Here, believing in God means you believe in the creator of this universe. Now, if you believe in Jesus or in Buddha with God, you're not believing in God.
Well, that's what, yeah, well, I mean, now I realize that, but that's what Christians are attached to.
Right, right.
God says He makes them satisfied with their belief. That is their choice, that would make them satisfied with that.
But this statement is regardless of anything else. Any person who believes in God, and we're talking about only one thing,
There is only one God, and you're either believing in Him or another false god.
You believe in Jesus as God, and you firmly believe in God, but you're not believing in God.
You are believing in a false god.
And believing in God also implies believing in God alone.
Because if you believe in God, you will not go to minute creatures as God.
then you don't believe in God, because when you believe in God, you know that He is
too glorious to have a son. You understand? You understand? Of
course. You understand that God does not need to reproduce himself, does not need to preserve
His species, and that reproduction and children is a characteristic of
mortals. So when you say a son of God, you don't believe in God in the long run.
Yeah?
Can you tell me if a creature that doesn't believe in God, they do it in spirit?
Right.
Then God is changing the nature of life for them?
They will do it, if they believe in God they will do it by instinct.
And if they come across it in the Quran, they will have no objection to it. They will do it.
In fact, there are a few individuals who reach the belief in God and they do the prayer by instinct.
They fall prostrate. The answer to the question in Surah 3, verse, I think it is 165.
Surah 3. Let's go to that one because
this is the Quran.
We have to take the whole,
the whole of the Quran.
Okay, I'll give you the verse number.
No.
You can't do it.
Yes.
It is 100 and what?
OK.
Righteous Jews and Christians.
Now this is Chapter 3, verse 113. "They are not all alike.
Among the people of the scriptures, the Jews and Christians, there are those who are righteous. They
recite God's scriptures throughout the night and they fall prostrate." See? They
actually do. I've met people like that. So they are doing this all by instinct.
However, they don't have the complete, the correct niyyah, you know. It's like they are
feeding their soul, but not the complete needs. It's like you feeding your body only
starch, carbohydrates, without the vitamins, and so forth. Your body will grow
and will be sustained, but it will be weak. That's why the next verse is important.
114 says, they believe in God and the Last Day, they advocate righteousness,
forbid evil, and they hasten towards righteousness. They are pious. Now next
one is the one I mean, whatever good they do will never go unrewarded. So they'll be
rewarded for what they're doing, but they do not have the complete
ritual, the complete creed. They have to come to Islam, they have to do their prayers. Our
advantage is that we have the whole thing described to us in detail,
as to how to develop and grow our soul.
But a Christian, or a Jew, or a Buddhist, or a Hindu, who comes to the conviction that he believes,
or she believes in God, and when I say God, you know what I'm talking about.
Not Buddha, and not a monkey, and not a cow, and not Jesus.
God, that's one God.
If that person believes in God, they will do the prayer instinctively.
They do it.
They bow and prostrate,
and they commemorate,
they meditate on God,
and they praise, they glorify God,
and they ask God for forgiveness,
they repent when they make a mistake,
and they are beautiful and they go to heaven.
This is all that is required.
Idolizing
a prophet,
or a certain person is wrong. All the Prophets want us to forget them and worship God alone.
Ya Mansoor, the brother who was sitting where Iqbal was, he with the beard, he was in Phoenix,
he lives in Phoenix, he called me yesterday, and he's writing, and he says that,
talking about the requirements, and he says, one is ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah, the first one.
You declare ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah, ash-hadu anna Muhammadan Rasool Allah.
And I said, no, that shahada is not possible.
Because how about Noah? What is the shahada for Noah, 'Rasulullah?'
Yes.
How about Moses?
And who?
How about Ibrahim or Jesus?
Why? The Quran tells us twice that we should not make distinction among the Prophets.
But what is required of anybody is to declare that there is no God except God.
So this is a very important point.
And it shows the tolerance of, well this is the truth,
God is the most tolerant.
And what is required is, some people don't even have a religion,
they come to the conviction that the universe is created by a creator,
who must be working, and then God takes over.
Once the person makes a decision, God teaches them to do the Salat.
And they may even do more than we do, more than the five prayers.
Because the five prayers are the minimum.
Whenever you feel like it, you should get up and do some prayers.
But don't say it costs too much, either.
But because of the hunger of their soul, and because they're reaching, they are fueled,
they may do a lot more glorifying of God, asking forgiveness, everything.
They don't believe that Jesus is the son of God or a God.
And they don't believe that Mary has any power
and they don't believe that Christ is divine.
divine.
They believe in God. So this is
I'm going to read the verse again.
Verse 62.
Those who believe,
like us,
those who are Jewish,
the Christians, and the converts,
any of them who believe in
God and the Last Day and lead
a righteous life shall receive their recompense from their Lord, and they have
nothing to fear nor will they grieve." Now this verse makes the hadith people very
uncomfortable because the hadith goes against this. Hadith will tell you that you have to be a
Muslim who believes in God and that Muhammad is included in order to go to heaven.
Hadith will tell you, a Jew or a Christian will go to hell, regardless, because it's made by Satan.
Any other questions on this important point?