This is a sign from Quran.
I am using a map. This is the way in which God has made it and put a sign in it.
It is the proof from the Quran that is for this place.
What if there is an idol inside the mosque?
What does that mean?
It's a little weird because I don't know anybody who is an Ahmadi.
There's no mosque.
Yeah, not many other people. There's no mosque.
That's what I'm saying.
Actually, it's not a mosque.
It's not a mosque. Why is there no mosque?
It's like saying there are only churches and synagogues.
There are only churches and synagogues.
You can count it as one of them.
How did you get there?
You have to find out.
If I am in Tempe, or Phoenix, or New York,
and I want to pray in the middle of the afternoon, I'll walk in any of these mosques and I'll go make my wudu and pray.
Just like at work, I'll go make my wudu and find a place to go pray.
Well, here we have a choice. A mosque where all they love is the minaret, for honoring people.
So, I wouldn't, I wouldn't, I would run for my life. I would run for my life.
But in another place, there isn't that choice.
Right? Then it's just a matter of convenience. I pray where I am.
This one is here, so I can pray in it.
When we would go to the Ahmadiyya mosque here in Tucson, we would go to the idol of Imam Ahmad.
Let's move it up.
It is open 24 hours a day, so you wouldn't go there, you wouldn't go there, you wouldn't go there.
It's a real small place.
It looks like something of a miniature dome.
Yes, you say the Name.
See, what I'm saying is, maybe, like, you're in Los Angeles, and there is the Islamic Center of Southern California.
Well, of course, have you seen it? But maybe there are people who go there, who talk only about Quran.
But I went one time, and they just cut off the microphone, yeah, but the people got the
message, or some of the people did, yeah.
There are also some people who don't know how to do it, but they think they know how to do it.
I'm sorry if you need to think that, but I know how to do it.
Yeah.
It takes time, but we have a bunch of people that can do it.
So, it's very nice to know how to do it.
Yeah, yeah, I get it when I put the light on.
When I put the light on, there are lots of people in the kitchen who are like,
Yeah, we got the lesson.
There were three people who became very emotional.
They were yelling at me.
I'm very thankful for that.
Remember that?
I don't think anyone would forget.
And then I had, actually, a long discussion after that about the very thing that the brother was talking about.
When I tell them that I am a Muslim, I tell them that Muhammad is a Muslim too.
If I go to pray, I tell them that I am a Muslim. They say, no, you are not. Why?
I was going on with the names of Muhammad, that they give to Muhammad, they give him actual names of God, exclusive names of God, they give to Muhammad, like Al-Muhaymin, one of Muhammad's names.
This means Muhammad is the supreme being.
Taha is in a Surah, you know, you heard it today.
That's one of his names that are written in mosques on the wall.
A servant, a healer.
Yes, Muhammad, a servant.
I have a list here.
202 names.
God has 99 names.
Muhammad has 202.
How can they believe that?
Unbelievable, isn't it? I don't blame you if you don't believe me, but I have the list for you.
I don't know if you believe me, but I have the list for you.
.
It means Furqan, in fact. Or "the statute." It means the criterion, in fact.
When a person has faith, it is a law from God that enables him to distinguish right from wrong.
Well, lots more people are hearing that, that stuff that you say, from all the communication and stuff.
You say there's a lot of positive response from all of them.
So, you've been saying that you're getting a lot of positive response from all over the world.
Yes.
So, have there been any correspondence with people trying to do these things,
and they're mocked where they are?
The last one that was sent to me, I think, from Singapore.
Yeah.
This fellow who lost his friends.
Did you read it?
No.
You read it, don't you?
Some people read it.
They don't know about it.
That person, he said, chose
God.
And when he came to that point,
he gave up his friends and said,
"I need Your contentment."
See, when you see the truth,
there is nothing anybody can do.
It doesn't matter what they do.
You're willing to lose your neck
or die.
As for his friends, well, it's too bad.
You don't really care...
You have no choice anymore. Once you see the truth, you have no choice.
And you really don't care about pleasing people after a while, you know.
That's right, exactly. In fact, we see them as unfortunate,
these kinds of people.
That's why there's so much in the Quran about,
about, "Oh, I wish I didn't take this friend as a friend.
He took me away from the message after it came to me."
I've seen some people that...
and God says that many people are going to hell
because of friendship with some other people.
Well, that's because they put the friendship,
they'd rather keep the friendship than keep their belief.
Right.
We had a friend of ours, and he said,
"I lost a friend, but I'm happy I saved my belief."
You see that?
I see some people with...
I don't know, I suppose it's just a matter of time.
Sometimes when we don't see people respond,
I mean, you still have to be careful, because it does take time, because I see people that,
you know, they seem to be believing this, but they won't accept it. I mean, even as Muslims,
you know, as people have grown up with it, that they've been so turned off by, you know,
they actually, you know, don't accept all this stuff that we're against,
that they've actually kind of rejected the Quran, because they're still convinced that that
stuff is actually being taught there because it's been interpreted so, they'll read those verses
and they've been taught that that's what it means, so they reject it and reject it all
because it's a slow, hopeful process, because I think they're really good people there that
you know, in time, that they will. But I mean, I can see them saying, "I can't accept this," and they're
interpreting it in such a totally opposite way, because they can't even see the correct
interpretation. That means they're saying that these verses are non-existent. They're just
corrupt beliefs. So it's a confusing thing, I feel that I don't
know how to explain it.
I was talking to an Iranian who was talking about how
people in his country were prevented from reading the Quran,
which is put in the background. And I was trying to explain
there's this big growth around the Quran that has to be cut away
before the pure copy of the Quran can be used.
They put it up on the shelf and they don't read it anymore; they have to wash before touching it.
"You can't even translate the Quran into any other language."
They want to keep the Quran away from people.
"You can't just put it so holy that you can't translate it, you can't touch it, you can't look at it, you can't read it. We have other things."
"We have other things that were related to us from the past."
Right.
I mean, the fact that it's actually happened, you know,
it's true for people who have not had much education in the Middle East in their lives.
And the poor people in Morocco are just illiterate.
And they have their hopes and their cares and all sorts of things in their mind,
and also the sayings of the king, the big sayings of the king, like that.
The Dahir.
In other words,
the royal decree.
Dahir.
The name for a law made by the king.
This is put on the same level as the Hadith.
Or more importantly.
I mean, they put it, you know,
symbolically on the same level as the Hadith.
and sanctified by the Quran.
The king's picture is with words from the Quran
and his words are
therefore the word of God,
you know, indirectly, even when they mention the saints,
I thought that was the list of their iniquity.
We have the right, now.
But the Muslims, you know,
the head of the Islamic Da'wah Council in India is a,
is a guy like us.
Exactly.
They haven't found their guidance yet.
They don't have the proof.
Exactly like the Quran alone.
The head of the Islamic Da'wah Council in India, his name is Waheeduddin Khan.
What's his name?
Is he an Arab or Indian?
He's Indian.
He writes in English.
Okay, we're very late, so it was a very interesting discussion, so let's close it, go home, take
a good sleep, come back at six o'clock for Salat prayers.
Do you want a cake?
Oh, good, I'll have a piece. My soul is pleased.
Rukhansa Khan.
Rukhansa.
I have a question.
There is a verse, 2:133.
That's right.
And it says,
Baqarah, Baqarah, Baqarah.
It says, continue to worship your one God,
the God of your father Abraham,
And, these are the fathers, Abraham, Ishmael, and Isaac, the fathers.
This was to Jacob's sons, his children. To Jacob's children. The one talking is Jacob.
Right.
He's the God of your fathers.
Your fathers are Abraham, Ishmael, and Isaac.
Okay. Isaac was the great...
Isaac was Jacob's father.
Alright. Do you get it?
Yes.
And there are other verses, the hundred and thirty-fourth and the hundred and forty-first,
the identical verse.
Yes, yes.
Right?
Why is it repeated?
The Quran does this quite often.
Just to, for emphasis.
Yes.
Okay. Al-Fatiha.
Yes, although it may of course
ultimately be quite different from one country to another, depending on the dissatisfactions.
I think it has to do with the world that we live in, which is a world of revolutionaries.
When you're in a car, or a mountain, or whatever you want to call it. Now,
when you want to go to the Ka'bah, actually this is, this is a fact, the hills in Mecca,
where you have to drive around to go to the Ka'bah. Now, the shortest distance to the Ka'bah would be to
go this way. Even though the Ka'bah is dead straight, if you go up the hill or up the
mountain and then down, you'll go to the Ka'bah in a straight line. But you don't do that
when you go to the Ka'bah, you go like this. Therefore, the shortest distance, the right
Qibla according to them would be this way, even though the Ka'bah is here, because the
shortest distance is around the mountain or the hill. And the earth is the same way. And
between us and Mecca is part of the earth, part of the globe.
So it's like a hill between you and Mecca, and even though, if you want to go to the Ka'bah,
while you walk in this direction, you will still face this direction,
because your soul can go through the mountain, and through the wall.
Well, some of them, some of them, I cannot see with my own eyes, but if you follow, if you follow very well, you will see that there is a system.
You mean the software system?
Yes.
Did they go by the software system or how the plane goes?
Yes, but I can't follow that chart.
I told you, let's take the map and then go to it again, isn't it?
Oh, on the map?
On the map.
Right.
Let's find it out.
But they don't go by the map.
No, no, no.
Yes.
That's right.
It's a cheat.
But then the hadith says you have to take 20 minutes to the north.
Something that's 20 minutes, you have to take to the north east.
Of course, we told them they're wrong, but God doesn't want them to pray.
He said, God said, if you don't want to worship Me alone, I don't want you, you know,
praying in the right direction.
But we came to a point where the most important reason, the most important reason for praying
North-East was that the masjids in Tucson are praying East.
Yes, they're really doing that, kind of going over there.
I mean now, even if they find out that the right direction is, is what we're following,
they will find some other direction.
They don't want to find the right direction.
If the direction is from here, then we walk in a straight line.
But if we look in this direction, then we walk in another direction.
Did you see the point that Hamid is saying?
Let's get back together here.
Hamid was raising the point that if you walk in a straight line, you're going to hit Mecca.
But he flew.
So, if you fly from the south of Egypt, if you go on a straight line, you will hit Mecca.
Now, people who are praying right there, they're standing in circles around the Ka'bah.
and each position is part of a straight line.
Okay, now these straight lines are supposed to extend all over the Earth,
without any line cutting them.
Now what they are doing, for example, if they look in the North East,
they may, if they go that line, they may hit.
I don't think they will.
If they hit the Ka'bah somehow, that line will cut the straight lines
that are going from the Ka'bah.
Yeah, yeah.
You understand?
Then, just to be clear, about Abraham's place, or where he was,
when Abraham and Ishmael built the Ka'bah,
it says there's a focal point.
And the focal point has to be a point.
What's the point, you know?
Yeah.
But if you make a line that is curving,
what they're doing is a line that is curving.
They're not looking anywhere.
That couldn't happen.
Yeah, I mean the focal point would have to be the source of the ray, or something.
Anyway, so there is a commandment that we shall face it.
It is very important, but we cannot take it lightly.
I was in situations where people were praying this way, this and this way.
We had the Iranian group here in this mosque meeting every Saturday.
And they would face this way.
Yeah, you see.
Now they're exaggerating.
Now they're facing very north.
Those people there, I think, prayed that way.
It's interesting here, I just want to talk about...
Let's listen to God.
I think one of the things that confuses people now
is that they are being handed all these little compasses
that have instructions on them,
which give these really weird directions.
They vary a lot around the world.
But here, we see, I mean, we see here that
he's saying, we saw you, Muhammad,
turning your face about the sky.
So he's using the sky as a guide to find his direction.
Now, it tells us over and over again in the Quran that the stars are there for guidance by
night, correct?
So, if we look for a direction on the surface of the Earth following the stars as a guide,
we have to be following those lines rotating around the Earth, so that reinforces the idea
of those lines of rotation, if it's not lines on the surface itself.
There is no way they can justify that Qibla in the North East, except by this kind of claim they have.
The only way, because Zuma and Tarek and the others were debating with that individual on an individual and group basis,
and they went together to the geography department, and all the answers came, this is the right direction.
Well, how long ago did this whole business start, I mean?
Where?
Yeah, here in Tucson, but I mean in most of the communities I've been in.
How long has this thing been going on?
No, there were no differences between East and West.
No, but it's all over the country, all over the world they're doing it.
It became general, because the MSA, as it all started here, the MSA issued directions to all the branches everywhere that they shall face North-East.
And, unfortunately, North-East in the United States. And, unfortunately, the United Muslim Group also started to follow that.
Yeah. Yeah. They make a point. It's only because of us.
It's funny, actually, but they go out of their way to point out that our prayer direction is wrong.
They don't want to pray in the right direction.
Now, I'm going to pass the globe around, bring the globe, and if I look at where Tucson, Arizona is,
and where Mecca is...
Can you be sure about these map projections?
Yeah, tell me about it.
It's natural. It's natural geometry, I'd say, anyway,
because of the position of the building.
I'm going to pass the globe around, and if you locate Tucson, Arizona on this string,
and then Mecca is right here. It's very slightly south of east to draw the line.
So I'm going to pass this around and you can look at Tucson and Mecca. It's very clear.
Now, Mecca is right here and Tucson is here. The shortest distance, if you follow this line.
It's like you put a needle right here that will come out here. And this will mark it
exactly our direction here. Because the soul goes through the earth. This material doesn't mean a thing.
Well we're not, I mean our prayers aren't going through the earth. They're just the direction of...
A point of faith. Right. Well nothing's going in the other way. That's just where we face.
We're just in performance of a commandment, that's all.
It's a commandment, and nothing's going to that location.
I don't know, maybe, maybe there is.
I thought along the same lines.
Please pass it again.
But you actually, if you concentrate enough, your soul actually will go there.
I have to tell you this, but don't let it freak you out, but it is part of the lessons that God teaches us.
At one time I was interested in the out-of-body experiences.
I think I mentioned that, and I tried it, but I don't recommend it to anybody.
But when I tried it, I went through the ceiling.
And I noticed that these walls don't mean a thing.
I could see my body down there.
And I learned from that that the soul does not stop.
The first time, I just tried to return to it.
What I experienced next was strange.
Of course, it's weird.
You feel like you're never going to get back to your body.
Pardon me, Doctor?
You feel afraid you're never going to get back to your body.
The fear is, you see, that you're not going to get back to your body.
And this reverses later on,
where you don't want to go back to your body.
Because your body is not feeling well, and you don't feel any of the pain.
It's a way to get rid of the headache or the pain.
It's only good for a while, right?
Like for two hours.
I mean, it's good for a while.
It's fine for the beginning.
The beginning is fine.
Seriously.
I'm serious.
When you really concentrate on your prayer,
when you really concentrate on your prayer,
this ordinary station,
you had before prayer,
is forgotten temporarily.
And after this,
tahweel,
But after this tahweel,
I would like to raise a question.
I'm not so sure of the answer myself, but something that we can reflect on.
Let's concentrate.
Let's look at the verses now.
Yeah.
Now, it says here that, referring to the Qibla now, as the Ka'bah, it says here, 145,
However, even if you show the followers of previous scripture, every kind of miracle,
they will not follow your Qiblah.
However, before that, it says, even those who received previous scripture recognize
that this is the truth from their Lord.
Then 146, those who received previous scripture recognize this, just as they recognize their
own children.
The question I want to raise is this.
Is Allah not telling the Jews that in the final analysis, the right Qibla even for them
should be from their great-great-grandfather Abraham?
Because I note, this entered my mind recently, but I've never read any tafsir, wherein
the commentators say, this is telling the Jews now, that the Ka'bah is the first Qibla.
But the Jews are becoming also very nationalistic, they are still thinking of Al-Quds.
No, they don't have anything there now. They don't have anything.
The Qibla, I think, must be ascertained in the Sunnah of God now.
And they spread it.
Is it certain?
But they conquered the city.
So I'm just asking that question.
Is this telling the Jews that if they want to follow the real Qibla, they must move towards the Ka'bah?
Although I'm afraid now if the Jews come to believe that, they might decide to take it later.
Right.
Because we better not say it.
It becomes a holy land.
But it is the holy land for all. According to the Quran, many Jews are believers.
Many Jews are Muslims. Isn't that right?
Many.
Some Jews and Muslims.
Yes.
Some Hindus and some Buddhists.
Therefore that's also a holy land.
No, I'm not afraid.
They might invade it.
Nothing happens without the will of God.
This is the truth from your Lord.
Do not harbor any doubts.
Let's finish this subject with the knowledge that we have a commandment from God, and we
have to face the Qibla in Mecca, when we pray.
And it's a wonderful commandment because, as you see, we stand in one line,
facing the same direction. It's a very good organizational point.
You can imagine if we didn't have that, we'd be looking in a hundred different directions.
It would be very difficult.
Right. Right. Exactly. Right. That's the point.
We see that in Mecca, in the circle, you know, these people say,
I think in general that the most undisciplined people on this earth are Muslims.
But when they pray, they are the most disciplined people.
It's amazing, layer after layer, all of them, it is fantastic.
Did you see the movie?
Yeah, but I didn't know. I still don't know.
See, in the movie you see, but when you're there, you're part of the prayer, you have things to do.
You see, I had to miss a rak'ah just to see the movie.
And it's really dramatic.
You can't top it, and you'll see it's different.
You'll look, you'll look positioned.
Okay, so the only ones standing up are you,
are you two or them?
No, no, I'm standing up.
The only one.
Oh, you're not up there.
Oh, you can stand up there.
Did they call on you or anything?
They were coming to see me,
I think I'll have to do it.
Let's go to 2:148, page 16.
2:148 says, "To each is a direction.
Therefore, you shall race
towards righteous works.
Wherever you may be, God will bring you all together.
God is omnipotent."
"Wherever you may go, you shall turn your face,"
and there is a repetition, "you shall turn your face towards the Sacred Masjid.
This is the truth from your Lord. God is never unaware of anything you do."
"Wherever you may go, you shall turn your face towards the Sacred Masjid.
And wherever you may be, you shall turn your faces towards it."
So that the people will have no argument against you, except the wicked among them. Do not fear
and fear Me instead, that I may complete My blessings upon you, that you may be guided."
So you can see the repetition, indicating how important the commandment is, you see,
what is the message?
A blessing such as the sending of a messenger from among you,
to recite for you our signs, and to sanctify you,
and to teach you the scripture and wisdom, and to teach you what you never knew.
Therefore, you shall remember Me, that I may remember you, and be thankful to Me. Do not be unappreciative.
Any questions on this part? Yes.
Yes.
In the case of those, the Christians, the Hindus, the Buddhists, the Muslims and so forth.
Because 145 says that.
They will not follow your Qibla, nor should you follow their Qibla.
145 is related to that.
Yes, the direction of Mecca is for us. To each congregation is a law and a way, and we are not to follow their law.
So God says to the soul, "From Me is peace and righteousness." All of religion is peace and righteousness.
What's the time for prayer?
One minute is left. So it's about three o'clock.
Okay.
One minute for the prayer, so we can pray after we get back to our place, and finish this last part.
minute.
Okay, one minute is left.
Right, it's about six o'clock.
Okay, one minute.
Okay, so one minute is the last minute. So, do we have one minute left or are we done?
You may come to God because you want to be happy in this world and the Hereafter.
So after a year of praying five times a day, fasting the month of Ramadan, following God's
law, you still have problems.
Then you say, what is this? I came to
God because I want
to be happy. How come I have problems?
Then
you see, you're not a Muslim.
You didn't come to God. You're coming to happiness.
You must be proven
that you
know that God is the Master.
It doesn't matter what happens to you.
Happiness or misery or accidents.
You're coming to God.
What I mean is, it's a knowledge that is established in your mind, a conviction, that it doesn't matter what happens, it's not going to change.
Therefore, you must be proven, you must be shown that you have reached that conviction, and that is proven by steadfastness.
Steadfastness is very important. It may take 15 years, it may take 20 years, until you attain that steadfastness, it may take 2 months.
But the state of perfect happiness is not the object.
The object is belief in God, knowing that God is the Master.
In fact, when you say, why is this happening to me?
You're not a Muslim, you're not submissive, you're objecting.
You are objecting.
You're not a Muslim yet, and you don't deserve the perfect happiness.
Where there are no problems.
When you say, why is this happening to me?
I prayed my five prayers.
Because you haven't come to God, you have come to happiness.
This is your objective.
You want a life without any problems, so this is what you want, and this is what you're
worshipping.
Now, what are the choices?
You can be steadfast for 15 years, and then you attain the perfect conviction, the perfect
happiness that comes as a bonus, you see.
That's something on the side, not an objective.
It will come as a natural consequence, and you will be convicted that God is the only Master.
The other choice is to have, say, 15 years of misery, and then go on.
In other words, you be steadfast for 15 years and then attain perfect happiness,
or have the 15 years of misery plus eternal misery. That's the other choice.
There is no other choice.
So, steadfastness is very important.
Seek help through steadfastness.
You are steadfast. You are unshakable.
It doesn't matter what happens.
Something happens to you.
Why did this happen to you? I'm not going to pray today.
It's cutting your losses. Why do you pray?
When you are convinced, nothing is going to change that knowledge.
Okay, question's good.
Very good.
I was going to say, I was trying to think about the other thing.
I was trying to think about the other thing.
Sometimes, you know, we can talk about, I know when we disobey God,
we all act like a kid,
but I remember our first time seeing a child trying to get drunk,
I would say, I don't think there's anything tempting in that,
the first time that we did that,
you know, we all had a gift,
and we were told, you know, "Take care of that."
That's why the verses of the test came immediately after steadfastness.
Because God wants you to show the angels and to show Satan that you are convinced that He is the only Master,
and nothing is going to change that no matter what happens.
Extreme success, extreme failure, death, sickness, death of a world.
But then, it was like, I know, if I miss the Quran study, if I miss a beat, but then...
still, what I'm trying to say is, you don't want to, you don't want to, you don't want to.
I went through a 15-year test, and again, not submitting, but that same test was like a 40-year test.
So is that going to take you around the world?
You know, like if you think, "Oh wow, this happened, so then, okay, I'm in this test."
The test, in your case, was being far away without transportation. That's the test.
Now, so you have to struggle, you have to go around and find a ride and do what you can.
You have to do your best to go to the Quran study.
That's what you're supposed to do.
But then, if you can't find a ride, and there is no way you can make it,
then you satisfy the requirement, and then you submit to that.
You have to submit.
After you do what you're supposed to do, after you do your best,
and you cannot accomplish it, then you submit.
You don't object.
Some of us do a lot of this.
I get, I get students.
I always remember when I was teaching the young men and women,
the emotions involved are intense.
And I think this is the case when I talk to a student,
and I notice that there are other students who have the same feeling.
But something that kind of surprises me,
because I'm not the same kind of guy as probably other students,
is that I'm past that age, and they say,
"Well, you know, we don't have jobs, and we need more money, we need more money, we need more money."
"So a ton of money would be okay, but we don't have a lot."
We are told we should be patient, because it's good.
But sometimes it's really difficult.
It's a challenge.
You want your reward, but you didn't even work.
God is good for everything.
I even have to say that I'm happy that I've read this.
because I didn't get it before. But my faith didn't get worse because I didn't get it. My faith didn't get worse. And on the opposite, I think it's...
The teachings of the Quran, the meaning of the Quran will come to you at the right time, when you read it, at the time you need it.
It's like, you know, the Quran is never a boring book, but every time you read it, you get something new out of it.
And you say, "I've read this a million times, how come I never saw this before?"
Yes, yes. Because you were not ready for it.
But, but, you know, it's so important that I think that this is a, the real realization that needs to be achieved, I think.
The lesson that many of you would learn to see, perhaps, is how you relate it to your real life.
I think if you step back, you will see it's a good thing, that God trains in you certain qualities, some of the qualities you need.
For example, you can find yourself with a lack of wealth.
When you eat or drink, it's always sparse.
You can, you know, count the food.
And, uh, if you have, uh, a child, or if, you know, you could not have a child,
or if you're given a child, and then this child is taken from you,
then you are tried, and then you get your reward.
Or things like this, you know, and, uh...
And when you're successful, you're rewarded for it, that's all.
But the idea is, I'll give you a good example.
When you were young, you probably did this, I did this.
When you were young and not quite sure of your religion,
you know how the examination periods are really tough,
you know, they really make you pray to God.
And I noticed that I and my friends were more religious
during examinations than at other times.
You know, when you don't need God, you know, you don't pray as much, you're not as religious
or receptive.
But when you're in a squeeze, then you turn to God.
So, God says, you must be steadfast under all circumstances.
And we get an example in the Quran where people are riding a ship, and a storm comes,
and they're about to drown, and then they turn to God.
But here's what happens when they reach the shore.
As soon as they land safely, they forget God.
That's not steadfastness. Steadfastness means to think of God on the ocean, on the land, whether traveling or at home, in stormy conditions or in peaceful conditions.
Excuse me, we need to remember something that you said last week, too.
I think you need to remember
that the test is coming in difficult because you said about
you can't do this, you can't do that, so now you're thinking about
what you could use to do this test.
I think you need to remember that.
Yes. Everything you said. As long as the sun comes up and you can see it, you're still alive.
There are many things you have to think about. How much do you pay for this?
We give that great price, as we're doing by the way, and many times we waver after.
I think this thing about how easily we forget is, I think, very, very normal.
It should not be normal.
Like, this is what happens.
Allah, I want this letter, let's say, from my mother.
And every day you're missing it, praying, "Allah, I want this letter."
And after waiting three or four weeks, the mailman comes with the letter.
And when you see it, you forget Allah. You thank the mailman, you give him a tip,
and after reading the letter, then you realize you have thanked everybody except Allah.
It's very common.
No problem.
You have to also seek help through steadfastness and Salat.
If you are steadfast and you do your Salat, you're going to receive help.
Right.
and in 2:156,
when a disaster strikes them, they say, "We belong to God, and to Him we are returning."
So ultimately, in other words, the submitters say, "What does God want with me?"
When I got in trouble in Libya, and they threw me in the dungeon, I was very upset. I was
objecting for a couple of days.
Why, why, why did this happen to me?
And then I was, I didn't read any books, nothing. I was afraid I would forget the Quran, I was reading it continuously.
And then I came to a verse that said,
I was objecting violently, then I totally submitted.
You know, this is what God wants us to do.
This is what this verse means.
When it says that we belong to God, I said,
"Well, this is what God wants to do with me.
There's nothing anybody can do."
That's why you just have to accept it.
Okay, that's when I was talking about the first song to hear.
That's when I was talking about the first song to hear.
Is that okay?
No.
Okay, that first song.
I know it's not okay,
because we should keep that second song to sing with you.
But it was okay for us, us being human, to hang our heads for a while, as long as we could get back as quickly as we possibly could.
Right.
That was the second part.
It was the Quran that reminded me.
Okay, okay.
So that's what I was coming on to.
Thank God.
But that was the toughest test that I ever had in my life.
That was really, that was the toughest test.
But the rewards were beautiful after that.
And then just two days later, I was really honored. You know, the order from the president came and they kicked the doors, they beat up the jailers, and they had me in a government limousine and brought me into the, what they call, the People's Palace, where the second man in the country was.
The bodyguard gave me a big hug and asked me what happened, and he is the one who put me in.
They pretended like they rescued me.
But God was doing the whole thing.
But only after I submitted, and I had said this, and then this verse, I identified with this verse right away,
2:156. Look at it. If a disaster strikes them—to me that was the biggest disaster ever.
Because it's a place where there are no laws, there are no courts. They don't have to put you on trial any time.
They don't have to release you. They don't have to justify or give you any reason.
You don't know what will happen to you. And on the walls of the dungeon I saw those lines marking days and weeks.
People would put a cross each week, you know, and I didn't know how long they...
Yeah, really, I thought I'd never see my children again.
And it happened before. I mean, they took Imam Musa al-Sadr of Lebanon, and he disappeared.
He never came back again.
There's lots of speculation what happened to him.
Also, I know from experience that when they do this to you, even for one hour, you become an enemy of the state.
They won't let you go out to speak of the barbaric treatment against them.
The barbaric treatment and the barbaric cruelty in the dungeon and all the horrible things that happen to human beings over there.
They won't let you go. But it was no less than a miracle.
Yet it's very easy for God to do it.
So when we look at this verse again, 2:156.
When a disaster strikes them, they say, "We belong to God, and to Him we will return."
So this is exactly what I said by instinct. Alhamdulillah, all I said was, when God wants to do for me,
who's going to do anything about it? And I had a great sense of relief.
And only then I can imagine the angels working on my release.
They go and work on the people and make them make this rash decision of letting me go?
Unheard of.
Really, unheard of. I haven't seen anybody go in and come out.
Yeah?
The objection?
The objection is simply lack of faith in God.
When I was put in that disaster,
I just complained.
I forgot.
My faith in God was not strong.
I was objecting to the test. I was thinking, why is this happening to me?
That shouldn't happen to me. That was objection. That was bad.
Because for as long as I was flunking the test, I was in bad shape.
But when I made that statement, we belong to God and He can do anything with us,
I will submit. Then everything, the test was over. There was no point in continuing the test.
But had I continued with that attitude, why is this happening to me?
I would have remained there.
Okay, our next picture is Adam Baruni, he's getting up now.
Adam, want to take the Hajj pilgrimage?
Inga, why don't you take the Hajj pilgrimage?
This is the Adam, not the one I was talking about.
He's getting up. When did he stop getting up?
Huh? A couple of days?
Masha'Allah.
He's busy, you know. He's sitting there eating food, drinks and so on.
Throwing them up in the air and chewing on them.
He's having fun. Masha'Allah.
Okay.
Indeed, Safa and Marwah are among the rites of God.
So anyone who observes Hajj or `Umrah commits no error by traversing the distance between them.
If one volunteers to do more, then God is Appreciative, Omniscient.
As for those who conceal the revelations we send down, and the guidance,
after We have made them clear for the people in the scripture,
Except for those who repent, reform, and proclaim; I will redeem them.
I am the Redeemer, the Most Merciful.
Those who disbelieve, and die as disbelievers, upon them is the curse of God,
and the angels, and all the people.
They abide therein forever.
The retribution is never commuted for them, nor are they respited.
Your god is one god.
There is no god except He, the Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
The pagans had idols on Safa and Marwah,
and the Muslims had something against walking
between them. No, no.
Okay, I see. Hajj, like all worships in Islam,
came through Ibrahim.
And Safa and Marwah are two mounds where Hagar used to go up them to look and see when Ibrahim was coming.
Because he left them there, he left Hagar and Ishmael there.
And he'd go to Sarah in Palestine for a couple of months, and come to Hagar and Ishmael for a couple of months.
So she used to go up, and they were really in distress just before the discovery of water.
So she would go up and look for Ibrahim, and then go to this one,
because he came with the supplies. The supplies were running down.
And then the well of Zamzam sprung out from the earth.
And then caravans would stop and buy the water from them, and they became rich, etc., etc.
So, this is a commemoration of the fact that God will take care of you.
So some people just can't imagine that God will provide for you when you never expect.
When you put your trust in God, the verse says those who fear God will be provided for
when they never expect. And some people just can't imagine that.
So this symbolizes the fact that Ibrahim followed the instructions.
He took Hagar and Ishmael and put them in a barren desert, no plants, no water, nothing,
and said, "You're going to live here."
Can you imagine going in the middle of the desert?
Not like the desert where I'm going here.
If you've seen the desert in Yuma, between Yuma and El Centro, where it is just yellow sand dunes,
this is how Mecca looked.
And there were no plants, nothing, no water.
And this is the area that, as you see in other verses in Quran,
"I have settled part of my family in a plantless valley near your sacred house."
He left them.
He left them with some supplies.
This is the lesson that God selected for you.
Why?
Because God provided for them.
The water came out.
The caravans came.
The support really came.
With it.
God provided for them.
So, this Safa and Marwah business is a commemoration of that.
And it reminds you that God will provide for you and take care of you. He guarantees that.
When God says, "I guarantee you provision in this life," guaranteed.
All I want you to do is worship Me alone.
I'm going to take care of all your needs, and I just want you to make a decision.
Worship Me alone.
So, Safa and Marwah have the symbol for you.
The verse says: "Whoever volunteers good, God is Appreciative, Aware."
Right, what is this now?
I have the verse here, and I want you to see it.
Let's go further to it to see it. I can see it.
It's bringing it to like modern day times.
Right, because it's traversing the distance seven times.
So, but if you want to do it more, if you want to commemorate, because you commemorate God.
You say, "Allah is the greatest," all the time you are going back and forth, you are saying that.
You are saying, لَبَيْكَ اللَّهُمَّ لَبَيْكَ
It means, "I respond to you, my Lord, and I obey your commandments."
It's a big thing, so it says that if you volunteer more of this worship,
then you will be rewarded for it.
لَبَيْكَ اللَّهُمَّ لَبَيْكَ
Labbayk is an expression, like when a king calls a slave.
When the slave comes and says, "Labbayk."
It means, "At Your command."
Literally, "At Your command."
So you say that when you make the Hajj,
you always have to say that.
Labbayk Allahumma: "My God, Our God, I am Your slave."
You called me, and here I am.
I am truthful in my absolute obedience to You.
Beautiful words, yeah.
Yes. But this is what it says here.
Yeah, and you are told already.
Yes, but in other words, you are not to think of idols by doing this.
You are doing it because of My command. In other words, some people say if you're going around the Ka'bah, then the Ka'bah is your idol.
It was only because of that. It's like God telling the angels to fall prostrate before Adam.
But it wasn't for Adam; it was obeying the commandment of God who said it's okay to go around or traverse the distance between them.
And in this way, you are not idolizing the Ka'bah or idolizing Safa and Marwah.
Because it is a commandment from God.
Now, you see, God was telling us it's alright; the contrast is with Adam. It's okay, "I am telling you."
Yes, "I'm telling you."
And for voluntary worship, there is more reward.
Because these are authorized practices.
While we are on this subject, I must say that
all pillars of Submission are shown in this surah
in the sequence of the year.
The first one was the Salat and then the Ka'bah,
and then comes the fasting in the ninth month,
and now this is Hajj in the twelfth month.
So, you remember when we went through the fasting verses, do you remember? Yeah?
No, not fasting. It's next to...
Oh, is it?
Oh, oops. This is an oops.
So, I think the Hajj, yeah, Hajj comes after the fasting.
When you make the Hajj after.
Right.
So, this has to do with the Safa and Marwah.
Yeah.
Because Behrouz is not here, right?
Behrouz is not here.
Yeah.
Thank you.