Thank you very much.
This is a good question.
Thank you.
All of us are going to perform the pilgrimage.
And we know that the pilgrimage is a pilgrimage.
Concealing or distorting or making any changes.
The Umrah is pilgrimage to the same land at any other time.
The manner is exactly the same as Hajj.
Just at another time.
Any time of the year.
Hajj has to be on the 9th, 10th, 11th, and 12th day of the 12th month.
9, 10, 11, 12. The month number 12.
On the ninth day, you have to be standing on Arafat.
You know, you know.
So, Umrah is doing Hajj at any other time.
The rituals are identical.
We uncover their cover.
So it just shows that there's no hope once death is coming.
Always.
Every time.
Most of the people who die,
they are the people who die in disbelief,
and like I said,
this life is the only time that God will
put them to the test, in this life of ours.
They were in defiance,
and they failed then.
They deserve no other than perdition.
In other words, we're told that
as long as the person is alive, there's hope.
Once they die as disbelievers, they are finished, they are condemned, and they incur a curse.
In fact, the angels beat them up at the time of their death. They are in pain.
You think it's the pain of death, but it's really the pain of being beaten up.
I'm not sure if they realize it or not, but they're being slapped in the face and kicked in the butt.
You can read it in the Quran.
The meaning is clear to me.
And if a person asks, "Why is this happening to me?" I've talked about this before.
If I find myself away from home, and I didn't travel far enough to shorten the contact prayers.
The people who have died now have found that they don't have any second chance or possibility
once they have died and they are now in danger.
They are told by the angels that they are lost.
Once the people have died, that's it.
The test is over.
So, the point is,
the Quran says the angels beat them up. The verses are clear, thank you.
I think if somebody gets shot, whatever, and say they go through a pain, but that pain a disbeliever goes through is the angel's beating, which a believer does not. A believer, right, even if he gets shot or something, he's in peace. The angels receive his soul. There is no pain. His passing is peaceful. There is no pain for the person's soul, no pain.
They probably don't feel the shot.
I can guess very well that the believers die very peacefully in their sleep
or something.
Very peaceful.
So, as for the guilty, they have a critical problem.
They are guilty of transgression.
But how much does he desire it?
Right.
How much does he desire it?
He knows what is in store for him.
He is at peace, and he is happy.
That makes it easy for him.
So, could that be like the du'a?
That's the one when you ask, you know,
"how do you deserve an honorable exit from this world?"
Do you want me to be perfectly honest?
Oh, I see, yes. I mean a good entrance and a good exit.
Yes, I'm glad you asked that.
Well, a good exit means to exit as a believer.
But I still have that question.
Yeah, could be.
If you ask me how to get it, is that what you're asking me?
Nine o'clock in the morning?
Yes, the concept is the same.
The subject of martyrs, by the way,
in a previous age, people had to prove they were believers
by actually going into battle.
But now we're in an age where the whole thing is mental.
There's no way you can go and fight for possessions, for example, to make more money.
So, you have to engage in it mentally.
The whole issue of fighting is strictly against people who are trying to stop you from practicing the
religion.
Right.
That's right.
What would you call a conflict of interest?
A conflict of interest.
Yes, "Ilahukum" is "your God." "Ilahun Wahid" means "One God." Your God is one God.
La ilaha illa Huwa, Ar-Rahman Ar-Rahim. There is no god except He, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Yes, it depends on the grammar.
It says,
إِلَٰهُكُمْ إِلَٰهٌ وَاحِدٌ
لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ
الرَّحْمَٰنُ الرَّحِيمُ
Okay, we have to be quick now so we can celebrate Fahima's birthday.
And Sami, his friends are celebrating his birthday, so he was going to come, but I told him to go enjoy his day.
Are there any questions before we quit? Yeah.
There is a verse that I quoted in my book that says,
It's not that I made a mistake. It's where God says, "My favor to you has been `adheem` (great),"
and I wanted to put a footnote that this is from verse 2:151, because it also discusses this.
No, I made a mistake. That's not where it is from. Just a minute... It's where God says,
"My favor, My favor to you has been `adheem` (tremendous), and it consists of this, this, and this."
I'm going to pray in the morning at 6 o'clock.
When you people get up in the morning and come here to make dhikr at 6 o'clock, there
is joy and celebration and happiness.
The angels are all excited.
And you received an award.
Because I wanted to put it.
And you passed the test.
Uh, with you.
Because,
when the messenger is given scripture and wisdom
and taught you what you did not know.
This was an instance of the Fadl al-`Azim on the Prophet, and I wanted to write it on your book, but I don't have it.
It's not one of these. It doesn't say Dhu al-Fadl al-`Azim. You just say Fadl al-`Azim.
Some of these verses are like that. See, I just mixed them up here.
But it will be in the pamphlet.
What I'm doing now is I'm putting this in one of my books, but being very careful, not like this,
because then you will not know what this is, or this, or this also, unless you have a
clue.
See, I need to, I've got notes in so many of my books, now I need to bring them all
together, just to get one Quran with a good margin.
What I'm doing now is, all of my notes that are separated,
I'm putting them in one Quran, and then I destroy them.
So I will not tell... So I know it's already...
It has taken... It's going to take a month.
Lose my Quran? Well, that would be a week lost.
Because I want to give it to him.
I'll tell you the meaning of what I'm doing when you come home.
If this was you, and you came from the North Pole,
there would be no question which is a straight line.
Because you just choose the...
I choose the...
This one.
All right.
So this is a straight line.
That's clear.
that if you walk straight from here, you could get to the South Pole, which is directly opposite you, and back again to where you started.
It's not really a straight line, it's a curve.
Yeah, it's a curved line, but it's a curve of perception.
So, if this was where you start, right here, and if you draw those radiating lines,
you still have your north, south, east, and west lines, but then your east
and west lines don't follow these anymore, because when you go east and west, it's actually
like this: you go straight east, and you walk until you come back to your starting point. So that
all those connected lines define a plane, and the center of the earth is also a point on that plane.
So then, yeah, if you observe this, let's say this is overhead, like the north-south line or so forth,
The lines would be a curve. Your bearing would shift, say, from east-south, to north-south, then to west-south.
Are you following? You know it's not following these lines.
It's just a curve. It's kind of hard to see.
So, what are we doing?
If you were facing the other way, you see, that's why the compass prevents you from that.
Yeah, the problem, yeah.
This is what you keep the focus on.
That's why we have the great circle route, and that's why our compass gives a rhumb line route.
If you walk directly to it, even though we don't, because we don't perceive the curvature
of the Earth, and if we walk a straight line, eventually we get back to the same point.
This is a great circle to us, you see. It's not flat. It's a sphere, it's a sphere, it's a sphere, it's a sphere, it's a sphere, it's a sphere.
The line, now if you put them in their real positions, the line is just like this over here.
Lines projecting from anywhere on Earth to Mecca, just like the North Pole.
These lines which cut the Earth in half.
This is what we'd consider a straight line, where you'd walk,
and eventually get back to the place where you began.
So here it's easy. You just go like that.
Yeah. Because here it's visual. You know, we can...
But I mean, you could...
You know, our visual location of this, because even the Earth being egg-shaped is not this perfect sphere.
Yeah, but still, it's not that much distorted, you know.
but those lines are put on the Earth by using astronomical measurements
in order to locate those lines, to locate where you are on the sphere in relation to those lines.
The most accurate way to locate is not from the surface with a compass, but astronomically, yes.
Yes, but then these lines are already drawn. And this you can find out by time,
in relation to your Greenwich time, and in relation to the stars.
Yeah, the projection here is a model.
Yeah, but I think if you were using them really, they might, you know, on the real Earth,
they wouldn't be quite as straight as they look here.
It's slightly flattened because of the rotation of the Earth.
The distortion isn't that drastic.
The point that I was raising is, because I asked you, you see, so if you walk straight east,
we take Mecca. Well, not entirely east. It's slightly south.
I mean, the distance is so great that it's only about a half a degree.
Yeah, well, yeah, even that.
If you were standing here directly on the earth, on the axis, you would have no question
where to face, right?
No.
No, because you would just be following this, these lines, which is a rhumb line, or
that line.
That line.
So actually, no matter where you're standing on earth, these lines, you can actually have them where you're standing, which would represent the straight lines to you.
Suppose you are like this now, if I was standing, you'll still have this line that goes north-south,
If you trace it on the earth, the path would be one of the straight lines.
Then, to cut that, the path would be your east and west, which would be like this, right?
So if you walk directly east, you'd be going like this.
Because when you're facing east, you're facing this way.
That's the direction that you'd be walking if you walked the straightest line that was possible,
without veering right or left.
Try to visualize it as if this was the North Pole.
I would still have to say that my bearings would be like this one or something.
If you were to walk this way, if you were to walk like this, if I followed this straight
straight east. That's because you're thinking in terms of these lines here. These are
imaginary lines. For that to be a straight line to you, you'd have to be standing this
this way. But you are not. Where am I standing? You'd be standing like this, facing the center
of the earth. Because that's the center of gravity. Because if you were standing like
Like this, you'd be like this, see?
Can you visualize, you know, a pin standing like this?
Just like this.
But if you're going to keep it perpendicular to the...
That's what you're talking about, it being perpendicular to the surface,
the curved surface, right?
You know, if it stays upright, I still don't see any problems.
Yes, I was just going east.
Yeah, but you'd be walking...
I don't think there's no slant to it.
See, again, if, for instance, this was...
You're standing here. This was north and this was south.
Then this would be east and west, right?
Yeah.
There's no question about that.
Here, east and west, it's not like this.
If, for instance, again, if you're standing here, you see, east and west would be like
this.
Well, the angle here is going to keep changing, because it stays perpendicular to the, you
know.
So there would be, between this perpendicular line, and that one,
if you cut that straight through, and remove the curve, then there would be an angle.
No, I don't think it would be.
Great discussion.
That would be great.
There would be an angle between this and that.
No, but that's... See, there's no question about this being a straight line.
Certainly there can be drawn a line connected from your north and your south, right?
And it would cross where you're standing.
If we could draw lines on this globe, you know, we'd be able to...
Sorry.
I don't know.
Not that one.
Okay.
Let's shoot a line.
I did that one.
You did what?
You see, the radius of the circle that you draw would have to be, it would have to be
the center of the Earth, the center of gravity.
Do you have some of this?
Yeah, I have some of this.
You mean the idea of sticking that pin all the way through?
What are you talking about, the center of the earth?
The center of the earth is the radius of all straight lines, at least apparent straight lines.
The radius of this circle, we call that a straight line, right?
The radius of it is the center of the earth.
like when a satellite circles the earth it can be circling any which way it can be circling like this
it can be circling like this it doesn't have to follow this if it if it would try to
circle this way it certainly wouldn't wouldn't circle the earth it would just sort of fly away
So it would have to have the center being the center of gravity.
That's the way we walk, around the center of gravity.
Okay, now I'm starting.
A satellite couldn't just drift around here, it would have to.
If you drifted as if there was some kind of a rod in the center of the Earth.
Yeah, exactly. It's like a string, you know, when you go like this with a bucket.
You could twirl it like this, or you could twirl it like that.
So what you're saying is, you know, if we had a tack on the surface.
That's why you're talking about it.
Yeah, we'd be standing like this, because we're drawn, you know, if we draw a line from the tip of our head to the tip of our feet, it would hit the center of gravity.
They think that there's something else going on there, because we don't walk like that on the surface of the Earth, because we are.
Basically, they're sticking to that.
To what?
We're sticking to the Earth.
Yeah.
It is as if there is a string tied to our feet
and somebody in the center of the Earth
is twirling us around if we were to walk straight.
Can you imagine that?
I'm wondering if that has to be so,
whether the center of the Earth
or merely the surface of the Earth.
No, it's the center of the Earth, the center of gravity.
Because all this curvature is encasing.
It's like a whole bunch of circles with one center.
And that's what makes the sphere.
so that you know, if this was the curve, certainly the radius would be something like
this. Yeah, we wouldn't be standing like this, standing like this, it would be like if you
had your radius in your circle, and we'd be standing in such a way that you can draw
lines like this from your... from your edges, right? And you'd be standing in a way that
because you would still... you would always be perpendicular. Yeah.
So there wouldn't be what you're talking about. Yeah, you cannot, we don't stand this way or this way.
So, being perpendicular there, but what you're saying, you're suggesting that we couldn't see.
See, there's only one circle like this that can intersect where we stand, Tucson and Mecca, right?
And the center of that circle is the center of the Earth.
The center of all these, these, not the latitude, the longitude.
There's all of these, these longitudes are circles, actually, because all of them have one center.
Possibly. I mean, because in this act, you know, if this point is a perfect point, it's not the tilt of the Earth that counts.
So we're dealing with a different concept.
I mean, it's not the physical position of our bodies.
Well, it has a great deal to do with our perception, if we were standing this way, if we were standing
this way for instance, a straight line for us would be like this, you know, but we'd
be sort of right at the same point.
No.
That's kind of hard because you have to have a surface to be able to determine, you know,
how to be walking in a straight line.
Because if you were standing this way, your surface would be this way.
If that was a curve, you'd actually be going this way.
If somebody's standing straight, that's a curve.
You guys standing this way, that's a straight line.
I've thought about this a long, long time ago when I was trying to determine.
What you're suggesting is that you'd never hit Mecca by walking that way if you kept
the earth as your center.
I mean, if you kept the center of the earth as your pivot.
Yeah.
You're suggesting you could never actually hit Mecca by walking?
Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
So when the sun goes 15 degrees per hour, it's fast.
Then you can find this out.
The thing is, this is a convention that was designed by sailors,
Yeah, but it would follow, you know, the Quranic injunction, you use the star in the sky to guide you.
But the Arabs, good Lord, with their astral navigation...
Yeah, that's all an astral aid. That's just to tell the angles.
You can tell where you are on a globe like this in relation to these different lines.
A compass doesn't tell you anything. A compass is only general.
Because it is subject to distortion.
Yeah, over a short distance, you can use it in a fairly accurate way, but on a map, it's
a good coordinate.
How do you do it in a group?
Yeah, a compass.
You don't need to find out.
When you are alone, what do you do?
Somebody, say, is in Michigan, my home country.
This is not the same as a person facing from here.
Doesn't tell you anything.
I think this is wild.
Yeah, yeah. But theoretically, you know, if your compass was perfect, and would work
directly here with us, to true north, then you'd be able to determine it by, just by
by experience, people would travel in that straight line to the place. They'd be able
to say, like, if you were at this point, you know, this place would be in a certain direction.
Because the compass is actually like this. If you were standing here, and this was your
north pole, this was your south pole, this was your east, this was your west, your compass
going like this, and certainly you know that across from that would be your west and east.
You can do the same, you can always do that with shadows.
Yeah so what's your conclusion, you know, if you're pivoted, if you're pivoting on a point?
You know, if you had a wire attached from you to the center of the earth, it would pivot.
Subhan'Allah wa bihamdihi.
You'd be on the surface of the earth, perpendicular to the surface,
which you wouldn't be anyways, because you would be slanting if you go north or south anyways.
You'd be going like this. You'd constantly be perpendicular to the surface of the earth.
Yeah, but your pivot would not.
What do you mean?
Because if the...
Yeah, think of a wire, it's supposed to point right at the very center below.
This is the pivot, and you've got a wire coming out from that.
Now...
They're all different, aren't they?
Everything is different.
Yeah, you know, you can't say it's perpendicular because it's a curve, you know, but we perceive it.
But if we move that, if we simply move that, I don't see then how you would ever be on a slant, like they're saying, as long as the surface is curved.
No, you'd never be on a slant.
So there you are, perpendicular to the surface, pivoting on the center, aiming for the line that goes to Mecca.
You would. Why would you? Oh yeah, you want to find the line that goes to Mecca, right?
Now that, you know, you could still, yeah, that line that goes to Mecca would cut across lots of stuff, you see.
Now you're pivoting from the center, it doesn't require you following those
latitude and longitude lines either, you can still cut across them.
Yeah, but then you'd be walking at what we would consider a curved line.
A different curved line than these.
No, different from these drawn lines.
Do you understand exactly what I mean when I say that this is a straight line, right?
Yeah.
We can draw exactly the same lines from any point on the outer circle.
So let's assume this is two circles.
Okay.
And all the lines are arbitrarily drawn.
Yeah.
So let's take this as our line, and let's revolve it; but okay, let's say, you know, instead of putting it directly on that line, let's put it over in that area, so we're not putting it directly on that line, so you can still draw a straight line there.
Yeah, exactly. There's an infinite number of lines that you can draw there.
It's the same thing there, yeah, but it doesn't relate to the rotation. No, see, that's the problem now.
These lines are drawn in relation to the position, yeah, because it's based on the axis, yeah.
I'm not sure what we're supposed to do.
Are we supposed to face in that direction that we consider straight lines?
Yeah, that's right.
Wait, are we supposed to face?
In that case, that is what we're supposed to do.
We should be facing slightly north.
Difficult?
Yes, because when we're facing north,
No, but we are compensating, because we are slightly more than that already, so we have to be slightly slanted.
But it's only about a half a degree or so.
Yes, but that is relative to north and south. But suppose you were looking just at distances.
If these lines, if these things were drawn, you wouldn't be saying that we're north or south, would you?
Yeah, because to speak of north and south is a term of what we have defined here.
You see? But if you just look at this, in other words, we can graph this, but one strives to find the shortest distance.
Is that right? Well, no. No, not the compass, not the geodesic system?
The compass is only pointing at the magnetic force, that's all it is.
Yeah, but those are from people who can determine through mathematics.
Well, those little maps, those little booklets that come with the compass on a mat,
they give angles that are based on those shortest distances. They're like the planes fly.
But they're very inaccurate.
Yeah, well, they're inaccurate.
They may not compensate for magnetic declination at all these points.
You notice that the watch that I have doesn't point the same way.
The watch points very much askew, you know.
Because I had a friend that had one of those.
And hers had a book that gave all these different points across the U.S.
All the major cities, it gave only this.
Now, I have another question. Suppose we are here, no?
What do we do? We try to look here, no? Right?
Right? Is there no way of looking through it?
Yeah.
It's a longer way, but does it make any difference?
We still look east.
Yeah.
I mean, it's probably, in that sense, it might be a convenience.
That's the shortest distance we'll use.
But in any case, I don't see why the people of Tucson, to look at Mecca,
will have to look east.
Why do they not look west across Asia?
Because they don't turn to the West.
Yeah, but we look west, we're in between.
Yeah.
So what do you say, it's not the same?
Right.
But at the same time, isn't it the same?
Well, I guess God, I mean, made that big ocean.
But if we follow the verse that says wherever you turn, there is the face of God.
Yes, according to the verse, because God is everywhere anyhow.
You know, he went as far as he, he's permanent here, only since...
Pardon?
Yeah, you can ask for anything you want.
Don't call on me tonight.
I'm so tired. I'm so hungry.
I want to sit with you all day long.
Oh, good. Usually.
I just wanted to say, don't call on me.
I'm the first person here to call on you.
If I have anything to say, though, I will.
Okay, I hope so, because you know, God inspires all of us through the input.
This is the benefit of a group, because here we have like 20 brains thinking of the same
verse.
Otherwise we'd sit home and read the Quran by ourselves, it would not be as productive.
Well, I have, I'm going to mention two things before we start. First, we start our Arabic
lessons tomorrow after Zikr, and we have the best Arabic language lessons here. In two weeks,
we're going to have people reading the Quran in Arabic, in two weeks, if you do your homework.
In fact, I'm going to give you homework right now, from between Saturday and next Saturday.
All you need to do is memorize the alphabet.
I'm going to give you the Arabic alphabet and the equivalent, and the Arabic alphabets,
they are different at the beginning of the word, the middle, and the end.
The reason we're starting the Arabic language again is I found it very useful
in comparing translations, and in pinning down certain words, what words are
falsely stated. The second thing I want to say is at the end of
the Khutbah this afternoon, I mentioned that they printed a million copies of
the summary of the computer results, and another place printed a million copies,
and I didn't mean to make it all praise like this, because I received also a new
a new cussing word for me that comes from I think Indians. You know how
polite the Indians are. So now the new, the new bad name that I received in the
mail was a "deviated luminary."
I just forgot to mention it in the khutbah.
I need a new pair of glasses.
A new pair of glasses?
Luminaries.
Oh, I see.
All the medical terms are in Latin.
I have the luminaries right here.
Don't you need a tripod for both of you?
This one deviated again.
Okay, Bismillah-ir-Rahman-ir-Rahim.
In the name of God, the Gracious, the Merciful.
We're at 164, page 17.
The subtitle is overwhelming signs of God
in the creation of the heavens and the earth,
the alternation of night and day,
the ships that roam the sea for the benefit of mankind,
the water that God sends down to revive dead lands and spread all kinds of
creatures therein, the manipulation of the winds, the clouds placed between the
heaven and the earth, all these are signs for people who understand. I think we can
stay in this verse for hours, just to think about the overwhelming signs of
God. The creation of the heavens and the
earth. If you just think of how God designed
the digestive tract
of every, of this cat. See this cat here? Come here, you.
Come here, you're the subject.
Perfect.
Remember last, last khutbah I told you to touch your ear and see how the design is of your ear?
And then in there, there's the inner ear and the ear drum.
What is this design, you know?
Who designed this?
For the best audio reception.
Now look at the cat's ears.
How they're designed.
And we can make noise back here.
If you see their ear, and if you've worked with horses, the same thing.
The ears go like this, the sound is coming from the front, but if you make noise back
there, one ear goes like that, right?
And if the noise is over the back, both of them go like this.
Alright, so this is God's creation, the design.
right. So God said I'm going to create the human being, let's concentrate on the human
being, and I'm going to give him a mouth to eat with. Now, for the food, what is the food
going to be? It's going to be lettuce, carrots, and meat, eggs and potatoes. So how would you eat the carrots?
You have to have cutters. See the front teeth? Who designed that?
The four top ones and the four lower ones, they're cutters. They cut. And you see how
they're designed like scissors? We don't have anybody with overbite or underbite.
We're a perfect group, I have to say. This is what I meant today in the khutbah.
You know, I was, I came to, in the khutbah today, I came to the brink of saying
Alhamdulillah, I mean we have to thank God first, that we're all perfect. And I
hesitated and I didn't come out with it, but I don't see why not. Look around, you
don't see anybody with one arm, you know, or anything like that, not that it's bad.
So, there is something to it,
but when God promises those who worship him alone,
perfect. You just look around this mosque anytime.
Even the one person who came with one leg, remember what was his name?
He healed. He left with two legs. So God designed this, the creation. And the
creation of the heavens and the earth are enough signs for God. Now after you chop
the carrots, where will they go? They go to grinders. You see how they're
designed? The grinders, they're flat. The front teeth are designed like scissors.
They go, just like scissors, they cut. Then they go to the grinders to make it
fine, then they swallow. Now in the swallowing process here, you take it for
granted, don't you? But when you swallow, the air pipe is blocked first. You see
the movement in there? There is a sealing of the air pipe, so the food will go to
the stomach, not to the lungs. You take this for granted don't you? But God
designed it and you don't control it. And this is what it means that everything in
the heavens and the earth glorifies God. Because even the disbeliever glorifies
God. Because when the disbeliever swallows, his system is working according to God's
will. The air pipe is blocked and the
the digestive tract is open.
The disbeliever's heart pumps, and he has no control over it.
Can you stop your heart for a second?
Can you slow it down, or make it faster?
So this is what it means, that everything in the heavens and the earth glorifies God.
In the creation of the heavens and the earth, I can go on and on as you see,
The alternation of night and day, one of my favorite subjects. You saw the picture
of the Earth today? And the spaceship happened to be between the Sun and the
Earth, so we took a picture of the illuminated side, the day-lit illuminated
side of the Earth. And the other side was dark. Now the Earth is turning and there's
alteration of night and day, because it implies the earth is round, it is hanging in
space. Who is holding it in space? Now how can the people avoid believing in God
when they think about this? This is what means overwhelming signs of God.
The axis of the earth is designed to create the seasons which control what
what kind of plants we grow, what kind of crops, what kind of food.
What else is there? Now the speed of rotation of the Earth,
controls how many hours we have in the day,
in day and night, and the speed is accurate.
We know exactly what time the sun will rise, 200 years from now.
It's so accurate they could predict where another planet was that they could never see, like the discovery of Neptune.
They had never seen Neptune, and the mathematical laws are so precise. They'd turn their telescope where they'd specified, and there it was.
That's how accurate it is. The whole balance of the solar system.
Now they do it by laser beam bouncing back.
The whole balance of the solar system is one second slower or one second faster, and it would be chaos.
this reminds me that the latest distance they measured was four billion light
years, they saw an object that is four billion light years away, which means if
that object died four billion years ago we'll still see the
light coming. Now four billion light years, you know
you're traveling at the speed of light for four thousand million years to get
there. That's within the small universe.
So the alternation of night and day implies a lot of information that tells
us how great God is.
The ships that roam the sea for the benefit of mankind.
Water is a crazy liquid that has the physicists puzzled, because things float,
things float in the water, not in alcohol or kerosene. Water has crazy properties.
University of California, I took that course at the University of California, the title is water.
It has the physics, physical chemistry and chemistry of water.
Because it's unique, something that God did
that makes the ships float in the water, makes you float in the water.
Unless you do something to drown, if you stand still you float in the water.
Also makes it evaporate and then go to a certain height
and hang up there. See the clouds coming up.
coming up, the clouds hanging between the earth and the sky, so they cool down
and condense again into pure water. All these are designs.
The water that God sent down to revive dead lands.
I was just talking today about desert plants, for example. Do you know that the
seeds of desert plants will not germinate unless a specific amount of
rain falls? The mechanism of it is there's an inhibitor around the seed that is
water-soluble, and you have to have a certain amount of water fall on it and
wash the inhibitor away. So this guarantees a reservoir of water for the
plant, for the seed. The seed will not germinate unless a specific amount of
water is poured. Who designed all this?
But if a person makes a decision that they don't want to believe,
they will not see any of this, as we know from the Quran. The manipulation of the
winds. If the wind stands still for three or four months, all life
will end. We need the wind because you know where all the water coming from, all
these clouds? Come from the Pacific Ocean, or the Atlantic.
because it's driven by the wind, otherwise it wouldn't be here, there'd be no water in the
underground. And you know how they panic in Tucson when the rain is late or
something, they have all those Beat the Peak programs, they panic. So you can
imagine if there's no wind, there'll be no Tucson.
The manipulation of the wind, the alternation of night and day,
the clouds placed between the heavens and the earth, all these are
signs for people who understand. Now the idol worshippers disowned by their idols,
165. Yet, some people set up idols besides God and adore them as if they
were God.
However, the believers love God more than anything else. If only the wrongdoers
could envision themselves when they face the retribution, they will find out that
all power belongs to God alone, and that God is very strict in imposing
retribution. Those who were followed will disown their followers. They will suffer the
retribution and all ties to them will be severed. The followers will then say, if we
could live our first life again, we will then disown them as they disown us now.
Thus will God show them the consequences of their works as nothing but sorrow.
They will never exit from Hellfire.
Now,
these verses are actually written in the past tense in the Arabic, so I guess in
the next edition I will make this in the past tense. And they are in the
past tense because God is telling us something that actually took place in
the future. God witnessed it and he's telling us what happened between the
idols and the idol worshippers. And we saw today the insignificance of the
idols, whether it is Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or Saint Francis or whatever.
The things that the people idolize.
The newspaper actually has prayers to Saint Jude, for certain things, today, I mean in
the newspapers in this day and age, in the personals, two days ago this lady wrote to Ann Landers
saying that she made a mistake investing her mother's life savings, and she was praying
she was praying to Mary and
to Jesus. And the title was "The Virgin and Jesus Will Not Help You." That was the title
for an item.
Now, we saw today the insignificance of the idols, we saw the picture of the
earth and how big those people were, Muhammad or Mary or Jesus.
Jesus. Now we have to imagine the Day of Judgment, because that day will come, and
the people will run to Jesus for example and tell him, "Are you going to help us?"
And he'll say, "What are you talking about? I need help myself."
Because he will be subject to the judgment, just like we are, just like all of us.
As a matter of fact, all of us will see Hell first, initially, so that we
appreciate Heaven inshallah when we get there.
But we must imagine what these verses are telling us: that the people
will go to their idols, they will go to Muhammad. You heard about the myth of
intercession of Muhammad, they will go, "Will you intercede on our behalf?"
And he's going to tell them, "Sorry, I have no power, I'm worried about my own neck,"
like Surah 21 tells us. The prophets will be worried about their own fate.
This is what these verses are telling us. This is what the Bible is saying in
Matthew 7:23, you can see it, Matthew 7:23 says that the
people will go to Jesus on the Day of Judgment and tell him, "Lord, Lord, have we
not prophesied in your name? Have we not performed miracles in your name? Have we
not glorified your name?" Etc, etc. And Jesus will say, "Away, out of my sight, I
don't know you." So in other words, he will disown them. You just listen to the
preachers on the TV and the radio on Sunday, and see how much glorification Jesus is getting.
So Satan succeeded in diverting their attention from God to Jesus. And
Satan did the same trick with the Muslims, diverting their attention from
God to Muhammad. They're all human beings, and they're all subject to Satan's tricks.
So these verses here are telling us that the idols will disown the worshippers.
These verses are actually identical.