In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
and he did so many other innovations besides that.
Yeah, it's quite clear.
The big problem is another thing, really.
Yeah, the big problem is the bidaa.
Oh, thank you.
And you know that. You know that.
What he's done in there.
You know, he, what he does in there,
he never said, uh,
that they never stand up for each other,
but, uh, he really did say that later on.
You know that?
Yeah.
Why is this? What's the, what's the reason?
But that's the thing, guys, these are the difficulties, you know.
If you want to perform the Hajj and Umrah, there's no other way to do it, you know.
Because if you want to do that, you need to be more careful.
Right.
Very different.
Well, that's just what I'm saying.
You're in Ihram.
You're in the state of Ihram, the state of Ihram.
It's not a lot of laws.
Because he won't be, or he won't be able to come to the Ka'bah, but he goes in there.
He goes in there.
He does the same thing.
He comes out of there.
That's true.
He is Satan.
But he goes in on it.
The criterion for him.
No, it wasn't an accident.
You're not in contact at all.
Normally, I come to that kind of work.
But I'm just getting ready.
I'm not ready by now.
But I'm only a warner for the world.
You wait and see what's going to happen.
I think we need a testimony.
No, very confused, Behrouz.
But the ummah is confused.
If you try to use a sanad with me...
That's not submission.
The first time, Rashad was not...
Rashad was not reading what they teach, was he?
No, he didn't know, Bernard.
He didn't know.
What did I do with that?
I just have the book over here.
This guy, this guy.
Yeah, I forgot.
I should have remembered, that would have been...
I can't think of it now.
Yeah, exactly.
I think that's the whole thing.
I think that's a crooked walk.
That's what I don't do.
This person says, "This is why I am devout."
Like I think.
It is not just for me to be devout.
It is for me to be pious.
It is for me to acknowledge it.
That is why you are devout.
Right.
This is the problem.
It is.
Yes! Yes!
Some of the prayers of the Baha'is say, "Allah, You're the Lord of everything."
But if He's not with us, He doesn't want us.
He wants Baháʼu'lláh to be with us.
Yes!
That's why I offer my heart to you, because I love you.
They were very far from the path of God.
And for example, the Quran tells of a community to which God sent two messengers,
but they disbelieved them, so He reinforced them with a third, and these three messengers of God spoke to them.
But these people don't want it.
This point is related to Arabism.
The Baha'is never entirely rejected the Quran.
It is also a holy word.
However, they invented a lot of superstitions.
They take a verse and alter it.
Even that is very bad.
Because they are using their own ego, they are using their head, not using their brain.
But instead of doing it for God's sake, they do it to make a name for themselves.
But in this case, this woman, she was 17 or 18 years old.
If I had to give this man a name, I would give it to him.
I mean, from a numerical point of view, it wouldn't fly at all.
But, what is your view?
What is your view?
Tell me, tell me, tell me.
Say, Muhammad is from Algeria.
He goes to the university.
I was in Algeria.
No, Algeria.
Yes, I was in Algeria.
In 1977.
1977.
Very nice.
A little bit tricky over there.
Like that?
Yeah.
Is that for...
For a piece of gem?
For a piece of gem.
So did you like it?
Very nice, yes.
Some people were nice to me.
Others were not nice.
.
But they gave me a car, and a hotel downtown,
but they would not allow me to go to a mosque down there.
So, I refused the car, I refused the hotel, and I went to sleep in the room of the consulate.
Were they willing to see the...
They'll be there.
...about the...
But you know in the...
They didn't talk about it. They don't talk about it anymore.
About the... I don't know.
In Algeria, you don't say about the...
I started to hear about him more here than in Algeria.
So you wrote a book about him?
I wrote a book.
I was into his thoughts on the 20th century.
And I wrote about him.
In fact, I keep quoting one of his quotes.
Ism, then Islam.
I don't know anything about him.
Did you have some cassettes of him?
No, I don't have any.
That's something that I had in some way or another.
I think I can bring the file to the place.
.
And then I talked to him, and he liked it. And I talked to him, and he said,
"I'm really worried."
Then when I came here, I talked with him for one year. Then I wasn't in touch with him for a while.
One time, news was coming out.
He was going to appoint a science advisor for two years.
Okay.
He was a cabinet advisor.
Science advisor for two years.
Then he joined the fabrications.
Could I borrow this for him and get a copy of it?
Of course.
It's not just any kind of book.
It's yours.
I'm trying to get him to read my journal.
He cannot be reached.
Oh, so I'm wasting my time.
You have another chance.
We have a friend in common who knows him, don't we?
Yeah, we have a friend in common.
What do you think of him?
He is an addict, I think.
He is now trapped by his kith and kin.
He is addicted, isn't he?
What position does he have?
I don't think so.
He has this habit that he inherited from his father; he prays five times a day and he doesn't know what he's saying.
He doesn't know how to apply it.
Not only that, I had further reason. He had this statement written on billboards,
He had a statement on the billboard throughout the country, and then after making it the
motto of the nation, he puts it in the official papers of the country, the government papers,
everything throughout the country.
And then he discovered it was not a hadith.
He looked into a thousand hadith a day.
Fifteen hundred hadith a day.
And then he discovered it was not a hadith,
because I told him.
I had a dream about him, and in it
it was said, "Beware of the path
that you're going on."
After this,
he told his advisor, he said,
"Who said this is a hadith?"
Then he studied about hadith.
And then he said, "Maybe you made a disciple out of him at that point."
Well, he was, but he's not there anymore.
You made a disciple out of him at the first point, too.
There was a time when you didn't give a cent for him.
Yeah.
But then you made a discovery about him.
I mean, for some of us, it's just what's coming from the outside.
This was the beginning right here. I wrote an article here.
But you know, he's trying to change the context.
Which one?
It's all about the beginning.
It's about the beginning of corruption.
Change Quran.
Qadhafi?
Yeah, he's trying to make some change.
He said, don't say,
don't say
'Qul'.
Yeah, that's more academic.
Yeah.
Well, that's a common thing.
But they capitalize on it, his enemies.
No, I've heard that before.
Yeah, but really, he doesn't want to send us.
He has no intention of sending us.
So, you see, this is why, when I hear bad things about all these leaders in the Middle
East, I wonder how much of it is propaganda.
A lot of it.
You know, because the propaganda machines are very active.
And we get things here sifted through from many sources.
And you can only judge them in the end.
History will judge them by their writings and by what they've done.
So I'm not going to be so fast as Douglas. So what I hear, you know,
about Qadhafi, some people say you can't buy vegetables now in Libya.
And then, you know, I've heard other stuff.
And I'm going to reserve my judgment about Qadhafi until I have studied more
of what he's read and written and investigated.
And I've been very attracted to what he's written.
He developed a systems theory, a methodology that he calls his general approach to Islam.
He wanted to think on many levels.
I think it was very easy.
That's the point.
Because he's a military person.
I'm not a political person.
I would like to listen.
His writings are really easy.
Thank you.
He's good.
I haven't been there yet.
Not with my...