We have something really important.
O you who believe, fasting is decreed for you, as it was decreed for those before you, that
that you may attain righteousness.
The fasting was decreed before.
It was originally written in the book of...
It says, like all religious practices in Submission,
fasting was decreed through Abraham.
The injunction prohibiting intercourse
throughout the month of fasting
is revised here to allow intercourse
during the nights of fasting.
So, what fasting was,
The rite first given through Abraham, you know, was a continuous fast throughout the whole month of Ramadan.
It was continuous, day and night, throughout the whole month.
As we will see here, actually, in verse 187, this is modified to allow intercourse
during the nights of Ramadan.
Verse 184, you shall fast during the specified days.
Specified days means the ninth month of the lunar calendar.
This is the month of Ramadan, the month of Ramadan is the month wherein the Quran was revealed.
You shall fast during the specified days.
The specified days are identified by the appearance of the moon, the new moon of the ninth month,
and end by the appearance of the new moon of the tenth month.
Those who are ill or traveling, shall fast an equal number of other days.
And those who find it too difficult may substitute the feeding of a poor person for each day of
fasting.
You see, God gives us all kinds of outs.
Whatever the reasons, if you cannot fast, there is an out.
If you have, for example, a chronic illness, or a heart condition,
then you can postpone the fasting. All these are dispensations, allowances from God.
Those who find it too difficult may substitute the feeding of a poor person for each day of fasting.
Whoever volunteers to feed more people, it will be better for them.
And then, notice the end of the verse.
But fasting is the best for you, if you only knew.
So, after all these allowances,
whatever the excuses, the reasons, even though God gives you permission
to break your fasting, it is
fasting is best for you. So, if you can
by any way, fast, then
then go ahead, it is best for you to do it.
Nobody dies from abstention from water and food for one day, 24 hours.
Well, it was not 24 hours, it was only an average of 15 hours.
Nobody would die from lack of food and water.
So, it is best for us to do, carry out this commandment, in fact.
185. Ramadan is the month during which the Quran was revealed.
And this is a very important statement.
Because the legends, hadith, and so-called stories that the Quran was revealed over a period of 23 years.
Obviously, it was not true, because this verse, it says,
The month of Ramadan is the month during which the Quran was revealed.
The fact is, throughout the Quran, we're told that the Prophet Muhammad was taken
on the Night of Power, the 27th night of Ramadan of that year.
That first day, he was taken up to the highest horizon.
And the Quran was put in his heart, the whole Quran, in that one night.
Just like you and I have in our heart the knowledge that God is the Lord of the universe.
That we bore witness that God is our Lord.
But we don't know about that because it's inside our heart.
We don't perceive it. It's in our subconscious.
In the same way, the Quran was put in Muhammad's heart.
Sura 53 gives the details.
How he was taken to the highest horizon, and the whole Quran was put in his heart.
Subsequent to this, Gabriel would go and bring out a portion of the Quran.
A portion that is small enough for the Prophet and his companions to memorize.
We find this in Sura 17, it says, we released the Quran portion by portion in order that
we may memorize.
Now all these references are shown at the very beginning of the book.
Go look at the beginning of the first two pages.
There is one big chart on one page, which says on the 27th night of Ramadan, you see that page?
On the 27th night of Ramadan of the year 13 before Hijra, 610 A.D., the Prophet Muhammad
was summoned to the highest possible point, Al-Masjid Al-Aqsa.
Al-Masjid Al-Aqsa is the highest possible point.
And this Quran was placed into his heart, as we see in 2:97, 17:1, 2:143, 53, 2:122, 97, and 2:125.
And subsequently, the Quran was released through Muhammad's mouth over a period of 23 years, namely between 610 and 632 AD.
At the moment of release, it was immediately written down and divinely guarded and preserved.
Now this is not what the majority of Muslims around the world believe, or accept.
We have stories, narrated from the Bible, and from other sorts of storytellers.
The Prophet was sitting in a cave, and Gabriel came to him and said,
"Read." And he said, "I don't know how to read."
And it goes on. So, it's like a storyteller's tale.
The Quran says nothing like that.
The Quran says he was taken to the Masjid al-Aqsa.
Going up to the seventh heaven.
But at the time, of course, there was no such thing as Masjid al-Aqsa in Jerusalem.
But most people don't think about that.
Masjid al-Aqsa in Jerusalem was built after the fact, 70 years after the Prophet.
That story is a fabrication; the story of the journey from Mecca to Jerusalem and then up to heaven.
He was journeying from Mecca to heaven, straight.
And this is the wording of the verse.
You might think it's the same thing, but it is not.
That was the first day of Revelation; that was the 27th night of Ramadan.
It hadn't happened yet.
How can that be correct?
So, when we look at the Quran and put all these facts together,
we will reach the truth.
I wanted to look at Sura 44, verse 3, because
for example, 44:3.
Therefore, the subject is very clear, but it's amazing how the average Muslim's view on it is so different.
Let me show you an example.
Look at this graph.
Look at the average in the room.
You can see that it's alarming.
Let me read you the numbers.
Sura 44, Ad-Dukhan.
Great.
Sura 44.
Verse 3, verse 3, it says what?
Ameen.
We sent it down on a blessed night.
We have revealed the Quran in a blessed month.
The Quran was revealed in one night.
The first time that was revealed was Sura Al-Alaq, The Clot, the first five verses.
This was the order of the revelation.
The first text that was revealed was Sura 96, the first five verses, 19 words, you know.
The second revelation was 38 words, Sura 68. The third revelation was 57 words, Sura 74.
The third revelation brought up the number 19, in Sura Al-Muddaththir, Sura 74.
The first complete Sura revealed was Al-Fatihah.
Which means the 19 letters of Bismillah Al-Rahman Al-Rahim came immediately after the mention of the number 19 in Sura Al-Muddaththir.
He received the Quran. He didn't know anything about it.
He received the Quran in his heart. He was taken up to the seventh heaven.
He didn't know anything about it.
He was definitely aware that something had happened, you know, and he was completely aware.
But because God says, "We will show him Our signs." So he was absolutely, he was completely aware.
Sura 53 says he was definitely aware. He was not imagining things. He was seeing the reality.
So he was aware that he was being appointed as the final prophet. He was given a message.
It's like some other verses tell, it tells the prophet not to hurry the revelation.
What I'm saying, was he aware, you know, that it was there in him, even if it wasn't quite clear what he was thinking?
Yes, yes, essentially, the indications were that he was aware.
Because Gabriel was telling him everything.
When Gabriel came, not just to reveal the Quran, he came with a whole bunch of instructions along with the Quran.
Like, for example, these verses belong to Sura 19, or Sura 16, in the specific position.
Or, this is now a new Sura, and it shall be entitled Jonah.
So, the instructions for, as of now, you will face towards Jerusalem, or as of now you will turn back from Jerusalem.
However, we did tell you to face Jerusalem.
But some of them are going to turn back on their heels.
No, I mean, the bad side is that they have to go back to Jerusalem.
Yes.
Right, but that's not what it means. It's still a divine command.
The change of the Qibla, it was a divine order.
Well, you set it up, you know, if you have a ball, you know,
and you throw this ball.
It's not that easy to set it back up.
The Prophet may have, maybe Gabriel had a ball with him.
The first house appointed for mankind.
Hey, are you sure it is Bakkah? We have it here and it's Bakkah.
So he would make it very clear that this should be written with a B.
And as I was showing brother Muhammad today, if it was written with an M,
the whole system would collapse. The whole mathematical system would collapse.
Because it is really
overwhelming, but God picked out the word that is most familiar to the Arabs at that time.
Regarding Muhammad, who was born there, it is his town, it is known as Mecca, the people go north and south,
they hear it, they know it is Mecca. So why Bakkah? This also shows the absolute obedience to the scripture.
They had an instance where God has said this is to be written in the Bible. It's fine.
But if someone said to you, "I want you to write down the true story in the Bible,"
you have to know something. It's ridiculous. You know it's true.
But then, when the divine authors came to write it in the Bible, that's it.
No way around it.
It only means there was no such thing.
No.
And they couldn't corrupt the word.
And it stayed like this, and then the generations that came after, that didn't dare to forge it, eh?
See?
They knew that it is sacred ground.
So they didn't dare. Of course, you must remember, God guaranteed the preservation of the Quran, so
So, even if they tried, they'd perish.
Absolutely, some people tried.
It's very interesting because this not only shows that
a spelling, which was not the normal one, has been preserved.
But later on, people began to notice that there's a difference.
Then they began to say, "Oh, this is another name." Oh.
But then there is no proof of that. They speculate that this is another, another thing.
When the most plausible explanation is that it was there from the beginning and nobody wanted to touch it. They were afraid.
It's interesting how when people make up an interpretation, they back it up with all sorts of stories.
For example, the letters before the surahs were put at the beginning of the surahs to get the attention of the people, to say, "Qaf. Wal-Quran il-Majeed."
So people will say, "What? What is this?" and so get their attention. And he said that this was a common thing in the Arabic literature.
This is to back up his assertion.
Now, it's very simple. All you need to do is show us some literature where they have these letters.
It's not true.
And, you know, it used to get me all upset because they always say things like that.
Why do you make a statement like that?
"It was very common in ancient Arabic literature."
I studied ancient Arabic literature.
And we have this recorded literature.
There wasn't a verse written on these stones. And there is no such thing.
This is not a common affair.
Because you will never find any such expressions.
Well, this Maududi follows his own thinking.
He should put A.M. before his books.
You'll say, "What's A.M.?" He'll say, "Abul Maududi."
Get the picture?
Yeah.
But it was a sign.
No, that is guesswork.
Why can't you explain then why only some of them needed attention and not all of them?
Exactly. That's another point.
Why do we have the letters attached only to twenty-nine chapters?
God doesn't want us to pay attention to the other chapters as well?
But the people, the interpreters, would back up their interpretations
with stories that are absolutely baseless.
Well, I mean, "I don't know what you're talking about."
Whenever a new revelation comes down, in fact, there's always somebody that has to write about it.
Right.
Yeah.
Now, how do we know what, how to differentiate them, too?
Whether it was just something that he was saying, or whether it was an actual revelation, you know, out of all these revelations.
I don't know.
Because Muhammad could not miss the visit of Gabriel.
If Gabriel visits you, he's not going to miss that.
No, his question I think is this.
The question is this, that how did the people around him, when the Prophet was reciting,
when the Prophet was reciting, how would the people around him know that now he is reciting Quran,
but at other times he is just talking from his own, how did the people know?
I understand the question. My answer was, he can't miss Gabriel's visit.
So when Gabriel comes and says,
قُلْ هُوَ اللَّهُ أَحَدٌ ﴿١﴾ اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ ﴿٢﴾ لَمْ يَلِدْ وَلَمْ يُولَدْ ﴿٣﴾ وَلَمْ يَكُن لَّهُ كُفُوًا أَحَدٌ ﴿٤﴾
He was telling him the Quran.
He was telling Muhammad at the time, and Muhammad was memorizing it.
And then he would say to the revelation scribes,
I have some more Quran now.
So he was telling them, قُلْ هُوَ اللَّهُ أَحَدٌ اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ
And they write it down, but that's not the end of it;
they memorize it just like we're doing now.
Now, that's what was going on.
But that actually is,
this itself is really one of the wonderful things.
In the Sirat an-Nabi,
the history, the biographical process,
the people around him knew.
They knew very well when he was under inspiration.
And then they themselves would
hear what he's saying and they would memorize it.
The people around him, they knew, the people knew the difference.
It is a very, very beautiful thing. They also knew when he would just speak, you know, ordinary things.
Although I don't know how true it is that he changes.
Because in some ways it's a form of, he becomes an instrument.
They know from his face and his utterance. It's not his, it's not his language.
It's just like, for example, all of us now. We know the way you talk to us.
But imagine if you were talking like Shakespeare. We all know that it's not you.
So it's a very wonderful phenomenon how the people with him would know that it's a revelation,
and they would themselves memorize it when he has ended.
As far as the physical changes are concerned, I really don't buy that, that he used to faint and sweat and all these things, that some doctors diagnosed him with epilepsy.
Yeah, I really don't buy that.
I don't go that far. I only say that there are some changes.
Yeah.
Yeah, but it's not exactly fair to be called that.
But it is something that exists in the books,
they show that he would not respond,
or anything unconscious, or anything.
But according to a doctor,
a Jesuit doctor
in the Philippines, an American doctor,
he's saying,
and he does not believe in the Quran,
he's even an enemy of Islam,
but this man told us very clearly
from the medical point of view,
these recitations would not have come
from an epileptic, he says.
Yes, well, that epileptic story. I don't blame them because they make up these stories.
But if you look at 17:106.
Kathryn?
17:106, this is page 196 at the top.
It says, this is a Quran that we portioned for you to read to the people over a long period, though we sent it down all at once.
There is another one, there's a verse that is 'to fix it'... but it's not fixed...
in my memory.
I'm going to find it, it is important.
It says that we released it over
a long period in order to fix it in
your memory. So, this
will indicate to me that
Gabriel would release
a few verses
and then would wait
until he memorizes it.
Now, I want
to remind you also of the angels
that went to Abraham, visited him, in the form of human beings. Then Abraham went and
slaughtered a calf for them. He roasted the calf and brought it to them. The angels
don't eat like this. They don't have the same digestive system as Abraham, or the needs
that we have. Even with you, in the eternal life, you will not need to eat. Or maybe you
will. Let's not go into this. But anyway, the angels wouldn't eat the roasted calf that
Abraham brought. So this tells us that the angels come to the people in the form of human beings.
They came to Abraham and there is no reason why Gabriel wouldn't come to Muhammad in the form of a human being
and help him release the Quran and take it to a memorizer.
Oh, here it is, I'm going to... this is a very important verse we're talking about the revelation
of the Quran, 25:32. Surah 25, verse 32, that you guys are the most informed people
in the world.
And to more serious things.
Verse 32 says, "The disbelievers said, 'How come the Quran was not
revealed to him all at once?'" We thus
released it gradually in order to fix it in your memory.
That's the reason why it was released over a period of 23 years.
Gabriel would read it. He fixed it in the prophet's memory and the companions of course who were around
him, they were also memorizing it along with him. They didn't know how to read or write
but that gave them a sharp memory and gave them a lot of time, nothing else to do. Because
because really it takes a lot of time to memorize it and to keep it alive in memory.
So this, "to fix it in memory," indicates
that Gabriel would release it in a few verses, then leave Muhammad,
to allow him to memorize it. So whether the revelation writers were there or not,
when the prophet met them
he would send somebody to bring them
and he would tell them,
I have some Quran for you
and you write it down.
Would it also,
would it not be
reasonable to say
that it makes sense
why the Quran has to be,
among other reasons,
revealed in portions?
It makes sense why the Quran
has to be revealed
on different occasions, because
some of them are really guides
for a specific occasion.
For example,
after the Battle of
Badr, after the Battle of Badr.
How can a revelation talk
about the results of
the Battle of Badr if
it has not taken
place? So that's
why we may have to use
this kind of philosophical language, that the Quran, as you say, is given as a whole,
put in the heart of the Prophet, and released at different times.
The revealing is there, actually in the heart, but potentially for certain occasions.
When the occasion comes, it becomes actualized, relative to the occasion.
But there is the occasion of Zayd and the divorce of his wife.
Now, the Quran was written before the earth was created.
And it was put in Muhammad's heart before these things took place.
It's one of the miraculous aspects of the Quran.
So, when Zayd divorced his wife and the Prophet was to marry Zayd's wife,
that's when these verses were released. That was the time for it. So this is a very good point that Douglas just raised.
Okay, back to you.
In that particular verse, you know, the prophet Muhammad, he didn't want to hear it.
Yes.
God just scolded him for doing it.
Yeah, because it was against the tradition. It was against the false religion.
But he was worried about what the people would say.
But how did he know? Was it because he was aware, at least somewhat, of the revelation?
When we go to that verse, it's very interesting.
But it's very interesting because, you know, where is his prophethood here?
Because actually it was there, but he was keeping it. Did he want it? Do you remember?
Yes, it was there. It was supposed to come out in the revelation, but he is scolded by the Quran. Didn't you point that out?
Oh, yes. He is scolded.
But there are many different kinds of inspiration and revelation. There is a kind where you are put in a situation where you either submit to God or you object.
He was put in that kind of situation, a situation where he was afraid of what the people were thinking.
thinking.
But when a certain inspiration comes to you from God, it just takes over, and you just
can't think of anything else.
Like Moses' mother, for example, throwing her baby in the river.
Have you ever heard of Linda throwing her baby in the river?
Or any mother?
No mother in the world would do that without a divine inspiration.
But it was some kind of an inspiration.
See, we all know what a loving mother you are, Linda.
I'll use you as an example for that.
We're going to see what kind of mother Donna is. She'll probably dote on him.
Very soon, very soon.
But this is the kind of inspiration that just takes over. There's nothing else you can do.
You do it.
Now what should we do?
What would be the inspiration?
A direct command from God.
A command from God.
God wants the prophet to marry
Zayd's wife to establish a law, a precedent.
That was the idea.
I mean, there could be many more.
So, and the Quran is not...
Okay, back to 185.
Ramadan is the month during which the Quran was revealed,
and I think we already stated this point earlier.
a beacon of guidance, clear proofs of guidance, and the Statute Book.
The Statute Book is the book of laws.
Regulations.
The final, final law.
Initially, the commandment, "You shall not kill," for example, that's it.
But here the Quran gives details, for example, the laws of murder:
murder for murder: a man for a man, a woman for a woman.
God wishes convenience for you rather than hardship for you.
He wishes to enable you to complete the count, and to glorify God for guiding you, and to show
your appreciation.
When you say, "I believe in God," you have to do something about it.
You can't just say, "I believe in God," and then you don't do the contact prayers, or you don't...
I don't know.
(Questioner): I have a question on that.
(Rashad): Yeah?
(Questioner): I'm just curious, earlier you were talking about travelers.
What is the problem with traveling, for example?
(Rashad): The idea is, it is hard. If you took a plane,
it could be a long journey.
If you take a plane from here to the north, you wouldn't be able to do it.
This is an example of the difficulty.
But if you are confined in a cabin, it is really hard.
It was really hard.
You know, in the desert, storms and...
That's why the Quran says if you can't do it, you shall feed one poor person.
And at the end of the day, you break the fast.
Even in these modern days, nobody would die from abstaining from food and water.
You know, it's hard, you know, to do it if you don't believe in it.
And this will show your appreciation of God, that you really believe in God.
And when it says to fast in the month of Ramadan, you fast no matter what.
And as for pregnancy, yes, it is hard.
It's hard, you can do it some other time.
You can fast some other time.
If you can do it, it's better for you than it is to not do it.
I'm not saying it's bad for you.
What can I do?
Because it's painful.
Oh, they can help you.
Yeah.
Did you pray?
When he was crying, they told me to ask him.
Oh, I see.
So I came here.
He put you down.
But you were coming for him.
Come on.
That's why he's so big.
That's so great!
Is that good? Let me pick up the booklet and give you one.
My servant.
Oh, I want to say that, you know, how
God designed Ramadan for the test.
When he was saying that Ramadan comes in the short days in the winter,
for the day, only 8 hours, and fasting is really nothing, it's just skipping your breakfast and lunch,
and then you eat, so there's nothing to it.
And if you take 100 people who will fast when the day is short,
and then Ramadan moves, and the day becomes longer,
and 15 people will drop out when the day is 10 hours.
Then we'll have 85 people fasting. And then the day becomes 14 hours, the fasting day.
And 20 more people drop out, so we have 65 people left.
And then the day goes on to 15 hours, and 20 more people drop out.
Because it's getting too long. You have 45 people left. And then the day is 16 hours,
long and hot, 16 hours long, then you have 20 more people drop out.
And the 25 that are left, these are the 25 die-hard believers who will fast no matter what.
And you can see how the test is designed. The whole universe is designed for that test.
And it's the same when you pray. Now you are praying
before sunrise. Whether you like it or not, or because you have to be at work at eight o'clock, or whatever.
So, you're praying, now, are you praying Fajr before sunrise because God says you pray before sunrise, or because you have to go to work at eight o'clock?
Now, now, the truth of you, this question will be answered when the sunrise is at 4 o'clock.
You're going to pray Fajr before sunrise, or you're going to pray at 7 o'clock? at noon?
That will show you whether you are praying Fajr because God said so, or because your
boss said, come to work at 11 o'clock.
The whole universe is designed for the test.
The axis of the earth is tilted 23 degrees just so the days would be longer, and the sunrise
would be different.
Just to test you.
Do you get the point?
When God tells you to pray morning before sunrise, this means that you are going to
as a die-hard believer, as one who really believes in God, who knows that God is the one running your life, and provides for you,
and promises to make you a king or a queen on earth,
you believe the Quran, you know all these things, then you will get up for the prayer, period.
even if for some reason you fall into the middle of hell, it doesn't matter.
And this is what this verse means by due appreciation of God.
He doesn't want to bother you, and disturb you, and get you up—of course not—in the morning.
He doesn't need our prayers. That's what's good for you, and good for me.
That's what prepares you to join the kingdom, for God's sake.
So, the day will come when you are resurrected to enter the eternal life, the real life.
You can close your eyes a few minutes and then open them, the next time you open
your eyes on the day of resurrection.
Now what would your position be?
Are you qualified to join the kingdom of God?
Or were you lazy?
You couldn't get up before sunrise to save your life.
But when your boss says, "Come in, we have an emergency and you have to come at 3 o'clock every morning for the next two weeks,"
you can go at 3 o'clock every morning for two weeks.
If you don't, you'll get fired.
But that's what distinguishes the believers from the idle person.
So don't be discouraged.
If you understand you're praying one prayer a day,
hopefully you will make progress.
That will count.
This is the motto here: progress is our most important thing.
Progress is our most important thing.
The important thing is that you do not regress into not praying.
You must progress into doing two prayers a day, and from that you progress to doing three
prayers a day, and so forth.
You make a point of never regressing.
Maybe you will never pray morning before sunrise.
That is a known, major struggle.
Because your body is a wild horse that you are trying to train.
It's a real wild horse. Your body is real wild.
It doesn't want to get up in the morning.
It's very difficult to get up in the morning.
And this is the wrong idea.
Because if you are strong, you will make your body get up.
Now, if your body is stronger than your soul, then you, you are in deep trouble.
But try to exercise your soul until you are stronger than your body.
Because your body is going to die.
And you are going to stay on.
You are going to stay on as a strong person.
And we must gain it.
So it's very important not to be discouraged.
And that progress is the most important progress.
You progress from one prayer a day to two prayers a day,
until you do the five prayers a day,
and then you progress to praying with passion every day.
So, that's just that.
So, God wishes that you fulfill your duties.
He wants you to fulfill your duties.
But the test requires that God does not interfere.
So, Satan and the angels will not cry out.
The idea is that God does not interfere, but God wants you to be saved, God wants you to join the kingdom,
He wants you to be a king or queen on earth.
He wants you to have absolutely no masters.
He wants you to be a king.
So, that's what this verse is saying. He wishes to enable you to fulfill your duty.
He wants you to pass the test.
But people that thrust and climb the fence need to be held.
God puts fences in front of them to prevent them from going to hell, but they don't care.
God wishes to enable you to fulfill your duty, and to glorify God for guiding you,
and to show your appreciation.
by fasting the month of Ramadan, by praying the five prayers in their time, by giving charity, being charitable, kind.
This country is under a terrible test right now with all the tragedies and the poor people.
And you should hear all the mean, average Americans. Take them all and throw them in hell, you know.
They were thinking in Phoenix of building a park for their vans, to give them some fuel.
And you should hear all the people speaking against it.
They dirty up this city, you know.
It's like, it's like their choice to be poor or hungry or whatever.
But this is the test. The test for this country.
And a Muslim must be of good character, must be kind, must be thankful that he's not
put in that position. They are human beings. They're having their own test in their own world.
So, these are the duties that God wants us to fulfill.
It's Salat prayers, Zakat (charity), the fasting of Ramadan,
and Hajj pilgrimage when we can.
Look at 186.
And when My servants ask you about Me,
I am always near.
I respond to the call of any caller who calls on Me.
Therefore, they shall respond to Me and believe in Me, that they may be guided.
So these are the requirements that your prayer be answered.
Are your prayers answered?
You shall be always, the day you fulfill the requirements, respond to Me, respond to God,
And believe in God. People who believe in God and respond to him, respond meaning they obey His commands.
Then He hears your call. That's not all. God says He's closer to you than the jugular vein.
Look at this thing. Closer to you than this. How could He be closer?
Because God controls the count of blood cells in your vein. He controls that, the flow of blood in your vein.
I think it's Sura 86, but I don't know if you look at that.
I don't know if you look at that.
I've been looking a lot at that.
Fifty. Sixteen.
Fifty, verse sixteen.
We created the human being and are fully aware of his innermost thoughts, and are closer
to him than his jugular vein.
Is it cold for people?
I'm going to turn the heat on now.
Is it off?
Okay.
So when My servants ask you about Me, I am always near.
Now, you may pray for something, and because you're a good believer, your prayer is answered,
but not exactly at the time you want it, because God does not ...
Sometimes we say, don't say, I don't know how to put this, but
as a king or queen on earth, the angels are all around you and they're eager to
complete whatever you want. So sometimes you may make statements
and they rush into completing those statements on the oral
because they don't know your qalb.
I'm going to give an example of it this way: God is, when you
pray to God, He knows what is best for you, what is the best time, so you may pray for
something that is not good for you at this particular time, and your prayer will
come to pass at the exact, the best time for you, at the right time. And if you recall,
I gave an example of where I thought that the prayer takes three to six months to get
fulfilled. Remember that story? I was thinking of the seven universes and how
how far it is. And, well, I noticed, that was my conclusion, that when I pray for
something, it is fulfilled, but it takes three or six months. So I came to the final conclusion
that it takes three to six months for God to answer the prayer. And the day I came to
that conclusion, I hit that, I was driving down the street in Tripoli, in Libya, and I
I hit that kid in the head, in the head, and it was going so fast it took me a half a block to stop.
That kid was lying down on the side of the street and was supposed to be dead.