More and more.
And I, uh, because these are very, very bad cases, you know, like old Arabs, that they take the money of orphans for their own use.
To the extent that no money is left for these orphans when they grow up.
And they do not even have inheritance rights, because they are not adopted. They just live in the house.
Okay, the next verse is very important, and we're going to close after we read this verse.
And I'd like to make a correction. It says, in effect, "Do not marry pagans."
I would translate it as "idol worshipers." Do not marry idol worshipers.
And when you look at the footnote, it says,
"Pagans include those who are not Jewish, Christian, or Muslim."
Most scholars of Islam say that this includes the ancient idol-worshipping Arabians, Hindus, Zoroastrians,
and also some of the Buddhists.
So, again, I will focus on the idol worshippers.
And this includes Muslims in the Sunni and Shia Muslim world.
But this is not a verse that says you shall not marry a Jew. It's really, I agonize over
this, because Christians, the worshippers of Jesus, are also idol worshippers.
But, we can marry them? This is a very tricky verse. Let us read it first, okay?
2:221 says, "You shall not marry pagan women unless they believe."
"A believing woman is better than a pagan one, even if you like her."
"Nor shall you permit your women to marry a pagan man unless he believes."
"A believing man is better than a pagan one, even if you like him."
"They invite to hell, while God invites to Paradise and forgiveness in accordance with His will."
"He clarifies His revelations for the people, that they may take heed."
So, in Surah 5, we are permitted to marry Jews and Christians.
But, you cannot marry a Muslim who does not believe in what is stated in the Quran.
When we receive the Quran, where every page says, "Do not worship idols," and the Quran
is complete and perfect, etc., etc., then our responsibility is not to deny it.
I mentioned before the example of God's chosen people, and how they have been suffering,
and you know, this, that, and the other.
It's because the responsibility doubles when God chooses you and gives you His message.
Your responsibility is doubled.
So when God gives you a message that says, "This message is complete and perfect,"
and you say, "No, it is not complete,"
then you have reserved for yourself a punishment many-fold.
And this is why there are now so many Christians and Jews,
but not all of them. There are those who do not believe in Christ,
or make confession.
And you have to believe this.
That's why if you break this law, you suffer a lot.
When you break this law and marry an unbeliever, emotionally, you suffer a lot of pain.
Number one thing: you follow this law. You marry a believer, even if you don't like him or her.
So if you're about to get married, then you ask your fiancé to believe, and this will
serve two purposes.
First, it will be a proof of genuine love.
He or she changes for you.
Second, when you're ready to make the commitment, you make it a condition for marriage.
If the candidate is a Muslim who believes that the Prophet is a deliverer, then you make it a condition as well.
And you depart, cut the rope, and you say, "No, I'm not going to marry you if you continue to believe that the Prophet is a deliverer."
Now, if you are lax in this commandment, you will suffer a lot of pain.
You are saying that they are not supposed to marry a person who believes in Hadith, right?
Right.
Okay.
But you are saying that the Muslim can't marry a Christian or Jew.
But those Christians cannot be idol worshippers, right?
That Christian should not be a Jesus worshipper.
What?
They didn't say that. They said, even as they are, because they were not subjected, they had not received the Quran, they didn't look at it.
And there is a possibility that they would become believers.
But the Muslim already looked at the Quran, and saw with his or her own eyes that the Quran says, this book is complete and fully detailed.
And they made a decision to reject that, and not to believe God.
And that person already made a stand, and God made a stand against that person that joined an imaginary partner with God.
But the Christian, the Christian didn't go through that test.
The Christian who believes Jesus is God, or a son of God,
may eventually, and it would be easier for that person to come to the Quran alone,
than it is for a person who already looked at the Quran and decided that it was not complete,
Although some of you may not be always worried about it, but it's a real problem
when you put it into practice.
But in actual life, I'm sure there are hundreds of thousands of these Submission girls who don't
even know one way or the other.
So they're available, don't worry.
Okay?
Okay? Because don't imagine that all of the Muslim women are worshippers of Hadith.
Some of them don't even know the Quran, nor the Hadith.
Right. These are just...
Yes. Yeah, they are the right ones for you.
Yes.
So...
Don't go on.
By the way, when I say choice of women, it's Turkish women, maybe more Turkish women.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Man.
Any question before it goes?
You're gonna have to
question yourself a lot.
I always
heard about it.
I always think of it.
You're a child now.
You're a child.
Try that again.
I do
worship God.
I worship God.
But there is an exception in Surah 5. Just look at it, in Surah 5.
Surah 5, verse 4... verse 5. Surah 5, verse 5.
It says: Today, all good things are permitted for you, and the food of those who were given the Scripture
is permitted for you, and your food is permitted for them.
Also, you are permitted to marry the chaste believing women, as well as the chaste women
who are Jewish or Christian.
Provided you pay them their due dowries, and maintain chastity, not committing adultery,
nor taking secret lovers.
Anyone who commits idolatry nullifies his work and will be among the losers.
So, you have the beautiful companions. They call them Hur 'In, I don't know, Hur 'In with...
You don't want to have them?
They are not promiscuous, nor do they have lovers.
Pure mates.
They are beautiful companions, pure.
The definition of pagans are those who say that Christ, the son of Mary, is God.
I would imagine that the majority of Christians who say this, if they take a stand, but if they are born into it and don't know any better, although there are many Christians who say that Christ is only a prophet. However, other Christians don't consider them to be Christians, because that is an intramural problem among them.
(Silence)
They ask you about menstruation. Say, "It is a harm."
You should avoid intercourse with women during menstruation until they are clean.
Once they are clean, you may have intercourse with them in the manner designated by God.
God loves the repentant, and He loves those who are clean.
I think this is the only verse around that deals with menstruation, and it is straightforward.
A significant word here that was not correctly translated in English is the word "Tawwabeen," the repentant.
There are two words in Arabic: one that means "to repent," and one that means "to continuously repent."
And the word used here is the one that means "continuously repent."
Not simply "to repent."
Not just "to repent once."
But the word used here, Tawwabeen, means to always repent.
And as we have been learning in the last few khutbahs, is that you cannot go to Heaven with one sin.
You have to be sinless to qualify.
As Adam and Eve committed one sin, they were kicked out.
And one way of erasing sin is repentance.
You have to repent continuously, you have to make it a habit.
Just as when you toss and turn in your bed and you are half asleep, you must train yourself to repent.
Just when you are half conscious, just as you turn in your bed, you repent.
And say, "My Lord, I repent to You." Then if you commit it again, you repent again.
This is the function of repentance: to erase whatever wrong you might have done.
And at the same time, the repentance will be accepted again.
So, God loves the repentant, but that's not the perfect English word.
I guess we can use multiple words to say, "God loves those who continuously repent."
Yes, this is one of the problems, especially with the Arabic language. Yes. And He loves those who are clean.
Yes.
I'm just curious about a specific case. What if you made a vow not to speed, but then you have to go faster on the road to catch a flight? Then you have to ask yourself, how do you deal with breaking that vow?
Okay, it's a difficult situation. You swore to God, but now you need to get to the airport.
Then you don't do it.
After this, you have to fast for three days; you'll see it's spelled out for you.
But if you have the means to make a different expiation,
that's when it's different.
There's nobody else involved except you.
But what if your vow involves someone else?
Say, you're going to meet somebody at the airport,
and there's somebody who depends on you.
So, in this case, you have involved somebody else.
Abdullah Arik pledged to donate $100 to the poor for breaking his oath.
Now, the poor, even though they are unknown, they are still involved in it, so he can't take it back.
And the easiest sin to deal with is something that only you are involved in.
Well, unless you make it a vow, then...
it was just words. That's all that God had found.
There are two kinds of expiations: the pre-meditated broken promise where somebody has to be
involved with it at all.
This is an involved story.
Yeah?
I was thinking that, um, because I know when I, when I make the sincere decision, you know,
You know, what it's like... I was thinking it was more like the intention behind it, also, you know. Like when you say that, like, 'I promise never to sin or fall to temptation or whatever it is,' your intention is not to.
Right.
Well, you mean it.
You are sincere.
Right.
You're not perfect and you're going to fall, but at the time you said it, your intention was pure, that you're never, you're never going to.
You mean it.
So, can you say that the intention behind the vow is something that...
Yeah, that's what I'm saying. It does depend on the type of offense you're committing and requires expiation.
So, the expiation for a broken vow, if you planned it from the start, it doesn't work at all.
It doesn't work at all?
Yeah, from the very start, it doesn't work.
And maybe they'll turn back like that.
Yeah.
When you vow you will not sin again, and then you fall and you sin, that's what it
says.
You are supposed to be reminding yourself all the time.
Never again! And God will accept again from you.
You have to expect weakness. You have to have exasperation against yourself, not other people.
I am sorry God, I will never be arrogant again.
So he is saying this, I am telling you, really, it comes to that point of perfection.
As far as 'Azm is concerned.
If you have a bad habit of lying, you say, "Never again will I lie."
You intend not to lie again.
It is not a wish or an empty intent. You have a real intention. You have to set them up.
And the intention and planning will be there for it.
This kind of planning.
So, and you keep reminding yourself, not letting go of it, that's it.
Because you get rid of a bad habit, and then another bad habit, and so forth.
And you're cleansing yourself one by one.
So, this word 'Azm is very important.
And it's not just somewhere here, it's in the verse itself.
And the impression from the verse is, and I describe it in that way, to the extent that when you are half-conscious, tossing in bed, asleep, as soon as you are half-conscious, you say, "I repent. Forgive me, God, for my sins. I repent. I'll never do it again." You make it a habit. God loves the repenters. It's positive.
Repentance is also a recognition of God, a dhikr, a commemoration of God.
And if you can find an excuse to repent to God at every chance that is given, then you're in good shape.
You told me, Jeff, a few years ago, that the reason for God's allowance...
But if you think like that, on every day of your life, there's going to be more and more
of this happening.
If you don't worry about what's going to happen tomorrow, you know, if this process
is kind of giving you, you know what I mean, it's delivering this kind of thing
around the world, you know, that kind of stuff, you know, you need to support that.
You know, I think a lot of people still tell themselves that, well, I'm going to do it
or do that.
You know, I'm going to do it or I'm not going to do it.
You know what I'm talking about?
I think that if you relegate this body to that state, you won't be as successful as you are today.
Well, it's the bombardment from Christianity that sees this human being as a sinner.
The original sin, the idea that we inherited sin in this body, you know,
it's the spirit that was sinning.
But we are now in the body.
And hopefully it's going to end. But the sin is not yours.
You don't have to be a sinner.
You must be ready to die now. If you want to go to heaven, then you have to think about this.
We have two separate worlds. We all strive and those straying will not make it, so you must be ready.
You have to be ready, you have to be ready all the time, and if you bear in mind that you cannot put the hereafter on standby, not on a single standby, then actually as a believer in God alone you have to be determined not to have anything in your head, none.
And the way to address them is repentance.
The things that you cannot repent from are the ones where you know something is wrong and
you do it, knowing it is wrong.
You can't repent from that; you have to pay for it.
You have to pay for it here, and that's the only alternative, actually.
Because paying for it over there is a whole different ballgame.
There's no such thing as paying over there.
You have to pay for it here.
So the price would be even steeper, I suppose,
for sins in front of the people.
Now this is where the
purification acts come into existence: the five prayers.
You will get your sins erased.
Fasting of Ramadan is a positive deed that erases the negative deeds.
Erases sin.
Because there are, almost surely, sins that you are not aware of.
You passed by your brother or sister and you didn't greet them, or you frowned at them.
Or there was something in your mind
against your brother.
you read a phrase.
I read something like that
about the great sins he committed
before he seriously became
a believer in God alone.
that these are,
if we weren't aware of it,
if we hadn't read the Quran,
And even if you read it, they do admit that, because it's in the Book, that these are forgiven more easily.
Not only forgiven, they are converted into credits.
The Quran teaches that when you come to God, if you repent, you know, if you come to God, if you turn in your repentance,
you apologize for all the past sins, you show remorse and determination never to do it again, they actually become credit.
I remember one time I was flying to Egypt, and there was a gentleman next to me, I think he was a major in the army,
And he was collecting all the bottles of liquor, you know, to keep around him and drink and get numb.
So I couldn't help telling him, "You know, you're accumulating a good number of sins this way."
And he said, "Are you familiar with the Russian proverb that says, 'the more sins, the more credit'?"
He said, "Yeah, I've got to accumulate as many sins as possible, so I can convert them to credit."
That was the best excuse I've ever heard.
I think that was the only verse he ever remembered from the Quran.
And that's true.
That you spent a life of idol worship and sin and so forth,
and then you became repentant.
When you come to God, then what did you pay for this great credit?
I have a feeling that this great credit is accompanied by a punishing process,
which is quite real.
But when you look at what it is doing—the cleansing process and the conversion of sin
into credit—it is actually a blessing, a great blessing, the blessing of this life, because
everything passes, all hardships pass, but for the sin to be in your record, or to be documented,
it's an unequal deal, really.
And one verse says, "Those who are spared Hell,
they enter Heaven and have triumphed,
and have witnessed the great triumph."
There must be amongst the repenters,
those who continuously repent.
2:223.
Your women are a tilth for you,
and you may enjoy your tilth however you like, so long as you maintain righteousness.
You shall observe God, and know that you will ultimately meet Him.
Give good news to the believers.
Is this all clear?
The key sentences here are in verse 222, "in the manner designated by God," the key expression.
And in 2:223, "so long as you maintain righteousness."
So there are limits beyond which there will be abuse or misuse.
Let's have a question.
That's what I'm talking about, you don't want to do it.
Because you wouldn't know how to do it.
If you didn't know how to do it, you wouldn't do it right.
They are a field for you.
Now, this phrase, in comparison, it feels like this falls more on men than on women. You know what I mean?
Well, I mean, it's not just for the women or just for the men.
No, but it says that "they are garments for you, and you are garments for them."
What was that verse? Was that 2:223?
No, that was the verse that mentioned "garments".
2:187.
2:187?
Yes, 2:187 says... it says you may have intercourse with your spouses during the nights of the fast.
They are garments for you, and you are garments for them.
So it's a two-way, a two-way street.
Not just a one-way.
It is a fact of life that men are the ones who are usually the aggressors.
We have to hear Glenda's voice, my goodness. She was so quiet, we just had to know what she thinks.
Okay, let's see, another question, you know, I've got the, uh, 4:34 and all of these...
If He weren't Omniscient, then He wouldn't know what your transgressions were in the first place.
And if He were not Omniscient, He wouldn't have the power to forgive them.
God
is Forgiving
and Clement.
When a governor gives clemency.
we give the pardon,
A man is
on death row ready to die
for his mortal sins and
the governor calls, a plea of clemency
is made,
and the governor
receives clemency and gives his pardon.
So God is the ultimate one,
clemency.
That works like a check.
So, people swear a lot, you know, I hear people swear a lot, but it's
just not a good practice to say, "By God this," and "By God that," and "Goddamn this," in the name
of God, and so forth.
Or to use the words of scripture, the words of God, as part of idol worship.
That's one of the traps we want to avoid.
There's another way of seeing it.
A lot of people, they talk about God and they appear to be righteous in their speech.
But really, it's not what you say that's important.
You're held responsible for what you intend to do, or what your motivation is.
Here we have in the Quran what we know from psychology: the underlying structure of human behavior is motivation.
It's what you intend to do or what you're motivated to do that makes a difference.
Well, this is something you can read in modern psychology, which is right here in the Quran.
The person's motives or their intentions is the true way of deciding what they're all about and not just what they think.
And sometimes the motives are very deep-lying.
People can draw a line between this and that, to say something is one thing and another.
First of all, they must have a motive.
There's a very famous book on mathematics called Laws of Form, which also enforces
the mystical conception of the world.
The first sentence in it is,
"The motive is prior to distinction."
Before we draw a boundary between A and B, we have to have a motive.
That's quite good and important.
I think the question was about a person in the church, not for the sin, to receive a blessing from God through the Eucharist, not through the act of the church, but the intention was not to commit a sin, but to accept Jesus Christ.
And then a man said to me one day in the office, he had made an oath, and he said, "What am
I supposed to do to break my oath?"
I said, "You have to fast three days, or feed ten poor people."
He said, "Can I smoke now?"
He decided to either fast for three days, or feed ten poor people.
But in the case of saying, "I pledge I will never sin again," then the person cannot say,
"OK, I want to commit adultery."
He thinks he's supposed to fast three days, and then he can commit adultery.
This is a premeditated sin.
And you can see the consequences of this crime.
He decided to feed some poor people and he went around smoking, but that's not the point.
The conditions that he had created for himself were for breaking the law.
And he decides not to fast, but then says, "I'm going to feed some poor people and then go commit the sin."
So if you make a mockery of it, would you do it?
Like, I don't know.
"I don't care about the people that stand by it."
Idolatry is bad.
Idolatry.
And you really need to see it.
It's no better than this.
I mean, if you sin...
Anything is forgivable, but not idolatry.
I know, but...
You know?
You can't do that.
You can't defend them, but you have to say it.
Anything is forgivable.
We have to make a distinction between forgivability and repentance.
Forgivability is: anything is forgivable.
That's the first argument.
The other choice is idolatry. Some would say that all sins are the same, idolatry and
disrespecting the creator.
Crime, sex, killing, anything, everything is the same, but not idolatry, because you
can kill someone and get forgiven, so you can kill someone and get forgiven.
If this was our only choice, I would easily take this request to the Prophet.
That's our only choice. This is what we expect of him.
God chose him to be a beloved servant, just as he is.
And the people who really love Jesus are the ones who know him for who he really is.
The people who love Muhammad are the ones who follow him, and follow what he followed.
I've never heard of that.
I've heard of that.
That's not a big deal.
Anything is forgivable,
but idolatry.
Now if you talk about
the person who invites you to the temple
to serve Jesus as a god,
or a philosophical leader,
that's not forgivable.
When you talk about
to serve a saint,
or a religious leader or a Christian saint,
that is unforgivable.
They can become believers, but they can't defend their idolatry. They can become believers.
They can become believers.
A person can be an idol worshiper and become a believer.
Prophet Muhammad, in fact, was an idol worshiper and he became a believer. He was a martyr.
And then, for example, the hypocrites and the disbelievers give up the right to be forgiven
anyway.
So they don't make it to God.
Well, He says here, "When they are told, 'Come to the message of light,
to ask for forgiveness,' they turn their heads, puffed up with arrogance."
Whether you ask forgiveness for them or do not ask forgiveness for them, Allah will not forgive them.
Allah does not guide the wicked people.
We're talking about deliverance.
But the majority of believers fall into idolatry, and almost 100% of the believers go through a stage of idolatry at one point or another.
So, first the disbelievers are out, and the hypocrites are actually worse, because they are among the believers.
They don't believe.
A disbeliever, you know he is a disbeliever, and you are on your guard. But when it comes to the hypocrite who is among the believers, they say, "He is completely righteous." But when he gets a chance, he'll go to you and say, "This is not complete, that is not complete," trying to create doubt.
And he is worse, because he appears to be righteous, and you think he is a great Muslim, and you listen, and usually they are very eloquent.
That's a telltale sign.
The Quran says he will be in the lowest pit of Hell, because of that.
If a person says, "I'm a disbeliever," you will listen to him or her knowing that this person is a disbeliever.
A person comes to you as a great believer, and that leads you away from the truth.
That's a lot worse.
But weren't they believers at one time? I mean, hypocrites are people who believed at one time.
They do not have to be.
They were not the first.
It could be anyone else.
In fact, many of them became believers.
They were in it for the gain.
At first, they were, you know,
they would like to be seen as Muslims,
but at the same time, they were tired of the obligations.
So now, they are more afraid of commitment.
So, after that, it is much more of a front.
Let's talk about our people.
Unintentionally, intentionally,
someone goes out and drinks alcohol.
He is a sinner. He is not a disbeliever. He is not following the guidance.
He is a sinner.
If he sits around and says, "I don't drink," when in fact he does, that is hypocrisy.
The question is about Muhammad.
We have two people here from Seattle who are going to go back and hear this, I just heard
this recently, about how much we could, we could just the case of what's going on, and
I've heard you say it before, but they're going to have the same thing going at them, I know.
It's the idea that Muhammad was a good model.
He got the Quran and he followed it.
And let's look at his life and let's model our lives after his life,
which is just to give you the formula.
And we should do the things that he did, because he's the prophet.
He is a good model, so let's follow his model.
That's their argument.
The Quran refutes this. For example, the Quran says you gave attention to the rich man and you frowned upon the poor man because he was poor.
You're giving attention to the rich man because he's rich. The Qur'an says don't do that.
The Qur'an says the Prophet feared the people instead of fearing God. And the Qur'an says don't do that.
Therefore, this action is not godly. Not godly.
The Quran says do not follow the example of the prophet blindly.
Let me give you the Quran's criteria. The main difference between killing by mistake
and killing deliberately is spelled out carefully.
I have a question about Surah 4, verse 92 and 93.
Yes, 4:92 states the recompense for killing by mistake.
There is no believer who kills another believer except by mistake.
Whoever kills a believer by mistake, his atonement is specified.
Then comes verse 93. As for the one who kills a believer deliberately,
his recompense is Hell, to abide therein forever. God's wrath and curse are upon him, and He has prepared for him a great punishment.
He could not be a believer if he kills a believer deliberately.
We notice in 92 that no believer kills another believer, except by mistake.
But in 93, it doesn't just say a believer who kills a believer.
It says, "As for the one who kills a believer deliberately."
It says that for the killer of a believer,
and it goes on to say his retribution is Hell,
wherein he abides forever, and God is angry with him, and curses him, and has prepared for him a great retribution.
Next time if you slap me on the face, I'm going to cut you up, throw you on the ground, and then step on you, and trample you to death, and then whip you a hundred times.
But I want you to notice the point of the scenario.
The situation is a believer kills another believer; that is the story.
And the question is, is this person who killed a believer still a believer in this story?
So that person is not a believer.
But what is a believer?
Let me illustrate. I mean, I like to think of a person as I see them, and I've always been like this.
And as far as the person is concerned, that man doesn't grow.
I'll give you an example, just to give you an idea of what I'm trying to say.
You know, as far as belief is concerned, a lot of times what I hear is that there are a lot of people who tell us that they are believing.
And a lot of us might perceive ourselves as believing, but when a situation of a trial arises, we might turn back.
You know what I'm saying?
And in that case, we can tell who the true ones are.
We can recognize them by their mark.
It's the only way that we could really know our true selves.
And, um, um, like, you know, again, when I was raised in the world before I submitted,
it said, it said, it said, um, regarding the church, the focus is on the man, not the Lord,
the church itself.
We have to get to the truth from the people who are giving us the Quran, and the message is in
But it's only through the text that we really know what is right, and otherwise we don't really know where we're coming from.
That's right.
They just made it look like that.
That's what I wanted to say.
That's what I said.
It is needed for the redemption of the human being.
People can be overcome by their emotions,
because we can give in to them.
The time of death,
the eternal abode that we are heading for,
I guess, as we can understand it,
is not of much concern at the time of death.
But even in their life,
in their consciousness,
Thank you.