Well, I do, I have something to say, because this ākhiru da`wāhum, Alhamdulillah, I don't know how to say it, but it's not before Salah, it has to be after Salah, because it has to be the last of things.
If they come up with a du'a, and they come up with the taslim, then the last du'a will be this du'a.
According to 10:10, the final thing, the last thing to be said is Alhamdulillah Rabbil Alameen.
Yeah, but when you say As-salamu alaykum, As-salamu alaykum, this is, yeah, just a tradition that has no basis.
They have to explain it away.
but it's not
directed at God.
I mean,
you say the tradition
is that the angels
and others say, well, it's the people
on either side.
The last thing
you say
in their prayer.
the last thing or the ultimate,
can also be the ultimate.
The du'a is between
oneself and God.
It's not just about anybody else,
not the angels, not other believers.
We can have that,
but it seems to me,
No, but I'm saying that part there, I can't see how it can be considered in any way a part of the du'a or a part of the prayer.
I'm just telling you my opinion.
No, that's it.
The verse says, the last thing they say is, Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah.
Seriously.
You know, I...
there's nothing wrong with that
at the beginning and the middle and the end.
My impression is that
it is good to pray as well
in Heaven.
Remember there is no laghw in Heaven.
There is no time frame, there is no effort.
I mean, there is a specific reason given for Salah.
23, I guess.
The purpose of Salah is to remain in heaven, in a state of communion,
but you are not there.
Thank you very much.
I think of it now as the ultimate, the ultimate 'ubudiyyah, the highest form of prayer.
That's what I mean.
I am ahead of my time.
But for me, I think it's the ultimate, without a doubt, it's the highest form of prayer.
It's the highest form of prayer.
You have to, you have to do it.
When you stop, you do it.
You say it at the end of your du'a.
Do you remember how I first derived it?
You were talking about it.
Ahsan?
Yeah.
It means the highest form.
It's always the best.
You don't have to do it.
You should have done it last year.
Yeah.
So that's why I thought,
I'm coming.
But that's right.
You need to understand.
When you end up in error,
you can't.
You can't do it again.
I was thinking, if we start with that, it's very nice, and the basis of faith is good, to
end up on top.
All right.
Thank you.
In heaven, we will be praising God.
And we'll thank Him for putting us in heaven.
And we'll ask Him for help in prayer.
Amen.
Thank you.
I remember you said last week your sister's in the hospital.
I don't think she'll come here.
Really?
Oh, really?
You'll come?
There is a new...
member.
He was sitting.
Oh.
He's the one in the suit.
A new member.
I cannot be staying tonight.
I need to go.
But yesterday I met somebody in my department.
He's a new member.
Yes, he is.
How are you?
I thought that...
Are you happy, Brother?
With you, I've decided to forget my problems.
Thank you, sir.
That number of churches...
People too, brother.
You make it?
Where's your brother?
Oh, he was in Turkey?
No, in New Jersey.
Oh, in New Jersey.
They want to consult me, so they need me.
Let me pay for the ticket here by telephone.
This is not what I want to do.
So, I think they will send me a ticket by phone.
They'll take care of my stay.
It all depends on...
When I met you here.
Are you going someplace?
New York City.
Just for a week, maybe.
Okay.
One week, maybe.
I don't know.
You know when...
No, it's just for a few weeks.
And then maybe,
because if you give me a ticket to go back,
I might use it to...
to go to...
Yeah.
Take advantage now.
Jameel and I believe.
Yeah.
More soup?
There's a guy.
For somebody.
Maybe, but.
From Michigan?
Yeah.
Oh, he had a fight with Wali or something.
And then he quit?
Yeah.
What's the story?
What did he do then?
Yeah, he had a fight with Wali... no, not Wali, Dawood.
Yeah, he hit him in the chest.
He's Mustafa.
Yeah, but what if he doesn't do it, and he's not coming here?
Well, I think he went home and he found Mustafa talking with his wife or something, so that
he won't be seen here again, never again.
So he said, if they come in here, we're going to ask.
It's a family affair.
Now, Daoud and Samira didn't come either.
They flunked the test.
Oh, that's who's over there.
He's a young guy.
I've never seen him around.
I've never talked to him.
You're losing weight. You've lost weight. Now you look well.
Very good. I want to lose weight again.
Well, I should gain some weight. I shouldn't lose any.
I'm already underweight.
But this is very good.
You know, I want to lose weight
for one simple reason. Because I thought my suits, my woolen suits
And you don't want to make a new one?
I don't want to buy a new one.
How can you?
You gained some weight?
Yes, about ten pounds.
Remember, I'm retired.
So now you're going to try to sweat it out in this Hajj.
My wife told me to jump.
As-salamu `alaykum.
Wa `alaykum as-salam.
I told my wife she has to oversee my exercise.
She is very hard.
She told me to jump.
Very good exercise.
For the heart.
But if your heart is already bad,
you cannot jump.
Just walk, I guess.
Walking is the best.
I think of how young people can die of that.
Richard Harrell,
one of the most
I'd be 36 next year.
He was very... he wrote several dictionaries and grammars inappropriately.
Maybe God willed him to go before he messes up the Arabic language.
Because the development of colloquial Arabic in the long run is a fight against classical Arabic,
which is, in the long run, a fight against the Quran.
And the Western orientalists have been trying to develop,
they want Arabic to be like Latin, it became French, you know,
French and Italian.
But I mean, it happens naturally anyway, they're merely recording what's happened.
Yeah, but in formalizing it,
they institutionalize it, which is
not very good.
It will cut the Arabs from Al-Islam.
There's the Egyptians,
there's the Syrians.
What is it?
A problem for them to
understand.
It's a form of imperialism.
Yeah, but they do it themselves.
I mean, Arabs do their own grammar.
That is true.
There has been no grammar written
in the world like it before.
There's some.
Yeah, there are.
This author is the one who
He was an Englishman, and he went and studied the language, you know, from the outside.
Collected the data and wrote a grammar on it.
But it was a grammar for non-Arab speakers, not for Arab speakers.
It was a, it was a, it was a grammar.
And of course there have been comparative work done.
When they have the modern students, they mix it up.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Because of the Muhkam and Mutashabih.
Another development.
Those are missionaries.
Yeah.
That's very interesting.
Oh, yeah.
He's trying to make a division.
Yeah.
So, you know, people who could read it, could read it very, very well.
The same people, the same people were taught how to pronounce it.
Yeah.
That's a different matter.
They just change, like, even English into colloquial English because it doesn't fit the grammatical
rules.
Every language has grammatical rules.
Even slang, dialect.
And you have a standardized English, so you have a standardized Arabic.
That's the accepted form.
What I'm saying is, you can say they're colloquial dialects, like the Pidgin languages.
When you talk about a grammar, it doesn't necessarily mean correct or incorrect.
You're only talking about the structure of the language.
So you can have colloquial, you can talk about the grammar of colloquial Arabic.
And you may say, well, this grammar is pervasive.
And if you're being purely descriptive, then you can think about the grammar and structure
of the Quran and the life of the believer, but you don't have to write that.
That is the truth.
Because I remember my father.
Some have written it in a manuscript.
Some have written it in an article.
It's really a rule.
The writing is still there.
But even the writing
wouldn't follow the rules of the Arabic language.
You'd have to make up the new rules.
...
Yeah, you can say, I want to write this.
You write it, it doesn't follow the rules.
...
Oh, the spelling is different, yeah.
For example, colloquial language uses
...
It's a short form.
There's a word in the classical language.
It has a prefix, a root, and a suffix.
It has three things in it.
But you can write it down.
So you can see.
It's only when you say this is the standard
that you can go to the correct grammar.
I'm sorry.
I use an example from my father.
He started to read and write, in accordance with the rules of literary art.
Because that's the only way he knew things, right?
He was taught in the literary art.
As time went on, then his father said,
Please write this letter for me to Mahmoud.
So he tells me.
the details.
My father said,
No, you cannot write it.
He said,
no.