Those who spend their money in the cause of God,
is like a seed that grows seven spikes, with one hundred seeds in each spike.
God multiplies the reward manyfold for whomever He wills.
God is Bountiful, Omniscient.
So this is the minimum you get for every dollar, it's 700 dollars minimum, not 10%.
You don't give exactly 10%.
and not follow up what they have given with reminders or with injury.
2:262.
Those who spend their money in the cause of God and do not follow up their charity
with reminders or injury;
their reward is with their Lord.
They have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
A kind statement and forgiveness are better
than a charity that is followed by injury.
God is Rich, Clement.
Without it, there is no reward.
O you who believe, do not nullify your charities
by reminders of your generosity or by injury,
like one who spends his money to be seen by the people,
and does not believe in God and the Last Day.
His example is that of a rock covered with a thin layer of soil;
a heavy rain falls on it and leaves it completely bare.
They will get nothing from their efforts.
God does not guide the disbelieving people.
The idea is that the money that we have is not really ours; nothing is ours, it belongs to God.
It's not our money.
He said you shall spend from the good things, not the bad things you earn.
Verse 2:264.
O you who believe, do not nullify your charities with reminders or injury,
like one who spends his money only to show off,
and does not believe in God and the Last Day.
His example is that of a useless rock
covered with a thin layer of soil.
When heavy rain falls on it,
it is left completely bare.
They get nothing from their efforts.
God does not guide the disbelieving people.
Then we read again,
Verse 2:264.
O you who believe,
do not nullify your charities
by reminders or injury.
So that is what is meant by injury;
hurting people's feelings.
And I've seen somebody
who is very shy. It hurts people's feelings to come and ask, they have
a sense of dignity, and we must preserve it for the sake of God.
As the whole Quran says.
Our existence here, we are not here to receive charity; we are here to work for God.
So charity must be for the cause of God.
You know, submission is not just the money.
And the parable of those who spend their money
seeking God's pleasure,
and from their own convictions.
Look, look at this phenomenon.
Look at it.
You can look at the phenomenon
over here.
Back to
265.
The example of those who spend their money seeking God's pleasure and from their own convictions,
is that of a garden on high, fertile soil.
When heavy rain falls, it just doubles its crop.
If heavy rain is not available, a light rain will suffice.
God is Seer of everything you do.
Here is a hard-hitting parable to draw the attention of the people.
He owns good land. He has to make food for his sheep and his cows.
And of course, he is not working for a pittance.
Verse 266.
Would any of you wish to own a garden of date palms and grapevines, with rivers flowing beneath it, and all kinds of fruit?
Again, this is emphasizing that while you are in dire need, you see all your work burn up.
This is to tell all you who believe to spend on charity from the good things you
earn and from what We produce for you from the earth.
Do not pick out the inferior thereof to give away,
which you would not accept for yourself unless you close your eyes. You should realize
that God is Rich, Praiseworthy.
So, let's define for us, what are the bad things that God has prohibited.
To give away old clothes that you don't need anymore, that are no good.
Just actually look at this. In the whole world, you know, old clothes.
Instead of throwing them in the garbage bin and getting away with it.
The charity must be from the good things you have.
Of course, it doesn't mean you shouldn't give it away, but you don't count it as your obligatory charity.
You just have to do it.
You don't count it at all.
Actually, that's something that you do on the side, though.
The little bits you give from the old.
268. The devil
promises you poverty
and orders you to commit
immorality.
While God promises you forgiveness
from Him and grace.
God is Bounteous, Omniscient.
He grants
wisdom to whomever He wills.
And whoever is endowed with wisdom is endowed with a great bounty.
Only those who possess intelligence are the ones who take heed.
So what do we learn from this whole section?
It is a great purchase.
you get 70,000% return and you do it and forget it, you do it and forget it, you never bring it up.
If you give it again, you don't tell other people, you tell the recipients themselves, you tell
And as you see in the next verse, 2:271, you keep the secret, and that implies that you believe in God.
You know that God knows it.
If you don't keep the secret, you turn people around you and then you throw them off.
You're reaping what amounts to a loss by not keeping the secret.
literally two things:
whatever charity you give,
or a vow you make,
God is fully aware
thereof.
The wicked will find no help.
If you declare your charity,
they are still good.
But if you
conceal them and give them
secretly to the poor,
it would be better for you
and would remit more of your sins.
God is fully Cognizant of everything you do.
Well, this verse talks to some of you in particular.
If you have any questions, let me check with you, okay?
No, I don't have any questions.
I just want to say, do you have any questions?
No, no, I feel confused.
.
Yeah.
So does that mean if you go around
saying you're a big giver, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, if there's any show-off, or you reap any benefit, that reduces the benefits that God has for you.
I think it's also so hard to take in and hear that, because if you're getting the benefits, you think you're going to get all the benefits you can, anyway.
Yeah.
I mean, I feel like I'm safe.
It's just different. It's just different than you think you're getting now.
You're getting a better reward from Allah now.
I would like to invite everyone here and now, all of us, to the book of Allah.
The book of Allah.
Not the book of the Bible, and not the book of the Bible.
Not the book of the Bible.
Yes. The book of the Quran.
Of the religion.
Yes.
That's the relationship.
You are not responsible for guiding them; God is the only one who guides whomever He wills.
Any charity you give is for your own good.
You shall give to charity only to seek God.
Any charity you give will be repaid to you, without the least injustice.
The point is that you can guide people, but when you do,
you are only doing so in the sense that
you are an instrument of God's will.
And it reminds me
of Ya-Sin, which I've been reading
a lot. Whether you warn them or you
warn them not, they will not believe.
So, people who are
going to believe will believe, and people who aren't going to
believe, are not going to believe.
You may be there as an intermediary,
you may be the first one to stick the Quran in their
hand, but not in their heart to believe it,
because they are not going to believe anyway.
All power belongs to God.
Charity is for the poor
who are restricted in the cause of God,
and are unable to travel the land.
The unaware may think that they are rich
due to their modesty, but you can recognize
them by their signs.
They never beg from people insistently,
and any charity you give, God is fully aware of.
Those who give charity by night and day,
secretly and publicly,
they have their recompense with their Lord.
They will have no fear, nor will they grieve.
In Morocco, there are people who will bug you about charity.
They're professional beggars.
They may not even be poor.
And I vividly remember one woman in America who could cry at will, you know, whether her
husband was just lazy and had money and just said, "Go out and beg if you want something,"
even though they have money.
Whereas you see people who are just sitting, reciting something from the Quran,
not even asking for charity, and people just throw down money.
It's a good illustration.
I've seen both sides.
So it's basically
more about the laws of
usury.
people who are persecuted
because of their belief in God...
I'm sorry, I just, um, to say again, that charity is a good thing and it's one of the five pillars.
And it explains a little bit more about our life.
These three verses are about
these three verses are about
the charity and
the poor who are persecuted for their
beliefs
and are trapped.
I'm thinking of all the people who I've seen chanting and one man who I remember was,
had a beautiful, and a most beautiful
voice. And he would just stand
in the street and recite from the Quran,
blind. And he
didn't seem like he ever
wanted charity. People would hear him and they would give him
what he wanted. He didn't seem like he
cared enough, you know.
You just felt really good when you gave something
to him.
And then there were these professional beggars
who would just go around
and they'd just go around
and you didn't know if they were really,
you know, if you were a tourist and you didn't live
there very long, you wouldn't really know for sure.
On the other hand, if you've ever been to Marrakesh,
you know that if you feed all the beggars in Marrakesh,
you'll be a beggar yourself.
In Morocco and in the East,
begging is not illegal.
It's actually something that
people do professionally.
I think these three verses
are making a distinction.
Here you can't just go around
and ask people for money, for a handout.
You can be cited as a bum or a transient or something like that.
Or really, you can be arrested for vagrancy
or something like that.
But in...
I don't know...
Oh, my God.
No, no, no.
They're plaguing us.
Oh, my God.
That's really them plaguing you.
They're doing something.
It's just the predominance of begging, all right?
It's not very predominant in this country compared to...
it's just not very predominant to see people standing around on the street, you know, with a...
And you'll see another guy who is showing his stump off, you know, showing no legs,
make sure you see it.
or somebody walks up to you
and shows you that he doesn't have any arms
or anything.
It's a different,
it's a whole different
profession.
But it's really the people
who are persecuted
because of what they believe,
they deserve,
they deserve charity the most.
You can recognize them
by their signs.
They never annoy people by begging. These beggars can be very, very much of a nuisance.
The next slide.
You're going to go to the next slide, that's where I'm going first.
Once I wanted to start with a new model, we've had a real big change in the world, and it's
a beautiful clarity.
And I must have had a crazy
driver follow me.
He was very mad.
He said, no, no, no, no.
I'm not going to stop you.
Then he got on the next road
and the driver was very mad.
And the car in front was going to turn around
and he'd hit the driver.
And then he was going really fast.
And we just witnessed these swerves for about a minute, and then he pulled out and did these swerves, and then he did it twice again.
He did it again and again after that swerve.
And then they can win the marathon, or make millions of dollars in this campaign.
But that's nothing compared to immortality.
And now the ego, we have the perspective that the ego is now the king, and the reward is now the disease.
We put them all in jail.
I mean, we didn't give them any help.
Yeah, he was that kind.
He was that kind of dictator.
No more bagpipes in the Masjid. Put them on the screen real quick.
There they go.
I think they're enjoying it.
It's not a famous thing, you know, when you walk home.
You can't just go...
If you're playing a musical instrument while you're on the street,
you just walk around and see you've got a guy with a $4 or $5 bill in your pocket.
For example, this is for the people who are actually the devotees that we see.
Very talented people.
We've got no basis.
Some of them were dropped from a hundred feet up into a can of water,
and they just had to put them in there.
That was the rest of the lie.
We did not obey.
No, I did that for charity, when I was holding a charity one of those days.