As-salamu alaykum.
Hey, what are we doing here?
Hey, what are you doing?
Shhh!
Thank you.
Alif, Lam, Meem. God, there is no god except He; the Living, the Eternal.
He revealed to you this scripture in truth,
confirming the previous scriptures, and He sent down the Torah and the Gospel,
previously, as a guidance for the people, and He revealed the Criterion.
Those who disbelieve in God's revelations have incurred a terrible retribution.
God is Almighty, Avenger.
Nothing is ever hidden from God, on earth or in the heavens.
He is the one who shapes you in the wombs as He wills.
There is no god except He, the Almighty, the Most Wise.
He is the one who revealed to you this scripture, containing specific verses;
they constitute the foundation of the scripture.
Other verses are allegorical.
As for those who have deviation in their hearts,
they pursue the allegorical verses,
seeking to create confusion, and seeking to interpret it.
And no one knows its true interpretation
except God.
And those well-established in knowledge say, "We believe in it. It is all from our Lord." Only those who possess intelligence will take heed.
Our Lord, let not our hearts falter after You have guided us, and shower us with Your mercy; You are the Grantor.
Our Lord, You will surely gather the people on a Day about which there is no doubt. For God never
breaks a promise. As for those who disbelieve, neither their money nor their children will
avail them in the least against God. They are fuel for the Fire. Like the people of Pharaoh and others
before them; they rejected our revelations, so God punished them for their sins. God is strict in retribution.
Say to those who disbelieve,
"You will be defeated
and gathered into Hell—a miserable abode."
That's all.
I like it.
That's enough.
Okay.
Okay, my understanding is that,
if you don't know this,
the first point I was going to make is regarding the mathematical miracle of the Quran, which has been in it since its revelation.
and the materials that we give to our students. We go into detail, and if you read them, you'll be pleased that we give them more content to help explain the mathematical problem that we are dealing with, just as we do for our students.
And who would believe in him? Would they believe him? That is the reason why we are all here.
See, if I'm not bogged down, I don't think I will be.
See, this person telling me that he can deal with the city, with the people, and the sects and all the other people.
I just thought from my experience talking to a Christian, or others you may encounter, when they try to tell you that you are off, the one thing we try to show them is something they already believe; this provides the strength in their faith.
Because this provides a point of strength found in all the scriptures; it's pointed out in the Torah from beginning to end.
I don't even know if this phrasing is right.
And it is a guide for the people, for all of you, and I guess it's my understanding that
it is a guide for the people, and it's a guide for all of you.
And so if you believe, if you just believe, God is going to give you what is due to you, and God
And no matter what they prepare, or what they conspire with their mouths, the angels will be
sweeping them away.
And He is All-Knowing of the innermost thoughts.
So whether you declare your speech or whether you keep it secret, you will be brought to account
for what you have done,
for all the things that you do.
And can anyone protect you from God?
Whether you are powerful and come out with full-fledged support,
or whether you come out with no name and no allies,
or whatever power you think you have to protect people with.
Are you secure from the One in Heaven?
He is the One who sent His messengers, but a lot of people claim they have partners with
God.
God's mercy is on it.
It's from heaven, that it's from God.
Whatever you sow, you will reap from God.
It's true.
God is with the righteous.
And they have His perfect mercy, and the vast mercy of God is with you.
And all of that means that you have to keep your faith.
Yeah.
A lot of people try to make it human-made, so it's not from God, but He is Al-'Alim, the Most Knowledgeable One, and He is the one that guides you to the straight path of truth.
That's the truth. For God is the One who knows.
The straight path was a choice for him, and he chose God.
This is the word of God.
It is not just a story, it is from God.
He was given so much, born in such a
rich, rich family. And God tells us about this in the record.
He thought he earned it on his own.
that He's helping us, He's helping us to live by the voice of truth, as a light.
And that those who have a disease in their hearts,
that sometimes they're stuck on their traditions and how it works,
but they can't do much other than argue,
and they get stuck in it and let that take them out of their right minds,
You know, they don't get away from conjecture, from what the rest of their sect stands for.
And so they say, "We want proof," but then they somehow do not want the proof when it comes.
And so being able to have proof, you know what I'm saying, things that are a clear proof, or...
they just come up with their own opinions on that.
and read it aloud instead of just reading it and they tell you that no one really knows the correct interpretation of it
except God, and those who are well-grounded in knowledge.
like Deshaun and other brothers and sisters, you know, have their own knowledge.
And, uh, and just some understanding of what it is.
And what, you know, what are the guidelines, the laws that we have to follow in order to be guided.
And it is saying that those who do follow it possess the wisdom.
You can't see God with your eyes, you can't touch Him with your hands.
You need Him on the ground. You need Him on the ground.
You need me to bring Him down. You need me to accept that He will walk down the road.
You must do it. You have to do it.
Again, verse 8 is teaching you to ask God to guide you if you want to stay close.
That you must ask the Lord to guide you and grant you of His mercy.
I hope today that you will make your decision.
and I
bear witness here.
Our Lord,
You will gather all the people
for a day that is inevitable,
for God never breaks His promise.
and never
I can't say it's true or false,
or anything,
I can't say it's wrong
or it's right.
God never breaks His promise.
And we say if we commit to God, He'll give you peace here on this earth, and in this life and the Hereafter.
And God knows what's coming. And just believe in that, and commit to God.
In order to get that salvation.
And those who disbelieve, their money and their children will not help them against God.
Like the people of Pharaoh and those before them.
And folks before them also were punished, and none helped them.
And God is telling you that nobody is going to help you.
You are only a warner on earth.
and that they are included in the sign of God, that is, the initials in the word of God.
Thank you very much.
We will talk on this in detail, God willing.
There is a footnote, if you look at your handout.
In my translation, in Appendix 1, on the miraculous significance of the Quranic geometry,
after 1400 years, the mystery of these letters is now unveiled.
We saw in 29 chapters, in 29 surahs, that these letters are the miracle of the Quran.
They were mysterious, they remained mysterious for 1400 years, as God willed them to be;
a secret, that there is a secret in Quran that will be unveiled in the future, not in
Muhammad's time.
So these letters are the miracle of the Quran, and it was these letters, and the mathematics
associated with them, that I present as a sign that this translation is authorized
by God.
As a chemist, I had no business translating the Quran.
And I refused to publish it.
I did it for myself. I hid it.
Who's making noise back there?
Attention!
I refused to publish this or have anything to do with it, unless there is a definite sign that I am authorized to do this.
Now 1400 years now, when you look at it, it's very simple, but nobody, nobody ever
found it. All over the Quran, it's throughout the Quran. Nobody ever saw it. So this was
definitely a sign, and I mentioned this in Footnote 21. So when anyone attacks this
this translation to you, you can throw them this footnote if you want, and you can ask...
them, whether by this letter, or whoever found it, God will just pick out any way to
let them discover the miracle of the Quran. Anyone who doesn't know the miracle of the Quran.
Another thing, in fact, I am too embarrassed to mention this thing, to the extent that I didn't mention it in the introduction,
which I should have, and I probably will in the next edition. This happens to be translation number 19 in history.
This is the 19th translation. A friend of mine got me the list of the translations from Beirut.
He got it in Beirut where they have a list of all the English translations.
And so this is another sign. There are so many signs that I had.
God showed me a sign that this is an authorized version, that God approves of this.
And to remove any hesitation about it.
And as time goes by, day after day, I have a letter on my desk that came today
from a prisoner who was practically illiterate.
You can tell from the way he's writing the letter.
And he was telling me that he lost his Quran.
Somebody stole his Quran from him.
Then he's saying how he treasures it because it's easy to understand.
He had a Yusuf Ali translation, but it's just very difficult.
The archaic, the classic English of Yusuf Ali, it's a very good translation, but the English was not accessible to everyone.
And Islam, like any other religion, is first, when it comes to a new land, is first embraced by the oppressed and the poor.
and these are the best of the elite. They end up being the best of the elite.
So this fellow is imprisoned with such illiteracy.
But God made the Quran available to them through this translation.
And that's just one example, not to mention the letters I haven't seen yet.
So these letters, A-L-M, were a sign for this translation.
It says the main thesis is that Sunnah is de-authorized in this version of the Quran.
You notice this emotional praise of my person, which is what they use for their accusations.
They are reacting to something that's been happening continuously.
When they argue with you, or discuss with you, the issue of Quran and Hadith,
and God alone, idol worship, they make a classic statement,
that you are idolizing Rashad. This is classic.
And they act as if the Prophet wanted to go and beat him up, or go and shoot him or something.
But this is the classic line they always say.
You are idolizing Rashad, you are worshipping Rashad, you say he is your savior.
Whatever they want you to say.
But I'm going to address this issue in detail in the next slide.
But I'm going to mention a rule of thumb that will clear up drastically who is worshipping whom.
You can use this as a criterion for yourself and for anybody else.
I want you to open Surah 9, verse 31.
I'm going to repeat this from my book here, so I hope you promise not to fall asleep in the next few minutes,
when I let you see all these things.
Surah 9, verse 31, top of page 129.
They have taken their priests and rabbis as lords besides God,
as well as the Messiah, Christ, the Son of Mary. They were commanded not to
worship but the one God. There is no god except He. He is glorified far above the partners they ascribe to Him.
Now I want you to notice the first part of the verse. They have taken their
priests and rabbis as lords besides God.
The explanation was given by Muhammad, and it applies to every congregation, every religion.
They have taken their scholars, their imams, their priests, and their rabbis as gods besides
God.
How?
How did they do that?
I was supposed to worship God alone, but how did they take the scholar, the imam, and the priest, and the rabbi, as gods besides God?
What is the criterion? And this is what I want you to never forget. The criterion is, if the scholar, or the priest, or the rabbi, or the scholar is saying something that is identical to what God says,
says. Then, you are not worshipping him, you are worshipping God. God says, you can obey
God, the Messenger, and those who serve among you, or the Imams among you, or the Priests
or the Rabbis, among you, because they utter the same things that God
has uttered. However, if the imam, or the priest, or the rabbi, or the scholar, says something
that is different from what God says, if you follow that, then you are worshiping this
imam, or this priest, or this scholar, or this rabbi. If he says something that is different.
A good example, last night, Brother Mujahid went to a meeting, and they were having a Quranic study.
And in the middle of the Quranic study, he asked the brother, "Can I ask you a question?"
And the brother said, "Go ahead." So he said, "How come you pray the noon, and the afternoon
silently, when there is a commandment from God that you must not pray too loudly, nor too silently,
but seek an intermediate tone?" So they gave him a long
story about the Hadith and the Sunnah and the scholars. Now here is an example where the
scholars said something different from what God said. And then you are given the
freedom of choice. You are going to choose the words of God or the words of the scholars or the Imam.
The Imam is saying, "Pray the noon and the afternoon in silence." And God says,
"You shall not utter your prayer too loudly, nor too silently." This is in Surah 17, verse 110. You shall not pray too loudly, nor too silently.
Very clear commandment. Now, the person here makes a choice. Is he going to worship God or worship the Imam?
Because here we have a difference. See? So the criterion is, if the Imam or the priest or the rabbi or the scholar
is saying something that is identical to what God said, then you are worshipping God, because God said that.
I mean, if the Imam, or the priest, or the Rabbi is saying, "You shall worship God alone,"
if you don't obey that, what does it mean? It means, you will not worship God alone.
You have to obey that, because he is saying something that is identical
to what God said, and you are not worshipping the Imam in that case, you are worshipping God,
because he is uttering the words of God, whose commandments are identical to what God's commandments are.
So, Mujahid asked them, he said, "Whose words do you follow?
Do you follow the words of God, or the words of somebody who said what the Prophet said?"
So they told him, "You don't have permission to speak."
He said, "Uh oh, what is the problem here?"
They found, in essence, they had no reply to this.
He is coming very strong with the direct commandment on his side.
...
Then Mujahid said, "I mean, we're here discussing Quran and religion and I don't see why I need permission to speak when everybody is having a discussion here."
So they said, "Okay, the whole thing is over."
And they finished everything and they left it at that.
So this is the criterion. Let's look again at the top of page 129.
They have taken their priests and rabbis as lords, or gods, besides God.
And this is what the Muslims did, almost to a man, by the millions.
This has been an obsession with them.
And they have taken their scholars and imams as gods besides God.
Because they said things that are different from what God said, and these people follow the scholars.
Because they're worshipping. And if, over the words of God, you follow the words of the scholars, you're worshipping the scholars.
You follow the words of the Imams. If they're different from what God said, you're worshipping the Imams.
But this is the classic lie.
For a long, long time, people have said that they saw him at the time,
that he was going to die.
He didn't, he didn't.
They say that he died, just as they say anyway.
And you are believers.
Why don't you,
why don't you just go and see him,
because he is going to come to you,
because he is going to be with you,
because he is going to be with you.
And, uh,
we love the fact that he is here,
I have a question.
One guy was a teacher at a very large university.
And he was teaching from a book.
And the teacher said,
"Let me tell you about a teacher, a colleague,
who wanted me to teach him."
And I said,
"Okay, let me teach him."
And the teacher said,
"Okay, you teach me."
And I said,
"Okay, I will teach you."
What I was trying to do, I thought, "I'm going to test him out on the things that don't make sense, from what the prophet taught and what he said."
Don't just sit here talking. Let's talk about the topic at hand.
Yeah, that's what I am trying to explain.
There are all kinds of things involved.
I am trying to tell you that,
in anything that you are exploring,
whatever you are trying to say,
if you have anything to respond to that,
then there is some truth in it,
but if something else goes wrong,
So, if you started having more and more signs,
go back 50 years,
you can only see the first organized church, or the church before that.
I never saw, so far,
in reading all kinds of books where they talk about Muhammad.
They talk about Allah, God, but nobody else.
If you look at my...
If only, yeah, if you told them
They believe in Allah,
verbally,
but not really, you know.
I'm not picking on Turkey,
but I have to acknowledge
that we were appointed
to expose so much.
And the more you move
east of Turkey,
to Pakistan, where you see
the name of God and Muhammad's name
put everywhere, in the mosques
and so forth.
And it's a lot of shirk, a lot of shirk.
It's almost like a wife saying of another man, "He's my husband."
Or, it's like saying, "He is my husband."
It's like saying, "He is my husband."
It's like, you know, making a mistake like saying, "He is my husband."
So this is where these people are coming from.
Because this has been ingrained in their mind, this fallacy, and they've been hearing it all the time.
How do you distinguish whether you are worshiping God or the messenger?
How do you know? This is the test, you know.
In other words, if I say something that is different from what God said, are you going to listen to me or listen to God's Word?
You can tell. If you are worshiping God, you are not worshiping me.
By that I can tell.
And, as you know, I wouldn't dare say anything
that's different from what God said.
He would not let me get away with it.
Yes.
As long as it conforms with the Quran, and you accept it, then you will not waver anymore.
If I say something that is different, then there is no excuse, it is your duty to tell me that I am wrong.
And this is what we do here. You may look at me like I'm a clown or something, right?
I wouldn't dare say something wrong.
I would.
Thank God.
So this is, the name of this heading is A-L-M.
It's God's sign that this translation is authorized.
and I wouldn't, I wouldn't print it otherwise.
I was very demanding, and things went awry.
I saw so many signs, maybe someday I will write them down.
I mentioned a lot of them in our newsletter.
You see, now, there's an awesome responsibility with this.
If I write one sentence here that is wrong,
and I mislead a hundred people, I will pay the price for that.
And bear in mind, I'm the biggest victim in that case.
I don't want anybody else to sin, but I have enough of my own.
So I don't want to mislead anybody and be responsible for misguiding them.
So the responsibility is on. And without comparing with Moses, and if you remember, Moses was very reluctant.
He just said, "I'm sending you as My messenger, go and deliver the message to him." And he said, "But I don't know how." He didn't know how.
And God said, okay, I'm going to send Aaron with you. And he said, well, I committed murder in that country, and I'm afraid they will kill me.
He was just making all kinds of excuses, and God would respond to him.
A.L.M.
I don't think we even comprehend the significance of this.
The opposition is beginning to realize what the significance is,
And now, there is a conspiracy of defiance to use Jahiliyyah money as a threat.
Instead of attacking as they used to, now they are just completely frightened.
So it is bound to overwhelm them, it is bound to devastate them, whether they like it or not.
Because it is not from a human, I have nothing to do with it, because I have nothing to do with it.
The new book, you see the new book?
Everybody see the new book?
Yes?
That new book is going to demonstrate the act of God.
Let me get it in fact.
We don't have one copy here.
What I'm showing is the visual presentation of this code, where I have, for example in this
surah, A.L.M. Well, I couldn't do it in this surah, because Alif is a very frequent letter,
so I marked the initial letters with a star, not A, L, and M, but all the other initial letters.
So they can see, for themselves, how many letters are there. They can see the count.
The book before this, The Computer Speaks, was all numbers, and to be honest with you,
I don't blame them for not reading the numbers, especially when they are skeptical and everything
else.
But this here will force the issue on them.
What can they say?
There's nothing they can say.
The counts are there.
But I talked about the fellow from Algeria who wrote and said, "There are 56 Qafs," and
counted the Qafs, and how they repeated and re-repeated it, and had a group of people
check it, and every time they'd come up with 56.
And all I did was make a Xerox copy of that surah, sent it to them, never heard from them again.
You're right, I'm sorry, yeah, you're right.
I didn't mean to say that.
You were talking about...
I hope you enjoyed this lecture and I hope to see you in the next one.
Take care.
Bye.
Now, Alif, Lam, Mim. These initials also mean God is One.
Because all these numbers are based on the number 19, which means God is One, right?
Right? All these lessons, without exception, every single one of them, are multiples of 19.
And 19 means God is One. So, 19 means one. Wahid.
So, in other words, God is providing the meaning of these initials.
We may be able to resume the Arabic language tomorrow morning, insha Allah.
And we didn't get to the numbers, but we will, maybe tomorrow.
But one, the word "one" in Arabic is Wahid.
And the four letters, Waw, Alif, Ha, Dal.
Waw, Alif, Ha, Dal. Wahid.
And when the Quran came down, there were no numbers.
The alphabet was used as numbers.
And Waw was six.
Before they invented the numbers, the letter Waw was six.
The letter Alif was one.
Six and one is seven, right?
The third letter Ha was eight.
Waw is six, Alif is one, Ha is eight, so six and one is seven and eight is fifteen.
Dal is four. Fifteen and four is nineteen. So the word Wahid is nineteen. 19 means
God is One. So, A.L.M. means God is One. So that's the meaning of these first letters.
Something nobody ever knew before this group.
I had three people here who were insistent about not using the name of Ali in our events.
They were, I don't know what the occasion was, but I think they wanted everyone to be experts in Arabic first,
before they could understand the Quran. And I quoted to them
Surah 41, verse 44, that says you do not need Arabic,
but if you are a believer, the only requirement is to be a believer,
and God will put the Quran in your heart. And just
to demonstrate to them
that what God said is the truth, some people happened to be sitting next to us,
and I told them that there is a Muslim here
who is relatively new, and you can ask her anything about the Quran.
Just go ahead and ask her anything about the Quran and see if the Quran is in her heart or not.
So they thought of the hardest, most difficult, most impossible question.
And they told Latifa, "Okay, tell us the meaning of Kaf, Ha, Ya, Ayn, Sad at the beginning of Surah 19."
And Latifa said, "I thought you'd never ask."
Yes, yes, did you know there's a numerical code in the Quran?
These initials, Kaf, Ha, Ya, Ayn, Sad, are part of the numerical code, and the sum of them is a multiple of 19.
I said, you mean you don't know about the numerical code?
But they were really... that was a great demonstration for them.
They didn't argue after that.
And I think something good happened to them.
However they disappeared, I don't know what was...
that may be a good sign.
So that's the privilege that God...
God, there is no god except He, the Living, the Eternal.
He sent down to you this scripture, truthfully, confirming what came before it, just as
He sent down the Torah and the Gospel previously.
You see how the numbering of the verse comes in the middle of the statement?
This is a continuous passage. But the number of the verse came in the middle,
indicating the deliberate numbering of the verse. As you know, part of this course
was that the first Surah of the Revelation consists of 19 verses.
And that's a deliberate positioning.
If anybody played around with that, that fact would disappear.
But Surah An-Nasr, 110, which has 3 verses, consists of 19 words.
And you will see it in this book.
This book will be here, insha'Allah, on Sunday.
There is another book that's called Quran, Hadith, and Islam.
We also cover the history of Quran and Hadith.
And you will not be at a loss, never again,
when we discuss the Quran and Hadith.
However, we discovered that we have the two lines here in the office,
and I mentioned this morning. So, they get it on Monday,
they print the book on Tuesday, and
we will hold this book until the other books are also ready.
Then we will ship them all next week.
It's going to happen.
We'll have some good exercise and probably get another ailment
as we unload the books.
That book will show you later that the first Surah of the Revelation
consists of 19 verses.
So, He revealed the Torah and the Gospels
previously as guidance for the people. People say that it's law, not a chapter.
God is the Teacher. He revealed the Statute Book.
The Statute Book means the book of laws. These are God's laws.
We have to obey these laws, if we want to have a perfect life, a happy life.