That they follow the Quran? This is why God says, right after describing disbelief in God's revelation, that nothing is concealed from God.
Because He knows what their hearts are doing, whether they are really believing or not. And based on that, they are isolated from Quran, they cannot see it.
The other part was covered very nicely by Martha.
The allegorical verses are things that we may not be able to understand
or fully comprehend yet.
There were generations who didn't understand what was meant by the earth being egg-shaped.
That didn't make sense to them.
And had they wasted their time trying to interpret that,
they would have just wasted time, and they might have ended up confused.
There are things in the Quran now that you cannot comprehend.
So, God reserves these to future generations.
Every generation has to see something new in the Quran.
But for our purposes, we have a certain understanding of them, and we have to be content and satisfied
with them.
As long as we're not digging and causing a lot of confusion, then it's definitely right
to study the Quran and try to understand everything, without confusing ourselves.
Past generations, for example, they didn't understand what the number 19 meant.
They had no way of knowing what the number 19 meant.
But God gave them a temporary understanding that there are possibly the guards who have the number 19.
Because after the number 19, God gives a general statement that the guards are angels.
It's just a general statement.
And that statement serves to give them a satisfactory interpretation at the time, for understanding.
Because, God knows that it is not important whether the people know that Hell is guarded by 19, or 19 million, or what.
It's not a crucial thing to the doctrine, or the worship of God alone.
At the end of verse 7 here, it says, indeed, only those who possess intelligence will take heed.
People who do not heed the Quran, people who do not believe in God,
people who do not worship God alone, they have to be stupid.
They are not intelligent.
And God who is folding the seven universes in His hand,
and they leave him and they seek the wisdom of a human being who lived on earth
a hundred years, who was very puny, helpless.
That has to be stupid.
When God has created the heavens and the earth, the sun and the moon,
He knows what the sun and the moon are doing.
But they go seek the wisdom of a man who didn't know that
where the sun is coming from.
The sun rises every day from the east.
They used to think it's a new sun.
And you don't blame them for that.
That was the extent of their knowledge.
But to go to them for wisdom,
that's not intelligent.
So only those who are intelligent
will worship God alone.
Verses 8 and 9 are wonderful prayers that you can use anytime. Verse 12 says to those who disbelieve,
"You will be defeated, and you will end up in Hell, and what a miserable abode."
And the book, Quran, Hadith, and Islam, that you will see at the end, an advertisement for the book itself,
it was just put in the back.
And if asked the question, does it make any sense that 3 million Israelis defeat,
consistently defeat, 150 million Arabs?
Consistently.
I mean, even on the physical level it doesn't make sense.
Is this what God says in 12?
Because those people were given the Quran.
Quran. When you are given the Quran, your responsibility is immediately doubled.
The people in this country who come to Islam, and they come to Quran, and then they end up
following Hadith and Sunnah. These people are in bad shape.
They are much better off as Christians, worshipping Jesus.
Because when they are handed the Quran, where practically every page
says worship God alone, don't go to anything else, then the responsibility is
multiplied manyfold. The Quran is a fantastic blessing or a fantastic disaster,
depending on if you uphold it or not.
So the Arabs were given the Quran, and they chose to abandon it, they don't need it.
So number 12 applies to them, say to those who disbelieve, you will be defeated, then
end up in hell, and the miserable abode.
This is God's promise, and it doesn't matter what the physical statistics say.
You may be 200 million, but you disbelieved God when He said the Quran is
complete and perfect, you will be defeated.
Doesn't matter how many you are, how rich you are, how many weapons you have, how
much weapons you have.
The 200 million Arabs, and God gave them so much wealth, just to make all the physical
statistics on their side.
Yet they keep losing.
And it's because they abandoned the Quran.
The Quran is in their hands, in our hands.
But they don't, they don't need it.
Mujahid demonstrated that to them last night.
He said, which words do you take?
You take the words of God, or the words of someone who said what the Prophet said?
I go a step further, I say, do you take the words of God or the words of the Prophet?
If the Prophet walks through this door and shows you his passport, proving that he is
Muhammad, the son of Abdullah, and he tells you something that's different from the Quran,
are you going to take the words of God or the words of Muhammad? I will put the question
that way. But of course, Mujahid will try to prove to them that the hadith is not from
Muhammad. The hadith, the hadith is not Muhammad. As you see in the last page of that
book which is coming. I said hadith, and not Muhammad. They are the hadith of people
whose grandparents, even the grandparents of their grandparents never saw the Prophet.
This was real Hadith to them.
So Mujahid was trying to prove that point.
They follow what God said, or they follow
things that were said by people who said what the Prophet said.
Amongst the two hundred,
looking in their eyes, I'm sure if somebody shows them
the truth, I'm sure so many of them will see the truth.
So, he will not be allowed to fail.
Some other way, but I know what you're saying, you're doing both.
I can't say either way, but you cannot keep him there.
Insha'Allah, God will find a way. What do you think?
We were talking the other night at the church, and they're talking about it right now.
Here, Paul, Yusuf.
They, they're thinking it's going to happen here.
I feel like they considered it might happen.
Yeah, yeah, that's what it is.
It's not the Hadith of Jesus either.
The Hadith of Mark, Luke, Matthew and John.
That's what the Gospels are.
These are the canonized books.
They are canonized because in the Council of Nicaea, they collected all the
scriptures of Jesus, the true and the false.
And they canonized these four and bound them together.
And they established the doctrine of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
And if you don't believe it, you go to any encyclopedia or even some dictionaries under "Nicaea."
And you'll understand the work.
I haven't read it all, but I can tell you.
It's from the time of Nicaea, right?
That Council of Nicaea was very important.
You know, to go away, you know what to do.
You know what to do.
For the first three centuries, Christians were all worshipping one God, and yet they did not mention the Trinity at all.
Even nowadays, we have these seven great Christian scholars,
I mean, they are very respected scholars who wrote the book "The Myth of God Incarnate,"
and they are censored and cursed and everything by the rest of the Christian world.
But verse 12 explains the defeat of the Arabs.
Wali, you wanna compete with Latifa and take the next stage?
She's a tough act to follow though.
I can do it.
The gospels, for instance, teach that he is the Word of God, the Lord Jesus Christ.
The Word, in the eyes of the people, is the Word of God.