Alhamdulillah. Ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah. Wa ash-hadu anna... The old habits come back sometimes. The days of ignorance and idle worship.
Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala doesn't want any other names mentioned in His mosques.
And all messengers of God want us to say La ilaha illa Allah.
Period.
I'm going to spend this first khutbah reading a talk that Imam Warith Deen Mohammed gave.
Imam Muhammad is one of the rare people that I believe knows the truth, believes in the truth, and his heart believes in Allah alone.
He is having a hell of a time with his people, trying to make them worship God alone.
and he's really a model, he's really a project, and if you read his writings or khutbas, you can see the truth in there.
Someday, insha'Allah, he will be as adventurous as I am, and he will come up with, come up against Hadith, insha'Allah,
and hear nothing other than the Quran.
This talk could be written by me,
but I'm going to read it without comment.
You know, when I see Muhammad as one person,
I'm very happy to get to know him.
I consider him as a friend of mine,
and I have his picture in my office.
That's how highly I think of him.
And insha'Allah,
God will guide him. There is no way he will fail.
With all the opposition against him,
he has been always victorious and he is guaranteed victory.
For as long as he upholds, La ilaha illa Allah.
As you know, once you see the truth, there is no going back.
There is no way you can go back after you see the truth.
Here is what, what Warith Deen Mohammed is saying.
Let us look at reality. Not only here, but all over this country.
Anytime you come together to do some good, you're going to have problems.
Especially if you're going to make your good spread.
If it's just going to be your private good, maybe you'll last for a while.
Maybe you'll last until you die.
But if you are doing good, and you're committed, and you're going to pass that good on to others,
so it will grow in numbers, you're in trouble. If you want to get together and
do some wrong, you're in the best situation, even the good people won't
bother you. But if you want to do good, you're in trouble. We have to understand
that, and that's the price that the righteous must pay in the world. You must
pay that price, accept to pay it. I knew people wouldn't like me when I made a
stand, and when they knew what I stood for. Now, Warith Deen Mohammed not only changed
the Elijah Muhammad system, but he changed it not to Islam as it is known
around the world, which is called Islam, but he changed it to the true Islam, which is a
big jump, I mean, it's a severe jump. So he says, I knew people wouldn't like me when I
made the stand, and when they knew what I stood for. I knew they wouldn't like me.
I knew I was going to have a whole lot of enemies. The more people knew what I
represented, I knew the more enemies I was going to get. But that's the price I
accepted to pay. That's the price all of us who want to do good have to accept to
pay. People aren't going to like you. People are going to make trouble for you.
People are going to try to undermine your work.
They are going to try to make you lose faith in each other.
They try to break your trust.
They do anything to defeat your efforts.
We have to accept that.
We don't have to have the CIA, the FBI, or the intelligence office of your local police department.
You don't even need that.
There are people out there in the society who will give you enough help
without those agents. On top of that, you have bad elements in the government. Some
Catholics are so prejudiced against the religion that they would
sacrifice their time and even their life to see this religion stop in America. And
Protestants who will do the same. Then you have some other Islamic groups that
do the same because they don't want to see me grow either. So you have the FBI,
the CIA, the Israeli intelligence, and the false Muslims, and even internal
infiltrations. I'm not going to name any, but there are some narrow-minded
Islamic groups that will work to defeat you too, because they don't want to see
you prosper either. We have to understand that we have enemies coming at us from
all directions who will do their best to undermine us. A lot of Muslims are not
satisfied with my leadership. I'm talking about Muslims of the world. This is an enemy within
I am talking about. I do believe the great majority of Muslims on this planet love
my leadership. They thank Allah for my leadership. But we have enough who are
hateful and jealous and dislike us enough to make trouble. Some of them are
here in America and some overseas too. We have to understand these things. We have
to accept reality. Don't think that everybody who comes to you in this name
or in these clothes is your friend. It may not be the case. Your friend is the
one who is truthful, who is open. Anybody who has to work with you behind closed doors,
anybody who has to tell you something secretly in your ear, you shouldn't trust them.
The person who comes out boldly before the community and lets them know,
"I am your friend, I am a friend of this community,"
those are the people we should be inclined to trust.
But those persons who stand behind, in the back,
but never want to be seen up front,
who claim to be with us, but are whispering things in our ears,
don't trust those people. I don't care who they are, I don't care what kind of
clothes they come in, you can't trust people like that. We have many masjids all
around the country, and all of our masjids are going to be visited. Our enemies are
already there. Every masjid is infiltrated. Right now, I'm talking to people who are
not here to help us, they are here to hurt us. He was talking in the masjid of Kansas
City, by the way. They are working for somebody or some agent or some agency, or
they are just part of the group of prejudiced people who are against
Muslims. They are here just to see that you don't succeed. Every masjid has them.
Don't think your masjid is going to be any different. We're talking to some of them
right now here. They are here in case there's an opportunity where they will
be able to take that advantage to set us back. That is their only purpose in coming.
We have to accept that, but we don't want to become paranoid,
alarmed to the extent that we're going to say, "I'm going to find him." No, don't try to find him.
Forget about him. Just know that he's here. But don't worry about him. Hope he keeps coming.
Maybe he'll hear a khutbah that will change his heart one day. I keep saying that
to them. Accept that he is here and he is a troublemaker, here to see if he can
upset you, or take you back, or throw a monkey wrench in your operation. Sometimes
they just ask a question after the good talk. They don't like to see the good
spirit of Iman. We had a good talk, the spirit is high, good, everyone is going home
in a good spirit. "May I ask a question, brother Imam? What about so-and-so and so-and-so?"
Now I did witness this myself. Just to—"What about so-and-so and so-and-so?"—just to
throw a damper on the good spirit. If you read the history of the people who worked
against Prophet Muhammad. The kinds of things they did, they were able to come
in and pretend to be Muslims. The Holy Quran says they would come in and
pretend to be the best of the Muslims. They would establish that they are the
most enthusiastic Muslims. They would say let us go in among them and establish
ourselves as the most enthusiastic Muslims. And then at a certain time let us
just quietly withdraw and then that will make everybody wonder and will break the
community of Muslims. The Quran tells us of this scheme they use and there are
many many other schemes and tricks they use to hurt the community, make you doubt,
make you not trust the community, be aware of the many schemes they work. Read the
Quran more, you have it in English. Abdullah Yusuf Ali, a good translation,
Pickthall, another good translation, read it in English. I haven't read my translation yet.
Someday maybe. Don't wait until you learn Arabic. Now this is very important, I agree with this.
Don't wait until you learn Arabic. Some of you will never learn Arabic. You will die
trying to learn Arabic. So, that's right, and it's a diversion from the Quran.
So keep trying, but in the meantime, read the good English translation of Quran.
Read it daily. Don't wait until Ramadan. Read it daily. Become more acquainted with
your holy book, so you will know the tricks that the world pulls to set back
the good work of the righteous. Isn't that so? You see how? And here in green,
we read it here in green, saying read Quran more. Don't wait until Ramadan. Read it
daily. Become more acquainted with your holy book, so you will know the tricks
that the world pulls to set back the good work of the righteous. He knows the Quran very well,
and this is exactly, precisely why he is guided, Alhamdulillah. We never see him
talk about
worldly affairs,
what is going on,
what's this, or what about the Middle East
commotion, this is what the
Alhamdulillah, wa ashadu an la ilaha illa Allah, wahdahu la sharika lah.
The second khutba will deal with what happened last Friday.
Last Friday we had a group of people come in this mosque and ask me to translate verse 2:239 right or wrong.
That was the biggest issue. They asked some other questions. But you can
know right away that the object was not to find the truth, which is our
objective. Our objective is to find the truth. Now if they were
sincerely seeking the truth, they would call and say, brother Rashad, we're coming
in a couple of weeks, and we want to discuss this issue of Quran and Hadith
and translation, and we'd like you to prepare and go to the library, do whatever you
want, so we can all help each other find the proof. But they wanted to come
secretly. They were telling everybody, hush, hush, don't tell anybody, because we
want to go and embarrass Rashad Khalifa. We want to go, their whole objective was to
harass me, embarrass me, and to use the quotation, catch him with his pants down.
That was the whole objective. It was not to reach the truth. So they come and say is
the translation of 2:239 right or wrong? Which is a silly question. I mean it's
not important if it's right or wrong, we have the Arabic text. Also, they were
comparing my first edition with the final edition of some other translation,
which is what we're going to do right now anyway. You don't ask a question like, why
were we created? Now that's a good question. That is a doctrinal question. Why are we here?
What is the purpose of our life? These are significant questions, not if 2:239 is
translated right or wrong. Do they know why they were created? Do they know why we are here?
Because very quickly, you know from the appendix in our translation here, that
initially there was God, nothing else, God created the angels, one of the angels had
rebellious ideas, he wanted to be a partner with God. This is where the whole
thing started. Satan wanted to be a partner with God, a God with God. And this is what
we're here for. We're here to prove that we worship God alone, without a God with him,
without any other partner with him. So that is an important question. So they
didn't come here to say, why are we created? Why are we here? What is the
purpose of our life. They came to ask, 239, verse 239, was it translated right or wrong?
Now what happened last Friday with all the rubbish things that went on, is
history repeating itself. You know very well they went to the Prophet Muhammad
and they said, what do you know about the phases of the moon?
Now, did they go? Why did they go to the Prophet Muhammad to ask about the phases of the moon?
Now, Muhammad grew up in a society that was idol-worshipping,
they were Muslims according to the religion of Ibrahim,
but they deviated from the true Islam to idol-worship.
They worshipped God perfectly, they prayed the five prayers a day perfectly to Allah.
But they also had Allat and Manat and Uzza, the other gods with God.
And Muhammad grew up in that society. And then Allah chose Muhammad, guided him
to the worship of God alone, and he gave him the message. So Muhammad started to
utter the message, worship God alone. What did they do? They were up in arms, they
attacked him, they persecuted him, and now they want to prove that he is fake, that
Muhammad is wrong. They don't want to know anything about the doctrine of the
message. They said let us go and prove that he doesn't know anything, he is not a
prophet, he is fake. That was their purpose. So they go to him and they say
listen Muhammad, how do you explain that the moon comes out at the beginning of
the month, thin, and rising early. And then every day gets bigger and later.
You know, they didn't know about the moon going around the earth or any of these things that we
know today. But every day in Saudi Arabia, in Mecca,
they wake up every morning and then at night
there comes the moon, and every day it's different. Until it becomes a full moon,
then it becomes smaller and later. And they went to Muhammad and said,
How do you explain that? What is their objective?
They didn't want to know about the phases of the moon.
They didn't really want to know if 239 is right or wrong.
They want to embarrass somebody and harass somebody and prove that he is fake,
he is fraud. They wanted to prove that Muhammad is fraud.
They didn't know about the phases of the moon.
They didn't want to know about the one God and the worship of God, and the Quran
was written before the creation of the heavens and the earth. But the Quran narrates that
story of the people who wanted the prophet Muhammad to prove that he is fake by asking
about the phases of the moon. What does this mean folks? This means
that these people are sitting peacefully somewhere and then God wanted them to do
something. And all of a sudden they were all picked
up and let's go prove that Muhammad is fake.
Actually God is doing that because the Quran is already written.
God was doing that because it serves the Muslim community.
It shows them who is who. And it brings things
It brings things to life, and forces certain issues.
Now I have repeated to them, I have talked to them...
What was I talking about?
Right, forces certain issues, that's right.
I have emphasized to them that my translation is an authorized translation.
And this of course burned them. And as you know I don't repeat this kind of
thing, I'm too embarrassed to say that. But this is the kind of thing that is
forced by these actions. What I'm saying is that God did it. Because it's
written in the Quran before they were born. So they were sitting in Mecca
somewhere, and all of a sudden they get the idea, let us go harass Rashad.
But it's not really their idea is it?
Of course they are good candidates for it.
So God wants to force different issues.
I am forced today in this khutbah to show you one reason,
one of the reasons why I think this translation is authorized.
And I wouldn't, I would normally be too embarrassed to mention it.
I mention it to a couple of you only.
But, it is this kind of confrontation that forces out certain issues.
I'm going to distribute this to you.
What I did is, I have examples of translations from their favorite translations, Abdullah Yusuf Ali's,
and Pickthall. Pickthall is one of their favorite translations.
And I'm going to compare one verse that they have in their translations and in my translation.
And then I will explain to you how I arrived at my translation, and why I think this translation
is authorized, and why it is. You know, I'm a chemist, I'm not an Al-Azhar graduate, I'm not an alim.
And my feeling when I started this project was, I have no business translating the Quran.
Does everybody have a copy? Share with each other.
There should be enough copies.
We're going to talk about the translation of verse
22:15, Surah Al-Hajj, verse 15.
And on the top you see the translation of Arberry.
He was a Harvard man, I think. Was he?
What's its... what's its name?
What's its name?
Cambridge.
He's a Cambridge professor.
And here's his translation of verse 15.
Whosoever thinks God will not help him in the present world and the world to come,
let him stretch up a rope to heaven, then let him sever it,
and behold whether his guile does away with what enrages him.
Okay? Now you know what to do.
If you don't think God will support you in this life and the hereafter,
you know what to do, don't you?
See, God told you in the Quran, and this is Arberry's translation,
just all you need is to place a rope to heaven,
and then sever it.
And then behold whether your guile does away with what enrages you.
This is Arberry's translation. Let's go to the next one. Yusuf Ali.
Next page is Abdullah Yusuf Ali. He says, if any think that God will not help him,
his apostle, in this world and the hereafter, let him stretch out a rope to the ceiling
and cut, parenthesis, himself, then let him see whether his plan will remove that which enrages, parenthesis, him.
See, now you know better.
This is what you do if you don't think, if you don't think that God will support him, his apostle, in this life and the hereafter.
Let's go to the next one. This is a very favorite translation.
Now we know what to do, right?
Is everybody holding the Pickthall translation?
It says, whoso, this needs some high intellectual pronunciation.
Whoso is wont to think, parenthesis, through envy, that Allah will not give him, parenthesis,
Muhammad, victory in the world and the Hereafter, and is enraged at the
thought of his victory, let him stretch a rope up to the roof of his dwelling and
let him hang himself. Then let him see whether his
strategy will tear away that which enrages him.
Now, this is a transgression against the doctrine. This is an invitation to commit suicide.
God is saying, according to Pickthall, "Go on and commit suicide."
This is my very favorite translation.
I must add here that this is the final edition of Pickthall's translation,
which they are comparing with our first edition of the translation.
This is the final edition. As you know brothers and sisters,
because we sit here every Friday to correct my first edition of the translation,
our first edition of the translation.
Which is by no means perfect, my goodness.
And we printed it cheaply and everything,
because we know that the final edition, if they are really fair,
they should compare my final translation with the Pickthall final translation.
Anyway, so this is what Pickthall says, now you know what to do.
The next translation is Sher Ali, published under the auspices of Hadrat Mirza Nasser Ahmed,
third successor of the Promised Messiah, and head of the Ahmadiyya movement in Islam.
There's idol worship right on the front page.
Whoso thinks that Allah will not help him,
parenthesis, the Prophet in this world and the Hereafter, let him, if he can, find
a way to heaven, and let him cut off the divine help. Then let him see if his
device can remove that which enrages him. So now you really know what to do.
Alright? Okay, now we go to, who's this? Muhammad Sarwar. Okay, another translation, the next page.
Those who thought that God would never grant victory to Muhammad, in this world,
Now, Muhammad is never in the Arabic text by the way, and it has nothing to do with the Prophet Muhammad,
but they translate everything in terms of Muhammad. He doesn't even bother to put it in parentheses.
But it is again from the beginning. Those who thought that God would never grant victory to Muhammad
in this world nor in the life Hereafter, parentheses, and now that he is victorious, parentheses,
should hang themselves by the necks from the ceiling, then cut the rope, cut the rope and see if this can do away with what has enraged them.
Enraged, why enraged?
Oh yeah, enraged them.
Now, now this is a, this is, we don't even, I mean, this breaks the doctrine of Islam,
of not committing suicide. Martha, can you tell me a little about this?
Okay, now let's go to the translation of Yours Truly here, and see if it makes sense.
If anyone thinks that God cannot support him in this life as well as in the
Hereafter, let him turn totally to God and sever his idolization towards anyone
else. He will then find out that this plan eliminates his worries. This is a solution
to any worries that you have in this world. And this should be consistent with
the doctrine of the Quran. If any one of us does not think that God can support us
here in this world and in the Hereafter, let us give Submission a trial. Let us turn
totally to God and cut out all idol worship from our lives. Then you will see
that all worries are gone. No more headaches, no more traffic tickets, no more
problems from the spouse, the wife, or the husband. Now how did I reach this translation?
And this is, well, I'm forced by circumstance to mention. I consider it one of the
signs that told me that this translation is authorized by God.
I do have permission to translate the Quran into English. What happened there?
It just happened that I started the translation back in St. Louis, and when I
came to this verse, I had finished the first 21 surahs, and it was 1971. And in my house I
had a huge table with all the tafsirs of the Quran and the translations. I had them
all on the table, spread open. I'd turn the page as I'd go with the translation.
I came to this verse, and I looked up the tafsirs, I found that the original mufassir, Ibn Kathir,
translated it, if you don't think that Muhammad would be victorious in this life
and the Hereafter, let him stretch a rope to the ceiling of his house and hang himself.
And everybody else took from him. And of course, it didn't make sense to me,
because it defies the doctrines and the laws of God that you shall not commit suicide,
you shall not kill anybody including yourself. So I left that verse blank. I am
saying this and God is my witness, I am saying it in a khutbah, a practice
of worship, and I'm responsible for it; every word in it is true. I left that
verse blank, and I went to verse 16. And I went on, and then I had to leave for
Hajj. Now, the title of this surah is Al-Hajj, The Pilgrimage. And I finished
like about 20 verses after that one.