In that conversation about the translation, you remember I brought this problem to you about teaching them what they did not know.
Yeah.
Yeah. I personally, in front of you, I remember I told you, I don't want you to have, I told you it's good to put it, but you know what's in my mind? I'll tell you.
Because, if these people really know what it means, it only means that Salat is taught by Allah Himself.
Right.
It must not come from Muhammad.
It's very clear.
It can be joined up with Ibrahim.
But prayer is taught.
Man do not know how to pray.
It is Allah who taught him how to pray.
Which strengthens the argument.
More, by accepting their additions in the books.
They didn't see.
No, they are not allowed.
But I'm sorry, I'm sorry Amr, but I don't want anymore, because that would be polemical, it's just something very disagreeable.
This last week, I talked to God, and I have, you know when the events are near, it's very hard to sleep.
But after a few days, I've analyzed who to pray for them. In one point of view, it's very critical.
Maybe in your khutbah insha'Allah, God has decreed it.
It's very interesting, because we have this problem, in brief, it is, uh, from a mash-up
combination, you know?
Yeah, you go ahead.
I'll give him a ride.
Go ahead, I'll give him.
See you tonight.
You know, tonight, there is a family coming from Los Angeles, all the way from Los Angeles
to visit me. They left at six o'clock. What time are they supposed to come?
Twelve hours. Too much. Anyhow, but
maybe they'll be too tired. If they're too tired, they will not come.
That's the same person I met.
He came here. Big man.
He was biding his time in his study.
Anyhow. Are you still recording, Paul?
It is a form of assertion, an assertion of power, again, the contagion of ego.
Some of those boys have busied themselves. For example, Asma is not interested in A or not A or B.
The idea was that we would push him in front.
So I was telling Carl.
If he plays a very careful game, if he plays a very careful game, he can enter a coalition.
Because he's a man looking for identity.
A cause.
He's looking for a cause.
And then, the only way the woodchip can have fireworks is by touching him.
Because the rest are cowards. They'll push him.
So they're using him.
And he's using Carl.
And he's using him against Martin.
But really, setting aside being one man or the other,
do you see anything about that?
It's only to show how smart they are.
You know, if they ever come again,
I think we ought to set it up formally.
If they ever come again, I think we should set it up formally.
I know I'm being recorded and I gave my permission.
You know, we have a mediator,
have written questions submitted,
have the mediator speak the question and then each man, what I was hoping they would have gotten in the first place.
You know, that is what a debate is.
It's an intelligent discussion between people from the very beginning