Dr. Khalifa:
I seek refuge in God from Satan the rejected (أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ) [A'oodhu billahi min ash-shaytan ir-rajeem]
We seek refuge in God from Satan, who was
the basic cause for us being here in this world.
And may it back... And may God make it backfire on Satan, give
us happiness in this world and forever,
through believing in God alone.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
We're gonna start with Sura 51, page
366.
And our teacher tonight, I forgot his name, I
don't know if you remember your... what's your name sir?
A woman: I think he forget his name.
Douglas: Rashid.
Dr. Khalifa: What's your name?
Douglas: No.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm serious, he actually forgot!
Dr. Khalifa: Rashid?
Douglas: Douglas. It's Douglas. Douglas Brown.
Dr. Khalifa: Douglas Brown?
Douglas: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You're sure?
Douglas: I'm sure of that. You'll find out later when I...
Dr. Khalifa: He's a very nervous teacher today.
And you can, you can guess... no.... first
that we're having a wedding tonight.
One handsome guy is groom and you can
tell who the prettiest girl in town tonight is.
So, as soon, as soon as we finish the Quranic study,
we're gonna have these two united, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Okay Douglas, take it.
Douglas: Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
If I lose my speech or get tongue twisted
tonight, you all know why. So,...
Dr. Khalifa: You're excused.
Douglas: Ok.
Douglas: In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[51:1]  By the blowing winds.
[51:2]  Carrying clouds.
[51:3]  And bringing bounties.
[51:4]  To be distributed by command.
[51:5]  What is promised to you is true.
[51:6]  Judgment is sure to come.
I'd like to stop here.
I'd like to stop first of all and bear witness
that the clouds and the winds have came and
they're bringing bounty outside right now.
And we know that that promise is true.
Today, Abdullah went over some more characteristics
of the code, proving
that when Allah says He has preserved the Quran, He's preserved it.
That Allah has all knowledge and it doesn't
make any difference what a person does or they don't do,
what disbelievers believe,
feel, and think.
It doesn't really make any difference what
type of power that a person has in this world,
influence or whatever.
They simply cannot overwhelm Allah.
He knows what they have and what they don't
have and he controls everything, their thoughts.
And just like Allah brings the rain, the bounty,
He brings the life by His command.
And it's distributed equally.
So then in one way or another, all of us are
nourished by the water.
The very process in creation by which rain
is produced is a miracle in itself
in terms of the orbit of the earth within a specific
angle in relationship to the sun and the change of the seasons.
Many people don't know that the 24-hour difference
in heat and cold in the earth causes the winds to flow on the earth.
That's one of the things that causes the winds
to flow, the alternation of light and darkness,
of the heat and cold.
And just imagine what it would be like if
it was night all the time or day all the time.
These laws that Allah has created. These winds
would not travel as they do in bringing the bounty to us.
[51:5]  What is promised to you is true.
God is telling us, as sure as we can see the
rain in front of our eyes, as sure as we can see
the majesty of the clouds in the sky and
how it becomes saturated and it falls,
this is true.
What God promises is true.
And the Judgment is sure to come.
Why do we know that it's sure to come?
Because God tells us it's sure to come. That's one of the reasons.
As was pointed out in the Khutba, the minimum
requirement to be a Muslim is to submit,
to submit to what God tells us and what He teaches
us.
One of the most recent discoveries concerning
the time of the Day of Judgment was made the other
day by Mahmoud and I think sister Ihsan
and Emily.
Verse... Sura 72 verse 27 speaks to the fact that only Allah gives His messenger any knowledge of the past, present, and future.
Only the messengers that He chooses may be
given certain information concerning the past or the future.
What Mahmoud and sister Ihsan and Emily had
done was they took the gematrical value,
the gematrical, I guess it's the gematrical
value of the name Rashad and the name Khalifa
and the Sura number and the verse number
and they added, they put these numbers in a series.
Just like Abdullah showed us today when we
saw the chapter and the verse and the chapter,
he put them in a straight line and it's divisible
by 19.
So, not only do we know that God's messenger
is given the knowledge of the future,
we also know that God willed that His Messenger of
the Covenant be given knowledge of the future.
And if people say "well, there are millions
of individuals named Rashad,"
okay, because you can just take the value of the word "Rashad"
and put it next to chapter 72,
next to verse 27 and it too is a multiple of 19.
But there is only one Rashad, Khalifa.
Confirmation of the time of the Day of Judgment
and what God promises us is true.
[51:7]  Despite the perfectly created sky.
[51:8]  You dispute the truth.
The stars, the sun, the moon, these clouds,
how Allah keeps the oxygen and hydrogen,
how He keeps certain gases within the earth's
atmosphere, how He prevents things that are
dangerous and harmful to us from entering
the atmosphere, how ever since He created the earth,
the cycle of the rainfall has not changed,
the evaporation, precipitation, none of this has changed.
Despite the perfectly created sky, the constellations
at night, where humans have given names to
these constellations, because when they look
up at these stars, they see certain patterns
that they relate to, certain figures and patterns.
And just like Prophet Abraham. He looked up
at the stars and he realized that this was not an accident.
These stars and planets could not be positioned
in the sky to produce this beauty, to control
the movements of other heavenly bodies.
There had to be some higher being responsible
for this.
And God tells us in the Sura, despite these
signs, these magnificent signs that are right before us.
When we turn on the faucet, we have
a sign. We drink it. Without it, we die,
let alone look at the sky. There is dispute. There
is confusion.
Why is there... what are some of the reasons
for the dispute and the confusion?
Well, we know that this is Satan's kingdom.
He's incompetent. He thought that he could be a god.
He entertained thoughts that he
could run a universe, a world, with creatures,
and God put him to the test.
And his incompetence, along with individual
decisions, intentions, create this doubt.
Although Satan was very incompetent, he is
also a master. He's a master deceiver.
He's extremely powerful. He's a hypnotist,
or whatever names we want to use.
He retained the power and ability to mislead
us.
And he has dedicated himself to that. That's
his purpose for existence, to mislead as many of
us as possible, to keep us disputing about
the truth and confused.
We know many times in areas where there are
droughts. They will spray the clouds.
They will seed the clouds in an effort to
make it rain.
Seeding the clouds in itself does not make
it rain.
There's no conclusive proof at all in the
first place that seeding a cloud will make it
rain or not, because Allah still controls
the processes by which it rains.
But what man learns is he learns some of the
laws and principles governing rainfall.
But he forgets the lawmaker.
He learns laws. He learns rules, but somehow
Satan is hypnotizing where he can't make the
logical connection between the law and the
rule and the lawmaker and the ruler.
So he disputes.
Any questions on the first eight verses?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, we need to comment on the first, on
the title of the Sura.
You know, a believer appreciates God differently
from people who are unaware,
or who are not strong believers.
You can see here that the title of the Sura
is the Winds.
And we learn from the first few verses that
the winds, their main job is to carry clouds
and bring bounties.
We need that water.
So, in order to appreciate God and these simple
words, just imagine yourself sending ten astronauts to space.
You, sending ten astronauts to space, and
you tell them "okay, you're gonna be out
there for three years, and when you need water,
I made an invention in the spaceship,
so there'll be these clouds on top of you, and they
will give you water."
You're sending them into space.
And you devise that system that will give
them water, clean water.
When they pollute the water they have on the
spaceship, it's gonna, you know, one of...
number one purification processes is distillation.
So, when they pollute, their own water is
gonna evaporate, it's gonna be pure water, and come down again.
So, you tell them that to assure them that they will have enough water supply for three years, or five years, ten years, or whatever.
You're sending them.
Just imagine that.
See, God sent this spaceship with five billion
astronauts.
You and me, we are astronauts.
That's right.
And God gave us this system. God devised this
system, where the water evaporates
and then comes down by... the winds drive the clouds
here.
How far are we from the ocean?
We're far from the ocean.
But these clouds came to us from the ocean,
by the wind.
It's a traveling system.
And it sends down pure water.
You appreciate God if you think, if you imagine
sending ten astronauts in space and you tell them
"I'm going to give you the exact percentage
of oxygen for you to breathe."
Now in 1967, we were technologically advanced
people.
1967.
But we put three astronauts in a capsule in
an atmosphere of 100% oxygen.
Pure oxygen, right?
To breathe.
And all it took was a spark.
And the three astronauts were combusted.
Ed White, Gus Grissom, and Roger Chaffee.
They are not with us today because of that.
We were really advanced in science.
But when you put anything in pure oxygen and
light a match, everything would be combusted. Everything.
Everything organic, that is.
In fact, this is for chemists.
If any chemist is here, this is the last thing
you do to find out if there is, for example,
radioactivity in the ashes of anything.
You put it in a closed thing there.
You fill it with 100% oxygen.
And you create a spark.
And everything will be combusted into ashes.
This is what happened to the three astronauts.
And this is why God didn't give us 100% oxygen.
We have 20% oxygen.
The rest is nitrogen.
And this is what they do now
when they send astronauts into space.
But they learned the hard way.
So, despite our...
I mean, we were sending people to the moon.
And we couldn't give them the correct atmosphere.
So, these few verses here will make us appreciate
God if we think of sending our own astronauts into space.
Of course, you know how the oxygen is generated
for us.
We breathe it, and we get out carbon dioxide,
which is not good for breathing.
So, God designed the trees, so they will take
carbon dioxide and turn it into apples
and give us the oxygen.
They take the carbon and give us back the
oxygen.
How do you like that for a system?
Can you do that for your astronauts?
You tell your 10 astronauts "you're gonna be out there for 10 years, and you're gonna to breathe out carbon dioxide, so I'm gonna give you
a couple of... I invented these plants or something that will take your carbon dioxide, turn it into food for you, and you'll get the oxygen back."
Such is God's creation.
And you think it's all evolution, right?
Are there any questions on these?
The winds and the rains, bounties.
We're talking only about the 5 billion human
beings.
You forget the 10 Decillion ants, and the...
about 200 Billion mice.
Ihsan?
There may be a few of them in this mosque, running
around.
The name scares her. This is why I said that.
Okay, back to Douglas.
Yes, Catherine.
Catherine: (unintelligible)
Catherine: But there's a verse in the Quran where God talks about those (unintelligible)
Catherine: Is that allegorical?
Dr. Khalifa: No. Did you take a bath today?
Catherine: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: What did you use? You used water. Yeah.
That's it. That's not allegorical. You actually used water.
Catherine: How is that washing (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh, oh.
The verse says "...removes the devil's, the devil's touch."
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I have to think about that.
Edip: Was that from the Bible?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's in the Quran, yeah.
Well, let's...
I can think of a few things.
A woman: I think your translation (unintelligible)
kind of I understand it is probably (unintelligible).
I think your translation is that He removes the devil's curse and He sends down water to cleanse you (unintelligible)
or something like that. So, it's not...
Dr. Khalifa: It's not connected? Yeah.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
A woman: I believe this is wrong, I think. Sura 8, verse 11.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you wanna read it?
[8:11]  He causes slumber to pacify you, and He sent down water from the sky to clean you therewith and removed the devil's curse from you...
Dr. Khalifa: And.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a separate issue.
A woman: [8:11]  ...He reassured your hearts and strengthened your foothold.
Dr. Khalifa: These are all separate issues.
But one of the things we use water for is taking
a bath between ourselves.
A man: Which verse?
A woman: In Sura 8, verse 11.
Dr. Khalifa: You can tell your astronauts "when the water
comes down on your spaceship, you can take a bath.
A woman: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: George.
George, go ahead.
Douglas: Why?
Douglas: However,...
Dr. Khalifa: We're taking advantage of his nervousness.
Douglas: [51:9]  However deviating that those who are supposed to deviate.
[51:10]  Woe to the falsifiers.
[51:11]  Who are heedless in their blunders.
[51:12]  They ask "When is the Day of Judgment?"
[51:13]  That is the day when they suffer in Hell.
[51:14]  Taste your retribution; this is what you defiantly challenged.
[51:15]  As for the righteous, they have deserved gardens and springs.
[51:16]  They receive their Lord's blessings in return for their works.
[51:17]  Rarely did they sleep the whole night.
[51:18]  At dawn, they used to implore for forgiveness.
[51:19]  A portion of their money was set aside for the needy and deprived.
[51:20]  In the earth, there are signs for those who are certain
[51:21]  Even within yourselves; do you not see?
[51:22]  In the heaven is your provision, and everything that is promised to you.
[51:23]  By the Lord of the heaven and the earth, this is as real as the fact that you speak.
In verses 9 through 23, God is telling us in verse 9 that the deviators are doing exactly what they're supposed to do.
And one of the reasons why they are supposed
to do this is because they've chosen to do it.
They have chosen to follow Satan instead of
submit to God alone.
They've chosen to deviate and because they
deviate, they incur.
They're going to meet the consequences of it.
And the consequences of it as we know are
Hell.
And we know in this so-called modern age,
scientific age, people like to appear what
they think is intelligent and have scientific
minds.
So, there are a lot of people whom you say "you
believe in Heaven and Hell?"
"Well, I don't know. I'm not too sure about that. There's not too much proof about it."
People like to pretend as if... some people
like to pretend as if they need more information
before they can be confident that there is
a Day of Judgment.
Well, if you say "there's a Day of Judgment."
"When is it coming?"
Well, now, they've asked the question.
They continually ask the question. And God knows they were gonna ask the question. And now they've received an answer.
And they still don't want it.
Now, God has revealed through the code when
the Day of Judgment will come and they still do not want it.
So, they are deviating because they're supposed
to deviate.
Their deviation is not because they are sincerely
seeking the truth and they're just simply ignorant
or they just don't know where to
look and when to look.
We're told in Sura 74 that the code and everything
associated with the code exposes the hypocrites.
It exposes the nonbelievers.
You know, as we grew up and we were children,
every now and then we may,
we may, for example, like we're driving down the street of the road
and we'll see a warning sign "don't turn left."
Somebody said "you'd. better be careful. Don't
walk that way anymore."
We're surrounded by warnings.
We don't take them all with the same degree
of seriousness.
Many of them we totally ignore.
We feel "well, it's not gonna happen to
me."
And this is the way these disbelievers and
falsifiers are.
When they're warned about the Day of Judgment
and they're warned about Hell, to them,
it doesn't make any difference.
God says in the Quran "the human being is
prone to only believe in what is in front of his face."
He only wants to believe what he thinks he
can feel and touch in front of his face.
And one of the things that I was thinking
about the other day is when we
when we went along with Satan and didn't come out and declare
that only God is god and that He is absolute,
we were then put in this world.
We could no longer stand the presence of God
because we entertained doubt in His power.
And when we were brought into this world, our
bodies were made visible to us.
Now if we listen to what God is telling us,
He's saying our bodies were made visible to us
when we came into this world.
Well, that implies that our bodies and everything
else that's visible to us in this world
is not permanent or is not absolute because we
came from somewhere else that made our bodies visible
and made us see the things in front
of our face.
See?
So, what happens?
Satan deceives us and whispers to us and we
begin to believe that
the only thing that's real is what is visible to us despite the
proof.
So, God in His mercy and His absoluteness revealed
a miraculous code, revealed an irrefutable proof
in the highest form of, you know, scientific language,
mathematics, right in front of his face
and he still denies it because he is supposed
to deviate.
And we see that as a result, the people, the
falsifiers have to taste their retribution.
And they will suffer in Hell because they
defiantly challenged all of the signs of God.
They defiantly challenged the revelation.
They defied and opposed God's messenger and
we know that the Muhammadans, the false Muslims,
defiantly opposed the miracle of the Quran.
And we know that they also defiantly opposed
Rashad as the Messenger of the Covenant.
In contrast to these people, the righteous
will be rewarded and as we know the descriptions of
Heaven and Hell in the Quran are allegorical.
They are termed in ways that make us think
of pleasure and contentment and happiness, life,
fruit, well-being, a garden with water
and springs and flowers and food, but we know that
we cannot describe Heaven or Hell.
What is the bargain?
What is the bargain for those who are righteous,
who heed the signs of God. They receive their Lord's blessings?
There is obviously no greater bargain, but
only a believer is guided to see that.
Only a person who submits and desires to submit
to God is guided to recognize that that is the greatest bargain,
that is the greatest
promise possible in this world.
And it's not free.
We're told in the Quran "do not think that
you are going to be allowed to say you believe without being tested."
We all have to go through tests in life, different
circumstances, situations to increase that belief.
And, IN SHAA ALLAH, hopefully until it approaches
a point of certainty.
We don't question what Allah says in the Quran. We don't question His signs with certainty.
Mahmoud and I were talking the other day and
when you read about the descriptions of the, of Heaven
for the believers, in light of the fact that we know that every letter of the Quran is divinely fixed and from Allah,
we know that
every statement in the Quran is true.
We are certain that every statement of the
Quran is true.
And we were kind of laughing the other day saying that it's a wonder that believers don't commit suicide
to get to Heaven as fast as they can, you know, because we know that it's true.
No.
What are some of the things that the righteous
do in order to get this reward?
We're told that they don't, during the night
or after sunset, they Pray.
They make their Evening Prayer, their Night Prayer.
Or they spend their time reading the Quran or
some form of worship, not the entire night,
but they don't spend their night in idle play
or things of no benefit to them.
And at dawn, at Fajr, wake up and make the
Fajr Salat.
The righteous recite their Prayers five times
a day because they know and they understand that
making their Salat is contact with God.
Douglas: It's contact and it's building up credits
and their soul is growing so that their soul...
Dr. Sabahi: ...yeah a lot of...
Douglas: Okay, I don't know. I don't really know the details of that.
Dr. Sabahi: No, this is an example for the phenomenon that...
Douglas: I'll give you an example.
Dr. Sabahi: ....but you don't see that.
None of us have ever seen an x-ray, but we
know what happens if we get exposed to too many of them.
Gamma rays.
In other words, man is capable of learning
that certain things exist
that he cannot directly perceive because of the effect that it has on him.
If he can rule out all of the possibilities
of anything else in the environment,
he knows that there's something there that's causing
this cancer or
causing this genetic mutation to take place.
And he tries to learn and discover it. And
if God wills, he learns that there is some
invisible energy, an x-ray or a gamma ray
that passes through his body or something like that.
He can't see it himself.
Just like when a person goes to the doctor
to get x-rays, when you see the picture, that's not the ray itself.
See?
That's an after-image or a trace that is actually
seen.
So, the doctor or the nurse looks at the trace
and knows that that was an x-ray or a particular
type of ray that passes through the person.
So, one of the ways we know that, well obviously
this is a proof that all that exists isn't
limited obviously to what we directly perceive.
Because so much around us affects us and influences
and we cannot directly perceive.
Douglas: Does that, does that...
Dr. Sabahi: Yeah, just, I think you quoted another verse that
God is saying this and then you (unintelligible) by explaining...
Douglas: I was saying you what I would refer to as a fact that
like if we look up in the ceiling and we see that light,
that's because of certain, right, stimuli. That's because of certain colors and
light waves that are hitting our eye, right?
That has to do with the light waves and nervous
impulses and what have you that eventually
lead to the sense that that is a light.
I see the light. Okay?
Dr. Khalifa: But you don't see electricity.
Douglas: Right, I don't see the electric. I can't see the actual light wave.
See?
So, in that sense what I was trying to say
is that man really limits himself
when he says that he only wants to believe what he
can see.
Dr. Sabahi: But we know that a lot of people do
that, especially these days to advance in science.
That's what, that's what makes science advance.
When people see things that physically you
cannot see it, but if you use up your brain
and brain power and imagination, you can see
things that (unintelligible)
But some people can do it.
And that's difference between (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You're in trouble, Douglas. Martha's gonna ask you a question.
Martha: No, actually I (unintelligible)
Martha: Actually, I (unintelligible)
Martha: We know so much, not a lot of things but we have no idea what is the concept whereby we hear each other speak
and somehow understand what that person is
saying, just zero, absolutely nothing.
We know that it happens, but we don't know,
we don't understand part of what mechanism
the ear receives these waves and then somehow
takes these waves and translates them into
something that then goes into our brain. I mean, we just don't know.
We have no idea how these things happen. And we do it.
Four-year-old children do it and two-year-old children do it. And it's language.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is mentioned specifically as a great
miracle in the Koran, you know, the language.
Just go to Europe.
Martha: So, we don't doubt it. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Within the radius of 50 miles, not 50, 20
miles in Europe, you can come across 15 languages.
Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Austria.
Within Czechoslovakia, there are several languages.
And it's just amazing how these people understand each other, but these people don't understand them. They understand each other and...
Martha: Even we all speak the same language...
Dr. Khalifa: It's a miracle.
Dr. Khalifa: It's still amazing.
Martha: It's an incredible miracle and (unintelligible)
at this point in our understanding
We're just bening predominantly beginning a deep understanding of
how that process happens.
(unintelligible)
God willing, (unintelligible)
and understanding. We don't understand the first thing about (unintelligible) 2 years old.
Dr. Khalifa: Some people even speak Turkish.
Martha: (unintelligible)
A woman: That's, It's like the math, it's a language, but it's
universal.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: One and one equal two.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible), yes.
Douglas: The first major sense that we developed in
the womb was hearing.
Hearing is almost fully developed in the womb
before birth, before birth.
Dr. Khalifa: It's amazing you remember that.
Okay, verse 24.
Douglas: Lessons from the past: Abraham.
Have you narrated... Excuse me.
[51:24]  Have you noted the narration about Abraham's honorable guests?
[51:25]  When they entered, they said "Peace." And he said, "Peace to you, strangers!"
[51:26]  He then asked his family to prepare a fattened calf.
[51:27]  He offered it to them, but they did not eat.
[51:28]  He became wary of them. They said, "Do not be afraid," and they gave him good news of a knowledgeable son.
[51:29]  His wife came in astonishment, pointing at
her face and saying: "I am a sterile old woman."
[51:30]  They said, "Your Lord said thus. He is the Most Wise, the Omniscient."
These honorable guests that came to see Abraham were angels.
They were actually on their way to Gomorrah, Sodom and Gomorrah.
They were commissioned to go and destroy Sodom
and Gomorrah.
Because the people of Lot had reached the
point of no return,
in terms of their opposition against God.
The practice of homosexuality and other kinds
of wickedness.
And so, their destruction was already written.
It was already predetermined.
And when they went to Abraham's house, he
gave them the greeting and welcome as a believer.
As we know, God commands us in the Quran to
greet the people with a hearty greeting, with a,
to give people a sense of welcome.
And they returned it.
But when he offered them the food, they didn't eat it.
And at this particular time, in Abraham's
culture, whenever you went to someone's house and
they offered you of their table and you
did not eat it, this would arouse suspicion and sometimes fear.
Because a guest should return, a guest should, you know,
eat of the offering that the host meant.
And he became somewhat worried as to who they
were and what they wanted.
And as we see here, they told him not to be
afraid. And they told him that he would have a son by his wife, Sarah.
And she could not believe it, obviously, because
of her age.
And she asked in a different way the same
question that Mary asked.
When the angel went to her and told her that
she was gonna have a son.
And we know in Sura 4, she said "How can
I have a son when no man has touched me?"
And the angel let her know that Allah could
cause life and create the birth of a child
or the conception of a child in the womb of
a woman anytime He wills. He created Adam and Eve out of nothing.
And I think this was Isaac.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Douglas: This was the birth of Isaac.
Douglas: And this was a miracle as well.
The birth of Isaac was a miracle.
So, we see that Abraham... God blessed Abraham with many,
many sons.
We knew... We know that in the Quran, God told him to
place four pieces of a bird on different hills.
Dr. Khalifa: Four birds.
Douglas: four birds on different hills and
called them together and they would come.
Dr. Khalifa: Many pieces of four birds.
Douglas: Here we have his wife having a child well beyond the age which is normally possible for a woman to bear a child.
We have the influence of Satan in the dream
where he thought he was told to sacrifice Ismail.
We also have the miracle when Abraham's father
was such a wicked, he was so so defiant, so arrogant and so wicked
when Abraham confronted him that he actually
built a fire to cremate him, to cremate his own son.
And we know in the Quran that Abraham sat
in the fire until the flames died down and he walked out.
The power of God, the power of Allah.
Douglas: Blessed with many miracles, many signs.
Dr. Khalifa: No, Ismail.
Douglas: Any questions or comments?
Dr. Khalifa: There you said it, his only son. Isaac was never the only son.
You said the truth right there.
A woman: But isn't that the reason they say it is because Isaac was his only legitimate son, but we know why.
Dr. Khalifa: This is how they justify it.
A woman: But it still...
Dr. Khalifa: It didn't say "take your only legitimate son." It said "take your only son," even if he's illegitimate."
But he was not illegitimate.
Did you say "you take your only son" or "your
only legitimate son?"
A woman: According to the Bible, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Somebody, of course, the Jews and the Christians
believe it was Isaac.
But that's a racial, that's a racial distortion.
They said "take your only son, Isaac,"
So, they made a boo-boo there, because Isaac
was never the only son.
So, when you tell them, when you confront them with that only son
business, because Ishmael was 14 years older than Isaac.
They tell you "oh, it's because Isaac was
the only legitimate son."
I said "OK, let's look at the Bible."
And the Bible consistently calls Ishmael Abraham's
son until Abraham dies. And then they say
"when Abraham died, his
two sons, Ishmael and Isaac, buried him."
So, there's no way out.
No. No, he didn't.
No, you read it in some novel.
From who?
A woman: It's in the first book of the Bible. I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it's not, it's not in Genesis.
OK, Abraham had... I mean, Sarah was sterile. She didn't have anything but Isaac.
Yeah, there were lots of novels that he said
he married this and that.
OK.
If he had any other children, they're irrelevant,
because the Quran and the Bible mention only Ishmael and Isaac.
Dr. Khalifa: Nobody else.
A woman: Right, because then the Bible says when Abraham
died...
Dr. Khalifa: His two sons...
A woman: And that would be an internal contradiction, because there is another mention of other sons in that, right in the Bible.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't think so. I don't remember.
But anyway, this is the verse in Genesis 22,
A woman: I'm saying that...
Dr. Khalifa: In Genesis 22, around 25, it says
"when Abraham died, his two sons, Ishmael and Isaac, buried him."
So, Ishmael was Abraham's son. He was the only son of Abraham for 14 years.
Isaac was never the only son.
A woman: Ok. What would be an (unintelligible) Isaac?
Dr. Khalifa: Isaac is the father of the Jews. Ishmael is the father of the Arabs.
The Jews wrote the... I mean, played around with the Genesis, the
Torah.
A woman: So, the idea is that they just wanted the miracle
to be a miracle with Isaac?
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right. They didn't want anything to Ishmael to have anything to to do with anything.
So, they made a big mistake, just like the two verses in the Quran.
Exactly. They made a glaring error.
And they tried to correct it in the newer
editions of the Bible. They say "take your only one."
Trying very hard, but they make it worse.
Your only one what? Donkey? Or...
A woman: Ishamael will... How could I... Ishmael lived... God commanded Abraham to send them away.
Dr. Khalifa: It was just another town.
A woman: Because I was wondering a period of (unintelligible) Ishameal (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: About three or four weeks.
Three or four weeks at a time.
Ok. Back to Douglas.
And 31.
Douglas: Sodom and Gomorrah.
[51:31]  Abraham said, "Where are you going, O messengers?"
[51:32]  They said, "We have been dispatched to guilty people.
[51:33]  "We are to shower them with stones of clay.
[51:34]  "Marked at your Lord for the transgressors."
[51:35]  We then delivered all the believers.
[51:36]  We found only one house of Muslim submitters therein.
[51:37]  We set it up as a lesson for anyone who fears the painful retribution.
Abraham knew that they were messengers of
God.
That in this context, angels are messengers
of God. They carry warning.
They carry the revelations, the knowledge,
and they also carry out commands from God.
It's interesting in terms of the Armenia,
the earthquake in Armenia.
After the devastating earthquake, they had
a lot of people on the news conjecturing.
And one of the major conjectures they came
up with was that Armenia is an earthquake fault. It's a fault area.
They begin to conjecture.
I mean, there's nothing wrong with theorizing,
but what we find is that when these disasters take place,
most people don't, well, at least the people who are allegedly the ones who are so called experts or the people who are paid to give their opinion, they make no mention of God.
That doesn't mean that some of the people
don't, but they seem to be locked up or blocked out
at any suggestion that there is a greater
power at work that causes these devastations,
let alone produces the bounty and benefit. They refuse to believe that there is a God, an intelligence, that this is by design,
that there are laws and rules.
They wanna believe that it's either by haphazard,
you see, or
simply due to some malfunction or something off in the earth's structure, just as an example.
And the messenger angels were dispatched to
the people of Sodom and Gomorrah.
And we know that they were showered with volcanoes, tremendous
earthquakes and volcanic eruptions.
And it completely destroyed that area of land,
totally.
It was so much devastation, fire, and heat
that we know that the salt plains,
it created miles of salt plains where there has been
tremendous heat.
And it's proof in verse 34 that these types
of disasters are commanded by Allah.
And the people who die in these disasters are already
determined. They're already identified.
In other words, only God controls the time
of death, and also people who are disbelievers
are identified by God, and this is one of
the things we see in verse 34,
[51:34]  "Marked at your Lord for the transgressors."
That these stones,
volcanic ash, this heat, this lava, all of this was marked.
No transgressor, not a single transgressor
could leave Sodom and Gomorrah.
Just a small family of believers who were
with Lot were saved.
And it doesn't make any difference if you've
got seismograph in your front, in your living room
to tell you that there are tremors in
the earth.
I mean, I'm saying it doesn't make any difference
what kind of alarm system you've got.
Your best alarm system, and I'm not dismissing
that, I'm saying the best alarm system is
submitting to God alone in this life, period.
Because we know that God is the One that controls
all things.
God controls, you know, circumstances.
A human being is supposed to take precautions,
use his or her intelligence,
but to also understand that God controls all things. You can have all the alarm systems and safety devices and all kinds of things you want,
but if a circumstance is to befall you, or
you were to come upon a certain circumstance,
there's nothing going to do to stop it from
happening, if it has been already written.
And God says in verse 37 that the destruction
of Sodom and Gomorrah was set up as a lesson.
Not only for a lesson for the survivors with
Lot, but for all time,
our generation and generations to come.
Because those soft plains are still there
for anyone to see and to reflect on the magnitude of that disaster.
And if someone says "well, what brought this
about or what caused it?"
Well, again, we know. We know that the code has confirmed that every word and sentence in the Quran is true.
It's fact.
And when a person is given the opportunity
to be exposed to the code, to all of the information,
and they sincerely want to believe, they know
that the Quran is from God.
And if God...God tells us what was behind the destruction
of Sodom and Gomorrah.
Are there any questions or comments?
A woman: I'm just listening to the news of Armenia
I'm hearing that in Armenia, now they're celebrating
Christmas (unintelligible) service.
And during the service, they were saying,
they're preparing it for Jonah's (unintelligible)
They believe (unintelligible) was saved. And nothing in the earth is permanent.
You know, it's interesting.
They're talking about how Jesus found us (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: They don't learn, do they?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Haven't learned a thing.
People bring their destruction on themselves.
We know that Sodom and Gomorrah, they were
all corrupted beyond reform.
And this is the one thing that... I mean, they brought
it on themselves.
So, it is God's law that when they do this,
they are destroyed.
Nowadays, where homosexuals are spread in the society, you cannot just destroy the city of Tucson because there are a thousand homosexuals in it.
But you can send a virus to pick them out.
And this is what's happening now.
A man: What happens to the children who are (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Their parents brought it on them.
A man: What if you got it from blood transfusion?
Dr. Khalifa: Right. They brought it on themselves. Their family,
Their family take the children out of God's
protection.
This is what happens.
It's actually a blessing for the children,
after all.
But if you... whatever disaster happens, it's because
the parents removed their children out of God's protection.
A man: How could it be that the parents actually develop the fate of the child?
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. We discussed this before. And we said when...
When the parents do not follow the commandments, God assigns to their homes, souls that deserve whatever is gonna happen.
The children are not so innocent as we think.
Remember Adolf Hitler was a cute child.
A woman: Who?
Dr. Khalifa: Hitler.
He was a cute, innocent child.
But God knew in advance that he's gonna be a tyrant.
So was Gaddafi.
Do you understand, Babak? Do you understand the point?
Babak: I have a hard time understanding it.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, the babies who will be born next year,
where are they now?
Remember, we existed before the earth came
into creation.
Okay, the children who will be born next year,
where are they now?
Babak: Not here.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. They're in some depository, waiting their
turn to come into this world.
Now you agree that God knows which ones are
good and which ones are bad, right?
Okay, God told the people in the Bible that
if you don't keep the commandments,
you will incur, you will remove yourselves from God's
protection for four generations.
So, what is the mechanism?
What is the mechanism here?
It's that when a baby is born in a certain
home next year, God will assign a certain soul to that home, right?
But God does that. He assigns
the souls to the homes and the
environments where they grow in.
So, God can pick out a good soul or a bad soul,
depending on what the situation is.
So, the people who pass AIDS onto their babies,
they brought it on themselves because they use drugs or...
Dr. Khalifa: But AIDS is mainly a homosexual disease. There's no question about it.
Babak: Rashad, I was talking about
Babak: children who are, for
some reason or another, need blood transfusions.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Babak: And they get blood transfusions, not from
their parents,
Babak: not that their parents have AIDS or drugs or whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: From the blood, yes. Even those.
Babak: But they get AIDS because of some other jerk,
who had AIDS or whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right.
Babak: And I just think of...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, we are, we are in an era now where believing
house will not need a blood transfusion, to start with.
Babak: We don't (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: We are in an era where when you believe in
God and follow His commandments,
you will not need a blood transfusion to start with,
neither you, nor your family.
Maybe difficult to fathom, but this is God's
promise throughout the Quran.
Babak: I'm sorry I don't mean (unintelligible).
But if you go outside in the street and there's an
accident, you lose some blood and...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, that, I'm saying this will not happen, to start
with.
God says He'll protect you from anything like
that.
If it has to happen, God will protect you,
will give you clean blood.
But I'm saying that it will not happen, to
start with.
Okay, let me... Because this is difficult to understand, and
I'm not bragging or anything, but I thank God first. I wanna tell you,
I'm speaking from experience.
And I mention this. It'll be boring to a lot
of these people here, because they heard it before.
But when I was a child, I used to go swim
in the canals in the countryside, the village.
And there's a disease in Egypt that if you
swim in the canal, you have to catch that disease called Bilharzia.
It's still epidemic in Egypt.
Dr. Khalifa: And every year, they'll take the children
and check them for Bilharzia, through a urine sample.
A woman: They don't even check them.
A woman: Then I used to watch it for so many years, people who lived in the countryside where they would go swimming
They'd never even check (unintelligible).
A woman: At the end of the summer, they lined them
up, did a check against (unintelligible). They do
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: the same with Bilharzia. They never even bothered checking.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, they asked them. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa Right.
A woman: They just did it. They lined them all up and gave them a shot.
Dr. Khalifa: These are the ones they knew they swam in
the canal, right?
Well, I was living in a city.
So, they checked all the children, at least
in my time.
They took a urine sample and check them for
Bilharzia.
And every time, I come out negative.
And they'll ask me "did you go to the village this summer?"
"Yes."
"Did you swim in the canal?"
Okay, now they sent a nurse with me, to make
sure that I'm giving them a urine sample, not a faucet,
not a sample from the faucet.
They'll go with me, and they will take the sample,
and it'll be negative.
And I'll go home, and my father would ask
me "did they check you for Bilharzia?" I say "Yes."
He said "what did they find?"
I said "nothing."
And my father shake his head.
It's God's protection.
So, I learned that from an early stage.
So, you can live in the virus, live in the
germs, and God will protect you.
So, I guess God knew that I'd be passing this
information on to you.
And before I do anything, I thank God for
His protection. Then, I'm talking to you from experience.
It will not happen. When you're a believer, it will not happen. You will not catch AIDS.
You will not need transfusion. You will not have an accident.
You don't even get traffic tickets, depending
how good you are.
You will get these as pinches whenever you
do something wrong.
But for as long as you're sincerely searching for God, God will give you time, will protect you, until you make a decision.
Your decision would be to remain in God's
protection, or step out of God's protection.
So, it's your decision. God left it in our hands.
Babak: What I'm saying is that everybody dies at some time.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Babak: Every one of us is gonna die
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Babak: for one reason or another, accident, (unintelligible), whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but...
Babak: And it's gonna happen.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, death is not a disaster.
Babak: ...disease that was an easier...
Dr. Khalifa: No, Death is a fact of life for each one of us.
Babak: The impression that I'm getting is that staying
with God is gonna protect us from all evil and all harm.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. That's right.
Babak: And as long as you believe that harmful is gonna come to us...
Babak: But at the end, maybe at the age of 90, or
500, or whatever, we're gonna die.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Babak: And we're gonna die of something.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. That's right.
Babak: We're not going to stop...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, but there are different...