Dr. Khalifa: In Sura 72, verse 6, that...
A woman: Is it fast dubbing or you wanna test it? Yeah. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Problem. And I know some people who used the jinns,
and the jinns became their gods.
And on the Day of Judgment, God will ask some
of those jinns about that, and they will disown each other.
I know one person who calls the jinns in,
and the jinn say "I'm Ali Ibn Abi Taaleb."
And, and they will ask about these things, you know.
And the jinn will play around with them,
will give them information that they actually believe.
Dr. Khalifa: And that caused their destruction.
A man: Is that information correct or wrong?
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, it's wrong.
A man: Is there any jinn of Ali, for example?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's probably not the jinn of Ali, not
the companion of Ali. Because Ali died too long ago.
I haven't heard of a jinn that's 1400 years
old.
The jinns want to play around, they can say
anything they want they say.
If the person is crazy about Elvis Presley,
they will come and say "I'm Elvis." They'll even sing.
Just to fool the humans.
Dr. Khalifa: See, what can keep the kids quiet? What can we do to keep them quiet?
A man: Ok. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, I have a better idea of separating them.
Dr. Khalifa: Everybody call your kids next to you.
A woman: Hooman.
A man: Makan.
Dr. Khalifa: Let them sit next to you.
They can hear something useful sometimes.
Oh yeah, I've got my kid here.
Yes.
Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh, it's nice and quiet this way.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
159 says,
[37:159]  GOD be glorified; far above their claims.
[37:160]  Only GOD's servants who are devoted to Him alone (will be saved).
[37:161]  Indeed, you and what you worship.
[37:162]  Cannot impose anything on Him.
[37:163]  Everyone of you will burn in Hell.
All those people who blaspheme against God
and are misled by the jinns, etc., etc.
Those who are not devoted to God alone have
chosen, insisted on going to Hell.
The Angels
[37:164]  Each one of us has a specific job.
So, when you look at your kid and you say "Mã Shã Allãh", there's an angel specializing in protecting that kid.
When, Mã Shã Allãh invokes that protection.
There's a mechanism for everything.
When you get up in the morning and you say "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem. La Elaha Ella Allah",
this invokes an angel to stay with you all
day and see to it that you have a nice day.
165, the angels say,
[37:165]  We are the arrangers.
Organizers.
[37:166]  We have duly glorified (our Lord).
[37:167]  They used to say,
[37:168]  "Had we received the correct instructions from our parents,
[37:169]  "we would have been worshipers; devoted to GOD alone."
[37:170]  But they disbelieved. They will find out.
Victory for the Messengers Guaranteed
[37:171]  Our decision is already decreed for our servants the messengers.
[37:172]  They are surely the victors.
[37:173]  Our soldiers are the winners.
[37:174]  So disregard them for awhile.
[37:175]  Watch them; they too will watch.
[37:176]  Do they challenge our retribution?
[37:177]  When it hits, they will be sorry; they have been warned.
[37:178]  Disregard them for awhile.
[37:179]  Watch them; they too will watch.
[37:180]  Glory be to your Lord, the great Lord; far above their claims.
[37:181]  Peace be upon the messengers.
[37:182]  Praise be to GOD, Lord of the universe.
You notice the Quran is teaching us to make
no distinction among the messengers.
So God says,
[37:181]  Peace be upon the messengers.
The next Sura,
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[38:1]  S. (Saad),* and the Quran that contains the mathematical code.**
The message, or the miracle.
And strange, but we went through this today.
So, we looked at the references in which this
word is used, Zikr.
And it seems to point, among other things,
to the mathematical code of the Quran.
[38:2]  Those who disbelieve have plunged into arrogance and defiance.
[38:3]  Many a generation before them we annihilated. They called for help, but to no avail.
[38:4]  They wondered that a warner should come to them, from among them. The disbelievers said, "he's a magician; a liar.
[38:5]  "Did he make the gods into one god? ...
"Oh no."
"How strange."
[38:5]  ... This is really strange."
Because every messenger came with a message
"there is no god except the one God.
"You must forget about the saints, the prophets,
the messengers, as, as idols."
[38:5]  "Did he make the gods into one god? This is really strange."
[38:6]  The leaders announced, "Go and steadfastly persevere in worshiping your gods. This is all you need.
[38:7]  "We never heard of this from the religion of our fathers. This is a lie.
These are the things that we hear, exactly.
[38:7]  "We never heard of this from the religion of our fathers. ...
This is their problem.
And repeatedly the Quran says "follow God's revelation." They say "No, we follow what our parents taught us."
So, one needs to have an open mind and a free, freedom.
You can't follow the parents blindly.
There's too much at stake.
And this means perfect happiness here in this world, but terrible misery here in this world. Heaven and Hell begin right here.
And all we need to do is step into God's kingdom. Then, we are guaranteed perfect happiness.
You step into Satan's kingdom and you're
guaranteed perfect misery.
Even if you make millions and live in mansions. And...
What did Christina Onassis do with all her
billions?
She tried to commit suicide six times.
Finally, she succeeded and went to Heaven because she was really in, she was, her circumstances.
She was abused, oppressed, misguided, mistreated,
whatever.
God knows her circumstances.
She died at the age of 38.
But she was a very unhappy person.
How about her father, one of the richest men
in the world?
And all, all God did was nullify the muscles in his
eyelids.
I mean, these are the weakest muscles in our bodies.
He couldn't, he couldn't open his eyes.
He was willing to pay a hundred million dollars
to fix that.
He couldn't.
He had the scotch tape. He had to keep it completely open all
the time.
And this is suffering, you know, because it burns if you...
Imagine keeping your eyes open all the time.
Just try it for two minutes and see what happens.
You cannot do it.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a simple design that we take for granted, but God designed it to clean our eyes, wipe our eyes, and scratch our eyes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But it also moistens our eyes.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a continuous flow of liquid in there.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Are we going with you?
All right.
Yeah, go ahead.
Come, it's your problem.
Thank you, Edip.
173 says,
[37:173]  Our soldiers are the winners.
By the way.
The believers are guaranteed victory, guaranteed.
You know, every page of the Quran tells us
that God is controlling everything.
It just takes a believer to take advantage
of that and enjoy it.
There's a distinction going on between God's
kingdom and satan's kingdom.
God's kingdom is characterized by perfect
happiness, perfect health, perfect wealth, perfect peace of mind.
Satan's kingdom is characterized by misery
no matter what.
It is proven over and over again that money, power, all the things that people work hard for, do not guarantee happiness.
All these people who have attained everything, money, mansion, power, fame, good looks, the front page is telling us they're unhappy.
So, I think this principle is very well established,
that money, power, fame, good looks do not
guarantee happiness at all.
There's a statement in Quran that says
"all happiness is in God's hand."
All dignity, happiness is in God's hand. All of it.
And the same expression,
(4:139) فَإِنَّ ٱلْعِزَّةَ لِلَّهِ جَمِيعًا
Does this mean anything in Farsi?
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: All Ezzat (dignity) belongs in God's hand.
And God decreed, made a law that He will give
it only to the believers.
God controls everything with all He gives.
"The more you thank Me, the more I give you",
God says.
What does this mean?
The more we are appreciative, the more God
will give us.
If we turn unappreciative, we lose everything.
Just make a point of thanking God every chance
you get, for everything you have.
Dr. Khalifa: Excuse me. Then, God will give you more.
A woman: If we appreciate what God has given us, and
we praise that, but in the meanwhile, we say that
A woman: "thank you Lord, this is from You." Is this alright? Or we shouldn't (unintelligible) that?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
You have to thank God for whatever
He gave you.
Thank God for your health, for getting your
children.
How much would you pay to have (unintelligible)
next to you?
A million dollars, right?
I knew of times when you were willing to pay
a million dollars for this.
Dr. Khalifa: All it took was Sura Al-Hamd.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: God never turned us down.
A man: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: How's your back, Mehdi?
Mehdi: Much better. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: See? We read Al-Hamd, yes.
Mehdi: Alhamdu Lillah
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) let's, Behrooz has been carrying (unintelligible) for the last week.
He did it in Stockton and again in Tucson.
Dr. Khalifa: So, at the end of this session, IN SHAA ALLAH,
we'll read Al-Fãtehah for him (unintelligible), good as new.
Behrouz: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Just take the back pain and throw it away from
here.
Dr. Khalifa: IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, no worries, not disbelievers.
Dr. Khalifa: Plenty of them, don't worry.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Number 9 says,
[38:9]  Do they own the treasures of your Lord's mercy. He is the Almighty, the Grantor.
But number 8, we didn't read yet.
Because they question God's wisdom about choosing
His messengers.
Number 8,
[38:8]  "Why did the message come down to him, instead of us?" Indeed, they are doubtful of My message. Indeed, they have not yet tasted My retribution.
[38:9]  Do they own the treasures of your Lord's mercy. He is the Almighty, the Grantor.
[38:10]  Do they possess the kingship of the heavens and the earth, and everything between them? Let them promote themselves.
[38:11]  Instead, whatever forces they can muster—even if all their parties banded together—will be defeated.
Look what's happening to communism.
God gave them 40 years of communism to clean
out the trinity, and then he let them do it.
Perfect plan.
Open up.
Wake up, Barbara.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, I believe you.
A man: What do you mean 40 years of communism?
Dr. Khalifa: How many years has East Europe been communist?
A man: Since...
Dr. Khalifa: Since 1945?
A man: (unintelligible) 44.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, 44, yeah.
A man: But I mean, East Europe, the Soviet Union
has been communist since 1936.
Dr. Khalifa: So, it's beginning now in the Soviet Union to break
up. Did you hear?
A man: Yeah, but the ideology does not break up.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: It's just that they are set up with the old
guys.
A man: They want to do away with the old guys.
Dr. Khalifa: And communism. Did you see the Romanian flag?
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah? What does it look like now?
A man: Who is now the chief of Czech?
Dr. Khalifa: He was an opponent of Ceaușescu.
A man: Is he communist?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, not for long, but communism is out.
Dr. Khalifa: Would you say communism succeeded?
A man: They are still in power.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
A man: For, for humans, with human standards, for what political purposes. They are still in power. They still control
secret services. They still control the army. They still control the media.
And they control... Because the people in the streets are socialists.
A man: They want socialism to work. They are disbelievers.
Dr. Khalifa: I see.
A man: And they want socialism to work.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we have to conclude that communism is a
success, a great success.
A man: The people are still supporting socialism.
A man: The people (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm agreeing with you.
Number 11,
[38:11]  Instead, whatever forces they can muster— ... —will be defeated.
Number 12,
[38:12]  Disbelieving before them were the people of Noah, 'Ãd, and the mighty Pharaoh.
[38:13]  Also, Thamûd, the people of Lot, the dwellers of the Woods (of Midyan); those were the parties.
[38:14] Each of them disbelieved the messengers and thus, My retribution was inevitable.
[38:15]  These people can expect a single blow, from which they will never recover.
[38:16]  They challenged: ...
"These people", I understand to be the Arabs.
And "one blow" I understand to be an asteroid
from space. IN SHAA ALLAH.
Number 16,
[38:16]  They challenged: "Our Lord, why do you not rush the retribution for us, before the Day of Reckoning."
They challenged God.
This is it. We usually read two pages.
Dr. Khalifa: We'll leave the floor open for questions and
discussion.
A man: What is this "the dwellers of the Woods"?
Dr. Khalifa: Midyan. Midyan.
This is another name for Midyan,
which is now Gaza, Gaza Strip.
Dr. Khalifa: That's what Midyan is.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No. People of the Woods.
A man: (unintelligible) woods.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: What is... Khashab. You have Khashab in Farsi?
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Khashab. Wood. What is wood?
A woman: Miz (table).
A woman: Choob (wood).
A woman: Khashab.
A man: Choob (wood).
A kid: Khashab. Khashab.
Dr. Khalifa: He knows it.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, folks. There's a new word in the Farsi language. The new generation know it.
Dr. Khalifa: Choob?
A man: Choob.
Dr. Khalifa: Choob.
Dr. Khalifa: So, it'll be the people of the Choob.
A man: People of the Choob for Woods.
A man: But the Woods here means the jungle, the forest.
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily, no.
A man: What did they do with it? They worked with wood? They were wood works-man?
A man: Carpenters?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Carpenters.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Najjar (Carpenter).
Dr. Khalifa: They did a lot of carpenting.
A man (Speaking Farsi): Najjar (Carpenter).
A man: They did carpenting?
Dr. Khalifa (Speaking Arabic): Najjar (Carpenter).
A man: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't call them Najjar. Whatever the Arabic says.
The people of the woods.
(38:13) أَصْحَٰبُ لْـَٔيْكَةِ
A man:
(38:13) لْـَٔيْكَةِ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: We don't have to put our own interpretation. Go ahead.
A man: It's funny when you say they get hit by a big meteor.
When I was in Tunisia, I was young, I was (unintelligible) the Saudis.
A man: So, they, they're the people that are closest to God.
Dr. Khalifa: They are the farthest now.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: Yes.
A man: Because of that time (unintelligible), you don't have to, to do
Ramadan.
A man: So, (unintelligible) they are the people that find out when is the best or the other.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
You see, having this message creates a great
responsibility.
It's a great privilege and a great responsibility.
Of course, God says that the Jews, for example,
are His chosen people.
It's written in the Quran a few times.
So, why are they suffering so much?
Why did Hitler kill so many of them?
Why were they scattered all over the world? Persecuted and discriminated against.
Because of the responsibility. They received the Scripture and they didn't follow it.
Now, the Arabs received the Quran, which is a lot
more powerful.
It is the complete message.
Every page says "God alone."
And they abandoned it. And this is documented in the Quran in Sura
25.
They deserted the Quran.
So, you can imagine that their retribution would
be a lot worse.
Dr. Khalifa: And it's inevitable.
A man: God, God says in Quran that He's never destroyed
a land before bringing a messenger.
A man: Could you say that when the messenger comes
that the land will be destroyed?
Dr. Khalifa: So, that's fine.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Yes?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, you can say that. That is the same.
In Sura 17, God says "I will not send the
retribution before I send the messenger."
God made it a condition.
Dr. Khalifa: So, all these miracles that are showing up, and the message, and the messenger, mean that there is severe retribution coming to the disbelievers.
A man: "By land" means what? Means people who (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, there's no land.
A man: (unintelligible) Nation. Nation.
Dr. Khalifa: No, just, God left it blank. He said "we do not..."
Dr. Khalifa: "we do not..."
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Let's look at Sura 17.
You can see the expression...
Dr. Khalifa: I'm trying to find it. That's in quote.
A man: Yeah.
A woman: 15.
Dr. Khalifa: 15?
A man: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the end of 15,
It say,
[17:15]  ... We never punish without first sending a messenger.
Because the messenger points out, gives the stories to the people and then they have to make a decision, have to make a decision.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, they're responsible for it.
A woman: This punishing, it means (unintelligible) this life or...?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, this life, yeah. It's talking about this world.
A man: Rashad, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: What's the verse number?
A man: I think (unintelligible) 24.
Dr. Khalifa: I want you to read it.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead. So, everybody could hear you.
A man: 24. (unintelligible) page 454. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is an incident where David was in a sanctuary
and these two people went in, knocking.
Dr. Khalifa: But 99 sheep...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, they were fighting over one sheep.
Dr. Khalifa: But, actually, there's a great lesson here but
I wonder why, why did you pick this out.
A man: I've seen it before actually, once before.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't know what it is?
A man: No.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just two, two brothers, two brothers.
One had 99 sheep and the other had one sheep.
God wants to teach us a lesson about being
very careful when you judge between the people.
And this, the fellow, they went to David to judge between them.
The fellow with the one sheep said "I have one sheep and he has 99 sheep and he wants to take mine. And he insists on it."
So obviously, the one with the 99... David said "no, keep your sheep, don't give it to the fellow. He has 99 of them. You have only one.
"So, if you give him your sheep, you will have
none and he will have a hundred. Keep yours."
So, even though this judgment is very clearly
fair, David still thought maybe he, he did the unjust judgment.
And he repented and he was asking God for
forgiveness and everything.
You can imagine how careful... This is what made David, David.
David is very special in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: One of the preferred, by God, prophets.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right. But this is David's judgment.
Dr. Khalifa: He told the fellow with the one sheep "keep
your sheep, don't give it to him."
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, even though this is a very clear and an extreme
example of, of a good judgment,
he, he said "maybe, I did the wrong judgment."
And he was repenting and asking forgiveness and...
I mean, our, our presidents back home, they kill people.
They don't just say "keep your one sheep and
he keeps his 99."
Dr. Khalifa: They kill people, commit murder, and they
steal billions of dollars.
A man: Maybe he would have taken another 50 from
the other one and(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: But this is (unintelligible) a question of, I don't think, I don't think that he should actually give it to him as a gift.
A man: Because it was a question of mixing them to let them
eat together or mixing each other's properties.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, he wanted it. He wanted it, maybe he wanted to buy it.
A man: No, he wasn't.
Dr. Khalifa: That's okay, they wanted to mix, but he doesn't
want to.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The fellow with the one sheep didn't want to do it.
A man: Yeah, (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: That's not the, that's not the point.
A woman: (unintelligible) about God (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) judge them (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You got it.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A man: Yeah, of course, but (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he (unintelligible) it, yes, yes, this is...
Dr. Khalifa: And he waited. He, he, he waited and he studied and he did everything, and then he judged. Emily got it.
Dr. Khalifa: He was afraid of, he was, he was thinking of God. Did he do the right
judgment?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, of course.
Dr. Khalifa: What would you do?
A woman: I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: Well...
A woman: I'm not in that situation.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, you are now. Somebody came to you and he says "I have one sheep and my brother has 99 sheep.
Dr. Khalifa: "And he wants to take my one sheep." So, what would you do? Would you wanna tell him to give his sheep to the other guy?
A woman: He can give the brother the sheep, but if he
doesn't want money, if (unintelligible)
A woman: If the brother, you know, is willing to help his brother,
he can make a business (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: It's his job.
A woman: That's right.
A woman: In that case,...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: Rashad, I have a question. It is my understanding that (unintelligible) about Sura 15, Ayat 91.
I think, yeah, because of the, when we start from the 7 pairs, Ok,
And I think it couldn't be the time of Muhammad,
but I wanted to know that is it the time of Muhammad,
Parivash: and, and you, but my understanding is it could be.
Dr. Khalifa: Seven pairs have to do with the end of the
world.
Parivash: Okay. No, but after that it says,
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Dr. Khalifa: [15:88]  Do not be jealous of what... other...
Parivash: Okay. And after,
[15:89]  And proclaim: "I am the manifest warner."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: For (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: ... a while but then, at the, at the crucial time, the
jinn says "bye."
Dr. Khalifa: You are.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: To become a good one.
You're converting him right now by reading
the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: When you read the Quran and think about it, our jinn is also reading the Quran at the same time and thinking about it.
A man: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: And your jinn will tell you "don't, don't Pray, don't
believe this.
"Why go through all the trouble?"
This is, this is his job.
And you tell him "no, I'm gonna Pray five
times a day because I want to be happy all my life.
"I'm going to follow this because this guarantees
me victory and happiness."
And he tells you "oh, forget it, this is all
nonsense."
Dr. Khalifa: So, you continue to debate like this until
you convert him, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: Then, what happens after that?
Dr. Khalifa: Then, you become friends. You become identical.
A man: So exactly, my question was this, though.
A man: When I'm here, because there's too much power
and energy, I believe everything, but I'm going out.
Of course, I'm not sure (unintelligible) myself.
I'm going by example.
A man: On the outside, the jinn is going to whisper
to me.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the jinn will whisper to you.
A man: So, if I'm a believer, OK,
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: There's a challenge between me and the jinn.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: Especially early morning when I'm tired.
A man: "Let me sleep, OK?"
Dr. Khalifa: The jinn is telling you to sleep.
A man: Yeah
A man: So it's still (unintelligible) my question is...
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is all of us.
Dr. Khalifa: Our jinn is always telling us to, like to, not to worship
God alone.
A man: So, do you mean all the time, as long as I'm alive,
I have a challenge between me and the jinn?
Dr. Khalifa: No. No.
Dr. Khalifa: There'll be a time when, like Karim said,
there'll be a time when he's completely converted.
As a matter of fact, he can be ahead of you.
Dr. Khalifa: Tomorrow, you're gonna be here for the
Khutba, Friday prayer?
A man: Me?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: So, you're gonna hear an example of a jinn
that is cooperating with you.
A woman: When our jinn is in real motion, then after that, is that possible that our jinn guide us? I mean...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Sometimes the jinn will be ahead of you.
And the Quran, we were reading yesterday, or
the day before yesterday, how God matches
your companion, matches the companion of the
jinn, and the human companions are matched.
So, if you're destined to believe, God matches
a believing jinn with you, who's also destined to believe.
A person who's destined to disbelieve, God
will match a disbelieving companion.
Dr. Khalifa: Which makes sense.
A man: Rashad, what about astrology? Is there any kind of little jinns in that?
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is simply observations.
They notice that if the sun is in the zodiac,
and another zodiac, this and that, something happens on earth.
They notice that the people who are born under
a certain sign have certain characteristics, so they made notes.
And they compile them and computerize them.
Then, if you tell me that you're a Libra, I
can tell you what your characteristics are.
You're most susceptible to colds and things
like that.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, it's just observations, it's a compilation,
but it's very, it has a long way to go.
A woman: Rashad, I have a question, can I ask you jinns and ghosts are the same?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Jinns, we cannot see the jinns, but I guess some manifestations of the jinns, people will think they are ghosts.
A woman: Because if the jinns are the students of Satan,
and they in their first life they say, they totally agreed with...
Dr. Khalifa: Satan
A woman: Satan
A woman: how's the difference between
human and a jinn in the sense that they're saying they don't know?
Dr. Khalifa: God gives the jinns a longer life, and more
ability to fly in the universe and study God's signs.
But the humans, they are given 7:172.
Dr. Khalifa: Read it. Read 7:172 again.
A man: Rashad, jinns have that much ability to go to other universe because they have to be more clear than the people?
Dr. Khalifa: No, because they already made up their mind
very strongly that Satan is right.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, here God, God is the children of Adam, not the
children of Satan, not the jinns.
A man: Exactly, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: Difference, difference (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Not really, no, it's just that, that there's a different
allegorical Heaven for them.
Because...
How do I...
Let us say, compare you with a tree.
You and a tree.
Think of yourself as two creatures.
And I'm saying, gonna put you and the tree, I'm
gonna put you both in Heaven, I'm gonna give you steak,
I'm gonna give you potatoes,
and rice, and fruit.
Do you think the tree will go for that?
Dr. Khalifa: Do you understand what I said?
A woman: Yes, oh yeah, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, you are a creature and the tree is a creature.
Dr. Khalifa: And I'm telling you, I'm gonna put you
both in Heaven, where you can eat steak every day.
A woman: Then, no.
Dr. Khalifa: No what?
A woman: Because the tree doesn't like the steak.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the humans and the jinns are two different
creatures.
And God is telling us "I'm going put you
in gardens with grapes and pomegranates and fruit."
The jinns don't, the jinns don't care about that.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God is telling them that you're gonna
have your own Heaven which is with different things.
A woman: But actually it's going to be the same.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, actually it's gonna be the same Heaven.
Are they (unintelligible) souls the same as ours?
Dr. Khalifa: Um-hum. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh. She likes it first.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it just fixed.
Dr. Khalifa: They're creatures.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, it's my sleeping time, brothers and sisters, so I'm gonna retire and see you in the morning, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Audience: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: I got up at what time?
A man: This morning?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: 4.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, it was 1 o'clock.
A woman: Are you working?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Well, I left home at 1, so I got here about
20 after 1.
This is why people laugh at me when I say it's
my sleeping time.
Dr. Khalifa: It's chicken sleeping time.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: Sura Tawbah.
Dr. Khalifa: 50.
[9:50]  If something good happens to you, they hurt, and if an affliction befalls you, they say, "We told you so," as they turn away rejoicing.
These are all descriptions of the hypocrites.
[9:51]  Say, "Nothing happens ...
Dr. Khalifa: ... whether we're
submitters or objectors.
So God is telling us in 51,
[9:51]  Say, "Nothing happens to us, except what GOD has decreed for us. ...
And we have to accept it or object to it.
A submitter accepts whatever happens cheerfully.
Underline cheerfully, 19 lines, under cheerfully.
[9:51]  ... In GOD the believers shall trust."
In other words, if you're a believer, you
must trust that God will take care of you. God guarantees it for you.
And if something appears to be bad, you must
know there's some good reason for it.
[9:52]  Say, "You can only expect for us one of two good things in war (victory or martyrdom), while we expect for you condemnation from GOD and retribution from Him, or at our hands. Therefore, wait, and we will wait along with you."
[9:53]  Say, "Spend, willingly or unwillingly. Nothing will be accepted from you, for you are evil people."
Rejectors of God's messenger observed the
Salat prayers.
[9:54]  What prevented the acceptance of their spending is that they disbelieved in GOD and His messenger, and when they observed the Contact Prayers (Salat),* they observed them lazily, and when they gave to charity, they did so grudgingly.
This is an important verse you should remember,
it's 9:54, remember it.
When the people tell you that they think that
Salat began with Muhammad.
They think there was no Salat before the prophet
Muhammad.
You tell them, remind them of this
verse.
These are people who rejected the prophet, they disbelieved in God, but they were doing the five Contact Prayers. The word Salat is very specific.
Because Salat existed before the prophet.
Dr. Khalifa: Just at the time, they had been, they had been corrupted
by idol worship.
A man: You're saying that today (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, exactly, same thing today.
Dr. Khalifa: 9:54, this is another proof that the Contact
Prayers (Salat) existed before the Quran.
Mahmoud: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, this is a good point because this, this verse was revealed probably less than a year before the prophet's death,
and this is my chance to give Parivash a public apology.
In Sura... because I misunderstood her question yesterday.
She was saying that the verses at the end of Sura 15 about people who accept the Quran partially, could not possibly be
applicable to the time of the prophet, because the Quran itself
was, was being revealed, it was not in existence
really.
Even when the prophet died, they left the
Quran in the chronological sequence,
with instructions on the side, it was, it was not organized
at all into a Quran. Now, we have the Quran.
This is the Quran, the format that God wants,
and it did not exist until 20 years after the prophet's death,
Dr. Khalifa: they tried to put it together.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Look at those people, they are not believers,
but they are happy and rich, and this and that.
But they are not happy, you have to take that
word out.
Because God says He would cause the money
and the children to be the source of misery for them.
Then after all this misery, they leave the
world as disbelievers.
[9:56]  They swear by GOD that they belong with you, while they do not belong with you; they are divisive people.
They will create division, they will create confusion, because the statements that come out of their mouths is that of disbelief.
[9:57]  If they could find any refuge, or caves, or a hiding place, they would go to it, rushing.
[9:58]  Some of them criticize your distribution of the charities; if they are given therefrom, they become satisfied, but if they are not given therefrom, they become objectors.
[9:59]  They should be satisfied with what GOD and His messenger have given them. They should have said, "GOD suffices us. GOD will provide for us from His bounties, through His messenger. We are seeking only GOD."
And here is the distribution system for charities
other than Zakat.
It also applies to Zakat.
[9:60]  Charities shall go to the poor, ...
So in Zakat, it says your parents first.
They have to be poor.
If they are, they are not poor, then you go to the next
line, which is relatives: cousins, aunts, nephews, nieces, uncles.
[9:60]  Charities shall go to the poor, the needy, the workers who collect them, the new converts, to free the slaves, to those burdened by sudden expenses, in the cause of GOD, and to the traveling alien. Such is GOD's commandment. GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
[9:61]  Some of them hurt the prophet by saying, "He is all ears!" Say, "It is better for you that he listens to you. He believes in GOD, and trusts the believers. He is a mercy for those among you who believe." Those who hurt GOD's messenger have incurred a painful retribution.
[9:62]  They swear by GOD to you, to please you, when GOD and His messenger are more worthy of pleasing, if they are really believers.
Retribution for Opposing God and His Messenger
[9:63]  Did they not know that anyone who opposes GOD and His messenger has incurred the fire of Hell forever? This is the worst humiliation.
[9:64]  The hypocrites worry that a sura may be revealed exposing what is inside their hearts. Say, "Go ahead and mock. GOD will bring out what you are worried about."
[9:65]  If you ask them, they would say, "We were only joking and playing." Say, "Do you realize that you are mocking GOD, and His revelations, and His messenger?"
[9:66]  Do not apologize. You have disbelieved after having believed. If we pardon some of you, we will punish others among you, as a consequence of their transgressions.
[9:67]  The hypocrite men and the hypocrite women belong with each other—they advocate evil and prohibit righteousness, and they are stingy. They forgot GOD, so He forgot them. The hypocrites are truly wicked.
[9:68]  GOD promises the hypocrite men and the hypocrite women, as well as the disbelievers, the fire of Hell. They abide therein forever. It suffices them. GOD has condemned them; they have incurred an unending retribution.
So, here we read four pages, most of them about
the hypocrites, because they sit, sit with us, and they...
we look on them as believers, and then
they talk to some of us, and people listen to them.
And what, what comes out will cause doubt in the
hearts of, in the hearts of the believers.
But God reserves the lowest pit of Hell for
them, because, because of this.
Because they look like believers, act like believers,
so we have to be, we have to be aware as we grow.
Dr. Khalifa: Just because we're all here in the same room doesn't mean... you have to be careful to what you listen. This is a test for all of us.
A woman: Because they are more dangerous than you think.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: They could be very, very loving, friendly
people, and, you know, they're with us, and...
Dr. Khalifa: Then, they, they stab you.
A woman: Because they...
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, in fact, we have, we have many examples of this.
People that have been with us and very strong, who became very close and very friendly, but now we know they are not believers.
Well, because things are happening progressively,
and there's a drop-out point for some people.
So even though they believed, when the messengership point came, for example, they, they couldn't take it.
But they continue to come with us and come
to the meeting.
Dr. Khalifa: You know a few of those.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, we'll have five minutes of discussion.
A man: And then charity starts with the immediate relative (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, charity is something that's on the spot.
Earthquake comes and destroys San Francisco, and
the people on the street hungry, and
Dr. Khalifa: you don't even know their names, you help them.
A man: That's what is unlimited?
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Because it's limited by your means, and by
not being too extravagant. Go ahead.
A woman: (unintelligible) If you have a, a cousin, or something like that's poor and, but very disbelieving, arrogant,
all that, and then there's an orphan, that
is, you know, believing, and needs it even more,
A woman: you still give it to the cousin, (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, give the Zakat to the relative first. Unless, unless he's fighting you.
If he's just disbelieving, he hasn't made
a decision, he doesn't know, but he's not fighting you actively,
then you have to give
the Zakat to the relative first.
For God's sake, yes.
Because your cousin, who's not fighting you, maybe next week he'll read the Quran, discover God, and become better than you and me, right?
And maybe, when you help him, this will cause
him to believe.
Says "Wow, this is a good system! Those believers are charitable."
Dr. Khalifa: So, God tells us to consider them potential
believers.
A man: Charity begins at home.
Dr. Khalifa: That's it.
A man: Rashad, the people, like, I think everybody is
going to get the message
Dr. Khalifa: IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH
A man: But, what is our duty according to, like,
that we know the person who gets the message and he refuses,
and that we didn't give it to
him, that, you know, he gets it from somebody else,
A man: there's still our duty to go again,
or to (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Did he get the message from another source?
A man: Yes, from another believer, but they, they refused.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I see.
Well, if the circumstances come up, we're supposed to give the message anyway. When the circumstances come up.
God will create the circumstances for us to
deliver the message.
But we must strive, we need to strive.
We need to do something.
You know, as it is, the majority of people believe in God alone, worship the Quran alone, worship God alone, and that's it.
They're believers, and they're good.
They're going to Heaven.
But they are not the same as people who strive
for just (unintelligible).
Hey, look who's here.
The Turners are here.
Come on in, come on in.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
A woman: Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: You left Omnia home.
‘Alaykum Al-Salãm
Dr. Khalifa: She's asleep here in Tucson?
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, OK. I know how it is.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
Parivash: Rashad, I have a question. If, for example, my sister asked me to give her a...
Dr. Khalifa: Loan.
Parivash: OK, and she's very believer, and I trust her.
Parivash: (unintelligible) I commit sin if I don't have it...
Behrouz: written down.
Parivash: Yes. But God says
Dr. Khalifa: written down?
Parivash: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: If, if, if in your mind you don't, you don't care if she keeps
the money, and you never get it back, then it's OK.
Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: But if you want it to, to be repaid, God tells us to write it down, so you don't forget how much you gave her, and she doesn't forget how much she borrowed.
A woman: But if she doesn't care?
Dr. Khalifa: But if you don't care, if she ever pays it,
then it's OK.
A woman: I understand. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: This, this you write it down if you expect it to
be paid back.
Because I'm telling you, you'll forget.
Dr. Khalifa: You may give her $500, and then after a month,
you'll be absolutely positive that you gave her $1,000.
A woman: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes Satan will see to it.
A woman: And the person who gives the loan (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: What, the person who's giving the loan is in control.
So, it is, the person, right.
But the person who's taking the loan is the one who dictates the terms, who writes down, writes down the receipt.
I received $500 from Roxana, and I promise to pay it at $50 a month starting in February, and finish the payment at a certain date.
So, this is, God gives us the details of what
to write.
Because it'll be written in the hand of
the borrower.
And then, you have two witnesses.
This way, there'll be no confusion at all. Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, this was, came down at an age where
there were no accountants.
A man: This 9:58 that
[9:58]  Some of them criticize your distribution of the charities; ...
But when they receive their share they become
satisfied.
At least, we have seen three different (unintelligible), people who object to the taxes.
A man: But then, they try to get out as much as possible
from the public sector. So, the taxes just go up and up.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this is true in all countries, it seems, here also.
No, but this is a specific situation talking about the
community of believers.
And we've seen it also within the community
of believers.
We are living the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what was your first question, Naima?
Naima: (unintelligible)
Naima: How much you (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: As much as you can.
We're talking about believers who believe
in God, the Hereafter, follow the Quran alone, and worship God alone.
But that's the extent of it.
Dr. Khalifa: They're good people, they're going to Heaven, but they're not at the same rank, as far as God is concerned, like the people who, who strive.
A woman: But when they start to be, like, angry, this one,
too.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Yeah, right. You have to see your own circumstances and
how it is working.
But God says,
(4:95) لَّا يَسْتَوِى ... ٱلْمُجَٰهِدُونَ ... بِأَمْوَٰلِهِمْ وَأَنفُسِهِمْ ... ٱلْقَٰعِدِينَ
(4:95) فَضَّلَ ٱللَّهُ ٱلْمُجَٰهِدِينَ بِأَمْوَٰلِهِمْ وَأَنفُسِهِمْ عَلَى ٱلْقَٰعِدِينَ دَرَجَةً
God raises the strivers.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I don't, I don't push, I let it, this comes from
the people themselves.
A woman: I just have to really question you.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, you wanna see to it that the message
is delivered in the best possible and the most effective manner.
This all depends on the circumstances. Again,
(16:125) ٱدْعُ إِلَىٰ سَبِيلِ رَبِّكَ بِٱلْحِكْمَةِ وَٱلْمَوْعِظَةِ ٱلْحَسَنَةِ
Invite to the path of God with wisdom and
great diplomacy.
You're gonna do it so you don't chase them
away and you don't... keep the door open.
Dr. Khalifa: If they are not going to believe now, you
keep the door open for them.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, you're right, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: Was it good?
A woman: Very good.
Dr. Khalifa: Good. Alhamdu Lillah.
A man: Rashad
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: When you give the message for quite a while (unintelligible)
in different ways, and they always fight, that is normal, you can learn.
A man: When they ask you (unintelligible) or ask you something,
you tell them, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Forget it. Yeah.
A man: It has happened to a gentleman, I gave message to
him and I told him all the documentation (unintelligible) and he
A man: he replied to me.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: And he asked me to (unintelligible) him to (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Nope.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Very good.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But there is a point of where God asked us to
give up on them for good.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a question in Sura 13, it says "is it not time for the believers to give up on the disbelievers and realize that God guides
whomever He wills?"
A woman: That sounds cool.
Dr. Khalifa: Usually they catch it like that, Rajul, don't
they?
If somebody is gonna believe, they catch
it, they see it.
You can tell if they are blind and deaf or
if there is a, this concrete wall around them
or if they're wide open to the message.
I don't know, I think it's been rare to see somebody who is completely blocked and then all of a sudden they, they could see.
Well, Lisa and Susan, go to work.
You can go through this door.
I think Parivash finished cooking, so you
can have some breakfast.
Dr. Khalifa: You wanna go help them?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Susan wants to come and have breakfast with (unintelligible)
You're gonna bring the tape now?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm not, I know. When? When?
A woman: Right now.
Dr. Khalifa: Now? Yeah? A good time. It's a good time. Okay, wait, stay, stay where you are, stay. Just one minute.
Dr. Khalifa: Lisa and Susan have to go to work soon, so
just wait, wait a minute.
A woman: And maybe (unintelligible)
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Hurry up. Hurry up.
Dr. Khalifa: Is that the same tape?
A man: Yeah, it is.
Dr. Khalifa: You're recording it over and over.
A man: No, no (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
God ALONE
Verse 11 says,
[39:11]  Say, "I have been commanded to worship GOD, devoting the religion absolutely to Him alone.
[39:12]  "And I was commanded to be the utmost submitter."
[39:13]  Say, "I fear, if I disobeyed my Lord, the retribution of a great day."
[39:14]  Say, "GOD is the only One I worship, devoting my religion absolutely to Him alone.
These are all commandments from God to you.
I'm gonna read them again, starting at
11.
God is telling you to say,
Dr. Khalifa: [39:11]  ... "I have been commanded to worship GOD, devoting the religion absolutely to Him alone.
A woman: Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there is no room for Jesus, or Moses, or
Muhammad, or the saints.
A woman: Even Muhammad?
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: [39:12]  "And I was commanded to be the utmost submitter."
The utmost submitter never complains.
That's a sign of submitter or not.
The utmost submitter is content with whatever
God gives us, and understands.
[39:13]  Say, "I fear, if I disobeyed my Lord, the retribution of a great day."
Submitters also realize that everything has
a price.
And this is now after passing all the tests,
and you've passed your final test, you're in good shape,
then you cannot deviate outside
the path that God drew for you.
Because if you deviate, it's very expensive.
It seems out of proportion, but really it
is not.
You know, when I, when I got pinched in the past, I'd say "wow,
this is too much! I didn't do that bad!"
And the answer would come back "yes, this is it. You didn't do too bad, but this is the price for it." Yeah.
The pinch is always way out of proportion,
it seems.
I guess because, you know we, somehow we grew up with the
notion that God is forgiving, Merciful, which is true, but we tend to abuse this.
(unintelligible)
God wants to make you perfect.
And the system that I have noticed personally, and maybe you too, is that God will take one of your defects at a time.
And He will keep after you until you get rid
of that defect.
Then, He will start another one, until
you cleanse out of that one.
The end result is a perfect human being, if
there is such a thing.
You'll be following God's commandments perfectly. And you'll be a perfect human being.
So, the utmost submitter understands all these
things.
Remember that the utmost submitter has a perfect
life.
The only reason you have a headache is because
of something you have done.
I don't think there are any exceptions to
that, there are no exceptions.
You don't get a scratch or a headache without something you have done. So, it behooves you to find out what it is that you have done.
Don't defend yourself either.
I used to laugh when I tell some people "what
did you do wrong?"
They say "I didn't do anything wrong", you know,
they become on the defensive.
I say "hey, wait a minute, you're supposed to join me and, in attacking your "self" and find out what you did wrong. You become very defensive."
But we're supposed to do this ourselves, we
have to find out what did I do wrong.
But if I, if I'm too egotistic to pinpoint what
I did wrong, then I just go on,
because the punishment will continue until you, you know what
it is.
When you know what it is and you repent, it
never happens again.
The problem is solved.
So, an utmost submitter means no problems of
any kind.
It's almost unbelievable.
But you see, God taught us repeatedly.
God used me as a guinea pig, a happy guinea pig.
I mean, I put myself, myself in situations where a
problem should have, should have happened.
But it wasn't because of God, so a problem
didn't happen.
And the reason I'm saying this is because
Ihsan is sitting here, and she expected a big problem.
Thank you.
I had, I was busy with this translation, and I slept
here three nights in a row. I didn't go home for three days.
And then, the answering machine, the telephone
rang, the answering machine came on, my wife was on the phone.
This is Stephanie. So, Ihsan started to run away.
She said "this is it. She's gonna divorce
you, you're finished."
"This is it, a big fight."
So, as she was approaching this door here to
run away,
she heard us say "I made a batch of Italian cookies, they were so delicious, I'm sorry we finished all of them, so I'm gonna make you another batch."
She couldn't believe it, until now she can't
believe it.
But this is, God manipulates the minds and
the hearts of the people.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, this happened again when, three or
four weeks ago.
A woman: A few days ago.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? A few days ago, when this visit, I slept here
two nights in a row.
Dr. Khalifa: And she called, what did she say this time?
A woman: "I want to chat. I wanted to chat with you." I said "Oh, oh."
Dr. Khalifa: What did she want?
A woman: "I want to chat with you." So, I ran from the kitchen.
Dr. Khalifa: No, say it again. What did...
A woman: Chat
A woman: Chat.
Dr. Khalifa: "I want to chat." I forget what she wanted, but it was peaceful. She was also running away.
A woman: No, we were talking about (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh yes, yes, yes. She said "I'm the happiest person in the world." I said "what?"
Now, now, I, I was insulted.
"Hey, wait a minute."
Honest, this is what she said, yes, I remember
now.
She said "I'm the happiest person in the world." I said "what happened?"
She said "I found the car I've been looking
for, for a long time."
"I'm like a baby, I'm like a child who found
a toy."
This is exactly what she said.
Dr. Khalifa: She's been looking for a car.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I mean, this is a situation that warrants
a problem, right, with most people.
"Where have you been?"
"You're a half hour late."
"If you left your office at 2:30, you should
have been here at 3 o'clock. It's 4 o'clock now."
So, what I'm saying is that God, God's Mercy and
Grace allowed us to learn from experience.
We really have a track record, and it is, it is... Edip is not comfortable with my statements.
Because he has to go through what I went through.
When I make a blanket statement, "a believer
has a perfect life. No problems, no headache, no traffic tickets."
He says, he always tells me "what if we grow and we have a lot
of people and problems happen?"
They don't happen, God can handle them.
God's law is absolute.
Let me just read it with you again, because
I wanted to pass this on to the people.
Let's look at 10:62 or 11:62, what is it?
Page 216.
I think Edip will appreciate that because the
Arabic is so powerful and he knows it, he knows the Arabic.
The top of page 216, it says,
[10:62]  Absolutely, GOD's allies have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
In Arabic,
(10:62) أَلَآ إِنَّ أَوْلِيَآءَ ٱللَّهِ لَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
Very strong Arabic. It says,
[10:62]  Absolutely, ...
I tried to bring it in
the English as close as possible.
[10:62]  ... GOD's allies have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
The next verse identifies who are they.
[10:63]  They are those who believe and lead a righteous life.
That's it.
If you believe and lead a righteous life,
you have nothing to fear, nor will you grieve.
Dr. Khalifa: Why are you, why are you peeking through the, peeking through the crack? Come on in.
A woman: Is it Ok?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay of what?
A woman: (unintelligible) and I wanted to come by to Pray.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
Dr. Khalifa: That's fantastic.
A man: Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: Number 64 says,
[10:64]  For them, joy in this world, ...
We don't have to die first before we enjoy
Heaven. It happens here.
[10:64]  For them, joy in this world and the Hereafter. This is GOD's unchangeable decree. Such is the greatest triumph.
So, this is it.
God's law.
You have to, you have to realize that there is an admission
test.
And the admission test is very exacting.
It's very exacting.
It's usually in the first five years after
you claim that you've come to worship God alone.
It doesn't mean it will last five years. Don't be scared.
It comes within...
If you're proven to be a total submitter completely
in the first month, then it is over.
But you must realize it happens, and all the
while you're in God's hand.
The test is very tough.
Where is Mahmoud?
Did he leave?
Yeah, he's going to take his carburetor.
Mahmoud is doing, undergoing a test like this. He temporarily lost his wife, his kid, his cars, his computer.
And he's very cheerful, as you see. It's all temporary.
Everything will be restored and twice as much. He knows that.
He's a good believer. And we know that.
But what I wanna say is that when you have a problem, you understand. You must understand the root of the problem. What is it?
Why am I having this problem? So, if you're not in the admission test, then you did something wrong.
The admission test, simply you say that
you're gonna worship God alone, and Satan says otherwise.
He says "No, Behrouz doesn't mean it. He's just, he's just saying that."
And God tells him "OK, you can go and beat
him up, but within a limit. You cannot do this and this to him."
So, Satan starts on Behrouz, beats him up,
gives him backache, a few other problems.
But it doesn't fears Behrouz. He continues to worship God alone.
Then, he's proven to be worshiping God alone. Then, all the blessings open up.
Dr. Khalifa: Just, just watch.
A woman: I also got this cold and fever.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
A woman: I also have a cold and fever and (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You have cold and fever now?
A woman: Yeah, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, well, this is part of the fun of traveling, you know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: The only thing wrong I can think of that you
did may be feeling sympathy
for the people who, out of ignorance, were idolizing Muhammad
and Ibrahim and so on.
Dr. Khalifa: which is...
A woman: I just feel that they (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, their judgment is in God's hand. But I don't think...
I think your cold and fever will go away as
soon as you, you're convinced that that was wrong to do that.
Just a little pinch, a reminder from God
to us to make everything right.
But this is a common, by the way, this is a common thing that I went through and everybody goes through
that we feel for our grandparents and so on. They were, they were all nice people. We loved them very much.
Dr. Khalifa: And our wishful thinking tells us maybe they
didn't know or their intention were good and so on.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but no, but see, they had the Quran. They have the message there.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, Lisa, you better get going.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but you see, if they, if they deserved better,
God would have, would have seen to it that they received the correction.
A woman: Because exactly this like my father would say like (unintelligible) in this world.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: and enjoying life
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: And he was one in such that, you know, he
talks about (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: This, yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but this is fine, but you cannot generalize
it to the population.
A woman: No, no, not everybody. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: If you know a person personally and you see
very well that he is worthy of Heaven, he probably did go to Heaven.
Probably God understood his situation.
I'm sure, not probably, I'm sure God understood
his situation.
But we cannot generalize this and we cannot
sympathize with that for our own good.
Because if I say "maybe, these people have good
intentions" and we defend them, Satan will capitalize on that.
He says "see, he or she is defending the idol
worshippers."
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the case of the first covenant. I'm glad you, I'm glad you knew that. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This is a good example, actually. And that 99.9% this is exactly the connection.
A woman: Yes. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And it's wonderful to know that, because you'll
probably never again question the wisdom of Quran.
A woman: I didn't mean to, but the way I sounded, I probably...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly. It is the way it sounds.
See, Mrs. Amirali was perfectly innocent when
she was talking about those past generations,
but Satan will take that innocent statement
and will make a big mountain out of it.
He will actually say "she, she is defending the
idol worshippers."
Dr. Khalifa: And there is a law in the Quran that says "you do not befriend idol worshippers, even if they were your parents, your... and so on."
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Remember, he is a liar. Satan is a liar.
And if we're not, if we don't word our statements carefully,
especially when we're touching on the issue of idol worship,
he will take that and will
capitalize.
If I say the slightest thing in defense, away
from God, this is why I don't compromise.
When they ask me about white lies and little
insurance and things, I don't compromise.
Because if I say anything that is a little,
just slightly away from God's law, Satan will capitalize on it.
And says "see, he doesn't follow Your law."
Then, I'll get smashed on the head.
Because God invariably calls Satan's excuses. Then, He says "Yeah, okay, go test him."
Because God puts limits on him.
When He sends him to test you, He puts limits on you. He says "you can give her a cold and fever, but that's about it.
"You cannot give her a headache", for example.
We need to understand this mechanism.
We believe in God. God told us there is Satan.
And we need to understand what does Satan
do.
We read the other day, some of you were here,
some were not,
that Satan will come from your right, your left, from your right, right,
left, front and back.
He will come to you from every direction.
And he will, he will exactly catch those sentences
that, that may be
misunderstood to mean that you're defending the idol worshippers or deviating from God's law.
And he'll say "this person..." he will lie.
But he will use your words.
So, we don't wanna give him a chance to do
that.
Like Roxana said, she didn't mean to question
God's wisdom. She was just discussing the thing intellectually.
But it sounded like, if I didn't know her, I would think she was questioning God's wisdom "Why didn't God prohibit first cousins?"
"Why are the Christians wiser than God", for
example, in prohibiting first cousins marriages?
Satan will do that.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan will say "Roxana means that You're
not wise, as wise as the Christians."
Roxana: I think, I think it takes a while before we realize that every letter of the Quran has to be followed, otherwise we make mistakes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly. It takes a while. Yes.
It takes some while. Where is Martha?
Martha.
No jumping, Hany. Sit down. Sit down. Don't jump.
Shut the door.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, are you there? Oh, you're Praying.
Martha: I'm Praying, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. I just wanna keep the kids under control,
because they're jumping now.
A woman: You're off. Thank you.
Dr. Khalifa: Mrs. Amir Ali is not supposed to have a headache
or cold or flu or anything like that.
I think also we have to realize the limitations
of our bodies, I guess.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I don't wanna compromise with that.
Behrouz: Well, my, my problem...
Dr. Khalifa: I just remembered... Hmm?
Behrouz: My back problem is (unintelligible) I knew that I'm not supposed to pick up everything.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Behrouz: But surprisingly, in four days, I didn't have
any pain.
Dr. Khalifa: That's part of the test. So, you took Mahdi's...
Behrouz: Yes, I (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You love him so much that you said "I'm gonna take you backache."
Behrouz: I don't, I don't know if he's gonna love me this
much.
Dr. Khalifa: Because it's his, his anniversary.
God will love you and will remove it.
God loves you and will remove it, IN SHAA ALLAH.
The reason I said, I stopped in the middle
of the sentence "we have to realize the limitations of our bodies."
I'm gonna say "Alhamdu Lillah, Mã Shã Allãh, Subhan Allah" and all these, because you can brag when you say that.
If you give God the credit, you can brag about it.
Brother Abdul Hayy was here, and he came and
looked at my computer, my chair.
And he said "you're supposed to have a terrible
backache."
Because I'm sitting at the computer, on average,
ten hours a day.
He said "this computer is too high or too
low, the chair is this and that."
He said "do you have back problems?" I said "no."
He said "you're supposed to."
But, so this is what I mean by even the body limitations,
God will heal you somehow.
You're in your admission test, so don't complain.
Dr. Khalifa: You're not complaining, Alhamdu Lillah.
A woman: Okay, so Satan, he takes the sentences that
you say, and he turns them as tools to get against you.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
A woman: Does he use the sentences that you say in
your mind that sometimes you think?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, he doesn't know what's in your mind.
A woman: (unintelligible) Only what you say orally?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan and even the angels do not know what's
in your mind.
A woman: Oh, Ok. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. But, but, there's a big but. God knows what's in your mind.
You see this is at the end of Sura 2.
Dr. Khalifa: God is the only One who knows what's in your
innermost thoughts.
A woman: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Not only He knows what's in your mind, He
knows what's in your mind ten years from now.
That's in Sura 20.
God knows, He knows what is more secret than
the secret.
So, what's more secret than the secret?
It's the future secret.
So, yeah, so Satan doesn't know your, your, what's in your
mind, but God does.
So, and God says "do not have anything wrong inside, inside
your mind."
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Feroz: When evil thoughts come into mind, then Satan
doesn't put them there.
Dr. Khalifa: Your companion does.
The jinn. Your companion is in there, and your companion
puts those thoughts, and it is your job
to sift through them, and if it's, in fact,
remember the verse that says "the believers, when a whisper from the devil comes to them, they seek refuge in God." Ok?
Your companion is your devil.
And it's your job to, to counter those bad thoughts.
Dr. Khalifa: He will, he will ask you to do all kinds of bad things to lie, cheat, lose your temper.
A child: Ok. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Does this mean Batool loses her temper? No. No, way. Don't look at her like that.
Are you telling me that Princess Batool loses
her temper? No.
Dr. Khalifa: With two kids like that?
A man: Your companion is not in touch with Satan?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: He is Satan. He represents Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: He already has his built-in natural instinct to tell you not to Pray, not to worship God alone, not to be honest, etc., etc. Already, that's his nature.
A man: So, Satan has no, is not in touch with him. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's his seed. That's his seed.
And it's inside your brain. So, this is, this is the only access he has to your brain.
Dr. Khalifa: But it's your job and my job to convert this
seed of Satan into a God-worshipping jinn.
A woman: So, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: See, he's reading the Quran now. As you're reading, she is reading the Quran now. Excuse me.
Yeah, as you read the Quran, she too is reading
the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa And she is thinking about it.
Edip: You convinced her and
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Now, you are together, you are reading the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: She tried her best to keep you from doing
this. But you won and you brought her...