Dr. Khalifa: For the benefit of the people outside of Tucson,
I'm gonna repeat that we seek refuge in God
from Satan. Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem. In the
name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful. We're
starting today on Sura 64. And, where is, where
is Lisa? She's over there.
(unintelligible)
Oh. See there. Just go around. Go around with us. See, they raised their hands. First, I wanna welcome Salim and his wife.
She's here for the first time, and he was here
last week. So, I'm glad you came. Thanks, Stephanie.
And also, I didn't get a chance to welcome
Philip's wife. She was here two or three times,
and I was wondering who she was. Finally, he
told me. So, welcome to the group. You notice
in the new translation, the word "GOD" is written in
bold, big letters. And at the bottom of the page,
on the left side, you see the number 9? This
is the number of occurrences of the word "God" on
this page. If you count them easily, 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9. This is the total, the word
"God" on this page. And on the right side is the
total up to this page, from the beginning of the
Quran. The objective of this is to let the reader
participate in the mathematical code of the Quran,
which proves to the person that he is looking at
God's message to him or her. And this is not a
human-made book. Muhammad didn't just invent it
and make it up. You are reading God's message,
and this mathematical code gives you the
confidence that God is speaking to you,
not any human being who's trying to fool you.
The total number of the word God in the Quran,
as you know, is 2,698, which is a multiple of 19.
19 being the common denominator throughout the
Quran. And I'm using just this word as an example.
But every letter in the Quran is mathematically
coded, mathematically composed, and the whole
system is easily superhuman, as all of you know.
So, this is one observation I want to make about
the translation. Of course, the Arabic will go
in the empty rectangle here. We don't have the
Arabic yet. So IN SHAA ALLAH, we'll be sending it to
the press around mid, the end of April, towards
the end of April. No, towards the end of May,
or the beginning of May. I'm trying to calculate when
the night of power is. We're gonna send it off,
IN SHAA ALLAH, on the night of power, which is April.
May 3. Right, okay, there we go. I was adding
April 7 plus 27. It comes to April 34th. So, that's
very late in April, or very early in May. It will
take six or seven weeks to print, and then we'll
have the Arabic and the complete book with us.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
[64:1]  Glorifying God is everything in the heavens and everything on earth. To Him belongs all kingship, and to Him belongs all praise, and He is Omnipotent.
This is a heavy verse right
there. Glorifying God is everything in the heavens
and every thing on earth. And this includes things,
includes the bodies of the disbelievers. Because
the disbeliever does not control his heartbeats.
There's a specific number of heartbeats. And the
disbeliever does not control that. God controls
that. So, the human body is glorifying God. Every
atom in your body, every atom in this carpet, in
this wall, is glorifying God. They follow... We have chemists and
physicists here, and they know that every atom in
the wall or the floor or the ceiling, inside this
light, every atom has a nucleus and a certain
number of electrons, and they're continuously
moving in a specific way. It's just, it's a microcosm
of the cosmos.
[64:1]  Glorifying God is everything in the heavens and everything on earth. To him  belongs all kingship.
God is the one who hires you or fires you. God is the one who determines how many dollars you get. Not anybody else. God
decides the provisions. Somebody was telling
me today that they wanted... they were getting another child,
and somebody asked "can you afford it?" That's the wrong question. The question is not, can you afford it? The question
is "can God afford it?" Because God is the one
who brings the people into this world, and God
is the one who provides for them. When a child
is born, God provides for that child. Not you.
[64:1] .... To Him belongs all kingship, and to Him belongs all
praise. He is Omnipotent.
And God....these are all important attributes of God that we must know. Omnipotent means He backs up His guarantee. And He guarantees
you perfect happiness if you are in His domain. If you follow... if
you do your part, carrying out the commandments,
God will do His part. Perfect happiness, success
in everything you do. Guaranteed. God's guarantee
or warranty is much better than General Motors'
guarantee or warranty. When you have a warranty
from Lee Iacocca, you have confidence in it.
Because he backs up his warranty. Seven years or
7,000 miles. And you take this piece of paper, and
you're happy with it. Well, God is Omnipotent, and
He guarantees your happiness. It's true. God is
giving you a warranty in this Quran. And He says
"if you do your part, I will do My part." This is in
Sura 2, at the beginning, as you know. It says,
(2:40) أَوْفُوا۟ بِعَهْدِىٓ أُوفِ بِعَهْدِكُمْ
"do your part, I'll do My part." And our part
is nothing. What is it? Five Prayers a day,
fasting the month of Ramadan, the things that are good for us. This is our part.
It's like God is saying "come, you're gonna be
happy, and I'm gonna give you all the money
you want and all the health you want, on condition
that you do your part." A lot of people say "no,
I don't wanna be happy and healthy. I wanna be miserable." You don't wanna... Yes.
Now, God's part is overwhelming. It's great. Verse
number two. So, the word "Omnipotent" backs up this
guarantee. The guarantee is outright in the Quran,
23 times in the Quran. God guarantees you perfect
health. For example, in Sura 10, verse 62. I'd
like to go back to this, because a lot of people
can't envision. They can't envision that. But God
controls every atom in their bodies and can decide
how much health they have. When God tells you "I'll give you perfect health, when you do your
part", God, the Omnipotent, means that. You have
to share the new Quran, Greg, with somebody. Yeah.
This is the importance of Omnipotence. Okay, in Sura
10, verse 62, God says "absolutely, God's allies,
or God's people, have nothing to fear, nothing to
worry about."
(10:62) لَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
And then it gives you a description of these people. It says "those who believe and lead a righteous life." Those who believe in
God and they lead a righteous life. They
are nice people. They are honest, truthful,
and God is their god. God is always in their
mind, in everything they do, everything they say.
Those who believe and lead a righteous life. "For
them is happiness in this world." I'm quoting now.
I'm quoting those verses. Verse 62 of Sura 10.
"For them is happiness in this world." And this
is God speaking. "and in the Hereafter." So, this
warranty or guarantee from God is repeated 23
times in the Quran. Now as you know, Satan tricks
the other people who deviate from the Quran and
they have other sources like Hadith and Sunnah and
God knows what, all kinds of sources besides the
Quran. Their number one Hadith goes like this. "The
most righteous among you is the most miserable."
This is a very famous Hadith. Because Satan
knows that he cannot give them happiness.
And actually the Hadith goes on and says "the most
miserable are the prophets, and then the saints,
and then the believers." That's right. So, and this
is an authentic Bukhari Hadith. It goes directly
against the Quran. The Quran says otherwise. Says "those who believe and lead a righteous life
are guaranteed happiness." I'm gonna go back a
little bit again and talk about the title of the
Sura, Mutual Blaming. Mutual Blaming is one of
the names of the Day of Judgment. It's called the
Day of Resurrection. It's called the Day of
Judgment. It's called the Day of Reckoning.
It's called the Day of Mutual Blaming. Because this is
the day when a lot of people will be blaming each
other. "You're the one who told me this." "No, you're
the one who told me this." "You took me out of this
place." "You took me into that place." So, there'll be mutual blaming. In fact, the people of
hell will spend eternity beating each other. And
thanking each other for beating each other. "So, if
you give me 10 kicks, I'll give you 10 kicks."
Okay. Mutual Blaming. One of the names of the
Day of Judgment. Verse 2 says
[64:2]  He is the one who created you. Then among you there is the disbeliever and the believer. God is fully seer of everything you do.
There are only two kinds of people.
People in God's kingdom and people in
Satan's kingdom. There's nothing else. No other
choices. Although there are categories within
each section. For example, Satan's kingdom has the
disbelievers and the hypocrites. And both of them
fall under the bigger category of disbelievers.
Other names for believer and disbeliever is
appreciative and unappreciative. These are other
names. Appreciative of God or unappreciative.
And we're gonna get to this in Sura 76. Not today.
But these are the other synonyms
of believer and disbeliever. Appreciative and
unappreciative. Because God gave you a lot of good
things in advance. Then, He asked you to show your
appreciation. Let us take for example your eyes.
Just your eyes. And I've shared this with some
of you before. If you're walking out in the street
and somebody puts a gun to your head. And he says
"your eyes or five Prayers a day." What will you do?
Not your eyes or your money. You're gonna say
"you either give me your eyes or promise me to do
five Prayers a day." What will you choose? If this
A woman: Five Prayers a day.
Dr. Khalifa: If this is real...
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. Easily. Right? So, God
gave you your eyes in advance. If you want
to appreciate them, just close your eyes for a
couple of minutes.
It's something that we take for granted. I hope none of you is color blind. But if you look around and you see the red,
the blue and the green and all these nice colors.
God's people are perfect anyway. You notice.
Alhamdu Lillah. Thank God we all have two eyes
each. So, God gave you these eyes in advance and He
said "you do five Prayers a day." Appreciative and
unappreciative. The people who are not worshipping
God alone are not appreciative. I didn't mentioned
the lungs or the kidneys. Nobody will want to
substitute God's kidneys for the technologically
advanced artificial kidneys that they have.
They're small now. They're only about six feet
tall and four feet wide and three feet deep.
And these are the most advanced kidneys. They take
the patient blood completely into the machine.
And it's not as good. You should see those people. So, we thank God. He gave you all these things in advance. Number three.
[64:3]  He created the heavens and the earth for a specific purpose.
Designed you and perfected your design. Then to Him is the final destiny.
Footnote 64:3 says "we
are in this world due to God's immense mercy and
Most Gracious will to redeem us after we committed
the gross blasphemy. See the introduction and
appendix 7." You know, a lot of people say "why did God bring
me here? I didn't wanna come here." Because they
don't understand why we are here. If they read
the Quran, they will know why we are here.
And they will realize that we committed a gross crime
billions of years ago. And God decided to give
us a chance to redeem ourselves, to denounce idol
worship. But the majority of people insist on idol
worship. The vast majority of Christians insist
on worshiping Jesus. And the vast majority of
Muslims insist on worshiping Muhammad. It's
just the human nature. They're all humans.
And the Quran makes that statement in advance.
It says "most people, no matter what you do,
will not believe." Because God knows these are the
creatures who committed that blasphemy billions
of years ago. And I don't wanna bore you with
repetition of what it is.
And then God says that of the minority that will believe, the majority
will fall in idol worship. Because God knows...
I mean, this is what brought us here. We did
not uphold God's absolute authority. And this is
why we have that tendency to idolize saints and
prophets. The vast majority of people fall in that
trap. So, He created the heavens and the earth for
a specific purpose, which is redeeming those among
us who deserve to be redeemed. So, we can go back
and join, rejoin God's kingdom. If we fail, then we'll
be exiled from God's kingdom, and that is hell. It
only makes sense, like I told you at noon today.
If you're a chairman of the board of a company,
you don't want the lazy employees. It will cause
the company to lose. And instead of God firing
us completely, He said "I'll give you a chance
to educate yourselves, redeem yourselves, and then
come back to me. This is the specific purpose. God
designed you and perfected your design. And the
design of the human being is fantastic, and
we never tired from describing it. Like I was using
somebody the other day to give the example. Well, we can
use Greg now. See, Greg is scratching his face. Ok.
His hand is like this, but it goes like that,
and then it turns and scratches his face. He takes
it for granted. But this is quite a design. There
are two bones in your arm here that can go
around each other, so it can go like this.
I mean, how many times do you take it for granted? You go
like this. You don't even think. God perfected our
design. Can you scratch every part of your body?
This is God's design. Your arm is not too short.
You can reach every inch of your body. Not
me, but... If I maintain the natural weight,
I will. So, it's my fault. If there is any flaw
in your design, it's your fault.
Designed you and perfected your design. Anything
that goes wrong... This is very important,
because people will tell you "how about the
person who's crippled?" It's very important to
understand that that person is a victim of Satan. Something, something, they removed themselves from God's protection,
and that caused Satan's victimizing them. And
the perfect example that we know, and we talked
about it before many times, is Rabbi Kushner
of Boston. Rabbi Kushner of Boston. His book is
full of blasphemies against God, unfortunately.
Not all the Jewish people are like that, but he
is a rabbi, and he should know better. He wrote
this book "When Bad Things Happen to Good People"
and he totally misunderstands... He does not
understand Satan's role at all. And he says that
the bad things happen because God cannot control
everything. God is not Omnipotent, according
to him. His book is just full of blasphemies.
Now, what happened to him... his son was born
with this progeria disease, rapid aging disease.
And in 14 years, he died. So, what happened was,
Rabbi Kushner, by blaspheming against God in this
manner, he removes himself from God's protection.
And Satan fooled around with the embryo, with
his son, when he was inside the mother.
And the child was born defective. So, whose fault is
it? The child was victimized by Satan.
And Rabbi Kushner was victimized by Satan, in the same
way. Because God guarantees your health through
the angels, God's angels. God has some of the best
surgeons in the world. If you are to.... anything wrong happens
in your body, they can go in your body and fix it. ‘Alaykum Al-Salaam. And Satan has the same ability,
because he was an angel. So, remember that anything, any flaw
is a result of Satan's interference. But when you
look around here, this is the basic design
of God. "designed you and perfected your
design. Then, to Him is the final destiny." He gave
you two eyes. Because some people have accidents,
they lose one eye. So, they have another spare.
Even though everyone is perfectly guarded,
nothing happens against the will of God. And
God promises to protect you as long as you
are in His domain. He gave us two kidneys in case
one of them stops for some reason. And remember,
two ears and one mouth. I should learn from
this and stop talking. And put on the spot here,
because General Spooner went AWOL. He was supposed
to be here talking. He called from Memphis today.
He is alright by the way. Okay, verse 3 ends by
the statement "to Him is the final destiny." Okay,
so every one of us is gonna go back. And if we
did our part, we'll be prepared to join God's
kingdom. If we did not do our part, and we did not
develop ourselves, we will not be able to be there
physically. God forbid. The people who did not
prepare themselves will go to hell on their own
volition. God will not put anybody in hell. They
will go to hell on their own volition. And we have
examples. The bugs. You put the light fixer on and
you screw it in very tight, and still the bugs,
they work very hard to work through this thread,
and go inside to die. This is how the human beings
do. They work very hard to go to hell. So, God
gives us lots of examples in this world. Number 4, verse 4,
[64:4]  He knows everything in the heavens and the earth. And He knows everything you conceal and everything you declare. God is fully aware of the innermost thoughts.
Did you ever come across people who think that God is not aware of
them? They say "Who am I? God doesn't pay attention to me."
They think God doesn't see them. But this verse
here is telling us God is fully aware of
every single ant. There are some termites in this
building somewhere. We are not aware of them, but
God is. And He knows how much they're supposed
to eat and when to stop them. God is fully aware
of every single creature, every single atom. He
knows everything in the heavens and the earth and
He knows everything you conceal and everything
you declare. We just cannot have a complete
comprehension of God's Omnipotence and Power.
Look how He created you and the blood pumping
in your body in a perfect, perfect design. If you sleep
in your arm for a couple of hours at night and
the circulation is not right, you know, you get a nightmare or something to move you. Because the circulation has to be perfect.
He knows everything you conceal and everything you declare.
So, if you do your part, God is aware of it. Everything is recorded.
Consciousness of God is very important. Wherever
you go, just remember God is with you. You must
be conscious that God is with us here right
now. He's aware of everything we're doing. He is
aware that you are here to study His message. You
want to redeem yourself and go back to God, join
His kingdom. God is aware of that. And These are heavy
verses. Verse number five says,
[64:5]  Have you noted those who disbelieved in the past then suffered the consequences of their decision? They incurred a painful retribution.
God is teaching us from the past history. And these are factual observations. We know that Pharaoh drowned in the sea.
We know that. We know that Moses and the believers
crossed the Red Sea. There were no bridges then,
no Golden Gate Bridge. But they crossed the
Red Sea from Egypt to Sinai. We know Pharaoh
drowned and his body is full of salt in the Cairo
Museum. "Have you noted those who disbelieved in
the past then suffered the consequences of their
decision?" And usually it is the end that counts.
The believers may go through a purification
process, a polishing process, like the stone that
goes through a lot to become a gem. But there is
these machines, these polishing machines that are
very severe. So, the believer may go through that,
but he or she will emerge like a gem in the end.
And we have, we have... all these guarantees will be fulfilled. The
purpose of the purification process is just that,
purification, to make you a perfect human being,
a person who does not lie, cheat, trustworthy,
righteous. Purification. And God will take
each one of these at a time and cleanse you
from it through a polishing process. Remember
Jahan's Khutba on Friday when he didn't wanna
do the push-ups? See, he's young and he's
going through the polishing process. But he
will emerge like a gem. Purification process done
by the Master Purifier. But those who disbelieve,
their end is always bad, always. Their last
15 or 20 years are the most miserable years
of their lives. And the opposite is true
with the believers.
I think tonight we're gonna come to the law that says that "nothing
happens to you except in accordance with God's
will." This is one of the two important laws. The
other law says "nothing happens to you except as
a consequence of something you have done." These
are negative, negative. "Nothing except." "Nothing happens except
as a consequence of your work."
I was talking
to my nephew this morning in Egypt. And he was
telling me that he's doing everything right and
he wonders why he gets some problems. So, I went
with him through a typical day or something and
discovered he doesn't do the Morning Prayer. Maybe
once a week he does the Morning Prayer before
sunrise. So, I taught him the law. I said "the law is
nothing happens to you except as a consequence
of something you have done." I taught him that
God loves him and wants him to do the Morning
Prayer. This is probably what God is choosing at
this time to purify him. Every time he misses the
Morning Prayer, he gets a pinch until he does the
correlation and realizes that God is aware of him and
like he's watching as if he's the only one on earth.
And whenever he misses the Prayer, he gets the
pinch. The correlation is immediate. And this is
why we have also the other law that says "worship
God in order to attain certainty." This is how you
attain certainty. Because with this immediate
correlation, you're gonna realize that God
is watching you as if you're the only person in
the universe. And when you make a mistake, you get
a pinch. It's a kind pinch. It hurts, but it gets
your attention. It doesn't hurt permanently. It is
the kind that is restorable. God's pinches are all
restorable. You don't lose a finger, for example,
because you cannot restore that. But you get a
pinch that is restorable. You get a headache,
for example, because headaches go away.
You lose a few dollars. You can get them back
multiplied manifold. So, this verse, number five,
reminds us of these two laws, two important laws.
Don't forget them. I think we're gonna get
to the one that says "nothing happens except in
accordance with God's will." I believe it
is in this Sura. Oh, Ok. And the other law says
"nothing happens to you except as a consequence of
your work." Nothing happens. I mean, it's quite a
statement. It begins with the statement, nothing.
(64:11) مَآ أَصَابَ مِن مُّصِيبَةٍ إِلَّا بِإِذْنِ ٱللَّهِ
It starts with a negative. Number six,
[64:6]  This is because their messengers went to them with clear  proofs, but they said, "shall we follow humans like us?" They disbelieved and turned away. God does not need them. God is in no need, Praiseworthy.
See, they made a mistake when they said "shall we
follow humans like us?" Because the messengers are not
are not the ones that are being followed. It is
God's instructions that are being followed.
The messenger is one of the people around who is the
same as they are, and he himself is required to
follow the instructions. So, we're all following
God when we look at God's teachings and follow them.
But here, their ego is an important
test. So, we're told that the painful retribution
that is in verse five came to these people because
their messengers went to them with clear proofs.
I mean, Moses threw the staff, became a serpent
in front of Pharaoh and swallowed everything
else. He still did not believe. God made the Nile
into blood in front of them. They couldn't drink
for seven days. And they told Moses "ask your God
to give us water again, we will believe." As soon
as it became water again, they said "NA, NA, NA, NA, NA, NA. We will not believe." I mean,
what is this? Frogs, lice, locusts, nine plagues.
And every time they said "ask God to relieve this,
and we will believe", and then they reneged. So,
God is fair. When they drowned in the Red Sea,
they deserved that. But God gave them enough
warnings.
[64:6]  This is because their messengers went to them with clear proofs.
In this day and age, we
have the mathematical code of the Quran, proving
this is God's word. But they still make all kinds
of excuses to avoid it.
For seven, well, God's... I will go back to six, God's proofs are always
clear and overwhelming, as we are experiencing
right here in this mosque. The mathematical
miracle of Quran, as you will see, I'm writing
it now in appendix one, is just overwhelming.
I'm using here just the word God as an example,
and this alone is enough to prove that this is
not human made. Because the word God, now here we
are in the 20th century, using computers, and we
are sophisticated, educated people, three of us,
Lisa, Emily, and myself. We're working on these
numbers, the number of the word God. We are not
writing them. We're not inventing anything. We're
just counting them, keeping track of them. And you
have no idea how many mistakes we make. Computers
and all. So, it makes us appreciate the miracle
even more. I was typing a number, 2492, 2492, for
example, and I switched the 9 and the 2, make
it 2429. So, I was off by about 70. And there are
many other examples where I was off by one or two,
but the Quran is perfect. 2698 of them, that
is 19 times 142, and if you take the verses,
wherever you see the word God, for example,
in this page we have verse 1, 2, 4, 6, 7, 8,
and 9. You take these numbers. In the whole Quran,
wherever you see the word God, and add them up,
the total is 118123, which is also a multiple of
19. And this will be printed on the last page of
the Quran. This alone proves that this is not
human made. I just don't see how they will face
God on the Day of Judgment, people who can look
at this and still reject it. I'm just trying to
emphasize the words "clear proof", so clear.
Muhammad couldn't do this. How will he keep track
of the word God in the Quran without computers when
we made mistakes? And it's already in front of us.
Verse 7,
[64:7]  Those who disbelieved claim that they will not be resurrected. Yes, indeed, by my Lord, you will be resurrected, and you will be held accountable for everything you have done. This is easy for God to do.
And God set the system, so
it is automatic. Tomorrow morning, before sunrise,
you're gonna have two choices to make. You have
a decision to make. You're gonna get up before
sunrise and do the Morning Prayer, or you will
not. Only two choices. If you force your body
to get out of bed and do the Morning Prayer, you
will grow. Your soul will grow. And to put it in
our world's terms, you will make a deposit in your
post-retirement account, a few million dollars,
just with that one Prayer tomorrow. It's actually
more than that. I'm just using these numbers of
this world. The other choice is that you
become a slave of your body and you sleep,
because your body is telling you "oh, it's so much
fun to be in the pillow." Your body is telling you
that. So, if you're a slave of your body, you're
gonna sleep, and you lose, because the body
is gonna go to dust. You are gonna live on
with your growth and development or your shrunken
condition. God made it automatic. So, in the very
end, you're gonna be born into the Hereafter
what? Either developed, complete person, or a
deformed, shrunken person. It's in your hand.
[64:7]  Those who disbelieved claim that they will not be
resurrected. Yes, indeed, by my Lord....
Remember, these are mathematically composed letters. God
is telling them. "Yes, indeed, by my Lord..."
This is the Quran speaking, by the way. "Yes, indeed, by
my Lord. You will be resurrected, and you will be
held accountable." You'll be held accountable in
this manner. Remember in Sura 17 where it says
"nobody will need to be asked, what wrong did you
do?" It'll be obvious who developed and who did
not develop. In Sura 55, remember the verse
that says "on that day, the guilty will not
be asked about any of their guilt or their
sins?" You don't need to. Also, in Sura 17,
we learn that the differences in the Hereafter
will be fantastic, will be great. See, the
difference between Hani, a child, and his father,
is five feet. In this world, five feet. But in the
Hereafter, the difference between the people
will be like, somebody will be as big as a cat,
and the other will be as big as Phoenix, Arizona,
or the state of Arizona. So, the person as big
as a cat "you're gonna ask him, what did he do
wrong?" I mean, it's obvious. The difference will be huge.
See, we're really tiny. We are very tiny. An angel
can hold the earth in his hand, see, and you can
be as big as that. Remember, we were all in the
same company, billions of years ago.
"Yes, indeed, by my Lord, you will be resurrected and you'll
be held accountable for everything you have done.
This is easy for God to do." In fact, it's already
done. On the Day of Judgment, when God comes to
our world, the people will be automatically
stratified according to their size or degree
and development. If you're strong enough,
you'll be able to stand the presence of God,
and you will enjoy it. You'll be in Heaven. If you
fail to develop yourself, I'm not talking to you,
of course, it's the people on the street who
need to know that. But the people who fail to
develop themselves will have to run away from
God. They cannot stand the presence of God,
too much energy. And this is why God is advising us to
do the Five Prayers, to fast the month of Ramadan,
to be charitable, do all this. He gave us specific
things to develop our soul for our good, because
see the end of the verse? Verse 6, excuse me. Because God
is in no need. He doesn't wanna bother you and
have you get up before sunrise just to annoy you.
Why does God want you to get up before sunrise?
What does He benefit from that? Nothing. It's you
who will benefit from that.
As a matter of fact, my nephew was complaining what... specific
problem was the depression, that gets depressed
once a month or so. And this is directly related,
if you remember Douglas' Khutbah, it is directly
related to being up in the morning early. Remember
the hat with the light? And that research that was
done indicated that people who had extra light
in the morning, not at night.... Is this right,
Douglas? In the morning. So, it's not just.... you
cannot lengthen the day from the night side. It
is getting up early in the morning that induces
certain chemicals in your head and causes the
depression or not. There is a direct correlation.
Those who study statistics, the correlation is 1.0
between sleeping too much and headaches and
depression. You sleep more than 8 hours a
day, you're guaranteed to have headaches and
maybe depression. So, God is advising you for
your own good. God is in no need. Number 8,
[64:8]  Therefore, if you are smart, you shall believe in God and His messenger, and the light that we have revealed herein, God is fully cognizant of everything you do.
It's God's message to the
people. After showing us the positive incentives
and the negative incentives, God is giving you
the conclusion. "Therefore, you shall believe
in God and His messenger." Why does God want you
to believe? He doesn't need us. It's because He
loves us. God loves you. He wants you to believe
and follow this light of the Quran to be redeemed,
to be saved, to be happy here in this world and
in the Hereafter. You see this verse that talks
about retribution in verse 5? You see, a lot of
people make a mistake thinking that they have
to die first and go to the grave for millions of
years and then get up before they receive their
reward or their punishment. And they say "oh, forget it, come on." For millions of years,
they think. They don't realize that the happiness
and the retribution happen here. It is repeated so
many times throughout the Quran that we pay here.
It starts here. When you make deposit in your
post-retirement account, you draw interest
here and benefits in this world.
[64:8]  Therefore, you shall believe in God and His messenger and the light that we have revealed herein. God is fully cognizant of everything you do.
Number 9,
[64:9]  The day will come when He summons you to the Day of Summoning. That is the Day of Mutual Blaming....
Here you have two names of the Day of Judgment. The Day of Summoning, we will be summoned. It is as sure as the sunrise tomorrow morning. All of us, past,
present, and future generations will be summoned
before God. And that is the Day of Mutual Blaming.
[64:9]..... Anyone who believes in God and leads a righteous life, God will remit his sins and will admit him into gardens with flowing streams. They abide therein forever. This is the greatest triumph.
So, our part is so easy. And this is why Mutual
Blaming causes people who did not believe will
find someone who misled them, took them away
from the Redemption.....
Edip: And also this describes the selfishness of disbelievers. They are selfish and they will want to change everything, to give
as a ransom everything that they love, that they
have.
Dr. Khalifa: They probably gave up God and this world for the sake of their spouse or parents or children or whatever. But on the Day of Judgment, they want to give up those.
Edip: The love of disbelievers,
when they love something, their love is because
of their selfishness. They love, for example, their children because they have benefit.
They do not love anything they don't expect benefit.
For example, they do not do anything secretly,
good things, because they are in fact selfish. But
apparently, you may not see it. Any people who do
not believe in Hereafter, they are selfish in this
world. Let's go on, 15.
[70:15]  No; it is aflame.
[70:16]  Eager to burn.
[70:17]  It calls on those who turned away.
[70:18]  Those who hoarded and counted.
[70:19]  Indeed, the human being is anxious.
Verse 17 tells us that hell will
call, will invite people. In Quran, we find that
Allah personalized the substances. Understand? For
example, in chapter 41, verse 21, we see God makes
everything speak up, makes everything speak up. For example, in 41:11, we see earth and heaven speak. In 23, chapter
23:62, the record speaks. And chapter 50,
verse 30, hell speaks. And chapter 27:82,
computer speaks. God makes everything speak
up. But what is speaking in our language?
We're speaking.... You may understand speaking is only by words. But Quran explains the word "speaking." The word speak,
in 3:41, we see gestures, symbols, also is another
way for speaking. Allah says for Zakariya,
your sign is not to speak with anybody for
three days except, except gestures, by symbols you
can speak. This exception shows us that symbols
or anything that symbol gestures are also way of speaking.
Dr. Khalifa: Signals
Edip: Signals, yes. Thanks. Verse 18,
"Those who
hoarded and counted" is one of the important
character of disbelievers. They hoarded the
earthly goods and they are very careful about the
substances of this world. And also we can see this
character in chapter 74, verse 12, 15. And
verse 19 is very interesting. "Indeed the human being is
anxious." In Arabic, we see it has been created
as anxious. The word is "has been created." I searched
about this because Allah says in chapter 95, verse 4 and 5.
(95:4) لَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا ٱلْإِنسَـٰنَ فِىٓ أَحْسَنِ تَقْوِيمٍۢ
We have created the human being in
the best manner. Allah, and in another verse,
please open chapter 32, verse 7.
He perfected everything He created. He perfected everything He created. Allah's creation is perfect. But here
we see that human being has been created anxious.
Apparently, we may see a contradiction between
those verses. But if we carefully research on the
word "KHALAQA", we see in Quran when God says about
our creation, when mentioned about our creation,
He says "خَلَقْنَا ٱلْإِنسَـٰنَ", "KHALAQNA", we created.
And Allah when mentioned about His creation,
He says always "we created best, in best manner."
But here it is KHOLIQA, has been created,
not "we created." How do you say in English
for this? KHOLIQA, unknown. The subject is unknown here.
Dr. Khalifa: Passive, Is it passive tense?
Edip: Passive, yes. Passive tense. For example, we can see the
passive tense in chapter 4:28. It describes
the weakness of human being.
(4:28) خُلِقَ ٱلْإِنسَـٰنُ
You can see that verse. And also the human being
has been created hasty, chapter 21:38.
And when Allah describes the weakness and
anxiousness and hastiness of the human being,
He always describes this as KHOLIQA, not KHALAQNA. It shows us with our free will,
we change our creation.  Yes. OK, what is the grammatical,
Dr. Khalifa: Where is Martha? Is
Martha here?
Martha: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. What is the term, linguistic term for something
that was created? Instead of I created.
Martha: Yes. It's passive voice.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, OK, so, passive is right. I wasn't sure.
Martha: But I'm not sure if I (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, but the
human being can make himself worried, as you will see
in the next verses. In other words, the INSAN, the human
being is made something, it's made by the human, not by God.
Martha: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, right.
Edip: We can see in Quran,
(23:14) فَتَبَارَكَ ٱللَّهُ أَحْسَنُ ٱلْخَـٰلِقِينَ
Allah is the best of the creators, the best Creator of creators.
أَحْسَنُ ٱلْخَـٰلِقِينَ
There are many creators.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, we can create our own misery or our own happiness.
Martha: But the angel talks to us.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, God instructs. They follow God's laws. They carry out God's laws.
Edip:
(Arabic unintelligible)
Also they create lies.
Dr. Khalifa: This is just to
bypass these linguistic tricks.
Edip: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Dark grey car with the lights on. Small, dark,...
Dr. Khalifa: Eula, get
the make of the car next time, not now. But....
Dr. Khalifa: It could be. But Emily will find out.
Dr. Khalifa: OK, go on, Edip.
Edip: Yes, verse 20.
[70:20]  If touched by adversity, despondent.
[70:21]  If blessed by wealth, stingy.
Dr. Khalifa: What kind of car is it? No.
Edip: [70:22]  Except for the worshipers.
[70:23]  Who always observe their contact prayers (Salat).
[70:24]  Part of their money is set aside.
[70:25]  For the poor and the needy.
[70:26]  They believe in the Day of Judgment.
[70:27]  They reverence their Lord's requital.
[70:28]  Their Lord's requital is not taken for granted.
[70:29]  They keep their chastity.
[70:30]  (They have relations) only with their spouses, or what is legally theirs—
[70:31]  anyone who transgresses these limits is a sinner—
[70:32]  And the believers keep their word; they are trustworthy.
[70:33]  Their testimony is truthful.
And it ends with the same close statement.
[70:34]  They consistently observe their contact prayers (Salat), on time.
It's like the same verse 23. There are
some qualifications, some behaviors of Muslims,
important behaviors. First, they observe their
Contact Prayers. And we see this statement also
in 23, verse 2. And there are many common verses
between here and the beginning of chapter 23.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, I'm making a note of this for the index. Traits of the believers. (unintelligible). Ok. Go ahead.
Edip: Part of their money is set aside. Word by word
translation, they have a part in their money. A
part there is known, known by people. This shows
us this charity, the amount of Zakat is known by
people.
Dr. Khalifa: Specified.
Edip: Specified.
Edip:
(70:24) حَقٌّۭ مَّعْلُومٌۭ
Edip: 24.
[70:24]  Part of their money is set aside.
The amount of the charity
is known by people.
Dr. Khalifa: So, give me this back to printing. Specified portion?
Edip: Ok. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Specified portion of their money is set aside.
Edip: Specified. مَّعْلُومٌۭ
And there are parallel verses here between 23 and chapter 23. For example, you see the parallel verse in 23, chapter 23,
verse 4. It says, it specifies this as Zakat, just the word Zakat.
Verse 30,
[70:30]  (They have relations) only with their spouses, or what is legally theirs—
Edip: This is about captives of war.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it is not.
Edip: It's not?
Edip: In chapter 4:25, Allah gives us permission to marry with captives of the war.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it is not.
Edip: Please, open chapter 4, verse 25.
Dr. Khalifa: Look in the new
translation. Edip inherited some of the old stuff,
where they had wars and captives. And "what is legally
theirs" covers all the methods of marriage in the world.
There are places where there's no
marriage. But a man and a woman will live
together forever and have their children, and the
society will know that these belong to each other.
You don't have anything like that any.... So,
the Quran covers all the situations. There are
common-law marriages in this country. And the Quran
recognizes that. This is what legally theirs means.
Edip: And is there any question about this?
Dr. Khalifa: I have a few comments.
Edip: Let me talk about...
Dr. Khalifa: 4:25 talks about slaves. 4:25 talks about slaves.
Edip: Yes, slaves, you
can marry with them.
Dr. Khalifa: Right, but not war captives.
Edip: Oh, ok.
Edip: Ok. This is very important to note that the people who do not....
the worshippers who do not observe the
Contact Prayers are anxious. Anxious, I really
want a more stronger word than anxious. In Arabic,
HALU'A is worried, always worried. Nervous and
anxious and worried, always worried. A human... huh?
Yeah. Jittery and worried. Worried, depressed and
anxiety and worry.
If touched by adversity, they become despondent. And when blessed with wealth, they are stingy. Ok, now, you can ask
yourself these questions. "Do you worry?" Number 2, "Do you
become despondent when something bad happens to you?"
Number 3, "Are you stingy when you have money?" If you
have these three traits, then you do not belong
with the worshippers, the believers. I remember
my father's teacher had a debate with some of the
Mullahs. And he trapped him into this. He said,
"do you worry a lot?" He said "yeah, we're humans,
we worry." He said "if something bad happens
to you, do you become upset?" He said "yeah,
we're human beings, we do that." And then he
said... So, I said "well, then you don't belong
with the worshippers who observe their Salat prayer because in verse 22, it says,
(70:22) إِلَّا ٱلْمُصَلِّينَ
Except those who observe the Salat Prayers. So, the lesson
is that if you do observe your Contact Prayers,
this will cool you down. You will not worry,
you'll have nothing to worry about. No fear,
no worry. And you will not be despondent when
adversity happens. You'll remember what the
Quran says, that you may dislike something which
is good for you. You may not get the job that you
want, but God knows it is not good for you, and
you accept that. So, you will not be despondent,
you will not be miserable, because you didn't make
it in the job interview. So, then we have a bunch of
traits of the believers. They always observe
their Contact Prayers, verse 23. 24,
A specific portion, 2.5% of their net income is set aside
for the poor and the needy, 25. 26,
[70:26]  They believe in the Day of Judgment.
These are all traits of the believers. 27,
[70:27]  They reverence their Lord's requital.
They worry about it. In other words,
they don't want it. They know how bad it is,
just making God angry. God doesn't get angry, by
the way, but, I mean, violating His commandments.
27, eh, 28,
[70:28]  Their Lord's requital is not taken for granted.
In other words, when you look at this, you'll be
severe against yourself. You will not be lax. You
will judge yourself according to these criteria,
and make sure that you're a believer. You
will be strict with yourself. Number 29,
[70:29]  They keep their chastity.
So, I mean, you look
at this verse 29, and you keep your chastity.
You will not be lax or careless. Keeping the chastity
is something that is unusual in this country,
because the society evolved so much in the last
few decades. Maybe, I should get you the piece of
paper that Phil handed me. Just one second.
It's appropriate to this. Let me. It's for all those
born before 1945, which probably includes me
only. And...Okay, but here it says "we were certainly
not before the difference between the sexes was
discovered. But we were surely before the sex
changed. We may do with what we have. And we were
the last generation that was so dumb as to think
you needed a husband to have a baby." No wonder we
are so confused, and there is such a generation
gap. But we survived, okay. I think there are
some other points here that along the line that
"we were the last generation that was so dumb as
to think you needed a husband to have a baby." So,
in other words, what happened in the last few
decades is really very harmful to the people.
And we see what happened with AIDS, the spread
of venereal diseases, lesbian mothers, things
that those who were born before 1945 never heard of these
things. But verse 29, the believers do not take it
lightly, 29. I'm writing an appendix on chastity
and virginity for our children. Our children
better be different from the other children. It
is your responsibility to teach your children for
their own good that they must be virgin on their
wedding night. And I'm talking about boys and
girls. And I'm going to show in the appendix how
the happiness of your children depends on that.
The price is just too high if they don't follow
this verse, this very short verse, 29, they keep
[70:29]  They keep their chastity.
The price is really too high. Now,
even from the physiological and the physical point
of view, the boys and the girls, when they mature
first and they're ready for... they're not ready.
I mean, physiologically, they may have their
menstruation, or they may... the voice may change,
the boy's voice may change, but physiologically
and anatomically, they are not really ready for
sex. But in this country, they delve into sex
without being ready, and they hurt themselves,
and they pay the price when they grow up. This is
from the purely physical and physiological point
of view. But from the practical point of view,
God sees to it that those who violate this...
Cause you know, our boys and girls must be taught not to
violate this. That they must keep their chastity,
because when they do that, they pay from their
happiness. They will not have a happy marriage.
They will not have a happy life. And, mind you,
it is not easy. You must teach them that it is
not easy to keep your chastity, especially in a
society like this. Joe Sobran is a reporter with
the Los Angeles Times, and he had a wonderful
commentary only yesterday, or the day before.
He says "these boys, they go out and they have
sex as if there are no consequences. But the
consequences are abortions, dangerous things
that happen to... and children who these boys have no intention
of raising them or supporting them. They create a
lot of misery." That was Joe Sobran's commentary,
and he is not a Muslim. But here we are reading
the Quran, and God knows what is good for us.
And He is telling us that the believers must
keep their chastity. You know, all of you are young,
and you have children who are growing, and I want
to repeat and emphasize, and re-emphasize that it is
your responsibility. If you just do your part, God
will do the other part. You cannot just leave them
to the world out there. You have to do your part
by teaching them what the Quran is saying, what
God is saying. Because if you really love them,
you want them to be happy when they grow up.
And one source of misery will be to break these laws.
They are not physiologically ready. They'll be
breaking God's law, and the price is too high. And
I know you do want them to be happy. So, I am going
to write this appendix in detail, and you can use
it. Ok. Use me to give them these instructions. It is
very difficult to be a father or a mother, and you
talk to children about sex. It's kind of awkward.
But if you use the Quran, tell them "this is what
God says. Here is the appendix. Read it." And God
will help you, and will protect them. So, and
emphasize to them that it is not easy. You must
exert, tell them they have to exert a lot of control. Because the temptation is so great out there. And you are helping them this
way when you tell them "it is not easy. But you
must exert for your own happiness and your own good,
you must exert a lot of control. You must
resist." You know, they have a big thing saying
"say no to drugs." But you never see "say
no to sex." Even though it is disastrous. Is there?
Well, Subhan Allah. Ok.
Yes, this is a shock.
A woman: If you have 20 hours, they say, you know "use contraceptive whenever (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because this, I think it was Valentine's Day at the university, and they
distributed free condoms. It's like telling them
"go have sex", you know. They don't realize what they're doing, and how much unhappiness they're
causing to these kids. But this is good news.
Now, God is forcing. God says in Sura 41 verse 53,
that God will show them His signs in the
horizons and within themselves until they
realize that this is the truth. This is what is good
for us. There is a big campaign in the country
against alcohol. They don't do it because God
said so. But they are forced by the disasters,
the social disasters, and the broken families,
and the depression that is caused by alcohol,
the hangovers and headaches, diseases. Now, the
book, there's a book in the market, new book,
that is called "You Are What You Drink." I've
mentioned it before. And it lists unbelievable
disastrous health problems from alcohol. Because
it dissolves your brain. I mean, I'm talking
about cancer, blood pressure, heart disease. Established,
scientifically established.
A woman: Liver disease.
Dr. Khalifa: Liver disease, of course, it's known long time ago. And the same is happening with violating this verse 29,
[70:29]  They keep their chastity.
The same thing is
happening. There are unheard of diseases coming out.
AIDS is one of them. Uncurable. Skin cancer exposure. You're telling me that now, the... Naghmeh, you're telling me now the females
have a disease that is similar to AIDS. I heard
about it a couple of weeks ago. Do you wanna tell us more?
A woman: There's a cancer (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Young girls who are sexually active. Because they are not physiologically, they're not physiologically
ready. It takes maybe 10 years after the voice in
the boy changes and the menstruation of the girl,
maybe 10 years to really be ready to be pregnant
and to be in a marriage relationship. So, God
knows, God created us and knows what is good for
us. So, if you think I spend too much time on this,
it's deliberate. Because you have a lot of
responsibility. There are lots of beautiful,
wonderful kids running around here. And they must
be protected. Like I said "don't worry." You just
do your part. And you must know that your children
are in God's hand. You can't be with them every
time. But God chaperones your children. You're
a person. You're a person of God. And you must
have that confidence. You must know that God is
with your children wherever they go. If they're
riding a bicycle in the middle of the street, or
they're out with other people subjected to all the
temptations of this society. Don't worry. Drugs or
sex or accidents. Your children are in God's hand
and you must have that confidence. And being the
oldest of you, I've raised two kids. I know that.
I know. I'm speaking from experience. They've
seen how much God's protection is marvelous.
And they've seen how you just do your part and God
will do His part in the most magnificent ways.
So, I don't have relations with anybody else. In
fact, this is repeated in verse 30. It says
[70:30]  (They have relations) only with their spouses, or what is legally theirs—
So, there's a lot at stake. It is just not worth it violating these laws. These are very harsh. The punishment is very harsh. It seems
out of proportion. So, if you want to test it, go
ahead. You're gonna pay through the nose. If,
if you want to abide by God's law, then you attain a
lot of happiness and you avoid lots of problems.
Okay. Any questions?
Yes.
Right. They're being selfish, like the fellow who donated a million dollars to the cancer centre but it had to be announced over the microphone in the stadium. This is showing
off and he's doing it for selfish reasons. Maybe.
Maybe. I mean, he has to be a believer in God to
give things secretly. But the criterion is whether
the person is cutting a portion of his money and
giving it to the poor or not. The minimum is
2.5%. If the person is giving away at least 2.5%
of his or her money to the poor, then they're alright. Farhad.
Yes. This is verse 30.
Yes.
Yes. OR is very important. Yes. This is...The Quran is so accurate
that you have to pay attention to what Farhad
is just saying. OR or AND. There's a verse that
says you shall observe Hajj and Umrah. And I have
translated it, maybe even in the old translation,
OR Umrah. But we're supposed to observe, in
pilgrimage, there are two things you must observe.
Hajj and Umrah. They must be done. So, this is a
similar... The difference is just a dash. WA or AW. It's
the difference. You really have to pay attention to these things.
Edip: Yes, here, if you have spouses, you don't have legally.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. See, because you either
got married or either got together without the
benefit of marriage. I don't wanna tell you that
joke again. The guy in Africa who wanted to know the secret of happy marriage. And someone said "what is marriage?"
So, there are places in the world where there is no marriage.
Edip: What does legally mean?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, "legally" means that there may be societies where when the people reach the age of 21, they are actually
engaged at the time of birth, in some of those
societies. They had a boy in the family and said,
"this will be for my daughter." The tribe chief
or something. Because the daughter is not born yet,
maybe. But these are political connections. So, when they reach 21, they ship the boy and the
girl into their new house and they become husband
and wife, forever. She is legally his and he is
legally hers. But there was no marriage ceremony
or no such thing as marriage. So, the Quran must
cover all situations. They legally belong to
each other. In this country, the common law
marriages are legal as far as God is concerned.
There are two people who decided to live together
forever and raise a family. The intention is for
being together forever. They don't go through the
state and the papers and the priest or the Justice
of the Peace or anything. But they live together
forever. And that's legal as far as God is concerned.
A man: In many places like psychiatric hospitals and (unintelligible), the adolescents have the most serious emotional problems. (unintelligible).
Typically, they're children of parents who
were illicit. They engaged in a lot of illicit
sexual activity. They committed adultery. A lot of
these young people, they don't have any sense of
genuine love or affection. They, in fact, even at times,
express hatred and resentment toward their
parents. Because they can't see their parents
loving each other. These are the ones that are,
in fact, the most serious.
I haven't, God knows, I haven't come in contact with a single case of
an extremely serious emotional problems.
You know, this type of thing that is not included sometimes in
adultery or, you know, disregard for marriage. (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: By the way, I must clarify that when I talk about
problems in marriage, there are all those
problems in marriage. But for people who
keep their chastity until their marriage,
they will have the regular problems of bickering
over the budget and what to be spent where and
which house to pick out and which room should
be the living room and which room should be...
These are normal problems. I'm talking about
serious problems that are the price of the improper marriage.
A woman: You just mentioned that parents (unintelligible) children (unintelligible).
There's a verse in Sura 4, verse 19, is Quran saying that, you know, it's commandment "They can't do that. They can't get in here unless quiet"?
(unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is inheritance of the things that the wife
possessed. It is not inheriting the person. I,
I think I clarified this in the new translation.
"You shall not inherit your wife's forcibly" means
you cannot force her to write a will giving you
everything, giving the husband everything. That's
what it means. But arranged marriages are done all
over the world. And a lot of them are very successful.
Well, this is prohibited in the Quran. Marriage
against anybody's will is prohibited in the Quran
anyway. So, this...If a man inherits the wife in the sense
that you're saying, and she's happy and he's
happy and they get married, fine. I mean, widows
can get married. There's no problem.
There's a Jewish tradition about the brother marrying his
brother's widow. It's an old tradition in Judaism.
There's nothing wrong with it if everybody's
happy.
A person: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, well, no, this is against the Quran.
Pardon?
Speak slowly.
A woman: There are quite a few societies...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. There are a few societies there.
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, in
this society, you find everything here in this society.
Any other questions? Pari.
Parivash: (unintelligible) legally because many people here, they leave, when they wanna leave, they say, they suddenly leave because they don't wanna be legally and that's...
Dr. Khalifa: It's only okay if
they decide that they are together forever
and that they will raise a family, the children and
everything, as a couple forever. The intention
must be forever. They may break up next month
or next year, but if the intention was they're
getting together forever, then it's okay. It is
not okay to get together with the intention that if things don't work out, goodbye.
Parivash: Because most of them, they don't wanna have that responsibility.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Parivash: If wanna live and baby, they can have a baby. But I think they don't want that they have responsibility.
And maybe they live
for 50 years or more than that. Years.
Dr. Khalifa: Like I said, if the intention was that they live together forever, then it's perfectly alright. Yeah. Right. Some
A woman: Some people get married (unintelligible) and they don't wanna (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Right.
Edip: People's intention.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, some people get married and one or both have
intention of not being together forever.
That's prostitution. Yeah, the Quran consistently
talks about marriage and making it official and
everything. Yes, but I'm talking about generally,
in this country, for people who never saw the
Quran, never came across the Quran.
Dr. Sabahi: Ok, that's what I wanna...
Dr. Khalifa: Marriage is a very organized institution, according to the Quran, because God tells exactly who we can
marry and who we cannot marry. And it's an elaborate
and divine institution that is very organized, yes. I'm glad you point this out.
Dr. Sabahi: Yeah, I got the wrong...
Dr. Khalifa: Against the Quran.
Dr. Sabahi: Which is something that I wanted...
Dr. Khalifa: We're going against the Quran. The true believer is the hardest working person and the
best producer in his job or her job, wherever they
go. And they enjoy every minute of it. Believers
are very hard workers and the most honest workers.
And they are the best producers. And they enjoy
every second of it. They're not lazy. God doesn't
want the lazies. He wants people on the ball in
His kingdom. It was very good. Sura 16 says "the
rich believer is better than the poor believer."
And Edip wanted me to change this for possible
misunderstandings. But I did not, because God
meant that. It says "the rich believer and the poor
believer, both are believers." Both are equally
believing. But one of them is able to do things,
is able to give to charity, and able to further
the cause of God and spread the word of God and
do things that will make a difference. So, this is a motivation.
A man: Is it also (unintelligible)
Edip: Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, there are authorized printings
and they are the closest to the truth. They have
one of the mistakes in them. There are three mistakes in them, in
the authorized versions of the Quran printed in
Saudi Arabia or Egypt. Avoid the ones printed in
Iran. They misspelled them and messed them up. You
Dr. Sabahi: Even the verses, the numbering of the verses?
Dr. Khalifa: That's possible, but I know that they "simplified"
the Quranic Arabic and they wrote it in the modern...
Edip: In Turkey also.
Dr. Khalifa: Also in Turkey?
Edip: Yes, misspelled.
Dr. Khalifa: uh-oh. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: The first Quran ever in history
that is the way God wanted it to be printed.
From here, come out of here the next few weeks, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: Farhad?
Farhad: You mentioned about Persian translation. Another, another translation, its introduction in Persian language. Another translation is in
Arabic. Translating into Persian is convenient
because they use it a lot.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I have good news for you. There is a Farsi translation being done now from my translation. So, we should
have it in a year or so, IN SHAA ALLAH. We have
authorized Farsi translation. No. Susan Ray? No. It's done by
Behrooz. You meet Behrooz? Behrooz Mofidi Shirazi.
He's doing this. He's going very fast.
A man: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Martha, did you say something?
Dr. Khalifa: You are not reading your Muslim Perspective (unintelligible). You are not reading your Muslim Perspective.
Martha: Maybe.
Dr. Khalifa: Not maybe. You are not reading your Muslim Perspective. It's right there. It's the answer to your question.
Yes. It's perfect answer to your question in detail. So, go
read it. Now. Any other questions? While Martha is
reading the answer to her question.
Can you, can you what?
What was, what did she say now?
A woman: Me? I said, any other questions
that Rashad can avoid tonight by telling us to read them.
A woman: (unintelligible). That's actually very efficient, especially since it's five o'clock at night.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It only takes a
minute, but it answers your question perfectly.
The answer is "yes." The Prophet Muhammad was given
specific instructions. Every time Gabriel released
Quran from Muhammad's soul to Muhammad's memory,
he gave him instructions as to where these three
or four verses belong. And he wrote down those
verses and he put the instructions next to them.
So, when he died, he left the complete Quran,
but not in the order that God wanted for the
world. He left the Quran with instructions on
the side as to which Sura goes after what Sura
and which verse goes after which verse.
Martha: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. They followed
the instructions. They put the Quran together, but
then Satan tricked them into adding two verses.
And that was during Uthman's time. And this
triggered the war between Ali and his family
and the Umayyads.
Martha: If that's the thing that you're referring to, I read that part. The part about Ali and his family. I've read that part.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: There were 50 years of
bitter war, but unfortunately, the Umayyads won.
So, we got their version. We didn't get the version of the believers.
A woman: Did Gabriel come down from the sky to Prophet Muhammad?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: He was an angel. No, he didn't see him
A woman: Did he saw him?
Dr. Khalifa: No, he didn't see him as an angel.
A woman: Did he just dream him?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, he didn't dream. Gabriel
comes and takes and becomes part of Muhammad's
body and releases the... Gabriel built a
connection between Muhammad's soul and Muhammad's
physical body. He didn't need to see him.
A woman: So, I mean like did he talk to them?
Dr. Khalifa: No, not like that. When... the possession, you lose... In the possession, you lose your
identity completely. If you are possessed by an
angel or a demon or whatever, Naghmeh disappears
and the other entity takes over completely. And
you have no consciousness at all. But Muhammad was
fully conscious. He just had these words come to
him and he would write down the verses. It comes
to his memory. It's just like you're remembering
something. You remember that you took a final
exam three days ago, and the questions were this,
this, and this, and you can write them down. So,
Dr. Khalifa: this is how he received it.
A woman: But he knew that all
along it was a spiritual thing.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Well, whatever your dearest wish is, turn to God
and ask him for it. The best wish being to stay
on the right path. Al-Fãtehah.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)
Arrahman Arraheem (1:3)
Maliki Yawm Eddeen (1:4)
Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Ehdina Al-Serata Al-Mustaqeem (1:6)
Serata Al-Lazeena An’amta ‘Alayhim Ghayri Al-Maghdoobi ‘Alayhim Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
By all means, look at that miracle
on the wall and thank God because there is
no doubt that we are the luckiest people on
the face of the earth. Alhamdu Lillah. Congratulations.