A woman: It doesn't quite fit. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, OK.
Dr. Khalifa: I was gonna say, you don't remove anything and you just stick the end.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) on top of (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Nosrat, IN SHAA ALLAH, who will speak?
A woman: Yeah, and that doesn't quite work because
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): I pushed the button.
A woman: there's a little tiny, tiny hole right here.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Are you serious you're broadcasting? Are you broadcasting?!
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Yes, we're broadcasting everything.
Dr. Khalifa: I have one. If I would use it. (unintelligible)
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Don't do that. Don't broadcast it.
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): I broadcasted it.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I will take the size that fits and stick the
top of it. I can do it.
A woman: Watch this. Watch this. I have a better idea.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: A nicer, even an amazing one (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: Ready for what it is?
A woman: Here, watch this.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, this is difficult, then.
A woman: It's not as difficult. It's...
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Anyone who asked me "how was it?"
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Anyone who asked me "how was it?" I said "(Unintelligible)"
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): Maybe they don't know English.
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): They know.
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): No, It's possible that they don't know.
A woman: Then, you take your tape.
A woman: This is great.
A woman: See, it creates a very sharp border, a very...
A woman: Exactly, it's the same border.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, alright.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. That's good.
A woman: Yeah.
A woman: Go ahead, please.
Dr. Khalifa: I try to. (unintelligible)
A woman: You shouldn't, but...
Dr. Khalifa: OK, shall we go again?
A woman: Please.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, it's working.
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So after this, the verse that comes after says, "Now... ." It says "Now, you cannot claim on the Day of Judgement,
you cannot say "oh, I didn't hear
about this."
A lot of people will ask you, they say "what about a
person who is living in Central Africa
Dr. Khalifa: "in the jungle and never heard of Muhammad or Jesus or anybody?"
A woman: I know. They always say that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. This is a favorite question of some people.
A woman: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: They say "this person must go to Heaven", you know.
Dr. Khalifa: And you say "No."
He has no excuse because he already witnessed God.
And Ibrahim is a good example. You know, Ibrahim was just a child.
He went out and looked at the stars and said "this is my God."
And then, he reached God because we have the
instinct.
It was like being in the middle of the jungle.
Dr. Khalifa: So, every human being has that Fitrat. Exactly.
A woman: Fitrat
A woman: The heritage.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, and then the next verse says,
(7:173) أَوْ تَقُولُوٓا۟ إِنَّمَآ أَشْرَكَ ءَابَآؤُنَا مِن قَبْلُ وَكُنَّا ذُرِّيَّةًۭ مِّنۢ بَعْدِهِمْ
Also, you cannot use an excuse, say "oh, it's my father and my mother taught me that Muhammad or Jesus or Ali or Mary are very important."
"And I followed them, I believed them."
You cannot say that because you're an individual,
you're an independent person.
So, that is not an acceptable excuse.
You cannot blame it on your parents.
I cannot blame it on my parents.
And I cannot, I cannot plead ignorance and I cannot blame
it on my parents.
Because my parents taught me that Sayyid (Ahmad) al-Badawi will help you succeed in your examinations.
You know, "Go pray."
Not my mother.
My father did.
A woman: Why do they then say, if you do something good,
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): "May God forgive your father."
A woman: Huh? The...
Parivash: Tradition.
A woman: Huh?
A woman: No, no. The
Parivash: The word
Dr. Khalifa: Translate.
Parivash: It's like when you are a good person, they say
"God bless your father."
A woman: "God bless your father."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: And if you are a bad person, well, they say,
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): "Damn on your father."
A woman: But why?
Dr. Khalifa: I hear you say "you, son of a bitch." Excuse me.
Dr. Khalifa: But I mean, what is the mother's fault?
Dr. Khalifa: This is just a tradition. It's like she said.
A woman: Yeah, really (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Tradition.
A woman: The nicest thing, the nicest thing they say is this.
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): No, no, no.
A woman: When you do something bad, they say, "LA'NAT (damn) on your father."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: And when
you do something good, they say,
A woman (Speaking in Farsi): "God bless your father."
A woman: "God bless your father."
Dr. Khalifa: You know, This is just a tradition. Just tradition.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: Yeah.
A woman: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: So, now, when Sheytan had this idea in his
head that he can rule part of God's universe by himself,
the angels didn't know what was
in Sheytan's head.
Only God knew.
Now, God had two choices. He can take shaytan and wipe him out.
But in that case, the angels would say "Yeah,
why did God do this? Our friend Iblis didn't do anything."
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, as a mercy for the angels, God decided
to expose Sheytan first, Sheytan.
Expose and show his real rebellion first.
So, how will God do this?
He created Adam, the human being, from clay, this lowly material.
From mud.
And then, He told all the angels to fall prostrate
before this creature.
So, they all did, except Sheytan.
He refused.
And this is why I was rather sensitive to the
story that ends up giving us the impression
that he wanted to make Sujud, but he couldn't.
He didn't want to make Sujud.
The Quran says "he refused."
So, these stories are very dangerous.
This is why I just, I'm completely averse to them.
So, Sheytan refused, and the angels...
Now in the movie that I wrote, the script,
all the angels are falling prostrate before Adam,
and then except Sheytan.
So, they look and they...
You know, "Sheytan is still standing up."
You know, so, they all see he's exposed now.
Dr. Khalifa: Someday. We have it ready.
A woman: Someday IN SHAA ALLAH. Someday IN SHAA ALLAH. Someday IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: The title is "King of Chaos."
A woman: "King of Chaos."
A woman: Isn't that a great title?
A woman: Yes, it is.
A woman: Isn't that a great name of a movie or what? I love that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It's true.
Dr.Khalifa: This is chaos on this earth.
A woman: But that's a great title, you have to admit. "Holy Quran"
Dr. Khalifa: So now, Sheytan is exposed.
The angels know what he is.
Now, Sheytan is eloquent.
You know when Adam and...
Do you call her "Hawa" (Eve)?
A woman: Hawa (حوا) (Eve).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
When Adam and Hawa (Eve) made a mistake in Heaven,
they repented.
They asked God forgiveness and they made Tawbah.
Dr. Khalifa: And God accepted their repentance.
Parivash: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: And said "okay, we'll send you to the planet
earth and test you. You and your descendants.
"And if you make it, you come back here."
"Those who don't make it will go with Sheytan."
But how come Sheytan could not, was not pardoned?
Why Adam and Eve were pardoned but not, Sheytan
was not pardoned?
Because he continued to think and he still
thinks that he can rule part of this universe with God.
So, he spoke to the angels.
A woman: He still thinks...?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: He spoke to the angels!?
Dr. Khalifa: He's still trying.
Parivash: He's stupid.
Dr. Khalifa: And of course, he's stupid. From the beginning he was stupid.
Dr. Khalifa: And God exaggerated his stupidity by giving
him this tiny speck of land.
And God took care of even the provisions of
the people and everything.
And He told them "just take care of them." You know.
Dr. Khalifa: Anyway.
A woman: Maybe, it meant that Sheytan...
Dr. Khalifa: No, but he refused to make Istighfar.
He refused to repent.
He said "no, I can do it."
He said "okay, make me a god and I'll do a
good job." Sheytan said.
"I will prove to You", he says to God, "I will
prove to You that Your creatures will not worship You alone."
Parivash: Unappreciative
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. "Will not appreciate Your power."
Dr. Khalifa: "They will always...
A woman: But...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait.
Dr. Khalifa: "They will always put someone with You. They will not say "God alone.""
And this is why he's proud of all the human
beings who say Jesus with God.
A woman: Muslims...
Dr. Khalifa: This is why we have this criterion in the
Quran.
Allahu Wahdahu.
And then the next Sura you remember says,
idha du'a allahu wahdahu kafartum wa in yusrak
(40:12) إِذَا دُعِىَ ٱللَّهُ وَحْدَهُۥ كَفَرْتُمْ ۖ وَإِن يُشْرَكْ بِهِۦ تُؤْمِنُوا۟
When God alone is called upon, you refuse.
But when God and somebody else, anybody else,
then you're happy.
You know, different people.
You know, with the Jews, it's different. The Christians are different. With the Sunnis, it's different. With the Shias, it's different.
Every group of them, they want some name besides
God, they are happy.
You say "La Elaha Ella Allah."
They say "Muhammadun rasulullah."
Dr. Khalifa: You say "I don't wanna..."
A woman: "I can't say anything else."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, I say "I don't wanna say. I wanna say La Elaha Ella Allah."
"What is wrong with you? I want to say La Elaha Ella Allah."
They say "no, Say Muhammadun rasulullah."
I mean, "You're gonna tell me what to say?"
So, it's just some other name with Him.
Yeah.
A woman: It just came to my mind, I don't wanna forget
it, about my children.
A woman: They are really lucky, right?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
A woman: Because they start with worshiping Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: But you are luckier.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you get more credit than they.
A woman: I was
Dr. Khalifa: They are lucky.
A woman: an idol worshiper before though.
Dr. Khalifa: You
A woman: I was scared.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
This is why you get double the reward, you see.
A woman: Look at me.
Dr. Khalifa: For them,
Dr. Khalifa: you already brought them up
saying "God alone." So,
Dr. Khalifa: They are very lucky.
A woman: You know, Mana
A woman: Mana in the Quran session we had
in Masjid, she was so mad at Azar.
A woman: Because Azar was talking about the clean,
and she knows very good now because she, she...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. your children are very lucky, but you are
even luckier.
A woman: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. You see, it takes a lot more credit when you grow under
the influence of putting idols with God, putting names with God.
And then you break away from this.
You get more credit.
The Quran says that.
It says "I'll double... I will double the reward for you."
"And I will substitute all the sins of the
past into credits."
So every time, yes, we all do.
So every time, every time you called on Hussein or something,
that will be changed into credit
because of your repentance.
A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: So, Sheytan did not repent.
And he continued to think that he can rule
part of God's kingdom by himself.
And this is why he was not pardoned.
So, even worse than that, he stood up and
spoke to the angels,
and told them "God created me, and He gave
me all these powers."
"And I believe that I can help God, and be
His assistant, and rule part of the universe by myself."
This is what he said. "What is wrong with that? How can I fall prostrate to this tiny creature made of mud?"
Dr. Khalifa: And some angels agreed with him.
A woman: And Some angels did?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we had a division.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the Sheytan and his assistants, they became
jinns, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is in Sura 38.
A woman: Sura 38.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 38 says,
(38:69) مَا كَانَ لِىَ مِنْ عِلْمٍۭ بِٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ إِذْ يَخْتَصِمُونَ
A woman: Oh, my God.
Dr. Khalifa:
ٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ
is what?
Dr. Khalifa: The Highest Society, God and the angels.
يَخْتَصِمُونَ
They divided.
Now, in the movie, after this happened, I
had a ball of light came and took Sheytan,
and carried him to the planet earth, to his
prison, see.
This whole universe.
And also, all the other angels who agreed
with him, they became jinns.
A woman: La Elaha Ella Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
So, this is why he was not pardoned.
Adam and Hawa (Eve) were pardoned.
But not Sheytan, because he continued to insist that he can rule part of the, of the kingdon, God's kingdom by himself.
A woman: Rashad, I have a question. But when he said that most of them will not believe in You except Your servants, which are totally devoted to You, he was right. And in fact that's why it happened.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
A woman: But why did the Malaik (angels) (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: He said, but God wanted that. See?
Dr. Khalifa: God wanted to give him constituents to show...
I mean, look at the disasters, the accidents.
Dr. Khalifa: Remember the girl that came here on wheelchairs?
A woman: Yes. Jennifer.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is Jennifer.
Dr. Khalifa: She... this is a girl who came here briefly. She was studying religions.
But she was 17, 18 years old, a freshman at
the university.
Beautiful girl.
And she was riding in a car with her father
and her mother.
And there comes a drunk driver smashing their
car.
Her mother dies and her father almost dies.
His aorta was, got the operation. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And she is crippled for the rest of her life.
A woman: Terribly, too. Just completely. Just
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, from the neck down.
A woman: (unintelligible) Yeah.
A woman: And she has become (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: She looked at it.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm telling you, this girl would have been
healed if she continued to be... I really feel that.
A woman: I believe you're right. You know what, I think (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) become a Muslim.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Just about.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, almost.
Dr. Khalifa: He's just about. His sister and his mother became Muslim.
And now they're working on him.
A woman: Who's this?
A woman: Who?
Dr. Khalifa: Michael Jackson.
A woman: Michael Jackson.
A woman: Yeah, isn't that something?
A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH. IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: And how did the Malaik (angels) know about Adam
and his children that they are going to...?
Dr. Khalifa: God told them everything.
A woman: Bloodshed and...
A woman: Ah.
Dr. Khalifa: See, God told them everything. God told them...
A woman: He told them everything.
Dr. Khalifa: And He said that these creatures, the human
beings, they will not see Me.
He said "I'm going to have a perfect test
for Sheytan, to prove that he is an incompetent god."
And for this, I have created the human race.
They are people who have absolute freedom
of choice.
And those among them who side with Sheytan's
opinion, that I alone am not enough,
they will be his constituents.
We'll see if he can take care of them or not.
Okay? So, from the descriptions, from the description of of these conditions, the angels said "but this means that many
of them will choose Sheytan, and then they
will be divided, and they will have wars and bloodshed."
And God said "I know what you don't know."
A woman: And what was that?
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: was that... That was before the exposure of Shaytan.
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: He knew what was in Sheytan's head.
Dr. Khalifa: See, now we're going back.
A woman: But that was before.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, before Sheytan was exposed.
You see, because they said, you know what
they said?
They said,
أَتَجْعَلُ فِيهَا مَن يُفْسِدُ فِيهَا وَيَسْفِكُ ٱلدِّمَآءَ وَنَحْنُ نُسَبِّحُ
(2:30) بِحَمْدِكَ وَنُقَدِّسُ لَكَ
Are you familiar with that verse?
A woman: We just read it this afternoon.
Dr. Khalifa: They said نَحْنُ
Dr. Khalifa: The angels said "and we the angels,
نُسَبِّحُ بِحَمْدِكَ
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: "we glorify You, we praise Your Glory,
وَنُقَدِّسُ لَكَ
Dr. Khalifa: "and we hold You sacred."
A woman: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, the angels... when the angels said this, they were
not accurate.
Dr. Khalifa: Because there was one of them who was not doing this. They didn't know.
A woman: They didn't know. That's, that's the issue.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God said,
(2:30) إِنِّىٓ أَعْلَمُ مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God said "I know what you do not know."
Dr. Khalifa: Which is something...
Parivash: (unintelligible)
A woman: Allahu Akbar (God is Great).
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Also, this is why He said
"didn't I tell you that I know...
(2:33) أَعْلَمُ مَا تُبْدُونَ وَمَا كُنتُمْ تَكْتُمُونَ
"Didn't I tell you that I know what you declare,
and what you...
You know what's Katam?
Dr. Khalifa: Ketman?
Parivash: Yes. Ketman.
Parivash (Speaking Farsi): Concealed.
Dr. Khalifa: وَمَا تَكْتُمُونَ
A woman (Speaking Farsi): No, meaning (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Conceal.
Dr. Khalifa: "... you declare and what you conceal?"
أَلَمْ أَقُل لَّكُمْ إِنِّىٓ أَعْلَمُ مَا تُبْدُونَ
"declare"
وَمَا كُنتُمْ تَكْتُمُونَ
"And what you were hiding."
Because it became exposed, now.
Dr. Khalifa: The whole thing is in the Quran.
A woman: And that's the key
A woman: the key to the word?
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A woman: To Adam?
Dr. Khalifa: The key to Adam?
A woman: Yes, the words.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh, the names. Yes. he... God
A woman: The words. Yes. The names.
Dr. Khalifa: God taught him all the names, yes.
A woman: All the names and everything.
Dr. Khalifa: This is how we invented these machines, those videos, and cars, and this light. In other words, God gave Adam knowledge.
Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, so, where were we?
A woman: "I gave him knowledge."
Dr. Khalifa: Are you tired? I haven't started yet.
A woman: Then, the Sheytan, no.
Dr. Khalifa: Where were we?
A woman: The Malaik, they didn't know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, so now, those... Sheytan became confined
to this universe, this lowest universe.
A woman: And then in the...
Dr. Khalifa: Until the period of test is over. And we already see the results.
It is total chaos.
And I gave the example of this girl.
It's a tragedy.
A young girl crippled for life.
A drunk driver.
The woman dies. The man is injured.
And this is the kind of thing.
In the movie, I have her story in this movie.
And I have the drunk driver going there.
And one of Sheytan's assistants comes in the
car and takes over the drunk driver.
And actually, and tries to, tries to... I'm showing that Sheytan is
trying to have a perfect world, but he can't.
So, this sheytan (devil) is trying to steer the car
away from the other car where this girl was sitting.
But, but it's too late. He can't.
But because he took over this drunk driver,
he protected him.
So, which happens a lot.
So, the car is completely smashed.
And this guy opens the door and walks out, you know,
without a scratch.
You know, this drunk driver.
Even though the car is completely smashed.
And it happens. You see it a lot, happen, in accidents.
A woman: It's true. When the film will come out?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I don't know.
A woman: It will be fantastic.
Dr. Khalifa: Probably 5 years, 10 years. I don't know. When God wills. But we have it ready.
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A woman: Would you please answer this question?
I want to have that in the tape.
When people idol worship and ask the other
humans, the saints and everybody,
"Please give us this or heal us." Who is doing that?
Answer it, please.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, they are immediately out of God's kingdom.
See, the minute they ask anybody other than
God, they are out of God's kingdom.
They belong in Sheytan's kingdom.
And they actually, they take themselves out of
God's Mercy.
One of the...
It's, it's very simple things that take the people
out of God's kingdom.
There is the most prominent Mullah in the
Arab world today. It's Sheikh Metwalli Sha'rawi.
His name is Sheikh Metwalli Sha'rawi.
And I have a mutual friend.
One that is his friend and is my friend.
And he is trying to arrange a meeting between Sheikh Sha'rawi and myself, for 3 years now and it just never happens.
Something happens.
Like, I was supposed to meet him.
A woman: It cracked me up.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. I was supposed to meet him in Washington, for
example.
Dr. Khalifa: One time, then, his daughter got sick.
So, he went to see her somewhere.
So, I couldn't meet him.
And then, he came to Washington last January.
Last February. This last month.
And then, my father got sick.
So, I went to Egypt.
And I couldn't meet him. But anyway,
Sheikh Metwalli Sha'rawi is almost revered
by millions of Muslims in Egypt, Saudi Arabia and those places
like he's a holy imam, you know.
This Sheikh Sha'rawi.
And this is how he begins his speeches.
And if I ever meet him, I'm going to just
stay with his opening statement of his speeches.
He says,
الحمد الله رب العلمين والصلوة والسلام على اشرف المرسلین و خاتم النبیین سیدنا محمد وعلى آله وصحبه أجمعين
Now, the minute he makes that statement, he
is out of God's Mercy.
And he is not guided in his speeches.
He has to be on his own.
Because he's immediately in Sheytan's kingdom. And he doesn't even know it.
Because he says,
(1:2) ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
This, this is perfect.
And then, he mentions somebody else's name,
the Prophet Muhammad, but not only does he
put somebody with Him, he calls him
اشرف المرسلین
Parivash: اشرف المرسلین
Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, "the most honorable messenger."
Immediately, he broke the commandment that
says,
(2:285) لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رُّسُلِهِۦ ۚ وَقَالُوا۟ سَمِعْنَا وَأَطَعْنَا
Immediately, he broke the commandment that
came out of Muhammad's mouth.
A woman: Translate. Translate what he said.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Parivash: Yes, I...
A woman: I know. I want for the tape.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but for the tape.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, he called him
اشرف المرسلین
"the most honorable messenger"
So immediately, he broke the commandment that tells us "do
not make any distinction among the messengers of God."
And this is repeated in other places in Quran.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But in verse 285 of Sura 2, it is followed
immediately by the statement,
وَقَالُوا۟ سَمِعْنَا وَأَطَعْنَا
That the believers say "we hear and we obey."
Finished.
We will not make any distinction among the
messengers.
But here is Sheikh Sha'rawi saying,
اشرف المرسلین و خاتم النبیین
This is... okay, he is
خاتم النبیین
سیدنا
our master
سیدنا محمد
وعلى آله وصحبه أجمعين
So, I was gonna just hold him to that opening
and tell him "Sheikh Sha'rawi, you are out of God's Mercy."
Immediately, when you broke that commandment
that came out of...
Susan: That's what he does.
Dr. Khalifa: Susan.
Susan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Isn't it, isn't this what the Quran teach? I mean, isn't it logical?
A woman: You're right.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Where are you going?
A woman: I should go there because I don't want you to have the Dukhan (smoke) in the house.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, God bless you.
A woman: Dukhan.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
A woman: Dukhan is coming. Oh, no.
A woman: Here comes the Dukhan. We have two Dukhans now.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't, I don't mind it, but this is nice of you.
Dr. Khalifa: God bless you.
A woman: Thank you.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so we were saying, people when the... your question was, people who call on Jesus and Mary and Hussein
and Muhammad and Ali and all this, the minute, the minute
they call on them for any reason,
they're out, they're out of God's Mercy, they are immediately in
Sheytan's constituents.
It's just as simple as that.
Dr. Khalifa: And I was doing it for years and years.
A woman: So, all these people when they are in the...
A woman: I know, I was doing it, too.
Dr. Khalifa: So, thank God that
Dr. Khalifa: that I saw the light and came out.
A woman: So, all these people in churches, it shows
on TV.
They shake the head of the woman and say,
"hallelujah, Jesus healed this person and start walking"
that's Sheytan (Satan) healing that woman, not Jesus.
Dr. Khalifa: Not even Sheytan healing them. This is all fake.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: So, there is no reality?
Dr. Khalifa: No, they had, they had many TV programs, 60 minutes.
And some other TV programs, they showed that
all this is fake.
A woman: Alhamdu Lillah. I'm happier.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yeah.
A woman: Okay, anybody has any question (unintelligible) creation?
Dr. Khalifa: No, there is something that I wanna say. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: There is something that I want to say, but
I forgot. So, I'm gonna remember it, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: It was, did you finish, you said "I have it
in the movie that God sent Sheytan with a ball on the earth."
Did you finish that?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, see, Sheytan and all his, whoever agreed with
him were sent to this earth.
And Sura 38 talks about,
(38:69) ٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ إِذْ يَخْتَصِمُونَ
So, when this Feud
happened, we have two points of view.
One point of view says "Allah alone."
And this is God's point of view.
And the other point of view says "Allah and
someone else."
And now, we look at the Quran and we find
that the vast, vast majority of human beings
will side with Sheytan.
Sura number 12, verse 103.
It says,
(12:103) وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
Do you understand this?
وَمَآ
means "never", means "not."
وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ
means "the majority of people."
وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ
no matter how careful, no matter how hard you try
بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
they will not believe.
Most people, no matter what you do, will not
believe.
Okay?
Dr. Khalifa: This, this will not even believe in God.
A woman: You talk very kindly, they don't believe. You talk very roughly, they don't believe either.
A woman: That's true.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, no matter what you do.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
(12:103) وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
Okay, so now we know that the majority of
human beings will not believe in God. Period.
They just don't believe in God.
Now, the minority of people believe in God.
Now, we take this minority, look at this minority
in verse 106 of the same Sura, 12.
And it says,
(12:106) وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِٱللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
And the majority of those who believe in God
insist on putting other names with God.
So, the majority of believers in God are Mushriks (idol worshipers).
Therefore, the people who believe in God are
really the minority of a minority.
And this is a statement of fact.
It is not a law or a commandment or an order.
It's a statement of fact and we see it around us.
How many mosques in the world did you see
where only the name of Allah is honored and worshipped?
How many?
None.
A church, a synagogue, a mosque, a place of
worship, a temple, any place.
You don't find any.
You find one in Tucson and one in San Francisco
and one scattered around the world.
But these are very rare.
So, it is true that
(12:103) وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
(12:106) وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِٱللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
Except with other names with Allah.
They do not believe in Allah alone in other
words.
They do not believe in Allah without some
other names with Him.
Mary or Jesus or Muhammad and so forth.
A woman: I have a question which they ask me all the
time.
I want you to explain to them.
Ok. They said "God wanted to show the angels,
"Sheytan is arrogant and rebellious.
"That's why He created Adam and his descendants on the earth.
"Why God did that to us?
"And we have Sheytan in our hands and we have
God.
"And it's hard to choose.
"So, why do we call God is justice?
Dr. Khalifa: That's a very good question.
And it is perfectly...
The rule is that God does not inflict an atom's
weight of injustice.
(4:40) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ لَا يَظْلِمُ مِثْقَالَ ذَرَّةٍۢ
This is the law.
So, "why did God do this to us" is an invalid question.
It's not valid because we are the ones who did this to us.
Every single one of us was asked "Would you
like to have the freedom of choice or do you like to submit outright?"
And you and I and everybody said "No, we want
the freedom of choice.
Dr. Khalifa: Every single individual.
A woman: On that conference day?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Every single person was asked.
A woman: You mean the same verse 172?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no.
A woman: Which one?
Dr. Khalifa: This is verse, the end of Sura 33.
Dr. Khalifa: Al-Ahzãb (The Parties)
A woman: The end of Sura 33. Ok. Al-Ahzãb
(33:72) إِنَّا عَرَضْنَا ٱلْأَمَانَةَ عَلَى ٱلسَّمَـٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضِ وَٱلْجِبَالِ
A woman: Ok. We have the freedom of choice there?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa:
(33:72) فَأَبَيْنَ أَن يَحْمِلْنَهَا وَأَشْفَقْنَ مِنْهَا وَحَمَلَهَا وَحَمَلَهَا ٱلْإِنسَـٰنُ
Every human being, you and I and Parivash
and Senobar and Susan, Every human being on earth
was asked personally "Do you want
the freedom of choice or do you want outright submission?"
And every one of us said "we'll take the freedom
of choice."
You see, in that time, we thought it's very
easy.
You know, we said "oh, it's very easy. We're gonna choose you. We know You're the Master. You're our Lord." You know, it's very easy.
We underestimated the power of Sheytan.
A woman: That's right. We still do.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, of course.
I mean, even then, in that dimension, we underestimated
the power of Sheytan.
We said "who's gonna be stupid enough to choose this Sheytan, this creature of Yours? Who's going to choose you?
"It's very easy. Of course, we'll take the freedom of choice."
And this is why it says,
(33:72) إِنَّهُۥ كَانَ ظَلُومًۭا جَهُولًۭا
At the end, that the human being was stupid to do that.
Because we underestimated the power of Sheytan.
The power of Sheytan, he's so tricky.
And he dupes us, you know.
And you've met hundreds of people and you
see the amount of resistance when you tell them "God alone."
You say "Allah alone."
And the resistance is just too much.
And a lot of them, a lot of them are people with common sense
and logic and everything.
You tell them "God alone."
And the resistance is just fantastic.
And the majority don't make it.
99.9%.
They cannot break away from all the traditions
and customs that they inherited.
It took me 3 years to, when I wake up in the morning, to say "La Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah."
3 years to get rid of "Muhammad Rasul Allah."
Just one day, it dawned on me, I said "I'm gonna wake up on the Day of Resurrection saying
"La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasul Allah."
And Muhammad is a human being who is worried
with me, you know.
On the Day of Hashr, you call it Hashr?
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The Day of Hashr? Yawm Al-Hashr?
A woman (Speaking Farsi): Mahshar
Dr. Khalifa: Mahshar.
A woman: (Speaking Farsi): The Day of Hashr. Mahshar.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. On the Mahshar
Dr. Khalifa: See, the Prophet Muhammad
A woman: (Speaking Farsi): The Day of Mahshar.
Dr. Khalifa: Surat Al-Anbyã', Sura number 21, it says "The Prophet
"Muhammad and Moses, and Ibrahim, and all of them will
be in Mahshar. They will all be worried."
Dr. Khalifa: You know, what will happen to us?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: What I'm saying is, when they come to me,
for example, and say "you disrespect the Prophet Muhammad
"by not mentioning his name in your
Namaz."
Dr. Khalifa: If they come to me and say "you disrespect
the Prophet by not mentioning his name in the Namaz."
So, the answer to this is "disrespecting the
Prophet, or Ali, or Hussein, or any other Prophet, is a forgivable offense."
"But Shirk is not a forgivable offense. It's the only unforgivable offense."
Putting other names besides Allah is an unforgivable
offense.
Because the verse that is repeated in Sura
number 4 twice, that says, Allah does not
(4:48) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ لَا يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِۦ
God does not forgive Shirk.
(4:48) وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَٰلِكَ لِمَن يَشَآءُ
And He forgives anything else.
Murder, disrespecting a Prophet is forgivable.
Anything is forgivable.
But the only thing that is not forgivable
is Shirk.
Putting something next to God.
So, I am taking a chance on disrespecting...
if you want to accuse me of disrespecting
the Prophet, you cannot accuse me of being
Mushrik, of putting something besides Allah.
Because I say all my Namaz with only the name
of Allah in it, from beginning to end.
Only God.
Therefore, you cannot accuse me of Shirk,
which is the only unforgivable offense.
So, if you accuse me of disrespecting the
Prophet, I welcome that. This is a...
This is a forgivable offense.
But I tell them "for your information, I do
not disrespect the Prophet."
This is what the Prophet wants.
And this is what every Prophet wants.
La Elaha Ella Allah. God alone.
And this is what we find in Sura 21, verse
31, I think.
Where it says "every messenger I send with
only one message, La Elaha Ella Allah."
Now, notice there's something that we take
for granted by the way.
That La Elaha Ella Allah, which is the motto
of Islam, or the principle of Islam, La Elaha Ella Allah begins with La.
La Elaha Ella Allah
No other thing with Allah.
And you notice that in the Quran, every messenger
goes to the people and says
أَلَّا تَعْبُدُوٓا۟ إِلَّا ٱللَّهَ
My message is
that you shall not, a negative, you shall
not worship except Allah.
It doesn't say,
اعبدوا الله
worship God.
Because people worship God and go to Hell.
They worship God and they also put some other
names beside Him.
And this is why the consistent message in Quran is
أَلَّا تَعْبُدُوٓا۟ إِلَّا ٱللَّهَ
It's a negative commandment.
That you shall not worship except Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is the accuracy of Quran.
A woman: Now, you know why you always keep telling me "Mary, don't say that, don't bring them."
I said "I can't help it."
This is... There is only God. You have to talk only
God because I knew it. It's a responsibility.
A woman: I felt for you guys.
A woman: Now you know how I felt.
Dr. Khalifa: This is why...
Dr. Khalifa: This is why the reward is so fantastic.
In other words, you say "La Elaha Ella Allah" and you do it,
only Allah is in your mind, in your life,
in all your thoughts and no other names with Him,
you're a king or queen on earth.
You enter God's Kingdom where there is no
disease, no headache, no problem, no traffic tickets.
Really. Perfect life.
This is, I find this the most difficult thing for the
people to believe.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is why I wish you were here for the
last Khutba on Friday.
A woman: I wish.
Dr. Khalifa: I was bragging about everybody in this mosque,
you know, I say "the people here, you just..." because
we have beautiful babies, Alhamdu Lillah, Mã Shã Allãh.
You have to say Alhamdu Lillah and Mã Shã Allãh.
And I was saying it with every statement.
And we have people who left the Masjid.
And they had deformed babies.
I mean, things that we see with our own eyes.
And it's because when you come, especially
in places like your Masjid, this Masjid,
when you come to the message of God alone, and
you reject it, Whoa.
You see, when you come to the message of God
alone, Sheytan hates you.
But he cannot touch you because you're protected. You have guards around you, other angels.
A woman: Exactly like her.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You have angels around you, guarding you.
When you say God alone, no other names with Him.
A woman: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: But then, Sheytan is very angry with you and
mad at you because you rejected his point of view.
But the minute you step out of God's Kingdom, he's waiting for you and he beats you up, you know. And it's really disastrous.
In the movie that I wrote, I had... there's a Rabbi
in Boston, Rabbi Kushner is his name.
He wrote a book that says "Why Bad Things
Happen to Good People."
This is the title of the book.
And of course, bad things don't happen to
good people. Never.
This is God's promise in the Quran.
And this is a new age.
We are now in a new age where things are straightforward.
You stay with God and everything is perfect.
Not in the old times where you had to go and
prove yourself by giving your life
and being killed as a Shahid (Martyr) for God, you know. This is...
Because now it's all mental.
We are educated people.
There's a lot of science. And...
And the whole thing is by logic and by thinking.
So, once you make a decision, logically, to
be with God, then you are proven.
And you are immediately in God's Kingdom and
you are immediately protected.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm forgetting what I want to say. It's very important.
A woman: The Rabbi of Boston.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Yeah. Rabbi Kushner wrote that book "Why Bad Things Happen to Good People."
He had a child that had a disease called progeria,
Rapid aging disease.
The child became aged very fast. In 14 years, the child died.
So, the Rabbi and his wife were suffering
and the child was suffering, was miserable.
And he mentions it in the book for 14 years.
And in the book, his explanation of why bad
things happen to good people,
is that "God is unable to control the world."
"That God is crying with you."
"And God really wants you to be healthy, but
He just can't help it."
"There are too many people", you know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. And he goes to ridiculous lengths.
He says "are you willing to forgive God?"
You know, "and realize His inability."
"Just like you forgive your parents", etc, etc.
I mean, it's just blasphemous.
And you can see exactly why his son became like
this.
Now, here is a Rabbi who preaches the worship
of God.
Alright?
He preaches the worship of God.
A woman: La Elaha Ella Allah
Dr. Khalifa: And Satan is angry at him.
So, in the movie, I have somebody like him
preaching the worship of God.
And then, this woman and her husband are crying,
coming out of the church.
And asking him that their son was hit with
a car and died or something.
And they were crying.
And they're asking the priest or the minister "why did this happen?", and so forth.
And he says "believe me, God is crying with
you."
"And it's just... this is out of control."
In other words, I'm taking it from the book
of the Rabbi.
And then, next, I show the Rabbi sitting in
his home, watching the TV with his wife.
And his wife is pregnant.
And then, Sheytan comes in through the wall.
And he goes into her body and plays with the
baby.
You know, in the script.
And then, the baby is born deformed.
So, these are things that we actually see
happening.
So, this is why bad things happen because he blasphemes against God.
Do you think this Rabbi is in God's Kingdom?
Will he be protected?
So, the idea here is that Satan is the cause
of all these disasters.
First, his incompetence, his inability.
Second, his deliberate bad actions against
the people who do not side with his opinion,
once they step out of God's protection.
So, and this is why the retribution is doubled
for people who see the message.
Once you see the message, and you see God
alone, there is a double responsibility here.
You accept it, or you reject it.
If you accept it, you continue to be protected
from Satan, Sheytan.
But if you reject it, then you gave up God's
protection.
Dr. Khalifa: And Sheytan will play havoc with you.
A woman: Dr. Khalifa, I have a question.
It's different to the subject we are talking
about.
It's about the Salat (Contact Prayer).
Before the Salat, ablution is really important,
that's for sure.
But if we just get out of the shower, do we
have to do it again?
Dr. Khalifa: No, you do the ablution in the shower.
Dr. Khalifa: You go through the motions in the same order. Yes.
A woman: In the shower. Ok.
A woman: Ok. (unintelligible) That's good.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: See, the idea... remember the order?
Dr. Khalifa: The face, the arms, the hair, and the feet.
A woman: Yeah. Of course. I always do it
A woman: but I heard some people said,
in Hadith, it says only Ghusl Janabat is the only thing.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: But I...
Dr. Khalifa: Even in Ghusl Janabat, you have to do the Wudu.
A woman: You have to do the ablution in this direction.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Ok.
A woman: Another thing that I have is about, again, the
Salat.
In the midnight, when you wake up, and you
wanna do the Salat, do you have to do in
any direction, or you can do anything you
want?
Dr. Khalifa: Direction of Mecca, yes.
A woman: No, no, no. That's not what I mean.
A woman: I mean, for example, you can do 2 Rak'at,
4 Rak'at, whatever you want.
Dr. Khalifa: Anything.
A woman: Anything.
And another thing is, can you do it like kind
of meditation
just sit straight towards the Qibla, and just
meditate with God?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: Which one is better in Quran, within the Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: Whatever you feel like.
Dr. Khalifa: It's up to you. Whatever your heart tells you.
A woman: But you have to get out of the bed, and get
up, and do it.
A woman: Not in the bed.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't have to do anything. It's not required.
Dr. Khalifa: That's extra.
A woman: Can we do it in the bed?
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
I mean, that's not required in the middle
of the night.
It's not required.
Dr. Khalifa: That's extra.
A woman: That's the extra (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: It's beautiful. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: That's not required.
A man & a woman: (unintelligible)
A woman: When you are praying for people, for example, for
the the war, for the wars, for the
people you know, OK, the praying, how is it supposed
to be, the praying?
I know it's only ask of God.
But how?
Just mention the name, or what? I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: OK, the Prayers are given in the Quran.
The prayer for others, God teaches us how
to do it.
It says, for example,
رَبَّنَا ٱغْفِرْ لَنَا وَلِإِخْوَٰنِنَا ٱلَّذِينَ سَبَقُونَا بِٱلْإِيمَـٰنِ وَلَا تَجْعَلْ فِى
(59:10) قُلُوبِنَا غِلًّۭا لِّلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟
So, it's always, you cannot ask forgiveness
for a Mushrik, for an idol worshipper.
Because the example of Ibrahim. He asked forgiveness
for his father.
And this was wrong.
Why is it wrong?
Because God said "I do not forgive the idol
worshipper."
And you turn around and you say "please God,
forgive this idol worshipper."
This means you're not accepting God's decision
not to forgive, never to forgive the idol worshipper who dies.
By the way, a person who is an idol worshipper
at the time of death.
For example, I was an idol worshipper for
a long time, but I repented.
I discovered what the truth is.
Dr. Khalifa: But if the idol worship is maintained until
the time of death, then this is where it is unforgivable. It's finished.
A woman: Excuse me.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Even the Prophet Muhammad, and this upsets
a lot of people, he was an idol worshipper.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is in the Quran.
A woman: And this is the Quran.
A woman: It says in Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: See, and this shocks them. You know, they refuse
to see it. They don't wanna see it.
A woman: But he repented though.
Dr. Khalifa: Of course.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, this makes a better teacher out of
him.
Because I understand the mentality of the
Mushriks.
I understand how the people go before the
saint and pray to the saint.
Because I did it.
And for me, it was very valuable education.
So, this makes a better messenger out of Muhammad,
that he was just like the rest of his society.
Yes, in Sura 40, verse 66.
Dr. Khalifa: No?
It says "I was stopped from worshipping what you worshipped when the clear revelations came to me." I mean, it's...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: What Sura?
Dr. Khalifa: 66 of Sura 40.
A woman: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: They refuse to believe God, you know. They know better than God. They say "no, Muhammad was pure and beautiful."
"He never did anything like that."
A woman: No, it says very straight in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: There's some crazy guy out there on the street. Drunk, drunk (unintelligible).
It says,
(93:7) وَوَجَدَكَ ضَآلًّۭا فَهَدَىٰ
Like you say "zallan,"
Right?
So, he was
ضَآلًّۭا
And God guided him when...
But they refuse that.
My father wouldn't accept it.
I say "was he Zallan or not?
He said "no, he wasn't."
I said "God says he was."
"Do you know better than God?
Dr. Khalifa: You know, I tell him.
A woman: It's amazing because he knows how to read Arabic.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Exactly.
A woman: And I always beg him to go learn Arabic more and more.
Dr. Khalifa: Makes no difference. What did I tell you? See?
A woman: Now, I know you told
Dr. Khalifa: My father, there is nobody who knows Arabic better than my father.
A woman: me that statement.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean he studied the Nahv, the grammar, everything
that has to do with Arabic.
He memorized the Quran since he was 8 years
old.
Dr. Khalifa: He never lost it.
A woman: What he says about that verse?
(93:7) وَوَجَدَكَ ضَآلًّۭا فَهَدَىٰ
?
Dr. Khalifa: He said "he wasn't."
A woman: But that says...
Dr. Khalifa: He refuses. I know.
A woman: What you did?
Dr. Khalifa: I said "you're telling God "I know better than You. I know Muhammad better than You.""
A woman: Allahu Akbar. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Absolutely.
A woman: Listen to this question.
You, you had this question some times ago.
A woman: When somebody dies.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh no, I didn't finish that point.
A woman: You didn't finish that point.
Dr. Khalifa: I was saying that God says that I do not forgive
idol worship.
And then, you turn around and you say "please, God forgive this idol worshiper."
This is why Ibrahim was reprimanded when he
said "please, God forgive my father."
So, the proper way for this situation is to
say "please, God guide my father to the right path, to the right way."
You can pray for guidance, but not for forgiveness
if the person is an idol worshiper.
Like in the case of my father, I cannot ask
for his forgiveness.
Because God already said "I do n. t forgive
idol worship."
So, I can't go against God.
I can only say "please, God guide my father
to the right path."
So, this is an example of the prayer.
And this is why when you read the Quran, the
prayer of Quran for the others, God teaches us by saying,
(59:10) رَبَّنَا ٱغْفِرْ لَنَا وَلِإِخْوَٰنِنَا ٱلَّذِينَ سَبَقُونَا بِٱلْإِيمَـٰنِ
So, they had Iman (belief). They're Mu'mins (believers).
(59:10) وَلَا تَجْعَلْ فِى قُلُوبِنَا غِلًّۭا لِّلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟
It's always consistently.
So, you can ask for forgiveness to the believers.
Dr. Khalifa: The little things that we do.
A woman: The believers who are dead?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, it could be, it could be for the believers who died.
Dr. Khalifa: Could be, as long as, as long as you specify the believers.
A woman: The believers. Yes. That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: But didn't you say last time...
Dr. Khalifa: But you cannot name, you cannot name a person.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Because you do not know if this person is
a believer or a Mushrik.
A woman: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is why when the Quran teaches us,
it makes it general. It says,
(59:10) رَبَّنَا ٱغْفِرْ لَنَا وَلِإِخْوَٰنِنَا ٱلَّذِينَ سَبَقُونَا بِٱلْإِيمَـٰنِ
Those who were before us, the Mu'mins before us.
A woman: When one of our relative dies, or friend,
or whoever we know,
is this help if we, you just said "yes, it helps
to pray."
But we cannot pray in the name of like, for
my father, for my mother.
A woman: And say that...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, wait.
I didn't say it helps.
Dr. Khalifa: I didn't say it helps anybody.
A woman: So, okay, then I was confused.
Dr. Khalifa: You misunderstood.
A woman: Because you told me it doesn't help before.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, it doesn't help anybody.
Dr. Khalifa: But...
A woman: But when somebody dies, it's finished.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: It's his, it's whatever he did.
A woman: Then, why do they say "you can do it."
Dr. Khalifa: It's whatever he did.
Dr. Khalifa: It's very important. Du'a (prayer) is very important.
I'll tell you why.
Dr. Khalifa: You're saying "please God, forgive us and
forgive the believers before us.
A woman: Do you want me to turn on the extra light?
Dr. Khalifa: Sure. Sure.
A woman: Yes, this is very important.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the Du'a is very important.
I'll tell you why.
I read, they have a question and answer in
a famous newspaper.
Or you can do the other one, leave it the other
one, so we can see the outside.
Dr. Khalifa: Keep the outside light on.
A woman: On?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. This way we see if anybody is coming or what.
And I will leave that, I will leave this on and turn this off.
This is the best effect.
Here we have a queen turning the lights off
for us.
No, the other one. Yeah.
Here.
Nice
You can say "please God, forgive the believers
before us", because they were believers.
And the believers are all brothers and sisters.
God said,
(49:10) إِنَّمَا ٱلْمُؤْمِنُونَ إِخْوَةٌۭ
So, your real brothers and sisters are the
believers.
Because, even though you're not my sister,
from my father and my mother,
when you worship God alone and I worship God alone, we're gonna be together forever.
And my brothers and sisters were in the same house
with me for 10-15 years.
But a believing brother and sister will be
for millions of years, for eternity.
So, this is the real brotherhood.
(49:10) إِنَّمَا ٱلْمُؤْمِنُونَ إِخْوَةٌۭ
A woman: That's beautiful.
Dr. Khalifa: So, when you say "please God, forgive the
believers", you're really praying for your brothers and sisters
who will be with you in the same place forever,
and for a long time.
The question was in the newspaper "why does
God want us to pray to Him?"
Because God says,
(40:60) وَقَالَ رَبُّكُمُ ٱدْعُونِىٓ أَسْتَجِبْ لَكُمْ
God says in the Quran "pray to Me, and I will
respond to you."
(40:60) وَقَالَ رَبُّكُمُ ٱدْعُونِىٓ أَسْتَجِبْ لَكُمْ
So, the question was "why does God want us..." if everything is written down already,
"your videotape, my videotape, from birth to
death, are written down, recorded,
"so why pray?"
That was the question.
It turns out, the importance of prayer is,
it is a fantastic form of worship.
Because, first of all, it indicates that you
do believe in God.
In other words, if you don't believe in God, I mean,
who are you talking to?
"Please, God, forgive the believers."
Who are you talking to?
It indicates, it declares to Sheytan, God
points at you and says "See this, this person believes in Me."
Because nobody will pray to a non-existent imaginary
entity.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Nobody will pray to God if they didn't believe.
When you say "please God, give me a million
dollars."
Ok. Even though it's a materialistic prayer,
but it does indicate that you believe in God.
It"s the best form of declaring that the
person believes in God.
"Please God, give me a million dollars."
Who are you talking to?
To God.
So, this is the importance of Du'a.
"Please God, heal my sickness." You know.
"Please God, remove the headache I have."
So, you're praying, it proves that you believe
in God.
This is why God says,
(40:60) وَقَالَ رَبُّكُمُ ٱدْعُونِىٓ أَسْتَجِبْ لَكُمْ
Because every action that we
do, God is pointing at us and says "see, he believes in Me."
"He worships Me."
Or, Sheytan will say "see, he cannot worship
You alone. They have to mention Jesus next to You."
So, to every person, this life is all for
a test.
Everything else is just a waste of time.
Everything else we do.
We are here for the test.
(67:2) ٱلَّذِى خَلَقَ ٱلْمَوْتَ وَٱلْحَيَوٰةَ لِيَبْلُوَكُمْ
And God created death, because initially there
was no death.
Dr. Khalifa: But God created death and life
لِيَبْلُوَكُمْ
to test you, put you to the test.
A woman: There are some people asking me questions
about, like, you know we are going through the test now.
And, Alhamdu Lillah, it doesn't bother us at all.
We're really strong now.
A woman: But they are very worried about
Dr. Khalifa: the test.
A woman: Two of them, they really didn't worry, because
they have a good life without any problem.
And then, they were asking "what's happening? Aren't we a good people? We don't go through the test?"
I said "yes, you are."
But, I don't know how better I can explain it.
A woman: Can you explain it again?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, don't ever, don't ever ask for a test.
I mean, believe me, you're being tested enough
thoroughly.
Before you finish this life, you're gonna
be proven exactly if you believe in God alone,
or if you believe in God and some others besides
Him, or you don't believe in God at all.
You're gonna be completely... this is Sura
29, verse 2.
Dr. Khalifa: It says "do the people think they'll be
left to say "we believe" without being put to the test?"
Parivash: Sura 2, Baqarah
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 29.
Parivash: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 29, verse 2.
Parivash: verse 2, yeah, that's right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 29, Aya (verse) number 2.
Parivash: And even Sura 2, it says too, the same thing.
Dr. Khalifa: So, one... Of course, yeah.
وَلَنَبْلُوَنَّكُم بِشَىْءٍۢ مِّنَ ٱلْخَوْفِ وَٱلْجُوعِ وَنَقْصٍۢ مِّنَ ٱلْأَمْوَٰلِ
(2:155) وَٱلْأَنفُسِ وَٱلثَّمَرَٰتِ
Everybody must be tested.
But, the test never hurts permanently.
The test is characterized...There are tests
and there is punishment.
And the difference is, the punishment can
leave permanent damage.
But the test does not leave a permanent damage.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't lose a finger, for example.
A woman: You lose your money and stuff so...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you lose things... you lose 1000 dollars.
When God sends you 10,000. After the test is over and you pass it, then God sends 10,000 to make up for that 1000.
Dr. Khalifa: So, because the material goes and comes.
A woman: Well, you said...
Dr. Khalifa: You just throw your car, you know, or something, and God sends you enough money to make it up after you pass the test.
So, you can tell these people that if you
are with God, you're gonna be put to the test to prove the following.
That you believe in God under all circumstances.
Rich and poor.
Health and sick.
Under all circumstances.
Once this is established, there's a final
test.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, you are appointed king or queen on earth.
A woman: And, OK, then, for example, if we ask for test, that's damaging.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't ask for test.
A woman: More?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: No, I'm asking this for the people, they are in...
Dr. Khalifa: Don't ever...
A woman: Yeah, I know.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't ever ask for test.
A woman: "(unintelligible) don't You put us under test."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, there is a prayer.
A woman: (unintelligible) Du'a (prayer).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: OK, then, you ask God for the material and the Hereafter.
Dr. Khalifa: It's OK.
Dr. Khalifa: It's OK. Perfectly alright.
A woman: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Remember I said, because it is a form of worship,
and because it indicates that you believe
in God, even though you're asking for a million
dollars or something materialistic.
A woman: Ok.
A woman: And one more to last.
A woman: It is Mahmoud...
Dr. Khalifa: Really?
A woman: For now.
Dr. Khalifa: No way. Yeah.
A woman: Mahmoud asked me about the different Suras.
I asked you already last night, but I wanna refresh it again.
And the verses, when you read the verses,
some of them they're repeated so often.
And some of them, they are in a place.
It does...It's just changing the subject by the sudden. Why?
Dr. Khalifa: OK, practically every page of Quran says
"Worship God alone. Worship God alone."
A woman: Yeah.
"Worship God alone", every page. Is it doing any good?
A woman: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Is it?
A woman: No, it doesn't.
Dr. Khalifa: It is not.
Dr. Khalifa: It's not. Still the vast, vast majority of people have
to mention names with Allah.
So, this is why subjects are repeated over
and over.
So that, when you open the Quran at random...
see, I opened it at random, right?
And I read, it says
[12:97]  They said, "O our father, pray for forgiveness of our sins; we have been really wrong."
[12:98]  He said, "I will implore my Lord to forgive you; He is the Forgiver, Most Merciful."
This is Sura Yousuf, the story of Joseph.
And it says, oh my gosh, it says here
[12:103]  The majority of people, no matter what you do, will not believe.
A woman: Yes.
A woman: Subhan Allah
A woman: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa:
[12:104]  Even though you do not ask them for any wage...
A woman: La Elaha Ella Allah. That's right.
Dr. Khalifa:
[12:104]  ...For this is a message to all the people.
[12:105]  And even though the heavens and the earth
are full of signs, they pass by them totally heedless!
[12:106]  And the majority of those who believe, fall
into idol worship.
So, every page in the Quran, so you get the
message from here that you must worship God alone.
That it is very difficult, that the majority of
people flunk the test.
They flunk the first test, the majority, of
believing in God.
And then once they pass this test and they
believe in God, then Sheytan works on adding other names with God.
And when they pass this test, he divides them.
Maliki and Hanafi and Shafi'i and Sunni and
Shia and so forth.
So, this is why there are certain subjects
repeated in the Quran.
It's to increase the chance of people seeing
them.
Like you saw now.
You open the Quran at random, and this subject
of idol worship is repeated.
Dr. Khalifa: Almost every page.
A woman: Thank you very much.
Dr. Khalifa: You're welcome.