أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيْمِ
(36:2) يسٓ (36:1) وَٱلْقُرْءَانِ ٱلْحَكِيمِ
(36:4) إِنَّكَ لَمِنَ ٱلْمُرْسَلِينَ (36:3) عَلَىٰ صِرَٰطٍ مُّسْتَقِيمٍ
(36:5) تَنزِيلَ ٱلْعَزِيزِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(36:6) لِتُنذِرَ قَوْمًا مَّآ أُنذِرَ ءَابَآؤُهُمْ فَهُمْ غَـٰفِلُونَ
(36:7) لَقَدْ حَقَّ ٱلْقَوْلُ عَلَىٰٓ أَكْثَرِهِمْ فَهُمْ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ
(36:8) إِنَّا جَعَلْنَا فِىٓ أَعْنَـٰقِهِمْ أَغْلَـٰلًا فَهِىَ إِلَى ٱلْأَذْقَانِ فَهُم مُّقْمَحُونَ
وَجَعَلْنَا مِنۢ بَيْنِ أَيْدِيهِمْ سَدًّا وَمِنْ خَلْفِهِمْ سَدًّا فَأَغْشَيْنَـٰهُمْ فَهُمْ لَا يُبْصِرُونَ (36:9)
(36:10) وَسَوَآءٌ عَلَيْهِمْ ءَأَنذَرْتَهُمْ أَمْ لَمْ تُنذِرْهُمْ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ
إِنَّمَا تُنذِرُ مَنِ ٱتَّبَعَ ٱلذِّكْرَ وَخَشِىَ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنَ بِٱلْغَيْبِ ۖ فَبَشِّرْهُ  بِمَغْفِرَةٍ وَأَجْرٍ كَرِيمٍ (36:11)
Our guest is doctor Rashad Khalifa, who - he
devoted most of his life for his own mission,
reading, learning, writing, researching and
also preaching. But he is most remembered
by his last computer research, the divine
mathematical codes in the Quran based on number
19. According to the Quran, SURA number 74, verse number 30:
عَلَيْهَا تِسْعَةَ عَشَرَ
"over it are nineteen. But why 19?
That's what doctor Khalifa will explain
in this interview. Please, brothers and sisters
in Islam, welcome with me, doctor Rashad Khalifa.
Doctor Khalifa, I know I didn't introduce
you well enough...
Dr. Khalifa: You did very well.
Abdel Rahman: ...and I think the best
way to introduce you is to introduce yourself.
with your own words.
Dr. Khalifa: You did a good job. This is what really counts.
I did a research in the Quran, and I was blessed
by ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA to see the mathematical
code in the Quran. And this is really sufficient
for an introduction.
Abdel Rahman: Well, I think...
Dr. Khalifa: You did a good job, so we'll keep it like that.
Abdel Rahman: Thank you,
Abdel Rahman: But I think also we are entitled
to know how much benefit this...
It's great. It's honor actually to have
it, but we would like to know how this mathematical
codes goes and how far it's benefit, and beneficial
to the Muslim in his own living life? I mean,
the Quran is filled with miracles, and there's a lot of ways to approve that the Quran
is miracle. If you read it in Arabic, you
will see a lot of verses appliesto itself
that the Quran it's miracle and it's the
word, really the word of God. But...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is the first physical evidence.
The Quran is full of miracles, but all of
them are disputable, the linguistic excellence,
the scientific miracles, and all these things.
The Quran is full of miracles, but the mathematical
miracle is indisputable. It's physical
based on physical facts. Like BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIMbeing 19 letters, the
number of SURAs being 114. All these are
physical facts, like the sun rising from the
east. It is indisputable unlike the previous
miracles. So, and this is in accordance with God's
will in SURA of 41 verse 53, where God says
سَنُرِيهِمْ ءَايَـٰتِنَا فِى ٱلْـَٔافَاقِ
This is in the future tense. سَنُرِيهِمْ "We
will show them our miracles in the horizons,
and within themselves, until they realize
that this is the truth." So, the miracles of
the Quran are increasingly powerful. And then
we get to this mathematical miracle which
is described by God Himself as "one of the
greatest miracles." The SURA that you mentioned
74 عَلَيْهَا تِسْعَةَ عَشَرَ the verse 30, and then the verses go on and on, saying
that this is one of the greatest miracles. It says
(74:32) كَلَّا وَٱلْقَمَرِ
(74:33) وَٱلَّيْلِ إِذْ أَدْبَرَ
(74:34) وَٱلصُّبْحِ إِذَآ أَسْفَرَ
(74:35) إِنَّهَا لَإِحْدَى ٱلْكُبَرِ
It is one of the greatest miracles, and this
is God's own description of it.
Abdel Rahman: You mean here the miracles, it's the computer
age, right? That's whatALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA... I noticed...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the computer age...
Abdel Rahman: I noticed, excuse me for this, I noticed
you used God. You didn’t use ALLAH
which the Quran always says is ALLAH, because
the Quran came in Arabic. It didn't come
in English or in Persian. It come. قُرْءَٰنًا عَرَبِيًّۭا
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, I did say ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA
at least one time...
Abdel Rahman: I noticed you said God...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, it depends on what language you speak.
If you speak English, you have to say God.
If you speak Arabic, you have to ALLAH. So...
Because as you know, you're from Egypt
and you know the Egyptian cops use the word ALLAH.
They say IN SHAA ALLAH. They say MA SHA ALLAH. And
some of them are named ABDULLAH.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, ALLAH is the Arabic word and has nothing
to do....
Abdel Rahman: You mean using God, it's already okay?
Dr. Khalifa: Of course it is... .
It depends on what language you use. If you
meet somebody in the street and say ALLAH
here in the United States, some people think
ALLAH is a man who is named ALLAH, or ALLAH
is a rock somewhere. And this is an actual
happening. My son was in a class where
they told that ALLAH is a rock. My son had to
object.
Abdel Rahman: But this we have nothing to do with this because
you know there are...
Dr. Khalifa: What I mean is, it depends on what language
you use. If you use English, you have to use
God. If you use French, you have to use Dieu.
If you use Farsi, you have to use KHODA.
If you use Arabic, you have to use ALLAH.
Abdel Rahman: Let's go back again also to the computer.
I would like to know how far it's beneficial
to the human being. You know, I'm a Muslim and you
discovered that the computer age discovered
that the Quran... you discovered...
Dr. Khalifa: You're asking about the role of the mathematical
code...
Abdel Rahman: Yes, to the Muslims.
...as it applies to the Muslims and the non-Muslims.
This is mentioned in the Quran immediately
after the number 19. It says...it gives
you 5 reasons for the number 19. It says
وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ
that we made their number,
for the following reasons:
Number 1
فِتْنَةًۭ لِّلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا۟
to disturb
the disbelievers
فِتْنَةًۭ لِّلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا۟
to prove their disbelief.
لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ ٱلَّذِينَ أُوتُوا۟ ٱلْكِتَـٰبَ
This is the number 2 reason
is to make the believers among the Christians
and the Jews certain that this book, the Quran,
is from God.
لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ ٱلَّذِينَ أُوتُوا۟ ٱلْكِتَـٰبَ
Number 3
وَيَزْدَادَ ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوٓا۟ إِيمَـٰنًۭا
So, the people who believe that the Quran is
from God, before the number 19, without
the number 19, when they see the mathematical
code they will increase in faith.
يَزْدَادَ ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوٓا۟ إِيمَـٰنًۭا
And the fourth reason.
وَلَا يَرْتَابَ ٱلَّذِينَ أُوتُوا۟ ٱلْكِتَـٰبَ وَٱلْمُؤْمِنُونَ
If any of the Muslims, or
the Christians, or the Jews have any doubt
in their heart that this book, the Quran, is from God,
the mathematical code will help remove all
this doubt.
Number 5 in the verse says
وَلِيَقُولَ ٱلَّذِينَ فِى قُلُوبِهِم مَّرَضٌۭ وَٱلْكَـٰفِرُونَ مَاذَآ أَرَادَ ٱللَّهُ بِهَـٰذَا مَثَلًۭا
And to expose the hypocrites
and the disbelievers, they will say "so what?
this is not important."
So, these are the five reasons that God Himself
gives as the role of the number 19 or the
mathematical code in the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Make the Muslim strongly believe that the
Quran from God.
But there's SURAs, there's AYAs in the Quran by Arabic
approve to the Muslim
and non-Muslim that the Quran is miracle,
it's the word of God. Like, for example, like
(39:5) يُكَوِّرُ ٱلَّيْلَ عَلَى ٱلنَّهَارِ
ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, He said, He make... He cover the
globe with the night and...
Dr. Khalifa: He rolls the day around the night, and the
night around the day, proving that the
Earth is round.
Abdel Rahman: Ah, how, how the messenger of God approved
this? How the messenger of God knows that?
In the centuries later, there is such... to
approve this. So, if we go through the Quran, we will
find a lot...
Dr. Khalifa: So, let us say that this verse will cause someone
to believe in the Quran.
(39:5) يُكَوِّرُ ٱلَّيْلَ عَلَى ٱلنَّهَارِ وَيُكَوِّرُ ٱلنَّهَارَ عَلَى ٱلَّيْلِ
This person when he or she looks at
the mathematical code, God says in the Quran
- not I am saying - God says that his belief
will increase. His faith will increase.
يَزْدَادَ ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوٓا۟ إِيمَـٰنًۭا
So, this is an additional confirmation or assurance or increase in faith.
Abdel Rahman: Alright. There is also another thing. You
believe, you know, when you talk now you don't
believe in Hadith or Sunnah. Do you believe
in Hadith or Sunnah?
Dr. Khalifa: I believe that the Quran is complete, perfect
and fully detailed because God says so in
the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: And we don't have to use Hadith or Sunnah
at all?
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't matter or any other source.
Abdel Rahman: I noticed in the prayer here, you never mentioned
the messenger of God, like, you ignored him completely.
Abdel Rahman: Do you have anything against him? Because
you ignored... you said...
Dr. Khalifa: Is it true that I mentioned...
Abdel Rahman: Yeah, you say ALLAH, then when you prayed, you
prayed, you read Fateha, but you didn't
read Quran, you know. Something, it's actually
- I hope you will correct me if I'm mistaken
or something - new to me, new to any Muslim,
because we know that when we stay, we say
الله. اشهد ان لا اله الا الله و ان محمد رسول الله
This is about Islam. You can't separate it. You can't say
اشهد ان لا اله الا الله
I bear witness there is
no god but one God and you hold that the messenger
Muhammad is the messenger of God. If you hold
it, you mean you shall not..
Dr. Khalifa: Is that right?
Abdel Rahman: Well that's what I believe. I hope we will...
Dr. Khalifa: Let's look in the Quran again. If you look in the Quran, the Quran gives us the correct SHAHADA.
And this is in SURA number 3, verse
18 it says
شَهِدَ ٱللَّهُ أَنَّهُۥ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَٱلْمَلَٰٓئِكَةُ وَأُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ قَآئِمًۢا بِٱلْقِسْطِ
So, the SHAHADA according to ALLAH,
the angels, and those who know
أُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ
is
لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا الله
There is no محمد رسول الله there. This is one thing.
شَهِدَ ٱللَّهُ أَنَّهُۥ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَٱلْمَلَٰٓئِكَةُ وَأُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ
So, this is the correct SHAHADA
as dictated in the Quran. When you say
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
you violate the most basic commandment in
the Quran. The first one is the principle
of TAWHEED. You are not commemorating God
Alone. You are putting a name besides God,
another name beside God. You are making distinction
among the messengers of God. This is an important
commandment that you see in SURA 2 verse
285,for example. It's mentioned four times
in the Quran that you do not make, you shall
not make any distinction among the messengers
of God. And it is done so powerfully that any Muslim who makes distinction is not a Muslim at all
because the Quran says
لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رُّسُلِهِۦ ۚ وَقَالُوا۟ سَمِعْنَا وَأَطَعْنَا
and these are the MU'MENs
ءَامَنَ ٱلرَّسُولُ بِمَآ أُنزِلَ إِلَيْهِ مِن رَّبِّهِۦ وَٱلْمُؤْمِنُونَ ۚ كُلٌّ ءَامَنَ بِٱللَّهِ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتِهِۦ وَكُتُبِهِۦ وَرُسُلِهِۦ لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رُّسُلِهِۦ ۚ وَقَالُوا۟ سَمِعْنَا وَأَطَعْنَا ۖ
Abdel Rahman: That is the Muslim, he doesn't, he shouldn't have to say
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
but
he believe لا اله الا الله and he believe
all the messengers of ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, they
are equal, no distinction between...
Dr. Khalifa: When was the last time you said
لا اله الا الله یونس رسول الله
Abdel Rahman: Well, you actually do not say YUNES. When
you say...
Dr. Khalifa: Answer my question. When was the last time
you said
لا اله الا الله یونس رسول الله
Abdel Rahman: I hope you will understand me. I'm not debating
you. I'm not arguing with you. I am...
Dr. Khalifa: No no, I am trying to demonstrate the points
of the distinction among the prophets.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: When was the last time you said
لا اله الا الله یونس رسول الله
Abdel Rahman: Okay. When I say
لا اله الا الله محمد
Dr. Khalifa: No, wait wait, first answer...
Abdel Rahman: I will answer your question. I will not answer the way
you want. I answer it the way I want...
Dr. Khalifa: No no, just yes or no. It's a yes or no.When was the last time you said
لا اله الا الله یونس رسول الله
Abdel Rahman: When I say
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
it's admitting that I admit
all the messenger up to Muhammad, I believe
in them.
Dr. Khalifa: You didn't say that. It doesn't say that.
Abdel Rahman: That's what I admit.
I believe all the messenger including the
last messenger ofALLAH SUBHANAHU...
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad is not the last messenger.
Abdel Rahman: Well, this is another...
Dr. Khalifa: Where do you get that? Where do you
get that Muhammad is the last messenger?
Abdel Rahman: Let's continue.
Dr. Khalifa: No, let me ask another question. Is Muhammad
dead or alive?
Abdel Rahman: This is علم عندالله. As far as
I know, as a human being, he died.
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad is dead?
Abdel Rahman: As far as I know. Am I coming to be questioned,
or I question you?
Dr. Khalifa: What do you mean? No, we're dealing with
your question.
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
We're looking at this statement from the logical point of view. Forget anything else.
God gave us a mind that He wants us to use. So, you are saying
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
which means what in English?
Abdel Rahman: I bear witness that there is no god but one
God, and Muhammad is the messenger of God.
Dr. Khalifa: "Muhammad is the messenger of God". So, my
question is "is Muhammad dead or alive?"
Abdel Rahman: What do you think?
Dr. Khalifa: What I think, the Quran says Muhammad is dead.
(39:30) إِنَّكَ مَيِّتٌۭ وَإِنَّهُم مَّيِّتُونَ
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: We know that Muhammad is dead unless he's
1,400 and some years old.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Sitting somewhere.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: But he is in a grave now. He's dead, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Now, do you think a dead man can
be a messenger of God?
Abdel Rahman: No longer after he died...
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. So, why do you say Muhammad is the
messenger of God? He's not, he could not be a messenger
of God because he's dead, is this true?
Abdel Rahman: I will go for it for the time being, okay. Let's go...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, can a dead man be a messenger of God?
Abdel Rahman: He was a messenger of God and he already completed his mission.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, now therefore the correct statement would be
محمد کان رسول الله
Therefore the statement
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
is wrong, even from the purely logical point of view.
However, like I said the SHAHADA is in the
Quran. Unfortunately, the Muslims do not follow
the Quran. And it says
شَهِدَ ٱللَّهُ أَنَّهُۥ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَٱلْمَلَٰٓئِكَةُ وَأُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ
Therefore, anyone who says anything but لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا الله is not among
أُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ
He doesn't know. He is ignorant. It's due
to ignorance.
This is why in the KHUTBA you saw me say
لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا الله
This is it. This is all we say.
Abdel Rahman: Also, you said you believe in the Quran, nothing
but the Quran, and we don't have to believe
anything from Hadith. Why? We don't have
to pay attention to Hadith, why?
Dr. Khalifa: Because God says in the Quran that the Quran
is complete, perfect, and fully detailed.
And the question is "do you believe God or not?"
If you believe God, you'll believe that
the Quran is complete, perfect, and fully
detailed.
Listen to this. This is verse 114 in SURA 6. It say
أَفَغَيْرَ ٱللَّهِ أَبْتَغِى حَكَمًۭا وَهُوَ ٱلَّذِىٓ أَنزَلَ إِلَيْكُمُ ٱلْكِتَٰبَ مُفَصَّلًۭا
Shall I seek out other than God as a source
of law when He sent down to you this book
fully detailed? مُفَصَّلًۭا fully detailed.
Therefore, if you go to anything else, you will
be a rejector of the Quran. You have rejected,
you have disbelieved God. So, this is the reason why. It doesn't matter how great the Hadith is.
Abdel Rahman: You know the Muslims usually, when they use
Hadith, it doesn't mean that they are overlapping
the Quran. No, the Quran is divine constitution
of God to mankind.
And who apply, who perform that constitution
to mankind better than Muhammad, the messenger
of God, the one who redeemed it, the one who
received it, and delivered it to mankind.
People always like to follow the one who receive it,
and to see how he perform it, how he - he
show it to the people, then they follow
his way of performing the constitution of
God.
It means like when I follow the Hadith doesn't mean I am away of the Quran. As far
as I know, I hope you correct me if
I'm wrong. I'm just saying my statement and I'm
sure you will have a comment on it. That's as far as I know about the Muslim how they use Hadith.
What do you think?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, first of all if the Quran is fully detailed
- not if the Quran - I mean, I know the Quran is fully detailed. God says the Quran is fully detailed.
Therefore, you don't need anything else.
We know that the Hadith are... we know now
from many many years of research that the
Hadith are fabrications attributed to the
prophet. Now the Satan, SHAYTAN knows
that we love the prophet very much, and he
use that as a bait to catch...when you catch
fish, you put bait on a hook to catch the fish.
Abdel Rahman: I think, I think - if you excuse me for interrupting
you Dr. Khalifa - the Muslim, they are aware of a lot of Hadith being injected to Hadith, not like Quran...
Dr. Khalifa: No, I'm talking about the Sahih Bukhari, for
example. Sahih Bukhari is full contradictions,
blasphemies against the prophet. I can show
you literally hundreds of Hadiths that are
considered attacks on the prophet. They distract
from the greatness of the prophet Muhammad.
So, but the important point Abdel Rahman is
that God says the Quran is complete, perfect,
fully detailed. This is the important point.
So if you give me a Hadith that is fantastic
and great and has all the qualities of the
best things in the world, I still cannot go
to it because God tells me the Quran is complete,
perfect, and fully detailed.
But the fact is that the Hadith is actually a blasphemous
attack against the prophet, and I gave you
an issue of the Muslim Perspective in Arabic
proving that - I'm talking about Shahih Hadith of Bukhari
- they are a transgression against the prophet.
Abdel Rahman: So, you are ignoring completely the great teacher
of Islam which Muhammad peace be upon him,
he was a great teacher, was... He is the one
who received the message of Allah, and he taught
it to the people. So, I consider him he is my leader.
Dr. Khalifa: You are missing the point.
Abdel Rahman: OK. Let me know it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, you are missing the point.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: The Hadith was never uttered by the prophet,
has nothing to do with the prophet because
- did the Quran come out of the prophets mouth?
Abdel Rahman: How did it come out?
Dr. Khalifa: Did the Quran come out of the prophet's mouth?
Abdel Rahman: I will ask you, you won't ask me, how did it come out?
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't matter how.
Abdel Rahman: Okay, you tell me how it come out.
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran says that Gabriel brought it, released it...
Abdel Rahman: But how he revealed it to Muhammad?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, through Gabriel. God revealed Quran, yes, to Muhammad.
It came out of his mouth.
Abdel Rahman: Whose mouth?
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad's mouth.
Abdel Rahman: Muhammad's mouth.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Therefore, if you wanna follow Muhammad,
you follow Quran, because it came out of
Muhammad's mouth.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I don't know what the people like that...
Abdel Rahman: If I'm an Arabian illiterate, don't understand
that highly quality Arabic language of the
Quran, miracle of the Quran, and I would like
to understand, who will teach me and show me
the right way more than the one who revealed
from God, peace be upon him, Muhammad (عليه صلاة وسلام)?
How? That's why Muhammad, he brought the Hadith...
Dr. Khalifa: Are you saying Muhammad is the teacher
of Quran?
Abdel Rahman: He is interpreter of the Quran to the Muslims.
Dr. Khalifa: No, he was forbidden from interpreting the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: He was?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. In the Quran SURA 75 verse 19, it says
(75:19) ثُمَّ إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا بَيَانَهُۥ
(75:16) لَا تُحَرِّكْ بِهِۦ لِسَانَكَ لِتَعْجَلَ بِهِۦٓ
Muhammad don't move your tongue - or in
English here in American English, don't open your mouth.
(75:17) إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا جَمْعَهُۥ وَقُرْءَانَهُۥ
that we are the ones who will reveal it and put it into Quran.
(75:18) فَإِذَا قَرَأْنَٰهُ فَٱتَّبِعْ قُرْءَانَهُۥ
Once we have it in the Quran, you Muhammad, follow
the Quran.
(75:19) ثُمَّ إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا بَيَانَهُۥ
God is saying that I'm the One who will explain it.
So, the prophet is forbidden from explaining the Quran.
In another SURA, SURA 69, starting at verse
38, we see that if the prophet uttered
anything else other than the Quran, he will
go to Hell. It says... to go from the beginning...
It says
(69:43) تَنزِيلٌۭ مِّن رَّبِّ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ
(69:41) وَمَا هُوَ بِقَوْلِ شَاعِرٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تُؤْمِنُونَ
(69:42) وَلَا بِقَوْلِ كَاهِنٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تَذَكَّرُونَ
OK. Yeah.
(69:38) فَلَآ أُقْسِمُ بِمَا تُبْصِرُونَ
This is the strongest oath in the Quran
(69:39) وَمَا لَا تُبْصِرُونَ
I swear by the things you see
and the things you do not see. Now, this is not
swearing by the sun or the moon or the time or anything.
This is swearing by everything in the universe.
(69:40) إِنَّهُۥ لَقَوْلُ رَسُولٍۢ كَرِيمٍۢ
This Quran is the utterance of an honorable messenger.
(69:41) وَمَا هُوَ بِقَوْلِ شَاعِرٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تُؤْمِنُونَ
It is not the utterance of a poet.
(69:42) وَلَا بِقَوْلِ كَاهِنٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تَذَكَّرُونَ
It is not the utterance of a soothsayer,
or some... an Egyptian BAKKASH, somebody who's
BAKKASH.
Abdel Rahman: What's  BAKKASH mean?
Dr. Khalifa: Soothsayer, KAHEN
Abdel Rahman: KAHEN. Okay.
(69:43) تَنزِيلٌۭ مِّن رَّبِّ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ
It came from the Lord of the universe.
(69:44) وَلَوْ تَقَوَّلَ عَلَيْنَا بَعْضَ ٱلْأَقَاوِيلِ
If he uttered anything else
(69:45) لَأَخَذْنَا مِنْهُ بِٱلْيَمِينِ
(69:46) ثُمَّ لَقَطَعْنَا مِنْهُ ٱلْوَتِينَ
(69:47) فَمَا مِنكُم مِّنْ أَحَدٍ عَنْهُ حَٰجِزِينَ
None of you can protect him.
And because of this interruption in the English
language, I hope I didn't mess up the verses.
But this is the general idea.
(69:38) فَلَآ أُقْسِمُ بِمَا تُبْصِرُونَ
(69:39) وَمَا لَا تُبْصِرُونَ
(69:40) إِنَّهُۥ لَقَوْلُ رَسُولٍۢ كَرِيمٍۢ
(69:41) وَمَا هُوَ بِقَوْلِ شَاعِرٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تُؤْمِنُونَ
(69:42) وَلَا بِقَوْلِ كَاهِنٍۢ ۚ قَلِيلًۭا مَّا تَذَكَّرُونَ
(69:43) تَنزِيلٌۭ مِّن رَّبِّ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ
(69:44) وَلَوْ تَقَوَّلَ عَلَيْنَا بَعْضَ ٱلْأَقَاوِيلِ
(69:45) لَأَخَذْنَا مِنْهُ بِٱلْيَمِينِ
(69:46) ثُمَّ لَقَطَعْنَا مِنْهُ ٱلْوَتِينَ
(69:47) فَمَا مِنكُم مِّنْ أَحَدٍ عَنْهُ حَٰجِزِينَ
So, this... the prophet Muhammad was forbidden
from explaining the Quran, or uttering any
additional religious teachings, and this is
in the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: So, you are actually trying to tell me
there is no way we have to follow the
Hadith of the messenger of God, or follow
his way. We have the Quran, we have to stick...
Dr. Khalifa: You still miss the point. It is not the Hadith
of the messenger of God. It is the Hadith
attributed to the messenger of God.
Because the prophet Muhammad would never disobey
God.
And God told him "you have the Quran and nothing
else." And this is in verse 19, SURA 6. It
says
قُلْ أَىُّ شَىْءٍ أَكْبَرُ شَهَٰدَةًۭ
who is the better testimony?
قُلِ ٱللَّهُ ۖ شَهِيدٌۢ بَيْنِى وَبَيْنَكُمْ ۚ وَأُوحِىَ إِلَىَّ هَٰذَا ٱلْقُرْءَانُ لِأُنذِرَكُم بِهِۦ وَمَنۢ بَلَغَ
I was given this Quran
to deliver to you and the future generation.
Abdel Rahman: I think...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait a minute.
It did not say
أُوحِىَ إِلَىَّ هَٰذَا ٱلْقُرْءَان والحدیث
Abdel Rahman: No, I think I agree with your point for one
reason because we - we will be as Muslims
all of us, we will be judged by the Quran. But I disagree about one thing because - another thing because
the hadith I have to follow the messenger of God, the one who received the Quran and
who delivered it to me.
As a Muslim, if I ignore it...
Dr. Khalifa: You miss the point again. The Hadith came
from SHAYTAN, from Satan, not from Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: I have to be aware, which is right the Hadith
and what's wrong Hadith. But ignoring,
ignoring the messenger of God, that is a question
I would like to elaborate with you.
Dr. Khalifa: You mean if you follow the Quran,
you will ignore the messenger of God?
Abdel Rahman: No, if I ignore the Hadith., if I ignore...
Dr. Khalifa: This is the Hadith of Satan. If I prove
to you that the Hadith is from Satan, would you still wanna follow it?
Abdel Rahman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if I come to you just because the SHAYTAN
came to you and said
قال رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم
You believe it?
Abdel Rahman: If it's...
Dr. Khalifa: Say, Satan walks from
this door, wearing a turban, wait, and says
قال رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم
You're gonna follow it?
Abdel Rahman: It's been renarrated by most scholar religion
in Islam, which are - we know that they are
being following the messenger of God, and
they know what he saw, and they are witness
and we are taking them, holding them, they
are witnessed Muhammad, because...
Dr. Khalifa: They never witnessed Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: Well, that's...
Dr. Khalifa: The first Hadith, it was recorded was 250 years after
Muhammad, across 8 generations of the dead.
Abdel Rahman: So, from the period when Muhammad died to 250
years there was no Hadith at all?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: I see. You believe in the Quran...
Dr. Khalifa: There was no recorded Hadith. People were
making up Hadith at the time. For example,
you come to my house and I have only
fish to feed you. If you object, then I'll
tell you "well, the prophet said if you eat
fish alone you're gonna be great." So,
people made this kind of Hadith.
And it was not recorded or anything. So, Bukhari
came 250 years later and claimed that the
prophet said these things. And as you know,
Bukhari eliminated 90% of the things that
he wrote himself, and still whatever is left
the thousands of Hadith are attacking and
blaspheming against the prophet.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. Let's move to another point because
if we wanna continue talking about this
point, we will never finish it at all.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this point should be finished because
God says the Quran is complete, perfect and
fully detailed.
And the Quran says that telling Muhammad to
tell us that he brings only the Quran. The
last verse in sura 50 says
(50:45) فَذَكِّرْ بِٱلْقُرْءَانِ مَن يَخَافُ وَعِيدِ
Deliver the message of the Quran. It didn't say Quran
and Sunnah, or Quran and Hadith.
(50:45) فَذَكِّرْ بِٱلْقُرْءَانِ مَن يَخَافُ وَعِيدِ
Abdel Rahman: But there is a lot of SURAs also remind the
Muslim to follow ALLAH and the messenger of
God. For example, I probably I have some:
يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوٓا۟ ءَامِنُوا۟ بِٱللَّهِ وَرَسُولِهِۦ وَٱلْكِتَٰبِ ٱلَّذِى نَزَّلَ
(4:136) عَلَىٰ رَسُولِهِۦ وَٱلْكِتَٰبِ ٱلَّذِىٓ أَنزَلَ مِن قَبْلُ
(5:3) ٱلْيَوْمَ أَكْمَلْتُ لَكُمْ دِينَكُمْ
(33:56) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
You know, ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA also confirm
it to the people to pray to Muhammad
because ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA praying to Muhammad, as
far as I know, I hope you will understand
me and you will correct me if I'm wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: Let me correct you.
Abdel Rahman:
(24:47) وَيَقُولُونَ ءَامَنَّا بِٱللَّهِ وَبِٱلرَّسُولِ
(24:52) وَمَن يُطِعِ ٱللَّهَ وَرَسُولَهُۥ وَيَخْشَ ٱللَّهَ
(24:54) قُلْ أَطِيعُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ وَأَطِيعُوا۟ ٱلرَّسُولَ
(24:56) وَأَقِيمُوا۟ ٱلصَّلَوٰةَ وَءَاتُوا۟ ٱلزَّكَوٰةَ وَأَطِيعُوا۟ ٱلرَّسُولَ
Dr. Khalifa: So, why do you disobey him then? Why are you
disobeying him when he tells you to uphold
that the Quran is complete, fully detailed,
and you shall uphold the Quran alone?
Why do you disobey him and go to something
else?
Abdel Rahman: I see.
Dr. Khalifa: You see in the Quran it is telling you
(24:54) أَطِيعُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ وَأَطِيعُوا۟ ٱلرَّسُولَ
So, why don't you listen and obey the ALLAH and
the RASOOL?
Abdel Rahman: Okay. By obeying the messenger of God, and
obeying because I know that the messenger
of God he is been taught by ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, he was orphan and is taught
by ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, and he is, he
was perfect, he was perfect.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, is this the reason for you to disobey him?
Abdel Rahman: No, to obey him.
Dr. Khalifa: You're not obeying him when you go to other than the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: But you are disobeying him when you...
Abdel Rahman: Obeying him in the Quran and his way of life, way of life.
Dr. Khalifa: But if you follow anything other than the Quran, then you are disobeying the prophet.
Abdel Rahman: I see.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: So, therefore you must be the... if you are reciting these verses,
you have to do them yourself.
(24:54) أَطِيعُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ وَأَطِيعُوا۟ ٱلرَّسُولَ
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: If you obey RASOOL, you will uphold the
Quran, the whole Quran, nothing but the
Quran. If you go to anything other than the
Quran, you are not obeying the messenger.
Abdel Rahman: So, you believe in the Quran from
the cover to the cover?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
Abdel Rahman: You believe in this Quran, and our - speaking
to each other now we will speak according
to the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, absolutely.
Abdel Rahman: You say, you said, I think in one of your brochures
here, if you allow me to read it to you or
just you said here - you said: "Providing indisputable evidence
for the exposure and removal of two human-made
sentences that were injected into the
Quran at the end of the last SURA revealed
in Medina, SURA number 9."
Other words, you say here that the human being
been injected some SURAs in the Quran...
Dr. Khalifa: AYAs, verses.
Abdel Rahman: Some verses in the Quran. So, this Quran,
the one in my hand here, in Arabic, the one
in my hand in Arabic, it's not completely
perfect. It's been injected by...
man-made SURAs, you believe in that?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. And also...
Dr. Khalifa: This Quran is not correct.
Abdel Rahman: This is not correct?
Dr. Khalifa: But we know the correct Quran. I can show
you a Quran that is correct and complete.
Abdel Rahman: You will show me in a minute, but let me continue
this. ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA says
(15:9) إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا ٱلذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُۥ لَحَٰفِظُونَ
ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA took an oath on
Him to guard the Quran, because mankind couldn't guard the Torah or the Bible. So, ALLAH
Dr. Khalifa: And He did. That's right.
took an oath on Him to guard the Quran.
In your translation, you said "we have sent
down - for this verse - we have sent down
the revelation and we will surely preserve it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
In Yusuf Ali translation, what he says, he says "We have, without doubt, sent down -  excuse me let me...
In Yusuf Ali translation, which most of the Muslim people -
they are taking by Yusuf Ali translation the Quran "We have without a doubt sent down
the Message and We will assuredly guard it from corruption".
Dr. Khalifa: I agree with that.
Abdel Rahman: You agree about that?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. Well, I would like you to elaborate on
this point doctor Khalifa.
Dr. Khalifa: ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA carried out His promise
and He preserved the Quran perfectly. I can
show you a Quran that is perfect, in the way
it was sent down, and the way it was written...
Abdel Rahman: I would like to see it.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. The way every letter of it is preserved,
not a single letter is added, and not a single
letter is lost.
However, if you go to Egypt or Iran today,
you're gonna see that the Quran is printed
with some mistakes in them, but this does
not negate the fact...
Abdel Rahman: Let's be clear now...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait. Doesn't negate the fact...
Abdel Rahman: Let's be clear before you go.
Abdel Rahman: This Quran, it's been in the whole world through Iran
through Persia, through
Arabic world, this Arabic Quran
it's not real Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: There are some mistakes in it.
Abdel Rahman: It has mistakes in it?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: And you have the one...
Dr. Khalifa: The point is that God did preserve the perfect
Quran and we have it.
Abdel Rahman: Youhave it?
Dr. Khalifa: It's all over the world.
Abdel Rahman: With whom? With you?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's even here. You can find it here also as long as you mark the mistakes.
There are a few mistakes.
Abdel Rahman: But ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA says
(15:9) إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا ٱلذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُۥ لَحَٰفِظُونَ
Dr. Khalifa: So, how do you explain...
Abdel Rahman: We will never allow anyone to inject even one single...
Dr. Khalifa: So, how do you explain the fact that in Iran
today, they're printing millions of Qurans
that do not follow the Quranic writing? Like, for example, the word "SALAT" is written SAAD, LAAM, ALEF, HE,
instead of SAAD, LAAM, WAW, HE as
in the original Quran.
How do you explain that? Do you mean God failed to carry out
His promise? Is this what you think?
Abdel Rahman: No, I'm not thinking of anything. I would
like you...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. I'm saying that it doesn't matter
what people do with the Quran. They can take it
and mess it up and do anything they want. This is what they want to do. This is only
ink and paper. But the Quran that God sent
down is preserved exactly the way that it was written,
and without adding or losing a single letter.
So, this promise of God
(15:9) إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا ٱلذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُۥ لَحَٰفِظُونَ
is kept. However, I must point out something to you.
When there is a law, like the law of preservation
of the Quran, this law does not exist unless
it is violated. Do you understand what this
means?
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I'm following you.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. For example, if there is a law that
Abdel Rahman Salem cannot leave this room.
If you stay in this room forever,
nobody will ever know that this law exists. Is this true?
Abdel Rahman: As far as I understand.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. Now, but if you violate this law, and
try to leave the room, and then you are forced back in,
then we know that the law exists.
Therefore, the violation of the sacredness
of the Quran proves that God preserved it,
because we detected the mistakes. We know
exactly where any letters were added or removed,
and we have the perfect the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: You have the perfect Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: Because God fulfilled, God fulfilled His promise.
Abdel Rahman: Yes. Do you think you can...
Dr. Khalifa: And the perfect Quran is contained in here. It
is included in here, but people added some
of their errors in it. However, it doen't
make any difference because the perfect Quran
is in existence.
Abdel Rahman: If I am an ordinary Muslim walking in the
street, and I picked up this Quran,
you know, for the witness ofALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA,
how do I know this is right and this is wrong,
and this is injected?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. You are either a sincere Muslim
or you're an insincere Muslim, is this correct?
Abdel Rahman: Mmhmm.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, God knows that, right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, when God knows that you are a sincere
Muslim, He will see to it that you'll be
guided to the correct Quran, to the perfect
Quran. If you're not a sincere Muslim, you'll
be left to - you'll have a fake Quran. A fake Muslim has a fake Quran. A true
Muslim has a true Quran. This is a rule of
thumb.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. You also...
Dr. Khalifa: A sincere believer has a perfect Quran. An
insincere person does not have a perfect Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. You said also in your writing and in your
paper brochures you said: the old testimony, and
the new testimony, and also the final testimony,
referring to the Quran which I believe as
far as I know, also I hope you will correct me
if I'm mistaking - Muslims they don't like
to use or to apply this word this "old" and
"new" and "final" to the word of God. We
know that this word is being used by Jewish and
Christians, not by the Muslims. The Muslim,
he knows that the word of God, from Adam to
Muhammad, it's the word of God, never been
old, never been used, never been - it's
word of God. When we say the word of God,
it's the word of God. But...
Dr. Khalifa: You don't like the using "old testament",
"the new testament"...
Abdel Rahman: No, I'm just asking, wondering...
Dr. Khalifa: No, I like to use it, but if you don't like to
use it, go ahead and don't use it.
Abdel Rahman: So, that's the only answer you have, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: You said also "Mohammedans, the worst
enemies of God."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: "Beware of Mohammedans, the worst enemies
of God, according to the Quran."
Did the Quran say that?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: That the Quran said "the one who follows Muhammad will be My worst enemy?"
Dr. Khalifa: The one who worships Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: Well, the one who worships, you know the Muslim
they never worship Muhammad...
Dr. Khalifa: You indicated in the beginning of this interview
that you worship Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: How?
Dr. Khalifa: You said,
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
You worship Muhammad in your life.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. You put Muhammad's name
next to ALLAH's name. This is SHIRK. By definition,
this is SHIRK.
Abdel Rahman: According to SURA...
Dr. Khalifa: You made a statement "Muhammad is a messenger
of God", when he is dead. He is not alive.
Only God is alive, this is why God says
(25:58) تَوَكَّلْ عَلَى ٱلْحَىِّ ٱلَّذِى لَا يَمُوتُ
"put your trust in the living One, who never dies"
because Muhammad is dead.
And when you put his name
When you put Muhammad's name, a human creature
of God next to God, the name of God, this
is worshiping without knowing it. So, you're
worshiping Muhammad without knowing it because
you do not follow the Quran that came out
of Muhammad's mouth because of your reverence
for Muhammad, which is - another word for
it is idol-worship.
The Quran tells you
(2:285) لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍۢ مِّن رُّسُلِهِ
Do not make any
distinction among the prophets or the messengers of God
وَقَالُوا۟ سَمِعْنَا وَأَطَعْنَا
In other words, you do not argue, we say "we hear and we obey, we do not make any distinction." But you defy this and you're
making a distinction, and all this because you love Muhammad too much. Now, Loving Muhammad
too much is like the Christians loving Jesus too much and worshiping him.
And therefore, worshiping Muhammad, or doing or practicing SHIRK - God says there is a law
(5:72) إِنَّهُۥ مَن يُشْرِكْ بِٱللَّهِ فَقَدْ حَرَّمَ ٱللَّهُ عَلَيْهِ ٱلْجَنَّةَ
that heaven is forbidden
for those who make SHIRK.
And SHIRK by definition, when you say
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
This is SHIRK by definition, because
let me put it to you in human terms.
If you invite me to your house for dinner,
you're gonna invite me alone, right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You say "Rashad, come to my house alone by
yourself" and this will "I'm coming to
your house alone."
However, you can also say "I will invite
you to dinner to my house, but bring your
servant with you." Okay? Then, I'm not invited
alone anymore. This is SHIRK. There is a SHARIKA,
more than one person, coming to your house.
Even though you are acknowledging that that
other person is my servant, it still is SHIRK.
So, when you say
لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله
This is SHIRK by definition,
and this is exactly why God teaches us in
the Quran that the SHAHADA is
لا اله الا الله
The SHAHADA of "ALLAH", "AL-MALA'EKA", the
angels, and the "ULULELM", the people who know.
Abdel Rahman: Correct me if I am wrong...
Dr. Khalifa: So, Mohammedans is the correct expression
to describe...
Abdel Rahman: If I'm a Muslim, and I will say "LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH", by saying "MUHAMMAD RASOOL ALLAH",
means that I approve, and admit, and bear
witness that I will accept the message of
ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA came through Muhammad...
Dr. Khalifa: No. You are doing the opposite. When you
say: "LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH MUHAMMAD RASOOL ALLAH", you are saying "I reject Muhammad
and his message." This is what it means.
Abdel Rahman: How? Explain it to me.
Dr. Khalifa: By breaking the commandments in the Quran.
By breaking the commandment of making distinction
among the prophets.
By making... putting another name besides the name of God
and violating the basic principles of the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: I'm a putting a name inside by my God because
Dr. Khalifa: But that's against...
loving Muhammad is loving God. Because Muhammad, he devoted most of his life
to ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, to His message, in His path. I love him; by loving Muhammad...
Dr. Khalifa: If you love him...
Dr. Khalifa: Why do you disobey him then? if you love him, why do you disobey him?
He told you "do not make distinction among the messengers."
He told you that the SHAHADA is "LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH."
So, why do you continue to disobey him then
if you love him, if you really love him? Why
don't you obey him? Why do you not follow
the Quran that came out of his mouth?
You know we have to think about that.
Abdel Rahman: I'm listening to you doctor Khalifa. Go ahead.
Dr. Khalifa: The issue
إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ ۚ يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟
(33:56) صَلُّوا۟ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلِّمُوا۟ تَسْلِيمًا
Abdel Rahman: You do not believe in this.
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, I believe in this.
Abdel Rahman: You believe in this?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: How do you believe in it?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, do you know what يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى means?
Abdel Rahman: What means?
Dr. Khalifa: Do you know what "AL-NABI" means, in the Quran?
Also do you know that thirteen verses before
this, God says He and His angels do the same
thing for every believer?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: In the same SURA.
It says
يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟ o you who believe,
ٱذْكُرُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ ذِكْرًۭا كَثِيرًۭا commemorate
God continuously.
(33:42) وَسَبِّحُوهُ بُكْرَةًۭ وَأَصِيلًا
Glorify Him day and night.
هُوَ ٱلَّذِى يُصَلِّى عَلَيْكُمْ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتُهُۥ لِيُخْرِجَكُم مِّنَ ٱلظُّلُمَٰتِ إِلَى
(33:43) ٱلنُّورِ
So
إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
because AL-NABI is one
of the believers.
Why? "To take him out of the darkness into the light", just like the other verse. And it says "o, you who
believe do the same thing, help him also,
come out of the darkness into the light."
This is what it says. You have to understand...
Hold it. Hold it. You have to understand what the verse
means, because Satan messed up this verse
for the Muslims and made them, instead of
(33:41) ٱذْكُرُوا۟ ٱللَّهَ ذِكْرًۭا كَثِيرًۭا
(33:42) وَسَبِّحُوهُ بُكْرَةًۭ وَأَصِيلًا
AL-SHAYTAN AL-LA'IN,
Satan decided that he's gonna make the people
commemorate Muhammad day and night, andیسبحوه محمد day and night, instead of God
So, they keep saying
اللهم صلی علی محمد
صلی علی وسلم
عليه صلاة وسلام
Instead of saying "SUBHAN ALLAH", "LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH" and so on. So, SHAYTAN, Satan succeeded
in tricking and duping the Muslims
into commemorating Muhammad instead of God
by messing up the meaning of this verse.
Now, the expression "AL-NABI" in the Quran,
you have to watch this, and I challenge the
so called "ULUMA" in this subject, because
"AL-NABI" in the Quran is always in the
Quran during his lifetime, when he was alive,
the word "AL-NABI." Like
(49:2) لَا تَرْفَعُوٓا۟ أَصْوَٰتَكُمْ فَوْقَ صَوْتِ ٱلنَّبِىِّ
How can you carry out this commandment
now? "Do not raise your voice over the voice
of the prophet" when he is dead? This means, you
don't speak at all because his voice is still
if you do it now.
So the word NABI
(65:1) يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلنَّبِىُّ إِذَا طَلَّقْتُمُ ٱلنِّسَآءَ
How can the
prophet divorce his wife when he's dead?
(66:1) يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلنَّبِىُّ لِمَ تُحَرِّمُ مَآ أَحَلَّ ٱللَّهُ لَكَ
So, consistently in the Quran the word NABI
is during his lifetime. So,
(33:56) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
means Muhammad during his lifetime.
يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟ صَلُّوا۟ عَلَيْه
during his life time, help him, support him,
during his lifetime, not after he's dead, and every time you hear his name...
Abdel Rahman: ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, He always precisely
in the Quran when He mentions the things we are
carrying it as it is because we follow the
Quran as you said.ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA said
يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟
in the time of the messenger means after the
death of the messenger, do not صَلُّوا۟ عَلَيْ
Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: But, you don't know what the meaning of صَلُّوا۟ عَلَيْه means.
Abdel Rahman: Pray to him, like...
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Abdel Rahman: Or supporting him.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: That's all supporting...?
Dr. Khalifa: SALLU comes from the word SALA, contact,
connection, stay close to him, help him,
support him. It doesn't mean...it doesn't say: "say صلی علی وسلم" because it contradicts itself.
You know, it says in the beginning
إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
So, do you agree that
ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
Abdel Rahman: This is the present time.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Hold it. Hold it.
Do you agree that
ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I do.
Dr. Khalifa: So ٱللَّهَ وَمَلَٰٓئِكَتَهُۥ now يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, why are you telling Him to صَلُّوا عَلَى ٱلنَّبِىِّ if He's doing it?
Abdel Rahman: Since ALLAH and His angels praying on Muhammad,
I am as a Muslim, should pray on Muhammad,
and on every single Muslim who is believes in Islam.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but according to you, you are saying
"اللهم صلی علی محمد" right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But already ALLAH tells you that
He is making SALAT on Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: That's why I ask ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA to accept my
praying to Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but He's already doing it. You're asking
God to do what He's saying He's doing.
Abdel Rahman: For me.
Dr. Khalifa: But you can see that Satan messed up the meaning of this verse. What this really means is during
the prophet Muhammad's time, because of the
use of the word "AL-NABI"; o you who believe,
support him and help him and stay in touch
with him. This is what it means. But the Muslims
messed it up and Satan uses it to make the Muslims
worship Muhammad instead of God. This is why
I call them Mohammedans.
Abdel Rahman: So, we shouldn't actually do that. We shouldn't
actually mention Muhammad in - as I saw you
in the prayer, JUM'AH prayer here, you never mentioned
Muhammad for anything.
Dr. Khalifa: I'll mention if I need to. I mean, what do we mention him for?
Abdel Rahman: You never mentioned. You said - I mean, it's not...
Dr. Khalifa: What do you wanna mention him for?
Abdel Rahman: You don't have to mention.
Dr. KHalifa: Why?
Abdel Rahman: I'm a Muslim, you already know.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm asking you, why do you wanna mention Muhammad?
Abdel Rahman: As a messenger of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the Quran says only the hypocrites say
that. Only the hypocrites declare that Muhammad
is "RASOOL ALLAH", because we know that Muhammad
is "RASOOL ALLAH." We don't need to say it.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. It says
إِذَا جَآءَكَ ٱلْمُنَٰفِقُونَ قَالُوا۟ نَشْهَدُ إِنَّكَ لَرَسُولُ ٱللَّهِ ۗ وَٱللَّهُ يَعْلَمُ
(63:1) إِنَّكَ لَرَسُولُهُۥ وَٱللَّهُ يَشْهَدُ إِنَّ ٱلْمُنَٰفِقِينَ لَكَٰذِبُونَ
So, throughout the Quran only the hypocrites say
اشهد ان محمد رسول الله
Abdel Rahman: So, actually you're ignoring completely the,
the way Muhammad used to live, and to ignoring
to reject for us as a Muslim to know how Muhammad
he used to live his right way according to
the Quran, so we have to follow it.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you ignoring the way Muhammad used to
live?
Abdel Rahman: No, I would be glad to go for it.
Dr. Khalifa: So, why are you wearing a tie? Did he wear
a tie?
Abdel Rahman: I'm not going for... we are not going for outside as much inside in praying, worshipping...
Dr. Khalifa: Now, wait a minute. You're talking about the
way he lived.
Abdel Rahman: The way he used to live in belief...
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have your camel parking out there?
Abdel Rahman: In behaving muslim, see, you are going
for outside. Now, for the service we are going
for inside, the way he performed with the Quran, how he used to pray.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you agree that he gave the Quran?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you agree that his source was the Quran?
Abdel Rahman: Yes. How...
Dr. Khalifa: Even according to Hadith it says
کان خلقه القرآن
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: He represented the Quran, right?
Dr. Khalifa: And now we have the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: So, therefore if you want to follow Muhammad,
you follow the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. How do you know...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait a minute. Is this true?
Abdel Rahman: It's true.
Dr. Khalifa: Alright. So, this is what we're doing.
We're following the Quran, which means we're
following Muhammad.
However, Muhammad's job was to deliver the
message. He did the job. He did a good job.
And he's gone, and that's his role. He cannot
guide you.
Abdel Rahman: And that's it, no more? We don't have to
think of...
Dr. Khalifa: It's what the Quran says
(5:99) مَّا عَلَى ٱلرَّسُولِ إِلَّا ٱلْبَلَٰغُ
two negatives
Abdel Rahman: I think, as far as I know, in this SURA, it means like
you, Muhammad, do not force people to believe
in Islam. You are only responsible for delivering
the message, not to force it.
Dr. Khalifa: No. No, this is a general statement that is not violated anywhere
in the Quran, it is repeated.
(5:99) مَّا عَلَى ٱلرَّسُولِ إِلَّا ٱلْبَلَٰغُ
(24:54) عَلَى ٱلرَّسُولِ إِلَّا ٱلْبَلَٰغُ ٱلْمُبِينُ
And repeated many times.
So, the sole function of the prophet or the
messenger is to deliver the message.
Abdel Rahman: That's all?
Dr. Khalifa:
(28:56) إِنَّكَ لَا تَهْدِى مَنْ أَحْبَبْتَ
Abdel Rahman:
وَلَٰكِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يَهْدِى مَن يَشَآءُ
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: This is also supporting the same AYA, so you said it now. It's like you don't force it on people for believing,
no, you just deliver the message, and you
perform it, and teach the people how to do it.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. Now, you are adding other things,
because it says
(5:99) مَّا عَلَى ٱلرَّسُولِ إِلَّا ٱلْبَلَٰغُ
There's nothing else.
Abdel Rahman: These people come to the mosque here, who
they follow? They follow you, how to do, right?
Dr. Khalifa: No, they follow the Quran. They don't follow me.
Abdel Rahman: You teach them,
Abdel Rahman: you hold this Quran and you
teach them in the Quran, so they sit and listen
and look at you, and they say that's right,
that's right. Who is right?
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Doctor Khalifa right in a way of interpretingthe
Quran here. So, I am following doctor Khalifa. I am not actually...
Dr. Khalifa: No, you are not.
Dr. Khalifa: You follow doctor
Khalifa then you're not right.
Abdel Rahman: It's not right?
Dr Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.Let's also...
Dr. Khalifa: Anybody here, and we all know this, we do
not follow any person. And we emphasize here
we are worshipers of God alone, we follow
the word of God alone, and if I ever say anything
that is not in the Quran and it contradicts
with the Quran, I'm the first one to appreciate
alerting me to this, because then I'm wrong.
Abdel Rahman: If I am following...
Dr. Khalifa: Nobody follows me.
Abdel Rahman: If I am following the Quran, why should I
come to this mosque to listen to Khalifa?
Dr. Khalifa: You don't need to. You don't need to.
Abdel Rahman: ...here, I look at it in the house. I don't need to leave it
to mister, doctor Khalifa, right?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: Absolutely, you don't need anybody, you don't
need Rashad Khalifa or anybody. You just...if you
have the Quran, you don't need anybody because
you follow the Quran and nothing else.
Abdel Rahman: You said in your brochures here also, Islam being
practiced today.
Dr. Khalifa: Can I go back to your question,
why we come here to the mosque?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a commandment in the Quran that says
وَٱصْبِرْ نَفْسَكَ مَعَ ٱلَّذِينَ يَدْعُونَ رَبَّهُم بِٱلْغَدَوٰةِ وَٱلْعَشِىِّ
(18:28) يُرِيدُونَ وَجْهَهُۥ
It says "force yourself to be with those who worship God alone." Because it's a social function. This is why
God instituted the Friday Prayer every week,
so all the believers who follow the Quran
alone must get together. They must know each
other. They must be united, as you know. Throughout
the Quran these instructions are there.This
is the only reason we are here.
And there are replicas of this masjid in many other places around the world who do not have Rashad Khalifa there
because we have our leader
is the Quran. Our imam is the Quran. Our guide
is the Quran, the word of God. We are worshippers of God alone. And we go out of our way to destroy persons
or idols of any kind, alive or dead.
So, this is the reason we get together here.
Abdel Rahman: In your brochures, you had also, if you can comment in this, please - you said here "Islam being practiced
today is severely corrupted beyond recognition."
Can you elaborate on this for me, please?
Dr. Khalifa: Absolutely. The Muslims in the world today do not do
anything according to the prophet Muhammad's
teachings. You, for example, did you make WUDU, today?
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I do.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. Can you describe it to me?
Abdel Rahman: As usual.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, go ahead, describe it. Number one, you
open the faucet.
Abdel Rahman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You wash your hand.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
Abdel Rahman: I wash my face.
Abdel Rahman: Arms.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: My feet.
Abdel Rahman: That's as far as I know.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, you didn't do your head.
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I do my hair.
Dr. Khalifa: You didn't...
Abdel Rahman: My ears.
Dr. Khalifa: Your ears.
Abdel Rahman: My mouth, that's Sunnah. You said you don't follow Sunnah. According to...
Dr. Khalifa: I'm asking you what you did. About your actions
today...
Abdel Rahman: Well, exactly what I did. I said "NAWAYTO SUNNAH AL-WUDU", there's Sunnah before Fajr.
Sunnah is me washing my mouth, because I'm going to stand next to someone, I don't
wanna him to smell my smell. So, I wash my mouth,
wash my nose...
Dr. Khalifa: Being bothered by bad breath.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so you wash your hands first?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, then you wash your mouth?
Dr. Khalifa: Then your nose?
Abdel Rahman: Yes, wash my nose, and my face.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, you wash your face.
Abdel Rahman: And my arms.
Dr. Khalifa: Your arms.
Abdel Rahman: My hair.
Dr. Khalifa: Your hair.
Abdel Rahman: My ears.
Dr. Khalifa: Your ears.
Abdel Rahman: My feet.
Dr. Khalifa: My feet. 8 steps.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
They're 8 steps, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, now if we look in the Quran, this is
what came out of Muhammad's mouth.
I'm taking you as an example, because you're telling
me that the Muslims practice something that is
corrupted, severely corrupted.
If you look in the Quran, what came out of
Mohammad's mouth the following
يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوٓا۟ إِذَا قُمْتُمْ إِلَى ٱلصَّلَوٰةِ فَٱغْسِلُوا۟ وُجُوهَكُمْ وَأَيْدِيَكُمْ إِلَى ٱلْمَرَافِقِ وَٱمْسَحُوا۟ بِرُءُوسِكُمْ وَأَرْجُلَكُمْ إِلَى
(5:6) ٱلْكَعْبَيْن
4 steps.
Now, Satan will not accept that. He has to
have his 4 steps also.
Abdel Rahman: And this will hurt Islam if we add 2 or 3?
Dr. Khalifa: Of course.
Abdel Rahman: If I wash my hands...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: If I wash my hands and wash my ears, and if
I wash thoroughly, if I clean myself, that will hurt Islam?
Dr. Khalifa: Absolutely. You're not following the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: If I pray to ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA, He says
pray to God...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait, hold it, hold it, let's stay with the
WUDU. We're gonna go to other examples. I wanna show you that Muslims do not do anything
according to Muhammad's teachings.
Out of Muhammad's mouth came the teaching
that we should have 4 steps. You made 8
steps. 4 from God and 4 from Satan.
Abdel Rahman: What's wrong with that?
Dr. Khalifa: So, you have a...
This is what is wrong with it.
Abdel Rahman: What is wrong with it?
Dr. Khalifa: You have a SHARIK. You have another god besides
God telling you - who told you to do additional
4 steps? Another god!
Abdel Rahman: It's more clean.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, why don't you take a bath?
Abdel Rahman: I take a bath sometime.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, fine, but this has...
Abdel Rahman: Whil you take a bath, there is no need for WUDU
Dr. Khalifa: We're talking about the worship, okay? This
is talking about ablution as an act of worship.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I brush my teeth in the morning when I get up
but this has nothing to do with worship.
This is my hygienic practices.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. But we're talking about the WUDU as
a form of worship. Do the Muslims follow what
came out of Mohammad's mouth? The answer is for
you "no." You are not following... No.
Abdel Rahman: Yes, the answer is yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, you're not.
Abdel Rahman: I follow it, and I add some more.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, you add some more.
Abdel Rahman: Some more to be more careful.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Either you know better than God, or
you have another god that is adding steps
to you.
What is the source of the other 4 steps?
Abdel Rahman: Excuse me, doctor Khalifa, this is a mercy
of ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA when He say "you
people pray 2 RAKAT" and I come to the mosque, I do pray 4 RAKAT. It's mean like I'm not
following God. I'm praying for You ALLAH 2 RAKAT, and I added 2 RAKAT for extra for
me to make it more...
Dr. Khalifa: No. Then, you have another god who told you
to do 2 extra RAKATs. Because the number of RAKATs is mathematically coded according to
God in the Quran, according to God's system.
And if you add anything else, then you have
another god who told you to do those two RAKATs.
Let me show you from the Quran. Okay?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA ordered the angels to
fall prostrate, make SUJUD before Adam,
right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They fell prostrate before Adam. Who were
they worshiping?
Who? They made SUJUD before Adam. Who were
Abdel Rahman: Who were they worshiping?
Dr. Khalifa: Who?
Abdel Rahman: Who?
Dr. Khalifa: God.
The source of the order, right?
Abdel Rahman: God.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They were not worshiping Adam. Even though
they were making SUJUD before Adam.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They are worshiping the source of the order.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if you make SUJUD to God because Muhammad
told you to make SUJUD to God, you're not
worshiping God. You're worshiping the source
of the order, Muhammad.
Do you understand me?
You are breaking the mathematical code. The
number of RAKATs. If God told you to do 2 RAKATs,
you must do 2 RAKATs. If you add more,
then you...
Abdel Rahman: That's against Islam.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Abdel Rahman: I should do exactly 2 RAKATs, no more, no less?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. In your WUDU, you must do
the 4 steps, no more and no less. Okay, this is
WUDU.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, I ask another question about SALAT.
Did you pray the Noon yesterday?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Did you do it silently or loudly?
Abdel Rahman: Silently.
Dr. Khalifa: This is against the Quran. You are not obeying
the prophet Muhammad here.
Abdel Rahman: Why?
Dr. Khalifa: Because if you look in SURA 17, verse 110,
it says
لَا تَجْهَرْ بِصَلَاتِكَ وَلَا تُخَافِتْ بِهَا
وَٱبْتَغِ بَيْنَ ذَٰلِكَ سَبِيلًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Abdel Rahman: Which one? the Noon one?
Dr. Khalifa: 110.
Abdel Rahman: The Noon SALAT or all the SALAT?
Dr. Khalifa: All the SALAT, didn't say the Noon or what.
It said
لَا تَجْهَرْ بِصَلَاتِكَ وَلَا تُخَافِتْ بِهَا
Do not say your SALAT in a loud voice
or secretly."
Therefore, when you do it secretly, you have
another god who told you to do it secretly.
Abdel Rahman: No. According to my knowledge...
Dr. Khalifa: Why do you not follow the Quran?
Abdel Rahman: Well, let me comment on this.
Dr. Khalifa: No, the point that I'm making is that the Muslims are not following the Quran or Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: You are damaging, excuse me for this expression
and I hope you will correct me if I'm wrong,
you are damaging completely the "TA'LIM"
of Muhammad (SAW), even
in his early days, like Muhammad he followed
and he and his follower were silent in doing
SALAT, in Noon prayer and in ASR, afternoon prayer.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: Because they were weak at that time. They were
weak at that time, and they were aware, afraid of the KAFERUN.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you weak now? Are you afraid of the KAFERIN attack you?
Abdel Rahman: No, that's why we follow his way.
Dr. Khalifa: So, but he left you the Quran...
Abdel Rahman: It's like when you follow a Christmas way,
as a remembering. It's not damaging, sometimes...
Dr. Khalifa: So, you disobey the Quran in other words.
Abdel Rahman: No, we...
Dr. Khalifa: Did you see the prophet pray silently?
Abdel Rahman: No, this is the Sunnah...
Dr. Khalifa: This is what you heard, right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, you follow hearsay, and you don't follow
the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Right?
Abdel Rahman: Okay. This...
Dr. Khalifa: What do you mean okay?
Abdel Rahman: Well, I'm not gonna go through this because...
Dr. Khalifa: You are saying that I'm destroying all the TA'LIM of Muhammad, right?
Abdel Rahman: Mmmhmm.
Dr. Khalifa: And I tell you I hope I'm destroying
what you think is TA'LIM of Muhammad because
it is not.
TA'LIM of Muhammad is in the Quran, and he told you not to do the prayer silent.
Now, again, can you tell me what you say in
your SALAT sitting down? In the sitting position.
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I noticed also in your SALAT as soon
as you sit you said
السلام عليكم ورحمة الله
I mean, you didn't say anything at
all, right?
Dr. Khalifa: What do you say?
Abdel Rahman:
التَّحِيَّاتُ وَالصَّلَوَاتُ وَالطَّيِّبَاتُ لِلَّهِ السَّلاَمُ عَلَيْكَ أَيُّهَا النَّبِيُّ وَرَحْمَةُ اللَّهِ وَبَرَكَاتُهُ السَّلاَمُ عَلَيْنَا وَعَلَى عِبَادِ اللَّهِ الصَّالِحِينَ أَشْهَدُ أَنْ لاَ إِلَهَ إِلاَّ اللَّهُ وَأَشْهَدُ أَنَّ مُحَمَّدًا رسول اللَّهِ
السلام عليكم ورحمة الله
Dr. Khalifa: You don't say
اللهم صلی علی محمد و آل محمد
Abdel Rahman: Well, that's extra. You don't have to say
it.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. Now, this what you just said here nullifies
the SALAT, okay? It makes it zero.
Abdel Rahman: Do you know the occasion of this one?
Dr. Khalifa: It violates the Quran and makes it absolutely
null and void and useless and a waste of time. Even worse, it makes you a MUSHRIK. Because the Quran says
(72:18) وَأَنَّ ٱلْمَسَـٰجِدَ لِلَّهِ فَلَا تَدْعُوا۟ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ أَحَدًۭا
That the mosque or the masjid or places of SUJUD belong to God,
you shall not mention anybody else
أَحَدًۭا anybody else with God.
So, when you sit down and you mention the name
of Muhammad or, AL-NABI in the Quran, you're finished. You're a dead duck. The SALAT
doesn't mean a thing. You are disobeying
God and disobeying the prophet.
So, as you see, the Muslims are practicing
a religion that has nothing to with Muhammad.
And they misunderstand that. As you see, the WUDU is wrong. The AZAN is wrong.
The AZAN that they do - can you tell me any AZAN in
any place in the Muslim world that is devoted
to ALLAH alone? Anywhere in the world?
Abdel Rahman: Well, what the AZAN says?
Well why? It's always devoted toALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't mention Muhammad at all?
Abdel Rahman: No, It's mentioning Muhammad is against the
religion. By mentioning... once you mention
Muhammad, it's like
اشهد ان لا اله الا الله و اشهد ان محمدا رسول الله
It's mean I bear witness there is no
god but one God, and Muhammad is the messenger
of God. It's mean, this is the last messenger of
God.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the fact is that the AZAN  is not devoted
to God alone. There is Muhammad in it.
Abdel Rahman: Okay, Muhammad, he is the messenger. He deliver the message to me.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but he delivered a message telling you
to only mention God alone.
(72:18) وَأَنَّ ٱلْمَسَـٰجِدَ لِلَّهِ فَلَا تَدْعُوا۟ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ أَحَدًۭا
This is very clear Arabic. It's telling you that this worship belongs to God, do not mention any other names.
And you're telling "forget it. I'm gonna mention Muhammad next to You."
You are defying God and defying Muhammad.
You are going against the Quran.
So, let us just think, you know. The Muslims
are doing the AZAN wrong, the WUDU wrong,
the SALAT wrong, the ZAKAT wrong, the SIYAM
wrong, HAJJ wrong.
Abdel Rahman: How they do that, because I would like to
go through also the points that you said?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, you heard about the AZAN. You hear
about the WUDU.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You heard about the SALAT.
Dr. Khalifa: And now we come to ZAKAT, for example.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. If you look in SURA number 6, verse
141. It says that the ZAKAT must be given
on the day of harvest.
وَءَاتُوا۟ حَقَّهُۥ يَوْمَ حَصَادِهِ
Okay? Now, we, you and I, harvest paychecks or
dollars. We do not harvest wheat and corn
and so on, right?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the day we receive any money, we must give
the ZAKAT on that day immediately,
according to the Quran's teachings as who receives the ZAKAT and so on.
Now, the Muslims give the zakat once a year. Which means what? The hungry people have to
wait a year before they get the assistance.
Abdel Rahman: I know there is a distinguish between ZAKAT
and the SADAQA.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, we're talking about ZAKAT.
We're talking about ZAKAT.
(6:141) وَءَاتُوا۟ حَقَّهُۥ يَوْمَ حَصَادِهِ
the ZAKAT is "HAQ", must be...
Abdel Rahman: You interpret ZAKAT - "HAQ" means ZAKAT?
Dr. Khalifa: No. I mean, it's very clear in the verse. It says
(6:141) وَءَاتُوا۟ حَقَّهُۥ يَوْمَ حَصَادِهِ
Abdel Rahman: "HAQ" who?
Dr. Khalifa: ZAKAT of the harvest.
Abdel Rahman: It didn't mention ZAKAT now. Now, we are going by your word.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what is it? What is "حَقَّهُۥ"?
Abdel Rahman: What's "حَقَّهُۥ" means?
Abdel Rahman: Yeah, you tell me what "حَقَّهُۥ" means.
Dr. Khalifa: If you read the verse.
Abdel Rahman: "HAQ" means"SADAQA", mean...
Dr. Khalifa: No, SADAQA is not "HAQ." SADAQA is voluntary.
OK. There's a difference between ZAKAT and SADAQA. The ZAKAT is obligatory. The SADAQA
and there's "HAQ."
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But the SADAQA is voluntary. It's any
charitable act that you do to any poor person.
Okay?
Abdel Rahman: There is ZAKAT for Ramadan, and there is also
another ZAKAT for your money.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, there is just only one ZAKAT. It's one ZAKAT which is came to
us from EBRAHIM.
ربع العشر
2.5%. It came very simple "ربع العشر"
And it is given as soon as you receive any income,
whenever you receive any income. But the Muslims do it
wrong, do it once a year on their savings.
That's not the way it should be.
Abdel Rahman: How also you explain the fasting?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the fasting, they do not - they never agree on
the beginning or the end of Ramadan, as
you know.
They quit any productive work during the month
of Ramadan.
They become obnoxious creatures, and they are angry easily, and they're very bad people
and they blame it on the fasting.
This is not the way to do SIYAM.
And the HAJJ is ruined by going to Medina
and worshipping at the tomb of the prophet.
Abdel Rahman: No, this has nothing to do with HAJJ. Everybody
knows that when you go to visit the mosque
of RASOOL (عليه صلاة وسلام), it's extra.
Dr. Khalifa: Hadith says that "HAJJ is not complete
without visiting my tomb." And I don't know
when he said that, when he was alive or dead?
But this - whether it is part of the HAJJ
or not, it destroys the HAJJ.
Abdel Rahman: Yeah, you said you translate the Quran, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: And you said "my translation was authorized
by God."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: What do you mean by that? I would like you
to elaborate on this point.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, when I started to translate, I didn't want
to publish it because I thought, I said "I
will not publish it unless it's authorized",
and I demanded certain signs that it is authorized and I received the signs, and I published
it, and called it authorized.
Abdel Rahman: How you did you receive it?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, that's a long story that's beyond this
interview. So, let's leave it at that.
Abdel Rahman: Well, we would like to know it, you know. I think people would like to know how - what kind of authorization you say
Dr. Khalifa: Come to the conference and I'll give you
the details. I'm gonna give the details
at the conference.
Abdel Rahman: Can't you even give me a hint about it? Like here
probably here, you said "when I was in Mecca"...
Dr. Khalifa: I can give you a few hints.
Abdel Rahman: Yes, go ahead, please.
Dr. Khalifa: My English translation is the 19th translation.
And if you're aware of the mathematical
code, the number 19 is the common denominator
in the Quran, in the previous scriptures,
in you and me, in the universe. And also...
Abdel Rahman: You mean, if I'm a Muslim, I have to concentrate on
nothing but numbers in Quran.
Quran is not numbers. Quran is spiritual...
D. Khalifa: No, if you do that, you'd be wrong.
Abdel Rahman: Quran is spirit.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: The most important thing...
Dr. Khalifa: Just like...
Abdel Rahman: The Quran, the word of it, the constitution
I have to follow it, the living life of it.
If you approve by numbers that it is the miracle
of God, that's enough for me and I have to
move to another point.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right, you bet.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: So, how many times did we talk
about the number 19, since we started? We're not concentrating on the number 19, you
are.
Abdel Rahman: Okay, you concentrating...
Dr. Khalifa: We talked about SALAT, and ZAKAT,
and HAJJ, and the Quran, and the teachings
in the Hadith, and so on. We didn't talk
about the number 19.
Abdel Rahman: OK. let's talk about number 19 now.
Dr. Khalifa: But anyway, the signs were abundant that this
Quran is authorized. I give here in the Muslim Perspective details about my name, and the verses
and the SURAs where my name is mentioned and so
on. So, you have to look it up and come to
your own conclusions. This is why the translation
is authorized.
Abdel Rahman: And that's why you claim that you are a messenger
of God.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: You believe that you are a messenger of God, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Abdel Rahman: How do you believe that? Why do you believe this?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I gave you... like I said, I gave you several proofs.
Abdel Rahman: Give me.
Dr. Khalifa: And there are many other proofs.
Abdel Rahman: One of the proof is the...
Dr. Khalifa: The discovery of the mathematical code is one.
Abdel Rahman: I mean like...
Dr. Khalifa: This is something that's very simple. It's been in the Quran for 1400 years,
right?
Abdel Rahman: But no one discovered it but you.
Dr. Khalifa: No one discovered it but me.
Abdel Rahman: And that's why you are a messenger of God?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
It's mean like the one who invented the aeroplanes,
the things I can't even reach my mind, I
can't even - I can also put him as a messenger
of God because this is something...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, there are two points here. The first
point is that we're talking about the Quran
which is a special, divinely controlled book.
As you heard in the KHUTBA, no one can touch
a word in it unless they are sincere believers.
That's what God says. Do you believe that?
Abdel Rahman: Yes, I do.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you believe God when He says that nobody
will touch anything in the Quran unless he
is a sincere believer?
Abdel Rahman: How do you say it in Arabic? How do you say it in Arabic?
Dr. Khalifa: It says
(56:79) لَّا يَمَسُّهُۥٓ إِلَّا ٱلْمُطَهَّرُونَ
Abdel Rahman:
The one who - has nothing to do with...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. It says
وَمَنْ أَظْلَمُ مِمَّن ذُكِّرَ بِـَٔايَـٰتِ رَبِّهِۦ فَأَعْرَضَ عَنْهَا وَنَسِىَ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ ۚ إِنَّا جَعَلْنَا عَلَىٰ قُلُوبِهِمْ أَكِنَّةً أَن يَفْقَهُوهُ وَفِىٓ
(18:57) ءَاذَانِهِمْ وَقْرًۭا
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the person who is not a believer in the
Quran will have shields on their heart "أَكِنَّةً عَلَىٰ قُلُوبِ".
وَفِىٓ ءَاذَانِهِمْ وَقْرًۭا and deafness in their ears...
Abdel Rahman: has nothing to do with your point...
Dr. Khalifa: Hold it.
وَإِذَا قَرَأْتَ ٱلْقُرْءَانَ جَعَلْنَا بَيْنَكَ وَبَيْنَ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ
(17:45) بِٱلْـَٔاخِرَةِ حِجَابًۭا مَّسْتُورًۭا
(18:57) جَعَلْنَا عَلَىٰ قُلُوبِهِمْ أَكِنَّةً أَن يَفْقَهُوهُ وَفِىٓ ءَاذَانِهِمْ وَقْرًۭا
Do you agree that the believers cannot
understand the Quran, according to this?
Abdel Rahman: According to the Quran, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Therefore, the people who are not sincere,
the people who are liars, the people who are
disbelievers, they cannot understand the
Quran because God puts shields on their hearts,
their minds, and deafness in their ears. Do
you agree?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, God says that.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Therefore, if I am given access to the most
important secret in the Quran, can I be a
disbeliever who tricked God and discovered
the Miracle of the Quran? Is this possible?
Abdel Rahman: I think so...
Dr. Khalifa: Do you think anybody can trick God?
Abdel Rahman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. So, any disbeliever cannot trick God
and sneak behind His back and find something
in the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: I think when you claim you are a messenger
of God, you are not tricking God. This is...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, I'm talking about discovering the Miracle
of the Quran as a sign of messengership.
Abdel Rahman: Well, there are a lot of ways to discover,
hundreds, hundreds of scholars, they discovered
that the Quran is miracle by its word, by
its verses.
Dr. Khalifa: Inspired yes, then those are good people.
Dr. Khalifa: Are they good people?
Abdel Rahman: They taught us how miracle, how beautiful the
Quran, by its words is, not by its numbers. It's fascinating when you understand the Quran
by its words, by the Quran itself.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you familiar with the mathematical code?
Abdel Rahman: No, sir, I'm not.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so you have to look at it and understand
it first to appreciate that. Anyway, it is...
Dr. Khalifa: Do you think you can give a brief idea for
the audience?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Absolutely, okay.
Abdel Rahman: Thank you.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a psychical fact that "BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
which is the first verse in
Quran consists of 19 letters.
It is a physical fact that the SURAs of the
Quran are 114, 19x4.
It is a physical fact that the first words
revealed were 19 words:
(96:1) ٱقْرَأْ بِٱسْمِ رَبِّكَ ٱلَّذِى خَلَقَ
(96:2) خَلَقَ ٱلْإِنسَـٰنَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ
(96:3) ٱقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ ٱلْأَكْرَمُ
(96:4) ٱلَّذِى عَلَّمَ بِٱلْقَلَمِ
(96:5) عَلَّمَ ٱلْإِنسَـٰنَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ
These are 19 words.
It is a physical fact that this first SURA,
SURA "Al-'Alaq", consists of 19 verses.
It is a physical fact that this SURA, "Al-'Alaq",is
on top of the last 19 SURAs in the Quran.
It is a physical fact that"BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM" - well, let me go to deeper facts.
The number of verses in the Quran is 6346,
which is a multiple of 19.
If you count the word "ALLAH" in the Quran,
you'll find that it is 2698, 19x142.
The word "Quran" in the Quran is mentioned
57 times, 19x3
in 38 SURAs, 19x2.
When you take the verses where the word "Quran"
is mentioned, you find that the total
is 2660, 19x140.
"ALLAH WAHDAHU" in the Quran, when you look
at here in the index -
I will let you look it up yourself. Look
here mister Abdel Salem. "WAHDAHU", when it
says about "ALLAH WAHDAHU", SURA 7, verse 70.
This is "AL-QURAN WAHDAHU", so we don't
count it.
But here's "ALLAH WAHDAHU", 39:45...
Abdel Rahman: I think - okay, I should look like this and
you can concentrate...
Dr. Khalifa: No, you just get this from the library.
Abdel Rahman: You can do it, you can show me.
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is - to look on this way.
But you get this "Al-Mu'jam Al-Mufahas",
okay, from any library, any Islamic library, any Islamic center.
And look at page 745, and you look at the
SURAs and verses where "ALLAH WAHDAHU" is mentioned,
okay?
SURA 7, verse 70.
SURA 39, verse 45.
SURA 40, verses 12 and 84.
SURA 60, verse 4.
You add these numbers, they come to 19x19. OK?
The word "WAHED", when it refers to God is 19 times
So, this goes on and on, SURA "QAF"
has 57 QAFs, 19x3.
SURA "NOON" has 133 NOONs, 19x7.
The 3 SURAs initialed with "SAAD" have 152
SAADs, 19x8.
And it goes on and on, I believe you saw it
in the blue book.
Abdel Rahman: How do you...
Dr. Khalifa: So, this proves that every letter...
Abdel Rahman: Yes. How do you count, calculate all of this
from the Quran itself here, and at the same
time you say this Quran been injected
with different letters in different SURAs? How? Well, now...
Dr. Khalifa: You mean that 2 verses?
Abdel Rahman: There's only 2 verse been injected in the Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: The rest of the Quran is perfect?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. This is how the 2 verses were discovered
because they stand out like a sore thumb.
Abdel Rahman: What's that mean?
Dr. Khalifa: They ruin the words - listen to this - all
the forms, all the forms of the word God are distorted
in these 2 verses.
The word "ALLAH", there is 1 extra in these 2 verses.
Listen to me. The word "ALLAH",
there are 2698 in the Quran. If you include these
two verses, it becomes 2699 which is not a
multiple of 19.
The word "ILAH" is also by 1, and the word "RAB"...
Abdel Rahman: Let me show it to the audience before you go through
what kind of 2 verses doctor
Khalifa is talking about. It is in the SURA
"TAWBAH" in the last 2 verses, says
لَقَدْ جَآءَكُمْ رَسُولٌۭ مِّنْ أَنفُسِكُمْ عَزِيزٌ عَلَيْهِ مَا عَنِتُّمْ حَرِيصٌ عَلَيْكُم بِٱلْمُؤْمِنِينَ رَءُوفٌۭ رَّحِيمٌۭ
فَإِن تَوَلَّوْا۟ فَقُلْ حَسْبِىَ ٱللَّهُ لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ ۖ عَلَيْهِ تَوَكَّلْتُ ۖ وَهُوَ رَبُّ ٱلْعَرْشِ ٱلْعَظِيمِ
Doctor Khalifa, he according to his words
says "this is not Quran. This is been injected
in the Quran".
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: Would you please explain?
Dr. Khalifa: No, you're going away from the subject now.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: From the Mathematical Code.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The Mathematical Code proves that every letter
in the Quran, except these 2 verses that were
humanly injected.
Show me this book again, the two verses. Let me see it
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. These 2 verses are at the end of SURA number 9. OK.
Dr. Khalifa: I want you to read the title of the SURA to
the audience, okay?
And zoom the camera on him.
He's gonna read the title of the SURA,
everything that is written in here. SURA 9.
Abdel Rahman: SURA number 9.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: SURA AL-TAWBAH
مدنیه الا الآیتین الاخیرتین مکیه و آیتها ۱۲۹ نزلت بعد المائدة
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. This says that this is SURA entitled
"AL-TAWBAH." It is a Medinan SURA except the
last 2 verses. They were Meccan.
Now, if you go to Egypt and buy a coin that
says on it "this was done in the year 350 BC,
will the people laugh at you or not?
Because there was no date before Jesus Christ
called 350 BC. There was no dating then.
And everybody will realize that this a stupid
tourist who bought this coin.
Now, we are not stupid to accept a Medinan SURA with two Meccan verses at the end of it.
So, even this Quran that you carry is telling
you that these two verses are fake. They're human injected.
The Mathematical Code exposes them. The
word "ALLAH", the word "ILAH", the word "RAB"
are all increased by 1 because of these 2 verses,
for example.
Abdel Rahman: How did you discover it's been injected?
How did you find?
Dr. Khalifa: By the mathematicalCode. The Mathematical
Code confirms that the Quran is perfect, and that
these two sentences were added in it
to exalt the prophetMuhammad and to worship him.
As you know, they deal with the prophet Muhammad.
Abdel Rahman: So, by your mathematical - as you name it - the
divine mathematical...
Dr. Khalifa: No, forget the mathematics. You just read yourself
now at the title of the SURA that the whole
SURA is Medinan except the last two verses.
They're Meccan. How could that be?
When the prophet moved from Mecca to Medina,
everything revealed after that was Medinan.
How did the two Meccan verses get injected
in a Medinan SURA?
You do not find Meccan verses in Medinan SURAs.
You find Medinan SURAs in Meccan... wait a minute. You find Medinan verses in Meccan SURAs but
not the other way around.
So, if we think a little bit, you yourself
read it now. And this tells you that these two
verses are at least suspect.
So, the Mathematical Code prove beyond doubt,
plus a lot of other evidence.
Even in BUKHARI says these two verses are not correct.
If you read it carefully, and
you read the story of collecting the Quran, okay,
recording the Quran, it tells you that
every single verse in this Quran was witnessed
by more than one witness, except these 2 verses,
the last two verses of SURA 9. They were witnessed
only by one person, Khuzeimah Ibn Thaabet Al-Ansaary. Ansaary means he is Medinan, and the two
verses are Meccan. I mean, it doesn't take
too much intelligence.
Abdel Rahman: A lot of people, they moved from Medina to
Mecca after...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, not Al-Ansaar. This isKhuzeimah Ibn Thaabet Al-Ansaary. So, these are the only two
verses in the Quran that were witnessed by
only one witness according to the stories.
I mean, forget anything else.
Even assuming these stories are correct.
Abdel Rahman: So, you wanna say in other words those
two verses are not Quran, actually?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: Or probably they are from Quran, and they should
Dr. Khalifa: They're from Satan.
be in a different place.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, they are not Quran.
Abdel Rahman: You say they are not Quran period?
Dr. Khalifa: They are not Quran, period.
Abdel Rahman: They are not Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. They stand out by many many many overwhelming
evidence, proofs, many proofs. But this...you have
to write a book about that.
Abdel Rahman: You have to write a book about that?
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Abdel Rahman: Also, by inventing the divine mathematical
codes, that's why you claim for - we assume that
you are a messenger of God because of this one, right? Or there is any other evidence?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the fact that we want to establish here
is that no one can touch the Quran unless
he is a sincere believer, right?
Abdel Rahman: If you are a sincere believer, you are a messenger of God? I am a sincere believer.
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran says...
Dr. Khalifa: A sincere believer will not lie and say "I'm a messenger of God."
Abdel Rahman: If you are a sincere believer, does that make
you a messenger of God?
Dr. Khalifa: If you are a sincere believer, you will not
lie about God. Is this correct?
Abdel Rahman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Wait a minute, a sincere believer will not
lie about God. Is this correct?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, a person who finds something in
the Quran, especially if it is the secret
miracle of the Quran, this person must be
a sincere believer. And if this person is
a sincere believer as established by the fact
of discovering the secret of the Quran,
then this person will not possibly lie against
God and say that he's a messenger of God.
Abdel Rahman: But why, why you precisely say "I am a messenger of
God since I discovered this"? Why you didn't say
"o people, o Muslims, I'm coming
to correct something" like Hassan AL-Imam,
like Ghazali, like Muhammad Abduh, they didn't... they were
very sincerely Islam, and they correct a lot
of ways in Islam, but they never claim that
they are messenger of God. They...
Dr. Khalifa: Were they sincere believers?
Abdel Rahman: They were sincere believers.
Dr. Khalifa: Therefore, they will not lie about God. If
they were not messengers of God,
they will not lie about God. Did they claim to
be messengers of God?
Abdel Rahman: They never claimed they are messenger of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Right
Dr. Khalifa: So, they were not messenger of God.
Abdel Rahman: So, why you claim you are a messenger of God?
Dr. Khalifa: Because I am.
Abdel Rahman: Is it because of this mathematical codes only?
Dr. Khalifa: No, Because I am a messenger of God.
Abdel Rahman: Well, give me a proof that you are...
Dr. Khalifa: I just gave.
Abdel Rahman: No, not this, because this is...
Dr. Khalifa: My name also is mentioned in the Quran here.
If you open this index,...
Abdel Rahman: OK. Your name as "AL-RASHIN AL-KHOLAFA"
has nothing to do with, you know...
Dr. Khalifa: You're entitled to say what you want, but
what is the root word of my name?
Abdel Rahman: Your name is Rashad.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: Rashad has nothing...and my name is Abdel Rahman...
Dr. Khalifa: Hold it. Hold it. Hold it. I'm just wanna...let's go step by
step, okay?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The root word of my name is "RASHADA." Is
this correct?
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. We're talking about Arabic language. This is the index of the Quran again.
Abdel Rahman: OK.
Page 320. And the root of my word - is it here? Do you see it here?
RASHADA.
Abdel Rahman: Your name is Rashad, not "RASHADA."
Dr. Khalifa: I know
the root word of Rashad is "RASHADA",
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Right? And do you see "RASHADA" here?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, "RASHADA" is between this mark here
and this mark, alright?
Abdel Rahman: Mmhmm.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I want you to count the number of mentionings
of the root word "RASHADA" in the Quran. You count it
yourself, go ahead.
Abdel Rahman: Okay, whatever, I count it - you did count it, so
we won't waste audience time.
Dr. Khalifa: No, go ahead, you go ahead.
Dr. Khalifa: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5
Abdel Rahman: Yes, it count up to...
Dr. Khalifa: 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The root word of my name is mentioned 19 times.
The Mathematical Code of the Quran is based
on the number 19, as you see.
Abdel Rahman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, do you think this is coincidence?
Abdel Rahman: But this is not your name doctor Khalifa,
excuse me, "RASHADA" is an Arabic word.
Dr. Khalifa: It is the root word...
Abdel Rahman: My name is Abdel Rahman...
Dr. Khalifa: If my name, Rashad, is mentioned in multiples of 19,
would you believe it?
Abdel Rahman: No, I won't.
Dr. Khalifa: Why?
Abdel Rahman: Because simply it has nothing to do with the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you think this is coincidence, in other
words?
Abdel Rahman: No, not coincidence, but this has nothing to
do with your name, "RASHADA", Rashad,
has nothing to do with your name.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, we said that
there is a Mathematical Code in the Quran.
Abdel Rahman: Did you stop it?
A woman: Wait, wait, wait. Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: We were talking about number 19.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. The Mathematical Code of the Quran
is based on number 19.
The root word of my name is mentioned
in the Quran 19 times, which is "RASHADA."
Abdel Rahman: Not your name, again also I am saying not
your name. It's saying the word of "RASHADA",
or "AL-RASHAD", it doesn't mean Rashad Khalifa.
Dr. Khalifa: Hold it. Hold it. I'm not talking about Rashad.
I am talking about "RASHADA." The root word
for my name is mentioned in the Quran 19 times,
which is in accordance with the Mathematical Code.
But also my name "Rashad" and "Khalifa", if
you add the numbers of the SURAs and verses,
you come up with muplies of 19.
Abdel Rahman: WhenALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA mentioned Muhammad, He means Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: Ibn Abdullah.
Abdel Rahman: But when He mentioned Rashad, He doesn't mean He mention
Rashad Khalifa.
Dr. Khalifa: Because the Quran was delivered 1400 years before
Rashad Khalifa. God will not... God will not
Abdel Rahman: But He doesn't know...
Dr. Khalifa: Wait. God will not put in the Quran that
"I'm sending Rashad Khalifa." He will not say
that. So, He put it in mathematically-coded
terms that are not to be revealed until the
Mathematical Code is revealed. Okay?
Abdel Rahman: And that's...
Dr. Khalifa: This is probably why there is no other Rashad
Khalifa that I know of. There was one Rashad
Khalifa that born in my family. My cousin had a boy,
and he named him Rashad Khalifa, and the
boy died when he was young. And I advised
them not to do that...
Abdel Rahman: If I go to any Arabic country and I found
Rashad Khalifa
Dr. Khalifa: Who claims to be a messenger of God.
Abdel Rahman: No. Any Rashad Khalifa.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah?
Abdel Rahman: Nobody lives in this world by name Rashad Khalifa
but you?
Dr. Khalifa: I don't know anyone who's named Rashad
Khalifa but me.
Abdel Rahman: If we found someone by this name, what do you
think?
Dr. Khalifa: And he says he's a messenger of God?
Abdel Rahman: No, he will say "I'm Rashad Khalifa."
Dr. Khalifa: Well, fine. He's Rashad Khalifa. But if he
says he's messenger of God, that's
something else.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Does he say he is a messenger of God?
Abdel Rahman: You approve that you are a messenger of God
by the divine Mathematical Code...
Dr. Khalifa: By discovering the Mathematical Code.
Abdel Rahman: And 19 names of your name. What else?
Abdel Rahman: Can you...
Dr. Khalifa: There are hundreds of other things.
Abdel Rahman: Let's see, let's hear it.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I cannot tell you those things.
Abdel Rahman: Let's hear it because...
Dr. Khalifa: I'm giving you the physical evidence.
Abdel Rahman: In order to be a messenger of God, you have
to be above ordinary people.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: Above, like you are doing something...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. I don't mean yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. Wait a minute. No.
Abdel Rahman: Like you are doing something no human being can do it.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. This is not true. The Quran teaches that
Moses went to one of our servants.
عَبْدًۭا مِّنْ عِبَادِنَآ (18:65)
And this one of our servants taught
Moses a few things, and Moses was a very bad teacher.
So, I want to correct you that you're saying that messengers
are above the ordinary.
Abdel Rahman: But the Quran said thatALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA taught Musa some kind of devices in order to
appear in front of his own people.
Dr. Khalifa: The miracles of...
Abdel Rahman: Yeah people, in order to make the people believe.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: Hold it. This is not a human being ordinary. He is not the magic. This is not a magic. This
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
is something from God.
Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, I have given you enough poofs. And
I want you to ask anybody to give me a proof
that I'm not a messenger of God, one, one proof.
Abdel Rahman: You haven't convinced me.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's move on.
Abdel Rahman: You have not convince...
Dr. Khalifa: I don't wanna convince you.
Abdel Rahman: We are trying... you haven't convinced me
so far you are a messenger. You didn't give me
something
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: to astonish me or to make me say "Oh, he
is above mankind."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Abdel Rahman: So, I have to believe it.
Dr. Khalifa: Let me read something for you in here.
Abdel Rahman: Okay. So, you're holding this book and you
don't believe in it?
Dr. Khalifa: What do you mean I don't believe in it?
Abdel Rahman: You said this book is not correct.
Dr. Khalifa: No. The complete Quran is here. There is some addition.
Abdel Rahman: Some addition?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Abdel Rahman: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: You can't make statements like that.
Look at this
وَقَالُوا۟ لَن نُّؤْمِنَ لَكَ حَتَّىٰ تَفْجُرَ لَنَا مِنَ ٱلْأَرْضِ يَنۢبُوعًا (17:90)
They said "we'll not believe unless
you have a spring gush out of the earth."
أَوْ تَكُونَ لَكَ جَنَّةٌۭ مِّن نَّخِيلٍۢ وَعِنَبٍۢ فَتُفَجِّرَ ٱلْأَنْهَـٰرَ خِلَـٰلَهَا تَفْجِيرًا (17:91)
Or you possess a garden of dates and grapes,
with rivers flowing in."
أَوْ تُسْقِطَ ٱلسَّمَآءَ كَمَا زَعَمْتَ عَلَيْنَا كِسَفًا أَوْ تَأْتِىَ بِٱللَّهِ وَٱلْمَلَـٰٓئِكَةِ قَبِيلًا (17:92)
Or you drop the heaven over us,
the sky over us, as you claimed. Or bring
God and the angels before our eyes.
(17:93) أَوْ يَكُونَ لَكَ بَيْتٌۭ مِّن زُخْرُفٍ
or you posses a mansion, a fantastic mansion
أَوْ تَرْقَىٰ فِى ٱلسَّمَآءِ
or see you climb to the sky
وَلَن نُّؤْمِنَ لِرُقِيِّكَ
even if you do that we will not believe.
So, I cannot... I don't want anybody to be convinced.
All I can do is deliver the message and tell you
what the proofs are. And then it's up
to you to take it or leave it.
Abdel Rahman: In your book here "Quran, Hadith &amp; Islam"
- also one of the book you wrote about
Quran, Hadith and Islam - you said here "we don't believe in anything with intercession."
What does that mean? You don't believe in
intercession?
Dr. Khalifa: We believe the Quran that says
قُل لِّلَّهِ ٱلشَّفَـٰعَةُ جَمِيعًۭا (39:44)
"to God belongs all intercession." So, nobody possesses intercession.
Abdel Rahman: You don't believe that the messenger of God
will make"SHAFA'AT" to the Muslims?
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran says that the messenger of God will not have any SHAFA'AT
any intercession, it says
إِن تَسْتَغْفِرْ لَهُمْ سَبْعِينَ مَرَّةًۭ فَلَن يَغْفِرَ ٱللَّهُ لَهُمْ (9:80)
God tells Muhammad "if you ask forgiveness
for them seventy times, God will not forgive them.
So, there you have it.
Ebrahim made intercession on behalf of his
father, but his father is going to hell. It
does not matter. Ebrahim is God's friend.
So, I'm afraid we have to quit. If you have
one last question, I'll answer one last question.
Abdel Rahman: Well, I have a lot of questions, actually,
but if you're gonna quit, we won't go anywhere.
But I hope you will, before you quit, you will
comment or you will say something you would
like to say to the Muslims.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, what I'd like to say is that Islam
today has nothing to do with the prophet Muhammad.
And it is the objective of all the sincere believers
to restore Islam to the religion preached
by the prophet Muhammad.
As I mentioned in this program, the Muslims
around the world are not doing anything correctly.
Everything is wrong: the AZAN, the ablution,
the SALAT, the ZAKAT, the HAJJ, the fasting.
Everything is done not according to the teachings
of the prophet Muhammad that came to us in
the Quran. And it is the objective to restore Islam
to its original pristine purity as preached
by the prophet Muhammad, the final prophet.
سلام علیکم و رحمة الله
Abdel Rahman: Thank you doctor Rashad Khalifa. And I really appreciate your time.