In the name of God, the Gracious, the
Merciful. More and more people are
increasingly disillusioned with the Bible.
They grow up learning that the Bible is
the Word of God.
But when they study the Bible carefully,
they discover that it contains too many
unacceptable contradictions,
too much unacceptable nonsense.
And this shocks them and causes the
disillusionment.
A very good example is in the market
today, in the bookstores.
We find a book by Carl Sagan called "Contact", and on page 30 of this book, we find a very
good example of the contradictions, the
unacceptable contradictions in the Bible.
We see here that in the Gospel of
Matthew, there are 28
generations between David and Jesus.
But in the Gospel of Luke, we see that the
number of generations from David to Jesus is 43.
Now, how could this be the
word of God? Does God know how many
generations are between David and Jesus?
The names in Matthew and in Luke are not
even similar.
And this destroys the credibility of the
Bible as the Word of God.
How can we explain these contradictions?
This program will prove to you that the Bible
is in fact the Word of God.
But these indefensible contradictions
are there because they were injected by human beings. Any contradiction, any
nonsense you see in the Bible, is a
result of human interference, distortions
and injections by wicked people, or good
intentioned people. So, I will prove to
you that the vast majority of the Bible
is Divine truth.
The biggest contradiction of all is the
deification of Jesus Christ,
making him a god against his will, and
against the teachings of the Bible even.
We read in Matthew 27:46
that "on the cross, toward mid-afternoon,
Jesus cried out in a loud tone and the
Gospel of Matthew even write the Aramaic
that Jesus supposedly uttered on the cross
"ELI ELI LAMA SABACHTHANI?"
Which means
"my God, my God, why have you forsaken me?"
Now, this is not God speaking, saying "my
God, my God, why have you forsaken me?"
This also casts doubt and creates a serious
contradiction concerning the doctrine
that Jesus came here to die for our sins.
Because if this were true, then his
crucifixion would be a fulfillment of
his purpose and he would have said on
the cross "my God, my God, thank you for
fulfilling my mission." So, all these
contradictions
create disillusionment in the minds of
intelligent people. In this Bible here, we
find the theme at the beginning like
this "the man who hears my word and has
faith in Him who sent me, possesses eternal life." So, this verse is telling us
that Jesus was sent to humanity by God, that Jesus is a messenger of God.
And when we go to the book of Revelation, the
very first verse says the following
"This is the revelation God gave to Jesus
Christ, that he might show his servants
what must happen very soon." This is the
revelation God gave to Jesus Christ.
So, here we have God giving a message to
Jesus Christ in order to deliver to the
world. Jesus could not possibly be God.
Jesus is a messenger of God.
Many great Christians of course realized this
serious contradiction, the deification of
Jesus against his will and studied it carefully and researched the
subject thoroughly. This book is written
by Don Cupitt, a University Lecturer in
Divinity and Dean of Emmanuel College, Cambridge.
Michael Goulder, Staff Tutor in Theology in the Department of Extramural Studies at
Birmingham University. John Hick, who is H. G. Wood Professor of Theology
at Birmingham University. Leslie Houlden, Principal of Ripon College, Cuddesdon
Dennis Nineham, Warden of Keble College at Oxford.
Maurice Wiles, Regius Professor of Divinity and Canon of
Christ Church
at Oxford, and Chairman of the Church of
England's Doctrine Commission.
And the final author here is Frances Young,
Lecturer in New Testament Studies
at Birmingham University. And the essence or
the summary of the book is found on the
back where it says "for many people, the
incarnation of God in Jesus Christ
is the essence of Christianity." Here, a group
of distinguished theologians
and biblical scholars asked whether the idea
of the incarnation is essential to
Christianity and they questioned the
whole development of the doctrine.
Their thesis is that Jesus was as he is
described presented in Acts 2:21
"a man approved by God" for a
special road within the divine purpose
and the later conception of him as God
incarnate, the second person of the Holy
Trinity living a human life is a
mythological or poetic way of expressing
his significance for us. This reinterpretation of the doctrine of the
incarnation has been criticized as
sensational and destructive, but the
authors declare a constructive purpose. They have examined the evidence from the
New Testament onward with care and
fairness and have asked their questions
because they are concerned with the
consequences of their findings for a
full and living Christian faith for
today. Their work is something that no
thinking Christian can ignore.
I assure you that we do not have enough
time to give examples of the
contradictions and nonsense that is
found throughout the Bible, unfortunately.
But you heard me state earlier that the
Bible is in fact the Word of God, the
infallible Word of God. And here I am
talking about the original unaltered
Bible in the original language.
That was the Word of God.
The contradiction and the
nonsense have been injected into the
Bible by people who deliberately or with
good intentions actually distorted the
words of God and created doctrines that
are not in the Bible. However, the Bible
as printed today, 90% of it is Divine
truth. Unfortunately, the human race has
been duped into following the 10% of
contradictions and false doctrines
injected by humans into the Bible.
The Bible, being the Word of God, must be
corrected and God sees to it that all
these contradiction and nonsense are exposed.
The biggest problem that these
contradictions and nonsense create is
that millions of people throw the baby
with the bathwater. Because of these
contradictions and false doctrines that
have been injected in the Bible and the
nonsense that the intelligent people
cannot accept, these things
unfortunately drive millions of people
away from God and from the Word of God.
But we must be alerted that the Bible
contains the truth from God. For example,
the first commandment in the Old
Testament and in the New Testament which
is called the greatest commandment is to
worship God alone, the Creator of the
universes, the Creator who created you
and me and Jesus Christ and Muhammad and Mary.
It is the false doctrines that created
the Trinity and the deification of Jesus
Christ against his will and distorted
the Bible. Ironically, the distortions and
the nonsense and the false doctrines
constitute a minute part of the Bible. But
unfortunately, millions upon millions of
people follow these minute contradictions
and small false doctrines and they leave
the majority of the truth. They ignore,
for example, the fact that the Bible
clearly states that Jesus is not God.
Millions of people ignore the clear
statements throughout the Bible that
Jesus is not God and they insist on the
defection of Jesus against his will.
And in this way, they are being enemies of
Jesus Christ as he himself says in
Matthew 7:23
"Then I will tell them plainly, ‘I never knew you. Away from me, you evildoers!’" [Matthew 7:23]
Of course, God did something about the
contradictions, the falsehood, the
nonsense that have been injected into
His word, the Bible. And what God did was
to send a final edition of the scripture.
This final edition is mathematically
composed beyond human ability, as I will
explain to you. When you examine this
final message from God to you, you will
be sure that every letter, every word is
from God. You will be absolutely positive
that there is no human interference in
it and you will see which truth in the
Bible is confirmed by this final segment
of the scripture and you will see that
the contradiction and the false
doctrines are exposed.
As such, you will recognize which is the
truth from God and which is the
falsehood from human beings, human
interference into the Bible. So, this is
what God did to clear the confusion, to
settle the controversies, and to
establish the truth in His Bible.
This final segment of God's message to
the world settles once and for all the
subject of the crucifixion of Jesus. And
God tells us he was an eyewitness there, remember?
God tells us that the person of Jesus
Christ, that is the soul, left his body,
was raised to God before his body was
put on the cross. So, the people who were
torturing Jesus' body and crucifying it
were not dealing with Jesus Christ at
all. Jesus was gone already. He was raised
like anyone who dies. The soul was
raised, returned to God, and the body was
tortured and put on the cross. And the
heart was beating and the lungs were
breathing, but the person was not there.
Ironically, God gives us today a good
example of a person whose soul has
departed but his body is living with us
and his heart is beating and his lungs
are breathing, he's eating and he smiles
and everything, but his soul departed. And
I am talking about one of the people who
received an artificial heart, Bill Schroeder.
About a month after his
operation, he was having dinner with his
wife and we are told he had a stroke.
In my opinion, Bill Schroeder left. The person
is gone. And now his body is walking with
an artificial heart and his lungs are
breathing but the person is not here. He
does not recognize the time or the
people around him ever since that moment.
And this is exactly what happened
regarding the crucifixion of Jesus, as
told in God's final message that is
proven by mathematical code.
So, let me summarize for you what this
final message from God to the world does.
First of all, it exposes the contradiction and the
nonsense that have been injected in the Bible.
The second thing, it confirms the Divine
truths that are found in the Bible, the
majority of the Bible is Divine truth.
The third function of this final message
from God to the world is to settle the
great controversies, like the deification of Jesus, the
sonship, the claimed sonship of Jesus to God.
The the fourth function of this final
segment of God's Scripture is to confirm
all previous miracles, the unusual
happenings that cannot, that may be
unbelievable, like the parting of the Red
Sea, like the fact that Jesus revived the
dead, and created birds from clay by God's
leave. All these things are hard to believe.
So, this final segment of God's Scripture
being mathematically composed and
containing this physical evidence that
it is from God confirms those unusual
happenings that we call miracles.
Since every letter, every word in this
final segment of God's scripture is
mathematically composed beyond human
ability, when you read a statement saying
"Moses parted the Red Sea," this statement
becomes proven by physical evidence. When
you read in this message that Jesus
revived the dead, which is something
unbelievable, normally, when you read that
and you know that it is a miracle...
miracle by definition is an unusual
happening. So, when you read the statement
Jesus revived the dead, and you know that
every letter, every word is
mathematically composed beyond the human ability, then this gives you
physical evidence that the statement
"Jesus revived the dead" is a proven fact.
Unusual as it may be, it is God's miracle
that Jesus performed. So, these are the
four functions of God's final scripture
to the world. Expose the contradiction
and nonsense and remove it from the
Bible.
Confirm the Divine truths that are
contained in the Bible. Settle the
controversies like the virgin birth of
Jesus and the crucifixion of his body
after his soul has departed.
And the fourth function is to confirm
all previous miracles, the miracles of
Moses and Jesus and the unusual
happenings that we see in the Bible and
in the Quran.
I am sure you realize that we cannot
cover these heavy subjects in such a
short time.
And because these subjects are so heavy,
I am sure I raised more questions than
answered. And this is why I hope you will
get on the phone and call me with your
questions. Don't hesitate to ask. My phone
(www.submission.ws)
number is area code 602 791 3989. I am going to put
the address and the telephone number on
the screen for you. So, please write or
(www.submission.ws)
call. My address is 739 East
6th Street Tucson Arizona 85719.
(www.submission.ws)
And the telephone is area
code 602 791 3989
(www.submission.ws)
Thank you and God bless you.