United in this place of Prayer, each individual soul joined in
community of worship
One God
LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH
ALLAH-O AKBAR
Praise God. We bear witness that there is no god except the One God.
There's no other gods or idols besides Him.
In the last KHUTBA, we reached the
conclusion that you do not really believe in God
unless you know that He's doing everything.
You make the initial decision, this is our
role.
We make a decision,
a decision to be with God or not
and "not" means
you'll be with Satan
because there's no other choice. You're either with God or with
Satan.
And this is the decision where we have absolute freedom of choice.
After that you're either guided by God
or messed up by Satan,
but the Ultimate Doer of everything is
God.
And everything's happening in accordance with God's will.
I want today to compare our priorities.
I just remembered an idea, I have to write it down so I don't forget.
I want to use the board
here to illustrate something about priorities.
Most people do not know who they are.
We recognize now the human being as consisting of two entities,
just to make it very simple, the body and the soul.
The body goes on for, let's be optimistic, about 100 years
and then it dies, becomes nothing.
The soul is the real person,
the real "you."
This is the real person right here and
it goes on for eternity.
The body has requirements and the soul
has requirements.
The body... now, what I want to compare here
is what we do for this entity
and what we do for this entity.
For this entity, people
starting with an infant: the infant is given milk and nourished, given shots,
painful shots,
and grow in pains
and teething
and then they go to school,
the body goes to school. You know, you have to go to school, right?
If you wanna be... there's a commercial on
the radio and TV now by,
what is the name of that comic cat?
Garfield. He said "if you wanna be a fact cat, go to school, go to college." I think he said.
So, you go to school
and you take tests
and go through the homeworks
and the absence reports
and chastising from the parents and the teachers
and working very hard studying.
You know, school is not popular with most
of us.
You go through grade school,
junior high school.
Then, you go to high school and all the hard work
involved in it and you're so glad to
graduate only to go into college. Then, you're a freshman
and you study very hard and work and
you're very busy,
you know, devoting a lot of effort and
time and money to go to school because
why? Because this body, you want it to
dress nicely, you have good clothes,
and you want to buy a house, preferably in the foothills
with so many rooms and luxuries and
carpets and drapes.
This body wants that.
And you work hard for that.
You graduate from college and you apply for jobs.
You go to the placement office
and you stand in line for the interviewer, the people who interview you
and you are very polite
to be interviewed. You want to be bright.
You want to pretend to be bright and you
want to put on your best appearance
and some sense of humor and intelligence, abilities, you know. You pretend to be perfect
for the interview and you get
the job
and then you do a lousy job and you're fired.
Then, you apply for other jobs
and you're miserable.
You know, all this is, this is for the body because the body wants clothes, housing, food
and we do all this work for the body.
Now, what are they doing for the soul,
the average person?
Now, this is the real person.
Now, after all this, the body dies, goes to dust, becomes nothing.
There was a person... this body will belong
to a person called Rock Hudson, remember that name?
Rock Hudson. Ok. He died recently.
That's why you still remember him. And Rock Hudson was a very
successful person
lots of money, fame,
covers, magazine covers, in the front
covers, TV movies, wealth, Beverly Hills mansion.
This body, his body had a lot of fun
and he also broke God's law, as we know, and he died in humiliation.
Now, now the real person, Rock Hudson, does exist, the
real person.
What did he do for this body?
And what did he do for this? What did the fame and money bring him?
What was the value
of the fame and the money that he accumulated?
Remember George Liberace?
The glitter, the suits that he was wearing
and the showmanship and the clapping, the
people clapping for him, the performances he gave,
and how many millions of dollars he made.
But how much does he, the real person, have?
At the end, the mortician was afraid to touch him
because of the virus, AIDS virus.
Rockefeller, any of them. So, the body,
people work very hard for this entity here.
What do they do for "the soul"?
This is the question.
What I'm trying to bring out is rearranging our priorities, or putting our priorities in perspective.
What are we doing for the soul? What does the soul need?
The soul needs worshiping God Alone.
This is the first step
because the soul is part of God in any
way you want to look at it.
Because God said "I blew into Adam from My spirit."
So, the soul needs to worship God alone
and then it needs food, nutrition,
the five daily meals. The five prayers
are needed.
You need the fasting.
People like Rock Hudson, for example,
he put himself in the service of this body.
He was serving this body.
Whatever the body wants, he gave it,
but he neglected "himself."
And if "the soul" was this size when he started,
it is still this size now, didn't
grow. He didn't feed his soul.
His priorities were mixed up. I'm using a real person as an example
because here's a person who attained fame and fortune.
The conclusion from this is that anything that we do that is not
developing our soul is a waste of time.
If you do anything that has nothing to
do with God is a waste of time.
So, when you wake up in the morning,
until the end of the day, you ask yourself
"am I doing this for God?"
which is, which is another word for feeding your soul
because anything you
do for God causes your soul to grow and develop.
It is actually for yourself, for the real entity.
So, we have to rearrange our
priorities,
put them in perspective.
How much of the day are you doing for
the body and how much are you doing for you?
You went to school and suffered through examinations
to have a good job.
What did you do for you?
By the way, the hundred years compared to
infinity is zero.
So, this is the proportion that you should do for
yourself and for your body.
You should do zero for your body
and you should do 100% for you.
It is not intelligent otherwise
because this is zero.
It's going to be nothing.
So, you have to put this in the
service of you
and not the other way around.
Almost everybody out there has their priorities reversed.
They put this in the service of a vanishing garment.
TUBU ILLA ALLAH. Repent.
ALHAMDU LILLAH. WA ASH HADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH.
From this diagram, I want to
move on to comparing
a believer, a Muslim, one who submitted to
God, and a regular person.
I was looking out the window the other
day. I prayed my morning prayer
and about an hour later, one of my
neighbors...
I was looking out the window and I saw the
neighbor coming out
and he was obviously very sleepy.
His hair was all messed up and you can imagine, a person who just got up, you know,
he's walking like this. He can hardly walk.
He's young. I mean, he's not old.
His clothes are a mess
and he was out to get the newspaper.
Now, a Muslim wakes up in the morning, the
first thing he says, or she says
بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ. لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا ٱللَّهُ وحده لا شریک له
The first thing a person says. Remember we
pledged this in one of the KHUTBAs.
The first thing you're going... I hope you didn't
forget.
We do forget once in a while but
the first thing when you get up in the morning:
بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
"In the name of God"
لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا ٱللَّهُ وحده لا شریک له
because this is what you will say when you get up on
the Day of Resurrection,
whatever you say every morning.
And I have to repeat what most people say when they get up in the
morning and they look in the clock
And it is oh sh**, and this is what they will say.
This is exactly what they'll say on the Day of Judgement when they get up in the morning
"Oh sh**"
Because usually they are up late, you
know, they get up. They turn the alarm off and go back to sleep
And then when they get up next time, it's too late and they utter the four-letter words.
So, the Muslim gets up in the morning:
بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ. لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا ٱللَّهُ وحده لا شریک له
When you get up on the Day of Resurrection,
if this is a habit here,
it's gonna be a habit also
on the Day of Judgement.
God will see to it. God will help you.
And there is no place to go to, when you get up on the Day of Resurrection, saying
بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ. لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا ٱللَّهُ وحده لا شریک له
"There's only One God." There's no place to go but Heaven
on the Day of Resurrection.
So, this is what the Muslim does. Now, what did
my neighbor do when he got up in the morning
looking for the paper?
God is not on his mind.
Let's take the average person.
I hope God was in his mind,
but it didn't look like it.
And then the Muslim goes to do his
ablution or her ablution.
You go and do ablution in the morning
and you pray the morning.
This is the first thing you do.
And this act of ablution and the morning prayer is very refreshing.
You're alert.
You look nice.
You washed your face.
You combed your hair.
You will not look like this guy.
I mean, he really looked, looked terrible.
You only see that in the movies, somebody just got up
out of bed, you know.
The Muslim
commemorates God in every chance he or she gets.
The Muslim sees the sunrise and says "SUBHAN ALLAH."
All these are nutritions for the soul,
for you, the real person.
And your soul grows when you say "SUBHAN ALLAH," Glory be to God
as you see the Sun rising,
because you're always conscious of God.
The Sun is
rising exactly at the precise second
and from the same spot that it is supposed
to, without delay.
And God committed that sun in your service.
And you say "SUBHAN ALLAH."
You look at the flower and you do the
same thing.
Then, you make a telephone call to one of your friends or associates
and you say
"tomorrow, I'm going to do this and that, IN SHAA ALLAH," God willing.
There's a certain behavior of the person who has submitted to God because you know that "God is doing everything"
and you know that you will do this and that
tomorrow only because God wills.
But God will do that.
And the Quran gives you this very clear
commandment.
And then your kids get up and
you admire them and you say "Mã Shã Allãh."
"This is God's giving to you." This is
God's will that you have these children
and you thank God.
Now, the non-Muslim
is unaware.
God is not on his or her mind at all.
And they are neglecting the real person,
themselves, neglecting themselves.
They'll
be very careful to have breakfast,
but they will not give breakfast to
their soul.
So, you are living 24 hours a day, you are
commemorating your Creator. And you are...
Your Creator doesn't need that. God
doesn't need any of our prayers or our worship.
We do.
So, you are being prepared
for the eternal life which is coming.
You don't see anybody around who's 200
years old, do you?
You haven't heard of anyone.
It's coming, the Day of Resurrection.
And then, you'll be assigned
that eternal rank
depending on the spot where you
qualified, how much growth you did.
So, so far I talked about rearranging the
priorities or putting the priorities in perspective
and how much time we devote
to your soul,
the real person
and how much time you give to
your job and your boss and your family and so on strictly.
You can give time to
your family in the cause of God.
Our priorities must be in perspective.
This is why you are here for the Friday
prayer. You dropped all business and you
are here for the Friday prayer. This is
the correct priority. Anytime you are not
here on Friday,
you're out of God's grace.
It's a commandment for every Friday.
You drop all business and you go to the
Friday prayer. And God associates this
with business and profit. And God said "it
is better for you to drop business."
And because God runs the world, "God is doing
everything" and when you drop your
business and go to the Friday prayer as
God commands you to, God will see to it
that you make more money, more profit. And
you don't care but it will come.
"Rearranging or putting our priorities in
perspective"
I'm gonna read a couple of verses
from the Quran that deal with this
subject of priorities.
In SURA 18 starting at verse 45, it says "cite for them...
أعوذ بالله من الشيطن الرجيم
I seek refuge in God from Satan.
بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
In the name of God. It says "cite for them the example of this world like sending water
from the sky that causes plants to grow
on the earth and then turns to hay, blown
away by the wind."
This is this world. This is the example of
this world in verse 45 of SURA 18.
The plant grows. It is strong. You see all
those flowers out there? They're very
nice. Watch them. They're gonna turn into
dry something like hay and they'll blow
away. In fact, the time will come and you'll
say "I want to remove these stuff from
here" because it's gonna be dry and
shriveled. And this is how this world is.
The next verse
it says that "money and children
are the beauty of this life or the
adornments of this life."
This is the good things of this
life: money and children. In Arabic:
ٱلْمَالُ وَٱلْبَنُونَ زِينَةُ ٱلْحَيَوٰةِ ٱلدُّنْيَا
And I've heard many people, they say "God says that money
and children are the adornments of this life.
I have lots of children.
Where is the money?"
But generally, money and children
are adorning, are the beauties, or the
the adornment of this life, but and then the rest of the verse says
"However the eternal righteous works."
وَٱلْبَـٰقِيَـٰتُ ٱلصَّـٰلِحَـٰتُ
in Arabic
that "the righteous works that last forever"
to talk about the real person here.
are far better for you.
So, money and children and properties
in this world, they are the good things in
this life.
And God tells us what is better than that.
Like I mentioned in the last KHUTBA
worshipping God alone and nourishing
your real person, the Quran says, is much
better than owning everything on this
earth and twice as much.
All the real estate in Vancouver
and New York.
All the real estate in the whole world. All
the oil, the gold, the diamonds.
Believing in God alone and feeding,
nourishing your real person is much
better. When you have the right perspective, is much better than owning everything on
earth and twice as much. So, this verse 46
of SURA 18 says "money and children are
the beauties or the good things
of this world, but the righteous works
that last forever are far better and
provide better hope وَخَيْرٌ أَمَلًۭا
The end of the verse is خَيْرٌ أَمَلًۭا
There is better hope in them. There
is no hope in the properties. Rock Hudson
was very famous and very rich.
George Liberace's mansion still you can
go as a tourist and look at it, but he's
not there
because there's something better that he could have acquired.
That is righteous works and developing his soul
in order to withstand life next to God
in the Hereafter. If he didn't develop his
soul, he will not stand being close to
God. And the verse 47 says "because the
day will come when we remove the
mountains
and you see the Earth
barren." Everything will go.
"and then we will gather every single one.
The Arabic says فَلَمْ نُغَادِرْ مِنْهُمْ أَحَدًۭا
"We will not leave a single person."
God says "we're gonna gather everybody" to, for this
reckoning. How much did you do for this
vanishing garment? How much did you do
for yourself? The reckoning is gonna
be automatic, but every single one will
come to account.
The next verses go on and describe
why the righteous works, and feeding your
soul is the number one priority.
That when you do anything else, it's a
waste of time. Anything else that does not
develop your soul is a waste of time.
And missing a Friday prayer... I'm using this
because you're all here... when you miss a
Friday prayer for any reason, it's a
terrible terrible loss.
Because being once a week at
congregational prayer where you meet
your brothers and sisters, and it's a
commandment from God to do this. When you
miss it, you miss a lot.
I mean, I cannot put it in billions of
dollars.
We have to always remember the right
perspective.
And the advice in Quran is to commemorate
commemorate God 24 hours a day, every
chance you get. You can turn your work
into worship.
You can take the mail from the fellow. Open it.
He has a express mail thing.
And I need it. Bring it. These are papers
that I need.
It's one o'clock so I'm gonna read
some material and some kind of a quiz.
I want you to find out or think where it is from.
Ok?
Every addition or omission
of a word or even of a single letter from
the sacred text of the prayers
destroys the religious meaning of the
prayer as a whole and is to be regarded
as a grave sin,
a sin which could result in eternal
exile for those who commit it.
Remember there are certain statements of
Quran that says وَيْلٌ لِلْمُصَلِّينَ "woe to
those who are doing their prayer."
I mean, those are people who are doing their
prayer, but they end up in the negative
because they are heedless of their
prayers or because there are other
reasons. So, you must make sure that your
prayer is perfect, your SALAT,
your contact. I'm not talking about
supplications. I'm talking about your
Contact Prayers.
It is a recognized statement in Quran
وَيْلٌ لِلْمُصَلِّينَ
"Woe to those who are doing their Salat prayer."
الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَنْ صَلَاتِهِمْ سَاهُونَ
"who are heedless of their prayers." They are not aware or they
are neglecting something. Let me read
this again. And I wanted to apply it to
our Contact Prayer here. See, Barry is
visiting us for the first time and he will
wonder why do we do the prayer in Arabic
and why this particular prayer, for example.
And all of us asked this question.
In fact, it's gonna come up. So, let me read
this again.
"Every addition
or omission
of a word or even a single letter." Now, we in
this mosque fully appreciate the
mathematical composition of everything
that's connected with our worships, the
Quran and even the bones in our
body and everything else. So, we should
appreciate what is written here.
"Every addition or omission of a word or
even of a single letter from the sacred
text..." Al-Fãtehah is the sacred text that
God gave us,
the first SURA of Quran. We cannot add
anything to it. As you know, Satan
succeeded everywhere in the Muslim world,
they add the word "Amen."
And our people in Washington DC have a
radio program and I have one of the tapes
here talking about this "Amen." And they
got it from a dictionary, some
recognized dictionary and they read what
"Amen" is. It turned out to be an old
Hebrew-Greek something word that has nothing to
do with Arabic. It is not in the Quran, but
here this is why Satan tricked the people
into adding it.
"Every addition or omission of a word or
even a single letter from the sacred
text of the payers destroys the
religious meaning of the prayer as a
whole and is to be regarded as a grave
sin." So, here's a person doing the prayers
committing a grave sin. OK. Let me go to
another section.
As I go, you will guess what I'm reading
from. "He and his disciples evolved a
mystical theory according to which the
words and letters of the various prayers
are not accidental
nor are they only vehicles
for which literal... for their literal meaning." I mean,
ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ
"Guide us on the right path"
is wonderful but we are not saying the
Contact Prayer for this literal meaning.
There is much more to it. So, listen to this. "Nor are they
only vehicles for their literal meaning,
their order and especially their numbers..."
We certainly appreciate that "...reflect a
mystical harmony, a sacred divine
rhythm."
Next.
"No change can be tolerated in the text
of the prayers not even a minute one
because every change even of one letter
would destroy the numerical harmony
inherent in the text." So, every letter
that God composed in the first SURA
of Quran, Al-Fãtehah, is numerically
controlled.
The sounds, when you say
ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
this is composed by God for a specific reason, a combination that causes your contact with your Creator.
Oh, listen! It's coming up.
"It does not matter; therefore, whether the
change is beneficial from the point of
view of meaning and content." I mean, you may
think of composing a Shakespearean excellent
literary marvel that praises God. It doesn't
mean a thing. Forget it. It is not the
meaning we're after. It's the numerical
composition and the sounds.
"For this level of meaning is not the
most important one in the prayers.
The text was formed" by God - I'm adding this "by God" - "to reflect mystical
harmony and any change would destroy it."
The second point here is the liturgy
that is the contact prayers' Al-Fãtehah.
"The liturgy received new importance and
new meaning within the framework of
religious practice." After discovering the
numerical importance of it. "A completely new
dimension was added in this way to the
daily prayer service. It stopped being
just a reciting of requests and
praises of God in ancient formulas." Arabic, for example.
"And became a vehicle for becoming a
participant in a mystical divine
harmony. The prayers suddenly received a
new depth of meaning and importance
which was undreamed of in the thousand
years that had passed since they were
formulated." Next.
Okay, this will really tell you what this
is coming from.
The quiz becomes easier and easier.
"The fierce polemical tone of Rabbi Judah's
criticism of the changes introduced by
the Frenchmen in the prayers
can therefore be explained as a result of
his fear that the prayers may be
regarded as completely human in origin
and meaning making them secular and
meaningless in religious and mystical
practices." A lot of people accuse me of
being harsh with some people who are
making changes in the prayers or in the
Quran or in the practices of religion,
but there is a precedent. It is fear for
these people and it is concern for them.
"According to him, even if the content and meaning
of the prayer is religious, expressing
love and devotion to God, it still will
be just called a secular song like that
of the non-jews if it does not have the
added mystical dimension of hidden truth,
which cannot be revealed by the literal
meaning of the words alone. In his
polemic, Rabbi Judah does not defend only
the specific tradition of prayer which
he received from his parents and
teachers, he also defends prayer as an
elevating force forming a connection" - connection: SALAT - "a connection between
man and God, a connection that no mere
words can achieve." So, it is not just
the words. There's a numerical mysticism
in it. And the last section...
"All God-fearing people, when they pray,
have to direct their prayers when they
say "blessed is God" ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ
"When they say "blessed is God"
and when they kneel before Him and
thank Him and direct their prayers in their
hearts only to His holiness alone, within
which is His glory and which has neither
form nor image." You direct it to God Alone. AQEM AL-SALAT.
ALLAH-O AKBAR. ALLAH-O AKBAR. LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH.
(1:1) بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:2) ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
(1:3) ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:4) مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ
(1:5) إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
(1:6) ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ
(1:7) صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
الله اکبر
سبحان ربی العظیم x 3
سمع الله لمن حمده
الله اکبر
سبحان ربی الاعلی x 3
(1:1) بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:2) ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
(1:3) ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:4) مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ
(1:5) إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
(1:6) ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ
(1:7) صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
الله اکبر
سبحان ربی العظیم x 3
سمع الله لمن حمده
الله اکبر
سبحان ربی الاعلی x 3
اشهد ان لا اله الا الله وحده لا شریک له
السلام عليكم ورحمة الله x 2