ALLAH-O AKBAR, LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH.
I'm gonna get you going on time, In Sha Allah.
ALHAMDU LILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
The idea of mathematical composition of literature is an original idea. It's a new idea
and it is monopolized by God Alone.
This is mathematical composition of literary works.
If you go to the library and look at millions of books, you will not find one
that is mathematically composed. The idea is not known in human-made books.
And the Quran is the only book in the world
that is mathematically composed and is intact.
There have been fragments of mathematically composed materials
like liturgies and small pieces of the original scripture,
but the Quran is the only book in the world that's mathematically composed.
And the idea of mathematical composition is that everything is calculated, the words, the letters, the verses, the chapters.
I can ask you to write a book where chapter 2 contains 500 S's, for example.
This is a mathematical composition because you'll get to chapter 2 and you will write and count the S's and keep track of them.
So, you'll end up with 500 S's in chapter 2.
So, this is the simplest form of mathematical composition.
This can be made difficult by adding more specifications: chapter two has 500 S's
and chapter 6 has 300 H's and 200 R's, for example. Then it becomes more difficult.
You'll have to keep track of more things as you write.
And as you write, you'll have to make up sentences that make sense and serve a purpose.
It's not just calculations. It's two important things. So, the Quran is the only book
in the world today that is mathematically composed
and this is why I'm kind of monopolizing the KHUTBA these days.
You may have to bear with me one more time.
But I'm giving this KHUTBA on behalf of sister Ihsan Ramadan.
She made some significant discoveries that you have in front of you
and they're really profound.
What is happening these days is a concentration on
the parameter of the numbers assigned to the verses in the Quran.
Are these haphazard? Were they made by men?
Was it just somebody said "let us give this number 6 and this number 7 and they divided the verses haphazardly?
And the loud the message that's coming loud and clear is NO.
These numbers are assigned by God.
So, let me, the first new... I reported some new findings to you last week.
The thing that Ihsan found this morning. Was it this morning or last year? I'm losing track of time.
I think it is this morning
It's been, it's been very exciting in the office here.
And you can see that I am... my breath is taken away.
It is breath-taking.
One of the most important worships in Islam is SALAT.
SALAT, Connection between the creature and the Creator,
something that we practice.
And this seems to be the most important thing for any human being.
The Jews and the Christians, we know from Quran, lost it.
In Sura 19, by the way, the verse says that "Generations came after Moses and Jesus that lost the Contact Prayer"
which means they lost the combination. This is Ihsan's own words.
They lost the combination to the safe, so they couldn't make contact.
And the consequences given in the same verse: "therefore, they will suffer immensely"
because they lost the contact.
Imagine being in this sizzling pan called the world
and these contact prayers are the ropes that keep you out of this sizzling pan.
If you don't make this contact, you are burning in this sizzling... you are suffering the pains and problems.
Ok. The word "SALAT" in Quran, "contact prayer", this signifies it's importance.
If you look in the small sheet here, what we did was add the SURAs and the verses where the word "SALAT" occurs in the whole Quran
and the total is circled in red: 4674. It's a very big number.
It's a very big number which means if there was one verse
that came to us 32 instead of 31, for example, from God,
in other words, God assigned the number 31 and somebody in 1400 years changed it to 32, we would not have this,
will not be divisible because this is a multiple of 19. 19 x 246.
These are the numbers of the SURAs and the numbers of the verses
and any discrepancy with... this is the ultimate and scientific proof, mathematics,
is very sensitive.
76, for example, is a multiple of 19, but not 77, and not 75.
And the larger the number, the more huge the odds that this is haphazard.
So, you understand this one here.
Now, the word "Quran," you take the word "Quran"; it's a very important word.
And at the top of the page, what you see are the numbers of verses throughout Quran where the word "Quran" occurs.
And you take those verses, the numbers of the verses, and add them, as you see here.
If you look at the top of the page, it says ready and then the number 10. It's the number of the line. A equals. 185 is the first verse where the word "Quran" happens.
It's in Sura 2, verse 185, plus 82, 82 is the second verse where the word Quran happens, and this is in Sura, probably, Sura 4
and so on. So, we added up all the verses where the word Quran takes place
and the total is 2660 = 19 x 140.
Now, listen to this. The word "Quran" happens in the Quran 58 times.
58 is not a multiple of 19
but one of them, one of these is in Sura 10, where God says:
"every time you show the Quran to the disbelievers, they say, give us a quran other than this."
So, it is not this Quran. So, the word "Quran", "This Quran" of God happens 57 times
which is 19 times 3 and this total does not include that verse that says "a quran other than this."
So, you can see the accuracy and the intricacy of this. This is not human-made.
Now, the word "Quran", of course, it happens a number of times in certain SURAs. How many SURAs?
The word "Quran" in every shape, form, or grammatical shape is found in 38 SURAs, 19 times 2.
If you add the number of SURAs where the word "Quran" happens and the number of verses,
the total of the verses where the "Quran" takes place, the total is 2698, 19 times 142.
Does this number ring a bell?
Anybody? Gatut.
Exactly. This is the... the word "Allah" occurs in the Quran this total: 2698.
The evidence is piling up and, at this rate the world will end tomorrow.
I mean something, something is happening at this rate of the evidence piling and showing that we have a book from God
TUBU ILLA ALLAH. Repent.
ALHAMDU LILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
Like I said, I'm giving this KHUTBA on behalf of Ihsan. She mentioned some ideas today.
She said "if you're driving and the traffic light is turning from green to yellow to red
and you're driving very fast and you're contemplating, you know, "shall I cross or stop?"
And then, very quickly you notice a police car standing there at the intersection,
what will you do?"
You're going to stop. You know, this finishes contemplation.
It's done. You're gonna stop.
So, Ihsan made an invention, a terrible invention. That's a terrible invention.
She invented a machine that will electronically ticket you whether the police is there or not.
If you cross at the wrong time, there's an electronic machine there that will give you a ticket.
Now, what will you do?
You will stop. you see.
And the people who believe in God, know that God is with them, closer to them than their jugular vein.
and therefore, they know that every time they make a mistake, there's an electronic machine that will give them a ticket.
Now, are the people... do they believe in the police, or do they believe in God?
You know, they will believe that God is with them and they will know that any time they make a mistake, they'll get a ticket
and there will be the time to pay those tickets.
OK. That's another idea.
The other thing that I want to mention...
Ahmad, do you want to man the camera?
We're gonna edit this KHTUBA for you, so if you want a copy of it, we'll give you a copy.
There is a verse in Sura 68 that says
"on the day of judgement, every human being will be required, will be invited, because it's a privilege,
will be invited to fall prostrate before God when He comes to this world,
but the people who did not make SUJUD here, in this world,
will not be able to make SUJUD over there.
And the Quran says "they were invited to make SUJUD when they were able to."
So, this adds to the importance of the SALAT.
For if you make SUJUD here, you'll be able to make SUJUD there.
Finally, there's a a Psalms that I would like to read for you.
I had the KHUTBA marking it.
Psalm 62 says "Trust in God Alone"
"Only in God is my soul at rest. From Him comes my salvation.
He only is my rock and my salvation
my stronghold. I shall not be disturbed at all.
How long will you set upon a man and all together beat him down as though he were a sagging fence, a battered wall?"
If you put trust in men, in humans, instead of God.
"...though he were a sagging fence on a battered wall.
Truly from my place on high, they plan to dislodge me.
They delight in lies. They bless with their mouth, but inwardly, they curse.
Only in God, be at rest, my soul.
For from Him, comes my hope. He only is my rock and my salvation.
My stronghold. I shall not be disturbed. With God is my safety and my glory.
He is the rock of my strength. My refuge is in God.
Trust in Him at all times, o my people.
Pour out your hearts before Him. God is our refuge."
AQEM AL-SALAT.