Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
alhamdulillah with race God who I should
under era her in the blah blah ss-sorry
color and who bear witness that there is
no God except the One God
it is very important for any person to
know who God is to really appreciate why
millions of people fall into either
Boston why did they leave God and
idolize Mohammed or Jesus or Mary or
self Francis of Saint Jude with some
helpless creature
and the main reason is that the people
do not know who God is they do not
appreciate the greatness of God so my
purpose in this sermon is to share with
you some idea about the greatness of God
and to appreciate the greatness of God
we we have to think of this universe
that we are living in
our planet Earth is part of the solar
system as you all know and by the way
I'm going to talk to you strictly about
scientific facts established scientific
facts
this earth is part of the solar system
it is the only planet in the solar
system that has life we went to the moon
and we didn't see a single tree there or
a mouse nothing we sent two cameras to
Mars and with insya creature there
unless those rocks are featured as we
saw in one of the cartoon there is no
life in the solar system except here on
the planet Earth
our son the center of this solar system
is 93 million miles away now I want you
to watch this distances 93 million miles
away from us the Sun and the light comes
to us from the Sun in four minutes so
remember this relationship the light
travels from the Sun to the earth
93 made a might stand four minutes
the social system itself spans a
distance of two billion to four billion
miles this is our solar system so when
you go to the edge of our solar system
if you drive in two billion with a be
two billion miles away
how big is the planet Earth from that
point
it will seem small
okay let us now go a little further let
us talk about what the galaxy our galaxy
as you know it is called the Milky Way
galaxy and the solar system is when the
Sun of the solar system is one of 1
billion suns of stars in our Milky Way
galaxy
it will take four minutes for the light
to travel from the Sun to the planet
Earth 93 million mark you know how long
it will take to cross the Milky Way
galaxy if your travel had the speed of
light you will cross the Milky Way
galaxy our galaxy in a hundred thousand
years not four minutes or ten minutes or
one hour or ten hours for 10 days or 10
years
it will take you a hundred thousand
years to travel across the Milky Way
galaxy our galaxy
now so if you go to the border the edge
of the Milky Way galaxy and try to find
the planet Earth where is it
it's my new district just a tiny more
you know when you look in the sunlight
and see the city things flying those are
called marks and the F is not even that
within the Milky Way galaxy
well let us strappin that has gone on
edited further let us go to our
next-door galaxy our neighbor
you know how far it is our neighbor
galaxy
two million light years away
so if you cook in something and you want
to borrow some salt or some server from
your neighbors don't go to the next-door
galaxy it will take you 2 million years
going at the speed of light and 2
million years coming at the speed of
light and your cooking will be
Oh God
so 2 million light years
from our galaxy to the next-door galaxy
that so if you go to the next-door
galaxy and try to find the planet Earth
in the Milky Way now what are your
chances of seeing the planet Earth using
the strongest possible imaginable
telescope can use find the planet Earth
how about your house or you or any human
being of Jesus
can you see that from that galaxy our
next-door galaxy
so we move a little further
there are 1 billion galaxies in our
universe
this is 1 billion with Abby
a billion trillion stars in our galaxy
in our universe excuse me there are 1
billion galaxies in our universe
a billion trillion stars our universe
our universe now has this distances of
1015 up to 26 billion light-years
distances within our universe
and you can easily imagine this now if
our next-door galaxy and these are all I
remind you these are all scientific
established scientific facts
26 billion light years within our
universe
you have to admit with me that
when you go to the heads of our universe
it is hopeless to try to find the planet
Earth it is such an insignificant speck
in God's kingdom
it is an established physical fact that
when you go if you go to the edge of our
universe you cannot possibly see the
planet Earth you cannot possibly see the
Sun
of our solar system let alone the planet
Earth
so that's our universe before we leave
our universe that's the next step I
would like to remind you that
in fact I would do our calculation think
with you right now let us say the number
of stars in our universe is not a
billion trillion guesses take a smaller
number quintillion 20d
that's a smaller number of stars in our
universe and let us count from 1 2
quintillion
taking one second per color
it's like it'll say we're counting the
stars 1 2 3 4 1 second per count so we
take 1 quintillion divided by 60 you'll
get the number of minutes it will take
you to count from 1 to printed then you
take this number and divide by 60 again
you get the number of hours it will take
us to count from 1 to continue now we
take this last product and divide by 24
and you get the number of days it will
take you to count
from one to hotel
these are physical facts as you receive
just a simple dividing by the seconds
the minutes the hours and the days
/ seven you get the number of weeks that
you / follow you get the number of
months you divide by 12 you get the
number of years it will take you to
count just count to intelligence start
you know how long it will take you how
many years this is a mathematical
physical fact it will take you very to
billion with a be 32 billion years just
to parent a quintillion stars that our
universe I'm God created
God didn't just count them God created
them and we are talking only about stars
and our universe will not talk about the
planets that go with those stars
we're not talking about the
uncomfortable decisions of of heavenly
bodies and meteorites that are in our
universe would happen only about stars
the thumb is one of the stars our Sun by
the way it is one of the dim stars
the bright stars the definition
over Brightstar is it must be at least 1
million times as bright as our Sun look
outside and see how bright the Sun is
a bright star has to be a million times
as bright as this as our Sun
we had a conference here at the
University of Arizona that dealt with
bright stars on and the Sun was not one
of them because by definition a bright
star is a million times as bright as our
Sun
so it will take you thirty two billion
years just to count not to create us to
count a quintillion of the billion
trillion stars we have in our universe
that's how our universe now I will
prepare for a sock
this universe our universe the best as
we can imagine is only one of seven
universes
and it is the smallest and the innermost
of the seven universes this is a fact
that is in the forearm proven by the
fir'aun's mathematical code
we are all now familiar with the
mathematical God of the Quran that
proved that every word is from God that
it is not written by a mu and B that it
is God's Word God's message to the world
and this mathematically proven
statements say
that our universe with its billion
trillion stars a billion galaxies 26
billion light-years distances is the
smallest and innermost of seven
universes
can you imagine how big the second
universe is if our universe is twenty
six billion by tears across the second
universe that you imagine how big it is
about the third universe the fourth that
is allowing these we can imagine seven
balls inside each other the fifth the
universe I don't think can imagine the
size of the 50 of the groups
how about the six universe and the
seventh
I can tell you right now there is no
number in the world that can describe or
measure the circumference of the seventh
universe actually the first universe we
are the seventh universe the inner most
of the seven universes
there is no number that will describe
the circumference
of the first universe now prepare for
another shock most of you are familiar
with that statement in the Quran and
solar 39
where God says he is holding the seven
universities within the fist of his head
an Arabic and the Koran was similar to
what we are to the arena
God was not holding the seven universes
like this into hand God is holding the
seven universes in one hand and this is
Andy Gorica description
to give us an idea about the greatness
of God and who God is
it's an allegorical idea to make us
appreciate the greatness of God
and to make us appreciate and realize
the blasphemy of sailing that such great
God has a human son on the tiny tiny
speck called the planet Earth
I mean how can that be
we are a fortunate generation in that
with the established scientific facts we
can appreciate the greatness of God
and God tells us who he is and his
message to the world before our
and with the sciences we now accomplish
we appreciate that greatness and
therefore we can appreciate the
grossness that less than me who saying
that God has a wife or a mother or a son
we can appreciate we can realize how
blessed we must help terrible it is to
say that God has a partner another God
with you
how can we idolize Muhammad the tiny
human being who existed on a tiny planet
called Earth in a tiny solar system
what was Mohammed's role in deciding the
speed of rotation of the moon for
example
the moon rotates around itself and
around the earth yet we always see one
side of the moon the same side of the
Moon
because of the perfect synchronized the
movement of the moon around itself and
around the earth we see only one side
and if that movement was off by one
second we would see that other side of
the world
this precision in God's creation what
was the role of Mohammed or Jesus or
Mary or self Francis
in deciding that speed of rotation of
the moon this elaborate system
everything going in its orbit
precisely we know exactly what time the
Sun will rise in the year 2025 July 4 to
2025 we're not exactly in Tucson Arizona
for example we know exactly when what
time would the Sun Rise and from what
spot because the Sun follows God lost
God's creation and follows the exact
orbit
God was holding the seven universes of
his head
that's who God is
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
hahahaha
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
you