SUBHAN ALLAH. WA ALHAMDULLILAH. WA LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH.
ALLAH-O AKBAR. ALLAH-O AKBAR. ALLAH-O AKBAR. ALLAH-O AKBAR.
LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH. LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH.
LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH.
There's an extra LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH.
ALHAMDULLILAH. We praise God.
WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA
SHAREEKA LAH.
And we bear witness that there is
no God except the One God.
I think I have to explain this first. This is a gift from Naomi. And she got the biggest size they have. Extra large. She thinks I'm fat.
So, may God bless her and send her a wonderful husband INSHA ALLAH.
She and Apamea are inseparable. Edip is having rough time.
Today is really a fantastic day because we are going to share
together God's gift to us as a result of the
conference. As you know, God always gives us a gift every time we do something which is actually a
gift from God. The conference itself is a gift
from God but each one of us underwent efforts
and financial sacrifices and time sacrifices and
God sends... God is so generous. So, He sent us a gift
that is two great miracles. Each one of them makes
the parting of the Red Sea a tiny miracle. They're
all God's miracles, the parting of the Red Sea,
miracles of Jesus and all the miracles we... we see
in the Quran are all God's miracles, but this miracle
God specializes... I mean, honors especially by
calling it one of the great miracles with a... with
a very strong assurance in the Arabic language
(74:35) إِنَّهَا لَإِحْدَى ٱلْكُبَرِ
إِنَّهَا إِحْدَى ٱلْكُبَرِ
isone of the great miracles but
إِنَّهَا لَإِحْدَى ٱلْكُبَرِ
it is indeed, most assuredly, one of the great miracles.
And this is in SURA, as you know it has to do
it is based on the number 19. I would ask you to
situate yourself where you can see this.
It is in SURA 74, verse 35. It is one
of the greatest miracles 7 plus 4 is
11 plus 3 is 14, plus 5 is 19. This adds up to 19. And we're going
to witness this together in addition to
this miracle that you see in the wall.
and before I start explaining this,
hopefully, make it clear to you
I want to share with you how God collectively
inspires the believers because in this miracle
on the wall here, we have the first SURA
in the Quran consists of seven verses, as
you know. And then, we wrote the number of everyverse in the Quran. This is... these are the verses
in the first SURA. one, two, three, four, five, six, seven. So, this
represents the first SURA. It consists of seven
verses and these are the verses in it. one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven. The next SURA consists of
286 verses. So, you write this next to this number and then the number of every
verse in the SURA. 1 2 and so on 286. This will
represent SURA number 2. Now, you're putting
putting all these numbers next to each other until
you go to the end of the Quran and... and
you end up with the number of digits each one
of these is a digit. The number of digits is
12,692 which is a multiple of 19.
This is the number of digits in this long number
and the long itself is a multiple 19.OK. So, we know about this miracle on the wall.
Everyone who walks in this masjid can witness
a perpetual miracle that anyone can witness
anywhere in the world. Now, the collective
inspiration of the believers is that you
know, you met Ali Fazeli from New Mexico. Dr. Fazeli, a physicist who I was talking to...to
Abdullah and to a number of us and he said. OK.
This is the first SURA. It has seven verses. This is
the first verse. BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. This
is the second verse. ALLHAMDULLILAH RABI AL-AALAMIN.
This is the third verse and so on. Then, the
next SURA is 286 and this is the first verse says
"ALIF LAM MEEM." So, what happened to BISM ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM? It is not... it is not being
considered here. So, Ali said "why don't you put a zerofor
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM?" Put a zero here.
And this is the first miracle we're going to witness today cause Abdullah went to his computer
and he put zero for every BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. As you know, the first BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
the first verse, number one, has a number. So, there
is no zero in the first SURA and SURA 9 does
not have BISMI ALLAH. So, it will not have a zero. So,
when you come to SURA 9, it will look like this.
This is now SURA 9. You put the number of theSURA and there you don't put a zero. You start with
the verse one right away. One two three and so on. With the other SURAs, you put the number of
verses. You put the number of the SURA followed
by the zero.
Edip: Instead of 9, it must be total number
of verses. It's not checking on.
You put the number of the SURA. You put the total number of
verses. Yes. So, you put...you put also the number ofthe SURA here because the disbelievers say "why do
you ignore the number of the SURA?" Anyway, with
this miracle anything that the disbelievers want
God gave them. He left no excuse for them. But the
idea here is that we... Ali suggested the
zeros and sure enough when we put the zeros in forBISMI ALLAH, the end result was a multiple 19.
Now, these colors are supposed to be erased easily.
So, let'stake a number that represents SURA number one
at the beginning of SURA number two. SURA number
one has... is number one. It has seven verses. Then
you put the numbers of verses. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 and then you put SURA number
two has 286 verses. Then, the BISMI ALLAH has a 0
and then 1 2 and so on to the end of the SURA.
And you go like this to the end of the Quran. Now, these zeros... they're not zeros because they are
in the middle of the number. You have 11. If
you have 11, it's 11, right? You put the 0
in the middle of the number, it becomes 101. There is no
connection mathematically between 11
and 101. So, these zeros were inserted in
that big number and the end result is a very
long number that is 13,038 digits and is divisible by 19.
A woman: And the digits are divisible by 19?
The messenger: No.
The number of digits is not divisible by 19.
OK. This will take us to the second
miracle which is even greater than this
one if you can believe that. So, let us all
collectively fall prostrate before God.
I would lead you in the prostration and then we'll
make... we'll repent to God and ask Him to guide us.
TUBU ILLA ALLAH.
ALLAH-O AKBAR
ALHAMDULLILAH. We praise God.
WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLALLAH, WAHDAHU LA
SHAREEKA LAH.
And we bear
witness that there is no other god besides God.
These miracles that we're witnessing are
mathematical... strictly mathematical or structural
miracles. They have nothing to do with the
literary miracle in the Quran. As you know,
there is a literary miracle that has to do
with the distribution of every letter. This
is... you know... you know the the Quranic initials.
ALIF LAM MEEM at the beginning of SURA number
two. The counts of ALIF and LAM and MEEM are mathematically controlled. The counts of HAMEEM
in the seven HA MEEM-initialed SURAs are
mathematically controlled. Every letter in theQuran
is mathematically controlled. I'm talking about
letters. Also, words are mathematically controlled
in the Quran. We are talking about the literary
mathematical composition. The word God, as you
know, there's 2698
times in the Quran. And if you add the numbers
of verses wherever the word God is mentioned,
there's 118,123 which is also a multiple 19.
The word Quran happens in the Quran 57
times. 19 times 3. When you add the
SURAs and verses wherever the word Quran is
found, the total is 44008. 4408.
4408 which is also a
multiple 19. So, we're talking about a giant
Rubik's Cube which is consisting of literary...
two sections: a literary mathematical composition
where the letters and the words are mathematically
composed and distributed far beyond human ability.
In SURA 17, verse 81, it says "if all the humans
and all the jinns banded together to produce
a Quran like this, they cannot do." And it has
nothing to do with literature. It has to do with this
this impossible mathematical composition which
is very simple to understand but very impossible
to imitate. But what we're talking about today is
strictly mathematical numbers. You take any book
from the library. Every book in the library has
chapters and sentences and take those chapters
and number the sentences and see if there's any
mathematical pattern in them. You will not find any.
If you find anything, it will be by coincidence
and maybe one one chance of some some kind
of of the... like... for example the number
of sentences may be divisible by the number of
chapters by accident in one of the books. But that that
would be the extent of it. So, we're talking now
by strictly mathematics. It has nothing to do with the literary
sense. The second miracle that we are witnessing.
Let us take the Quran from the first verse to
the last verse and give these verses numbers that
Abdullah called a sequential number. So, BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM... we have so number one.
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM is the first verse.
ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ (1:2)
ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ (1:3)
(1:4) مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ
(1:5) إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
(1:6) ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ
(1:7) صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
These are the first seven verses of the Quran. And then we go to
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM of the second SURA.
This'll be number 8 and then the first verse of SURA
number two says ALIF LAM MEEM. That will be number 9.
Are you following me? So, we'll keep going to the end of
the Quran. The last verse is number six three
four six (6346) which is a multiple of 19. This
is the... all the verses of the Quran including
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM in every SURA. SURA 9 does not have any BISM ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. OK.
Now, of course, this is verse number one. This is
number two. This is number three. This is number
four. This is number five six seven zero because this
is the first BISMI ALLAH of SURA number two and this
is verse number one of SURA number two. And this
is verse 6 of the last SURA of the Quran. So, here
we have two sets of numbers. We have the number
of the verse and it's sequential number in the Quran.
So, the last verse in the Quran is number
six of the last SURA. It is verse number six. But
it is number six three four six in the whole Quran. Is this simple? Everybody's following this. Very easy.
So, what Abdullah did; he put all these numbers
next to each other to form one very long number
but he also put the number of the SURA before every SURA. So, before the numbers of SURA number one
he put... the number of the SURA which is
one. So, now the number representing the first SURA of
the Quran will be 1 1 1 2 2 3 3 4 4
5 5 6 6 7 7 and then we put SURA number two
and then 0 8 1 9 2 10 3 11 4 12...
are you following me? No. OK. The first
the first SURA in the Quran is
7 verses. And they are verses number 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
If you... when you arrange them from the
beginning of the Quran sequentially, they are also
number one two three four five six seven and then
the BISMI ALLAH of SURA number two is number eight. The
first verse in surah number two is number 9.
So, what we're doing in this column here
we're just giving a number to every verse of the
Quran from the beginning to the end. So, if you
go to the middle of the Quran, for example, verse
number one of the last SURA in the Quran. When you count
from the beginning of the Quran, it becomes number
six three four one. 6341. In other words, up to
the first verse of the last SURA, we have six
thousand three hundred forty one verses. When
you go to the last verse of the Quran, it is verse
number six in the last SURA.
(114:6) مِنَ ٱلْجِنَّةِ وَٱلنَّاسِ
this this number six here says the
last verse of SURA number 114 and it is number
6346 from the beginning of the
Quran. It is number 6 from the beginning
of the SURA. It is number 6346 from the
beginning of the Quran. OK. So far... so far so good?
So, Abdullah put the number of every verse and the
number of this verse from the beginning of the Quran.
So, verse number seven in SURA AL-FATIHA, SURA AL-HAMD is verse number seven and it
is also the seventh verse from the beginning of
the Quran. And then BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
of SURA number two is number zero, as you know
and it is the eighth verse from the beginning of
the Quran. The first verse in SURA number two is
the ninth verse from the beginning of the Quran. So, these
numbers you put next to each other to form one big
number, except the number of every SURA was at
the beginning of every SURA. So, this is SURAnumber one. The number representing SURA number
one would be...here it is... will be SURA number one
verse number one in the SURA. It is verse number
one in the whole Quran and then verse number 2 is also number two from the beginning of the Quran.
three this was also three. Four... this all one
number. 4 4 5 5 6 6 7 7. Then, we go
to SURA number 2. We continue the numbers. It
is SURA number two and we have the BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM is number zero. And it is the
eighth verse. See? This one is the seventh verse. The eighth
verse from the beginning of the Quran and then
verse number one of SURA number two which is the
ninth verse from the beginning of the Quran. And
then verse number two is the tenth verse from the
Quran and so on to the end of the Quran. We end up...
Now, I want you to observe this with me. This number
of the SURA is one number. The number of the other verse
another number and so on. Now, we come here to the
double numbers. The second verse of SURA number
two was number two but from the beginning of the
Quran, it is number 10. So, this is a number and
this is a number. If you count the numbers in
the long number, they are... there... they are... let me see...
12,806. Twelve thousand eight O six
number. This is a multiple 19. This is the
number of numbers. See, this is one number. It's ten
and this here also is one number. This is the last
verse in the Quran. This is verse number 6 3 4 6 in
the whole Quran. It is verse number six in the
last SURA. So, this is the number. This a number. This
is a number. The number of these numbers is
12 8 0 6 which is a multiple of 19. Now, if you
count the digits meaning there are two digits here. This
is ten, has 2 digits. These are four digits: one two
three four. Four digits. It is one number, but 4 digits.
When you count the digits in this long number, you
have 3 7... Excuse me... 3 7 0 8 8. This
is the number. This is one long number
that has... has 37,088
digits in it. This number of digits is a multiple of 19 and the long number itself is also multiple of 19.
ALLAH-O AKBAR. SUBHAN ALLAH.
The whole world should be a Muslim tomorrow. So. Is this... I mean, maybe this clarifies it.
Yes. This adds... this adds up to 19 and it is a multiple of 19. This is the total number of verses in the Quran. It is 19 times 334.
The number of digits in that number, the basic number which has the number of verses followed by the number of every verse.
This sheet of paper on the wall has the
number of every verse in the whole Quran.
And the number of digits there is
exactly twice as much as the number of
verses in the Quran. There is no...
it's not necessary to have that
connection, but it is true. Now I don't wannaconfuse you anymore. But is there anything else you can think of Abdullah
you need to point out?
Abdullah went to the computer to put
the zeros in there and then he walks out with this
piece of paper, casually. I said "Oh oh, Abdullah, you have a piece of paper in your hand." All I said was we want to start a new translation
of the Quran to be readyin case the demand increases and we have
to print some more, maybe a few Millions
INSHA ALLAH. At the minute, the suggestion of the new translation came,the flood was beginning already.
It's just awesome. I don't know what... there's something I
need to say but I forget what it is.
This really leaves us speechless. Is there anything that
is mysterious to anybody who'd be embarrassed to... if you
wanna clarify any point. Otherwise, we will do the prayer and as we prostrate to God, we remember
these miracles. Oh, this is what I wanna say... as you know, SURA 9 had these two
false verses and if we include these two false
verses 128 and 129 in that number,
you don't have anything. You don't have it divisible
by 19. The whole thing collapses and here we're
adding the zeros inside for BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIMs. We're putting in zeros for each one
and you still have a divisible... If
you include the 2 false verses, the whole thing
collapses. You have nothing. So, right now, we have something to talk about, something awesome
When we inject these zeros... Where is it? This is a
zero. BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM of SURA number two.
When you come to SURA 9, there's
no BISMI ALLAH. If you put the zero, this...
this is worth erasing...here we're struggling with these
numbers. They are big. I just
want to demonstrate for you SURA number nine.
OK. Open your eyes, now. The
number where we inject the zeros
which is the first miracle we talked about. We put the SURA number. 9.
And then you put the first verse in it which is number 1.
Put the verse numbers? 127?
Abdullah: The previous miracle? Yeah. You put the one under... First one you put 100
The messenger: Yes. 127, right?
We put the verse numbers. This is the total number of verses in the
SURA. If you put 129 which include the two false
verses, of course, the whole thing collapses. And
then you put verse number one two, we go on to 127
and this will represent SURA number nine and then
after that we get to SURA number 10. We put
the number of the SURA right after that and
then you put the number of verses which is 106
for SURA number 10 and then you put BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM, a zero and then the first verse and
then the second verse and so on to 106. Now, SURA number 10,
the number of verses and BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
has a zero. SURA number 9 does not have BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM, so there is no zero. If
and at the end, the end result is a very long
number that is a multiple of 19. If you
put BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM in SURA 9 and you put a zero here the whole thing collapses.