Man has always believed in some kind of
a god.
This need to believe in a supernatural and
omnipotent being led many to search for a
god, start wars in the name of a god, even create
a god if they had to. Hello. My name is Bill Buck.
In this report, we are going to present you what
we call the ultimate miracle. You see, when man
chose to believe in gods, most of these gods
had one thing in common. It was required that
they be feared, worshipped, served and revered.
Numerous religions sprang up to serve these
gods. Some of the oldest religions still exist,
today, namely Buddhism, Hinduism and Shintoism. Some
of these religions believe in many gods for
example, a god of fire, a god of water, a god of
love, a god of prosperity and so on. Then, came the
monotheistic religions. Those that believe in one
God. All of which are considered major influences
in global history and affairs. These are Judaism
Christianity and Islam and significantly they
share a common belief in one... global history and
affairs. These are Judaism, Christianity and Islam
and significantly they share a common belief in
one supreme God. Perhaps, the best way to portray
these is to look at Jerusalem where all three
religions mingle. We have a historical account of
biblical and other prophets and the miracles that
they are credited with having performed. Therewas Moses who we are told talked to God and led the
Jews out of bondage and brought them the Ten
Commandments. He even parted the Red Sea when
pursued by Pharaoh and his troops, according to the
Bible. There was Jesus Christ who is the son of the
living God to Christians. Through him Christians entered
into a new covenant with their Creator. Lastly
there was Muhammad. Muslim history tells us thatin Mecca, God revealed to him the Quran, the Muslim
holy book which is recited fervently and followed
by one-fifth of the world's population. For many
centuries and in spite of man's experience with
religion, there still remain many mysteries. The
most baffling and complex mystery of all remains
the identity and the concept of this God that man
has never seen and yet believes in so religiously.
This sea of religious confusion has been swelling
all the time. Many religions all claiming to be
right began to break into sects. During all this
time, man was advancing economically, socially,militarily and intellectually. Man continued to
advance technologically at an unprecedented pace.But in terms of religion, he was still in this sea
of confusion often misled by tricksters and deeply
disappointed with his unanswered prayers to this
unseen God. Disappointment and confusion led many
to lose their belief. Agnosticism and atheism have
become widespread. Many now openly reject or at
least question the existence of this God who
has been so popular throughout the ages. The
theory of Darwin became the accepted opinion
of many scientists and scholars who were able
to draw supportable conclusions from the proof
and arguments presented. But now most scientific
and religious thinkers realized that there are
deeper questions. So, where does that leave us?Are there any real solutions to this religious
dilemma? On the one hand, man cannot accept the
illogical practices that religion dictates to him
yet by denying God, man still doesn't find the
answers to some of his most burning questions
such as "Who am I? Why am I here? Is there a god?What is the purpose of life?" Just when man's
tolerance to manual labor reached a limit and theIndustrial Revolution lay around the corner, now an
intellectually enlightening revolution seems to
be around the corner. Previous generations were
converted to believe in God by means of miracles.However, modern man cannot believe in God becauseof
these. He has watched men walk on the moon. He is
presented daily with the latest technological
marvel. He has come across too many false claims,
fake miracles and fake prophets. He has become very
cynical especially when it comes to ancient myths
and beliefs. With some arrogance, he believes that
he knows more than his forefathers let alone those
ancient reporters of fantastic events. He wonders
what they would have thought of some of today's
miracles. Today's man needs something substantial.
He needs an ultimate miracle. All the miracles that
were supposed to have converted man over the ages
were limited to a particular geographical locationor a time period. By definition an ultimate miracle
would be something that is perpetual not limitedto a certain century or a geographical location.
It would be for all of the people to see all of
the time. It would be something that is physical
touchable, examinable, verifiable and irrefutable.A few years ago, noted scientist and television
personality, Carl Sagan, in his best-selling novel,talked about a mathematically coded message from
outer space. On page 431, the author states "myfondest hope for this book is that it would
be made obsolete by the pace of real scientificdiscovery." Well, it seems that Carl Sagan's fondest
hope has come true. Research over the past fewyears has uncovered just such a mathematical
code in a document that is over 1,400 years
old. There are other miraculous aspects to this
document. For instance, only in the past 20 yearshas science been able to witness the development
of the fetus in the very early stages. However,1,400 years ago, the development of the fetus in
the first 28 days had already been documentedand with such graphic accuracy that it left
Dr. Moore, chairman of the anatomy department ofthe University of Toronto, utterly amazed. For at
this stage, the embryo is only about one tenth ofa millimeter long and would appear like a dot to
the human eye. To discern its shape would requirea powerful microscope. However, microscopes were
not developed until the 17th century and yet1,400 years ago we find the following: "there after
we created of the drop a thing which clings, a
leech-like structure." Dr. Moore confirmed that
the embryo does in fact cling to the wall
of the uterus. Another passage describes the
stages of fetus development. "God makes you in
the wombs of your mothers in stages one after
another within three veils of darkness." Dr. Moore
confirmed the accuracy of this description, also.
He explained that the three veils could reasonably
be interpreted to mean the mother's abdominal wall
the wall of the uterus and the amnio chorionic
membrane. It goes on. We've all heard about the
Big Bang Theory but who would expect to find an
account about the Big Bang Theory 1,400 years ago
but there it is. "Do the disbelievers not realize
that the heavens and the earth used to be one
entity. then We parted them?" The separation process
resulted in the formation of multiple worlds. The
mention of these worlds has made several times
in the document. Also, it would seem that the
modern discovery of bridges of matter which are
present outside organized astronomical systems
is referenced in the verse which reads: "God is
the One who created the heavens, the earth and
what is between them." "Today we will only preserve
your body to set you up as a sign for subsequent
generations. Indeed most people are heedless
of our signs." Miraculously, it seems that the
Egyptians were exclusively gifted with the science
of mummification. In 1898, Laurier discovered the
mummified body of Ramses II of Thebes in the valley
of kings where it had lain untouched for 3,000
years. He had it transported to Cairo where it
may be seen to this day. The medical study of
the mummy of Merneptah, Pharaoh of the Exodus, has
yielded further useful information on the possible
cause of this Pharaoh's death. The lack of signs
of deterioration of the body proves that the body
did not stay in water for a prolonged period of
time. And in the heavens, for many centuries it was
believed that the moon had its own light. Science
discovered not too long ago that the moon really
did not generate its own light, but acted only as
a reflector of the sun's rays. "God is the one who
made the Sun luminescent and the moon a light and
He designed its phases to provide you with the
timing device. God did not create all this in vain.""God is the One who created the night the day the
Sun and the moon. Each one is traveling in an orbit
with its own motion." Today, it is known how the
celestial organization is balanced by the position
of stars in a defined orbit and how the interplay
of gravitational forces is related to their mass
and speed of movement, each with its own motion.
Sir Francis Drake proved the Earth to be round
when he sailed around it in 1597. "Are you more
difficult to create than the heaven that he built?He raised its masses and perfected it. He made its
night dark and its morning visible. Thereafter, He
made the Earth egg shaped." That was written almost a
thousand years before Columbus. We know now that
the Earth's atmosphere acts as a filter to prevent
harmful radiations from reaching the surface. Short
wavelengths like x-rays and ultraviolet rays are
filtered out at high altitudes. Protection from
these rays is vital to the existence of life on
Earth. "And We made the sky a protected ceiling." Then,there is the affirmation of the modern idea that
the origin of life is aquatic. "And We made water
a requisite for every living thing." Water is the
simplest chemical compound of importance to all
the living things. Most organisms consist of 50 to 95
percent water. Scientists know that absolutely
every living entity known to man requires water
for its existence. Many properties of water make
it essential to life's processes. Its ability to
dissolve a great variety of substances is vital
because most chemical reactions within organisms
can occur only in a water solution. Take the
field honeybee busy bringing in nectar from
flowers. On entering the hive with a full honey
sac - which is an enlargement of the esophagus-
the field be regurgitates the contents into
the mouths of young workers called house or
nurse bees. These, in turn, deposit nectar in
a cell and carry out the tasks necessary to
convert the nectar to honey. This we have known
for about 80 years. "And your Lord inspired the
bee. Build homes in the mountains and the trees
and what the people build for you. Then, eat
from all kinds of crops and obediently follow the
designs of your Lord." "Out of their bellies comes a
liquid of various colors wherein there is healing
for the people. This should be a sign for those who reflect."
Remember, this statement was made 1400 years ago.How in the world could somebody have known 1400
years ago that honey came from the belly of the
bee? This document also claims that there is a
healing property in honey. Honey does in fact
have mild antiseptic properties. The Russians
used honey to cover their wounds in World WarII. The wounds retained an amount of moisture
and left very little scar tissue. Because of
its density, no fungus or bacteria could grow
in the wound. It is also known that if a person
suffering from allergies from a certain plant is
given honey produced from that plant, that person
builds up certain resistance to the allergy. 1000
years before the discovery of the circulation
of blood and roughly 13 centuries before it was
known what happens in the intestine to ensure
that the organs are nourished by the process
of digestive absorption, we find a verse in thedocument. "From between the urine and blood comes pure delicious milk."
Only recently, was it found that from what the cow eats, there is
a separation of nutrients into the blood and
the urine and the remainder ends up as milk.Progress in botany 1400 years ago was nowhere
advanced enough for it to establish as a rule
that plants have both male and female parts.
Nevertheless, we read in the document: "God is the
One who sent water down from the sky and thereby
brought forth pairs of plants each separate from
the other." Today, we know that fruit comes from
plants that have sexual characteristics even when
it comes from unfertilized fruits like bananas. "Of all fruits God
placed on the Earth two of a pair." This document stated to
early man the remarkable premise that mountains
move like the clouds. We know this to be true now
since the earth rotates around its axis and around
the Sun, but to an ancient what could be more
contradictory to the obvious than that mountains
move and yet... "When you look at the mountains, you
may think that they are standing still. But they are
moving in the same manner as the clouds. Such is
the creation of God. We know now of continental
drift of folding which forms mountain ranges. The
Earth's crust is like a solid shell on which we
can live while the deeper layers are hot and fluid."Have we not made the Earth an expanse and the
mountains stakes?" The stake like stability of the
mountains is linked to the folding phenomenon in
that the folds provide the foundations for the
reliefs that form the mountains. From this aspect,
they are indeed like tent stakes driven deep into
the ground. "He makes his chest straightened like
one who climbs towards the sky." Fingerprinting
became a scientific method of identification in
the 1880s with the research of Sir Francis
Dalton. Dalton calculated mathematically
that no two persons could have exactly the same
fingerprint patterns. "We can even reconstruct the
tip of his finger." All of these scientific phenomena have been
taken from the same book. Other examples contain
infinitely more precious data which directly
relate to facts discovered by modern science
but it took modern computers to discover them. It
is only now that the numerous verses of this text
have finally become comprehensible. Dr. Maurice Bucaille, an eminent French scientist says that
it is impossible to explain how a text produced
1400 years ago could have contained ideas that
have only been discovered in modern times. Many
other scientific phenomena: the barrier between
salt and fresh water, the branch-like progression
of combustion, all were mentioned 1400 years ago.
In a notable recent experiment conducted by Nova,
it was found that at the exact moment of death
there is a slight weight loss in humans, but not
animals. This document states that at the moment
of death, God takes the soul away. And now we
come to the most incredible significance of
these discoveries. Remember, we said that modern
man needs an ultimate miracle to release himself
from the bondage of religious frustration and
confusion about his Creator. Well, it so happens
that this ultimate miracle does exist in this
document the identity of which we are about to
reveal. This ultimate miracle exists in the form
of a scientifically proven mathematical code that
is touchable, examinable, verifiable and utterly
irrefutable. Not only does it prove that the author
of this divine document is God Almighty, but it
also serves as the first physical evidence for
the very existence of God. And it serves as a
means for preservation for the document itself
so that the reader knows that every word indeed
every letter is from God Almighty. This document
is the Quran and the ultimate miracle is the
perfect and unchallengeable mathematical
code. This mathematical code, this signature of
the Creator has always been here in the Quran
for all to see but only recently was it revealed
and then only with the help of a modern computer
by Dr. Rashad Khalifa, the Imam or minister of the
mosque of Tucson. Briefly, let me explain. The Quran
consists of 114 chapters. 29 of these chapters are
prefixed with letters that remained mysterious for
1400 years. Nobody knew what they meant until now.Before we go into details of this, let us look at
a simple example that will allow us to realize
the magnitude of this miracle. Take a simple
sentence like Jack and Jill went up the hill.
There are seven words and twenty four letters
in this sentence and this is called the simple
mathematical structure of this sentence. Now let
us try and change this mathematical structure,
but still try and convey a specific meaning in
good English. Let us say we want to convey the
same meaning with a sentence containing seven
words and 26 letters. We must pad two letters in
Jack and Jill went up the hill. In trying to do
this, we soon see that the word Jack and the word
Jill cannot be changed. The word over cannot be
substituted for up because it conveys a separate
meaning. Similarly, the word the cannot be replaced by
a because a hill refers to any hill. In other
words, it becomes pretty difficult to change the
mathematical structure of a simple sentence and
still have an accurate and acceptable statement
in English. Now, how about if we try and group
sentences that conveys specific meanings into
a mathematical pattern not only controlling
the count of total letters but also the count
of specific letters within words. Suppose we want
to take Jack and Jill went up the hill to fetch a
pail of water and change the total number of A's
plus the total number of I's to 9 instead
of 8. There are seven words containing the
letters A and I that make perfect English and
cannot be changed. So, we can only try and change
the rest of the words but this will again convey
a different meaning to the sentence. It quickly
becomes apparent that changing this structure
to fit a pattern is almost impossible for just
one sentence. Prepare for the shock. The document
the Quran, contains an exquisitely sophisticated
control of letters across chapters, within chapters
in combination of letters between words, in total
number of sentences, in total number of words, all
interlocking with one another, rendering it
impossible to duplicate even with the most
powerful computers. Yet, it remains very simple to
understand. For example, 29 chapters roughly 160,000
letters are prefixed by mysterious letters. Chapter
50 starts with just Q. Chapter 2 has ALM. Chapter 19
has 5 letters as a prefix K H Y 'A S. Please note
that we have chosen English equivalents of the
Arabic letters for simplicity of illustration. It
was found that the letter Q occurs in chapter 50
exactly 57 times or 19 times 3. The A's L's and M's in chapter 2 occur a total of 9899 times.
and so on without
a single exception in all the initialed chapters
with the occurrences in those of the number 19.
At the same time that the A's L's and M's are
controlled in seven chapters that have ALM as a prefix, the A's and the L's are part of the
Arabic word for God. ُhe occurrence of which is
also being controlled as you will soon see. At once,
we realized that there is a deliberate superhuman
design that binds the books' chapters, verses, words
even letters. For if one letter was changed, deleted
or added, the whole system collapses. And the fact
that this system was discovered 1400
years after its creation proves that it has been
perfectly preserved. The foundation of this
mathematical code is the opening statement.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
And this contains exactly 38 alphabets or 19
times 2. In the language of the Quran, Arabic, it
contains exactly 19 alphabets and 4 words. These
4 words namely name, God, most gracious, and
most merciful appear in the whole book 19, 2698,
57, and 114 times, respectively.All these are multiples of 19. The total number
of verses are 6346. The total chapters are
114. Again multiples of 19. We are beginning to
see that this unique code must have been pretty
difficult to construct. "On it are 19. Indeed by
the moon, by the night as it passes. by the morning
is it shine. this is one of the greatest miracles."
Greatest miracle, indeed. And now we realize that
19 is the Creator's signature on everything He
created. For example, you and I have 209 bones
in our bodies: 19 times 11. A full-term fetus
remains in the mother's womb 266 days: 19 times
14. The Sun, the Moon, the earth line up in the
same position every 19 years. And on and on and
on. The viewer may wonder why 19. Well, using our
ancestral system of numerology, the Arabic and
Hebrew word for one has a value of 19. And this
is what the message of Quran is one. One God and
one Brotherhood of Nations under God. The Quran
was written under God's direction. One thing
is clear. No human being could have written
such a complicated and perfectly mathematically
coded text not then, not now, even with the aid of
computers. One of the most important functions of
the Quran's mathematical code is that it proves
and authenticates by physical evidence all the
miracles of the previous prophets and messengers.
Moses parted the Red Sea. Jesus revived the dead
and healed the hopelessly blind and the leprous
and so on. Now, these miracles are mathematically
composed within the Quran and proven by this code
to be true. God was the witness. His words are
divine and what He has proven by means of the
ultimate miracle is that the Quran is indeed His
word, the word of God. Therefore, let us look to it
to answer some of our most crucial questions such
as why are there famines, disasters and diseases.
And what is the overall purpose and meaning of
life? And what of peace? That elusive dream of the
righteous universal man. Given now that the message
of the Quran is one, One God, one Brotherhood. Think
of it. All the power and love in the universe
in one supreme being who has assured us that
He not only exists but communicates without
question to those who believe and seek out
the truth, His laws and commitment. Imagine what can
be achieved by following His laws and directions.