أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
Dr. Khalifa: This morning about 9 o'clock, Lisa asked me "do you know that you're giving the Khutba?
It was quite a surprise as you realize.
Then after the Khutbah, Lydia came to me and
said "do you know you're giving the Quranic study?"
And she took the beating on behalf of Lisa.
Actually, Lisa sent her to tell me that.
So, here I am.
First of all, we welcome a new member to our
masjid.
This person here.
I forgot his name.
This is the former, and still is, Muhtesem
Erisen, the one and only.
Mã Shã Allãh
Welcome back.
Before I start, there is also one more point
that I wanted to mention.
Thanks to our Iranian brothers and sisters.
There is a little bit of confusion now about
your arms, what to do with your arms when you pray.
Keep them like this and put them straight
down.
I would like to establish first, once and
for all, that it doesn't make any difference,
whether you go like this or put your hands
down.
But generally, what I do is I follow what
the Imam is doing.
The person in the front, whatever the person
in front is doing, I do what he's doing.
And I recommend that for you.
IN SHAA ALLAH, we'll be doing Sura 90, The Town.
And whatever we can afterwards.
At 8:30, the children will practice on us.
You know, they'll be singing at the conference.
So, we'll give them maybe 20 minutes, 20 minutes to 9.
20 minutes enough?
20 minutes to practice a new song on us.
It should be enjoyable, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Sura 90, The Town.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
[90:1]  I solemnly swear by this town.
[90:2]  The town where you live.
[90:3]  The begetting and the begotten.
[90:4]  We created the human being to work hard (to redeem himself).*
[90:5]  Does he think that no one will ever call him to account?
[90:6]  He boasts, "I spent so much money!"
[90:7]  Does he think that no one sees him?
[90:8]  Did we not give him two eyes?
[90:9]  A tongue and two lips?
Number 10,
[90:10]  Did we not show him the two paths?
[90:11]  He should choose the difficult path.
[90:12]  Which one is the difficult path?
[90:13]  The freeing of slaves.
[90:14]  Feeding, during the time of hardship.
[90:15]  Orphans who are related.
[90:16]  Or the poor who is in need.
[90:17]  And being one of those who believe, and exhorting one another to be steadfast, and exhorting one another to be kind.
[90:18]  These have deserved happiness.
[90:19]  As for those who disbelieved in our revelations, they have incurred misery.
[90:20]  They will be confined in the Hellfire.
So, that's the whole Sura.
I go back to the beginning, swearing.
God usually starts many of these short Suras
with a profound statement.
And this town, meaning Mecca, is profound.
Because God made it sacred by putting His
shrine there
to serve as the focal point.
or a point of organization for all believers
around the world.
When we stand in Prayer, we don't fight as
to which direction we should face.
God already decided for us that we're gonna face the direction of Mecca.
So, every believer, every Muslim around the
world is praying and facing that point.
So, the first verse is simply a profound statement,
as in many other Suras.
And it is the town where the Prophet Muhammad
lived
from whom this Quran was revealed.
"The begetting and the begotten" is a profound
statement again.
All these profound statements precede an important
proclamation.
The begetting and the begotten, this is a
profound fact of life.
Take for example birds.
The bird laying an egg.
The egg has been fertilized by two parents,
through two parents.
One half, a reproductive cell is half a normal
cell.
One reproductive cell from the male and one
half, the other half comes from the female.
They combine to form an embryo.
In birds, the egg is laid, it is fertilized.
And then, the fact that the birds sit on the eggs,
you know they take turns, the male and female in most species.
Taking turns sitting on the egg.
Why do they do that?
Who taught them to do that?
And what's happening inside that shell, the
egg?
After a period of time, that it is becoming obvious
more and more that it's a multiple of 7. 21 days in some birds.
21, 7 times 3.
The human fetus now is in the mother's womb
266 days.
It is now established scientifically. 266, not 265.
266 and that's 19 times 2 times 7.
That's still a multiple of 7.
Gestation period, is it called the gestation
period?
Is that the period inside the womb?
Ok. In many other species, I know it is a multiple
of 7, but I'm being distracted now.
However, "the begetting and the begotten" is
a profound statement.
After 21 days, the bird inside breaks through
the shell and comes out.
Then, they're walking around. If they're ducks, they go in the water and they swim. You know, as if they've been here forever.
As if they know everything.
Walking around, following their mother in the
water.
You can go to a random spot and see them. They just came out of the egg.
And they're full of wisdom, you know, just following the mother wherever she goes. And sometimes they go independently and pick at something in the water.
And they're identical to their parents.
With beaks and eyes. Where did this come from?
And you can do this with any kind of species,
any begetting and begotten.
Now here comes the proclamation. Number 4.
[90:4]  We created the human being to work hard (to redeem himself).*
As a result of that crime that we committed
millions of years ago,
where we did not make a firm stand with God's
absolute authority,
we are here.
And God designed our plan to work hard, to
redeem ourselves, to denounce that crime,
to prove that we are on the side of God's
absolute authority.
What do you call getting up in the morning
before sunrise?
It's not easy, is it? At the beginning, especially when our soul
is still small and weak.
The soul cannot wake up the body initially.
Because the soul is weak.
It is hard work.
And you are rewarded by growth, nutrition,
and strength of the soul.
[90:4]  We created the human being to work hard.....
The lazy person who does not work hard and
does not get up before sunrise, what is the result?
He or she ends up with a shrunken, weak soul
that will not amount to anything in the real life, the Eternity.
They will be born into Eternity deformed.
And we see this in Sura 68 where they cannot
fall prostrate.
On that big day when God comes physically
to our universe,
they will not be able to, they have no legs.
I mean, this is symbolically. They are deformed.
A stump cannot fall prostrate.
They are deformed.
It is lack of growth.
To get up in the morning before sunrise and
do the Morning Prayer is a gift from God.
If we deserve it, God will guide us into waking
up before sunrise to do the Morning Prayer.
For the young people, I don't want you to
be alarmed because it may be difficult for you, but eventually
you will be able to train
your body to get up in the morning before sunrise.
If you are unable to do it now, don't be too
disturbed.
It is normal. Let me tell you this because
I don't wanna be too hard on you.
It is normal to start out by doing one prayer
a day.
Let us say the Morning Prayer as soon as you
get up at 10 or 11 in the morning.
Then, it will be two prayers a day.
Then, it will be three prayers a day.
Then, you will do the Morning Prayer before
sunrise and you will enjoy it.
The ideal situation is to do the five Prayers
with the Morning Prayer done before sunrise.
Also, God tells us in the Quran that we cannot
do it every day. You're gonna miss once in a while.
So, always think of the positive and be glad,
be happy with the achievements that you do.
If you miss one time a week or something,
don't feel too guilty.
Be glad that you did six out of the seven
days, Morning Prayers before sunrise.
Ideally, you will not miss anything. You will do the Morning before sunrise and you will do the other four Prayers as well.
[90:4]  We created the human being to work hard (to redeem himself).*
There's a footnote here that says "see the
Introduction and Appendix 7 for the purpose behind our creation.
Redeem ourselves.
Go back to God's kingdom where we were.
We got ourselves out by being interested in
Satan's theory that others besides God can have power.
And the people are doing the same mistake
now.
They think Jesus can have power, or Mary, or Saint Jude, or Muhammad, or Ali, or Hussein, or Mahdi, or whatever.
People are repeating the same mistake.
We did. God saved us.
This is how we get redeemed.
By upholding the words of God alone and worshipping
God alone.
Number five talks about those who fail to
redeem themselves.
[90:5]  Does he think that no one will ever call him to account?
See, everything we do here is credited to
us or held against us, whatever we do here.
And anything is forgivable except idol worship
if maintained until death.
That's the unforgivable crime, because this
is why we are here.
We are here for just one reason, to establish
the fact that we know that only God possesses all power.
And so number five is telling us that every
one of us will be called to account.
With the majority of people, they'll be asked "why didn't you develop your soul?
How come you fed your body three meals a day,
but you failed to feed yourself, your soul?"
Most people go through their whole life without
feeding the real person a single meal.
This is repeated in the Quran.
Most people, no matter what you do, will not
believe.
And most of those who believe will fall into
idolatry, into idol worship.
And we see this everywhere, don't we?
Just think of any mosque in the world that
says the Adhan, for example, the call to prayer, devoted to God alone,
without the name of Muhammad or Ali or somebody
besides God.
In all of Iran or Pakistan or Egypt or Saudi
Arabia, there isn't a single one mosque
that is devoted to God alone, which goes against the commandments of the Quran.
What happened to their brains?
They're just repeating what they did in the
High Society.
[90:5]  Does he think that no one will ever call him to account?
[90:6]  He boasts, "I spent so much money!"
Isn't this what most people do?
They're preoccupied with the almighty dollar.
In the meeting with our brothers and sisters
in New York, I was asking them
"when you get up in the morning, what is your list of priorities?"
"Are you going to have three meals today?"
Just when you open your eyes in the morning,
ask yourself these questions.
"What am I gonna do today? I'm gonna have three meals today?"
That's about 30 minutes, at least.
"Am I going to the bathroom today?"
Two or three times.
"Am I going to work today?"
Four to eight hours.
"Am I going to exercise today?"
Thirty to sixty minutes.
"What else will I do? Will I watch the TV today for one or two hours?"
"Will I give God twenty-five minutes? Will I do my five Prayers today?"
Even with some Muslims, the five Prayers take
a back seat to everything else.
You ask them "why don't you come to the Friday
prayer?"
"Why don't you do the five Prayers?"
They will say "I had an appointment here and there, and I
did this and that, and there was no time for the Prayer."
But we thank God because all of us here, we work
our schedules around the Prayers, the five Prayers.
That's the proper thing to do.
It should be that when we get up in the morning,
on top of the list will be the five Prayers, at least.
On top of the list.
Then, if there is time for anything else, we
will do that.
This is why the verse that says "most of those
who believe, fall in idol worship."
Because when you give priority to anything
else, that's your idol.
Now, don't get me wrong. There are situations
where you are forced by circumstances to miss
a Prayer or two, or a Friday, an occasional
Friday.
And I don't want you to feel guilty about
that either.
Because God Himself in the Quran gives you,
knows what's in your heart, and gives you excuses.
But generally in your life, you're giving
priority to God and your duties towards God,
which are actually a gift from God to you.
So, when you get up in the morning, you think,
I'm gonna have three meals today.
I'm gonna give my body at least a half
hour for eating.
Eating, drinking, snacking, more.
You're really taking care of your body.
How about your soul?
The believers have their priorities in the
right order.
When I open up my eyes in the morning, the
five Prayers, this will take precedence over everything else.
Number six,
[90:6]  He boasts, "I spent so much money!"
Because they're devoted to that. Money is the god of most people, unfortunately.
If the boss says "you're gonna come tomorrow
at three o'clock in the morning", they will set the alarm at two o'clock.
They will get up at two o'clock, very
energetic, put on their clothes and go
to that field trip at three o'clock in the morning.
Yet, their job or their boss does not give
them that money. It is God who is giving them the money.
I want to share with you an important verse,
so I go get my index.
Speaking of money, in verse six, it's a very
important verse that we should all be very familiar with.
I think it is in Sura 29, I'm not sure, but
I will give you the correct Sura and verse right now.
Yeah, it is Sura 29, verse 17.
Let me have the whole Quran.
Lydia, are you gonna read it for us?
Dr. Khalifa: 29:17.
Lydia: [29:17]  "What you idolize besides GOD are idols from your creation; you." Whatever idols you set up possess no provisions for you. Therefore, seek provisions only from GOD. Worship Him alone, and be appreciative of Him; to Him will be your return.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a very important verse you must all remember, 29:17.
It says "the idols you set up besides God",
and it appears here that specifically the
money idol, the almighty dollar, do not possess
the power to provide for you.
Therefore, seek provisions from God, because
God is the Only Provider.
And as believers we know that. We must believe
that.
No one else is the provider.
Many of you have gone through this experience
and they know that the people who interview
you and give you jobs and so on, they have
no power whatsoever.
God is the One who's running them.
This is why verse 7, verse 6 illustrates the stupidity
of most humans.
[90:6]  He boasts, "I spent so much money!"
Or I made
so much money, you know, same thing.
The dollars assigned to you have been already
assigned to you by God before you were born.
And I know the argument. You say "you mean
I'm gonna sit down and money will come to me?"
"Yes, you'll sit down and money will come
to you."
I mean, God will see to it, as a believer you
will work and you will make money.
God will provide for you through the right
and proper way.
Because if you sit and do nothing, after 4
or 5 hours you're going to be hungry, you have to eat.
So, how will you eat?
You will go look for, dig a ditch or something
to make some money to eat.
So, you will work, and God will provide you
through that.
So, there is a system, a divine system that
we know.
Number 7, another question,
[90:7]  Does he think that no one sees him?
In other words, everything is recorded. Just
think that there is a video camera going with you wherever you go.
And you're gonna find that video tape
hanging in your neck on the Day of Judgment.
That will keep you on your toes.
Ironically, the believers do this automatically,
they don't...
They know God is with them the whole time,
and they know there are video specialists
with the most sophisticated video cameras.
I mean, the cameras themselves are invisible, but
they take 3 dimensional pictures.
It's the most sophisticated video tape, and
you're gonna have it hanging in your neck on the Day of Judgment.
As a believer, you have the privilege of editing
it.
You're gonna have a perfect tape.
[90:7]  Does he think that no one sees him?
What is the implication here?
The believers are aware of the invisible forces
and God's invisible soldiers.
This is what the believers, when God tells them, they're guaranteed perfect life, perfect protection.
They know they're perfectly protected by
God.
No virus can attack you. You're protected.
You may go through some tests. You may be
allowed to be invaded by viruses or bacteria or
headaches or whatever as a test, but you
will be restored.
You know you'll be restored.
We're all aware of the tests, and all the
tests for the believers are restorable.
Not the tests themselves, the believer is
restorable.
Whatever happens, there are things that can be erased
completely, but you are fully protected.
Number eight tells us,
[90:8]  Did we not give him two eyes?
I'm looking for somebody who recorded that
discovery program about the eyes.
That should make a believer of anybody, that
program.
I don't know if anybody recorded it.
I think I asked Phil Traverse to record it
for me, and chances are he did when I was away.
In that case, I will share it together on one
of those Fridays.
But I don't need to tell you how incredible
the eye is.
Just the muscles that focus the lens of your
eye immediately.
I mean, how fast does your eye move from this
to this?
It focuses immediately.
I look at the paper and I'm focused.
Excuse me, I have to put my glasses on.
My eye focuses with the glasses and I can
see the reading here.
Then, I look at Edip and it focuses on Edip.
It's not out of focus.
In a fraction of a second.
The muscles, if you look in the mirror, you can see your
muscles working.
Does anybody do that?
You look in the mirror and you turn the light
on to catch your pupil as it goes like this.
How many people... I did that.
Those who laughed, they know it. They know what I mean.
I must have been ten years old or something
and I went to the mirror with a flashlight to look in there.
Right.
And then I surprised my eye and turned the
light on and I could see the pupil goes like this.
These are muscles that work.
[90:8]  Did we not give him two eyes?
[90:9]  A tongue and two lips?
That was Mahmoud's last Khutba.
That tongue is an incredible thing.
We cannot eat without it, actually.
Because it keeps the food under the grinders,
those things, your teeth.
The tongue pushes it.
You confuse the tongue sometimes if you eat
on both sides.
Then, you bite your tongue.
If you're greedy and you don't follow the
Quran and the food is too good.
God said "eat and drink but not extravagantly."
You can confuse your own tongue if you eat
on both sides at the same time.
Then, the tongue doesn't know where to push
and you end up biting your tongue.
But it's an incredible... that tongue is an
incredible thing.
You cannot talk without it, either.
Just try to say anything and be conscious
of the movements of your tongue.
Up and down and to the side as you talk.
Everybody wants to say something, right?
Just say the word "talk" and you can see where
your tongue moves from up.
Because the T, when you say T, your tongue is up.
"Talk", your tongue goes down.
You cannot talk without your tongue.
Even the language is called tongue sometimes.
What a design!
So, God is telling us about His greatness which
is incomprehensible.
God's greatness is immense.
It's not just controlling your tongue, but
also the mosquito that's flying in the air.
The heart of that mosquito is being controlled
by God.
The amount of nutrition that is assigned to
that mosquito, which includes some of your blood
is also recorded.
And it is computerized to coincide with something
wrong you did.
Then, you get a bite.
Or to give you some entertainment, like on
our way to San Francisco for example, and
we went to pray in a rest area.
Boy, did we beat ourselves.
That was the fastest Prayer we ever did.
There were five billion hungry mosquitoes
waiting for us.
And they were so sly.
You know, they waited until we said "Allahu Akbar."
That was really something.
I think God wanted to give us more rewards, but no really, that was struggling, striving in the cause of God.
And we wondered why the rest area was so empty, you know.
We said "wow, this is reserved for us."
Now, we know.
So, God controls the provisions for not just your, controls the heart, not just your heart, or the heart of billions of people,
the heart of every creature on earth.
Number ten is a great blessing, a great blessing.
[90:10]  Did we not show him the two paths?
Right and wrong.
We come to this world perfectly unaware of
the incidents in the High Society.
We start out clean in this world.
And then, we receive two messages.
A message of God alone, a message from God.
And a message of God and somebody else from
Satan.
That's it.
There is no other path.
The path of worshiping God alone.
And you remember the statement in the Bible,
that path is very narrow and straightened.
straightened and what? Difficult?
Just look how much persecution we're subjected
to.
Which is a blessing because you get rewarded
for it.
And the other path is wide?
Look at all the cathedrals in the world.
The Crystal Cathedral in Anaheim.
They all belong to Satan.
All the big mosques and the big cathedrals.
The wrong path is wide and conforming with
the crowd.
Look how many people meet the Pope.
One of you, one of the most important people
on earth, would go to Los Angeles, nobody will even know.
When the Pope goes to Los Angeles, there's security and arrangements and a Pop Mobile and all kinds of things.
But when you go to Los Angeles, nobody hears
about it.
Yet you're a very very important person.
Such is this world, Satan's kingdom.
[90:10]  Did we not show him the two paths?
And here's God's recommendation on number
11.
[90:11]  He should choose the difficult path.
Because this is how you train your wild horse, your body.
God is recommending that we choose the difficult
path.
Again, we talk about getting up in the morning
before sunrise.
It's not really so difficult, I don't know.
But...
Yes, Sura 65.
A man: If you look at from outside, once you accept it, God makes it easy.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
God makes it easy and enjoyable.
But you see, you have to break that initial
barrier.
It is enjoyable.
I'm theorizing that our companion enjoys it
too.
Because I don't set the alarm anymore and
I suspect this is true with most of you.
I just don't set the alarm and in the last
few weeks, I traveled into different time zones,
Central and Eastern and all this.
And it doesn't matter where I am. Before sunrise,
something wakes me up.
And I suspect it is the companion.
So, he must enjoy it.
Thank God.
Maybe an angel.
I don't know. But there comes a time when you don't need, you don't need an alarm.
You don't need anything to make you get up
and enjoy it.
So, God does make it easy.
Sura 65, God says "those who observe God's
commandments, God makes things easy for them."
This applies to everything though, everything in life.
And this will include the gift from God of doing
the Five Prayers, the Zakat, the Zakat Charity.
It's not a popular thing,
taking money from your pocket to give it away.
I came back from a two week absence and they
opened this drawer.
And there were Zakat envelopes from anonymous
people, you.
You know, these are people who really believe in God, because where do they get the credit?
Because they believe in God.
I say to Lisa "whose handwriting is this?"
I haven't cracked that yet, but I know that they
are people that God loves.
He should choose the difficult path.
God's commandments.
Taming the wild horse.
You know, Discipline.
When we are praying, this is discipline.
Did you see Amir praying?
Actually standing still for about five minutes.
I mean, that's a miracle.
And he's rewarded generously for that. This is discipline.
I mean, at his age, I'd be running around all
over the place, jumping up and down.
But to be standing still like this, bowing
and prostrating before God, it's a tremendous blessing.
And a lot of discipline. This is what God means here.
Why he should choose the difficult path.
Number twelve.
A definition of the difficult path.
[90:12]  Which one is the difficult path?
And we have examples of it.
[90:13]  The freeing of slaves.
In the past, what was the civil war all about?
Anybody enlighten me with Civil war?
The historians? Lydia?
Put down the tab and tell me.
What is the civil war all about? Lincoln? Was it in Lincoln's time?
Does it have anything to do with freeing the
slaves?
Lydia: A little, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: What was it all about?
The North was fighting the South.
Lydia: (unintelligible) Social problems. But there was also (unintelligible) freeing the slaves was the basic underlying issue here.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Why was it an issue?
The North was fighting the South, right? What is...
A man: (unintelligible) The Southern economy is powerful.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, Ok. The South resisted.
A man: So, the idea that the North got involved in the Civil War to freeing slaves is a pretty (unintelligible) idea. They got involved in the war to destroy the economy of the South. (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, Matt?
Matt: (unintelligible) very economy of the North. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Hey, Rashada, hey, hey, hey, kid.
Matt: The North (unintelligible)
Southern economy (unintelligible). The Southern economy (unintelligible)
So, actually, the freeing of slaves was a big
issue for 50 years before the war started.
But it was mostly for religious purposes and
other stuff. It was a side issue.
Dr. Khalifa: So, part of it was that the South was resisting
the law to free the slaves.
Matt: They wanted to protect the social (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: They did not want to free the slaves.
Dr. Khalifa: Whatever the reasons, they did not want to
do it.
And therefore, it is given here as an example
of something that the human being does not want to do.
Yes, number 13 says,
[90:13]  The freeing of slaves.
is indicated as a difficult job that must be done by believers.
A man: In the United States, we still have a system
where the vast majority of workers support
a very small percentage of people who have
a large amount of money.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, economically, there's a situation of...
Dr. Khalifa: slavery.
Dr. Khalifa: But it is not the same as the slavery that existed at the time of the revelation of the Quran until a hundred years ago in this country.
I mean, you can see, you can actually see traces of it
until now.
I think the racism that we still see in this
country is the tail end of consequences of slavery and so on.
Dr. Khalifa: Number?
A man: The idea is that the (unintelligible) should always have a group of people.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: (Unintelligible), yes.
A man: It's not limited to one group. It's not limited to blacks.
Dr. Khalifa: But you can certainly define slavery as exploitation
of other humans.
And it is indicated by the Quran as a vicious,
terrible crime.
A man: But I think many people think that slavery is
a sin.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: This is why one of the laws of the Quran is "oppression is worse than murder."
Oppression is worse than murder.
The freeing of slaves, number 14, feeding
the hungry.
Feeding or charity.
Feeding symbolizes being charitable during
the time of hardship.
[90:15]  Orphans who are related.
[90:16]  Or the poor who is in need.
Number 17,
[90:17]  And being one of those who believe,...
It's not easy to believe.
Muhteshem can tell you a few things about his
encounter with disbelievers in Turkey. Tell us something.
What is the majority reaction in Turkey to
your ideas of the Quran and worshipping God alone, the Quran alone?
What was the reaction? Take a hundred people. Out of a hundred, how many people agreed with you?
Muhteshem: None.
Dr. Khalifa: Zero. All right.
Were they violently opposed to you? Or were there degrees of violent reaction?
Muhteshem: They insulted me literally, looking down on
me.
Dr. Khalifa: They insulted him because he says "follow the
Quran alone."
Looking down on him, because this is all in the Quran.
Yep.
We know that Edip, don't we?
And it seems to be that "these Muslims," are the ones who are doing this.
Christians are not, the atheists are not insulting the believers.
So, number 17, being one of those who believe,
is not easy.
[90:17]  .....and exhorting one another to be steadfast, and exhorting one another to be kind.
at the same time
[90:18]  These have deserved happiness.
We're not talking about happiness in the
Hereafter only. We are talking about happiness now and forever.
Happiness now and forever.
More and more, God is strengthening these
ideas in our minds through real life examples.
Our own life, right here in this mosque.
Number 18 says,
[90:18]  These have deserved happiness.
See the period there?
It means now and forever.
Number 19,
[90:19]  As for those who disbelieved in our revelations, they have incurred misery.
Now and forever.
[90:20]  They will be confined in the Hellfire.
So, these short Suras are loaded, as you see.
Just one short Sura, 20 verses, and it's
loaded with information.
Any questions?
Dr. Sabahi.
Dr. Sabahi: Verse 4 in Arabic, (unintelligible)
human beings (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: To suffer.
Dr. Sabahi: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily, but you see, KABAD (كَبَدٍ) is effort,
work.
Dr. Sabahi: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: TAKABADA, the verb TAKABADA, in Arabic, means "exert himself, effort.
What does the Farsi say there?
Is that a Farsi translation? Or a...
Dr. Sabahi: This is a different translation than...
Dr. Khalifa: English?
Dr. Sabahi: No, Farsi.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, Farsi. So, what does it say there?
Dr. Sabahi: It says that human beings were created
(unintelligible)
Not in pain but pain and suffering is part of it.
That is the way you're just, you're born. That's how everything
was nice and easy for you.
But you would never appreciate what you get.
So, but it is that you go through this pain and suffering and then you learn and then you appreciate it.
The good thing is that then you would be on the right path. And you appreciate more and you go to the right path
So, you've created this pain, and you keep
working hard to finding it in all these problems.
Dr. Khalifa: That's a typical interpretation of non-believers,
actually.
Satan is trying to justify the pain and misery
that his clients go through.
It is not the correct translation, because you understand from that that it means the human being must be in pain and suffering, right?
Dr. Sabahi: No, no, that's why I said (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: What do you understand when you read it?
If you can convey it to us in English.
Dr. Sabahi: I can't relate to the pain the way it is.
(unintelligible) You're not born, (unintelligible)
You make the wrong decision at the beginning.
You decided to go through this suffering.
(unintelligible) something like this,
that you made the wrong decision when you said (unintelligible)
in these conditions. These conditions are tough, but
the ones who are believers who are on the right path,
they can succeed, and overcome all these miseries
and pain.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, that would be incorrect interpretation.
Therefore, this is the correct translation
here.
[90:4]  We created the human being to work hard (to redeem himself).*
Because there is no pain and suffering for
the believers.
Dr. Sabahi: While the Arabic says (فِى كَبَدٍ). FI (فِى) means "in."
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily. Not necessarily. (فِى كَبَدٍ) would be
Because of the word KABAD, it would be "to
work hard."
There are other FI (فِى) words that do not mean
"in."
For example, when they say,
(11:110) إِنَّهُمْ لَفِى شَكٍّۢ مِّنْهُ مُرِيبٍۢ
(فِى شَكٍّۢ) means "they have doubts."
So, it is not exactly "in." Sometimes it is "in."
So, KABAD is a very clear word.
I think even the old translation said that. What did the old translation say, Catherine? Verse 4.
Catherine: It said (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Work at it.
It's "exertion." KABAD. TAKABADA. It's to exert himself.
Thank you for this point, anyway, because
it reflects what they're always thinking of pain and suffering.
Because they try to justify their life, which
is full of pain and suffering.
The believers' life has no pain and suffering. It may have... even in the periods of tests,
they realize that this is a test that they'll
be restored, and the pain and suffering will be gone.
Do you remember the pain and suffering you
went through when you were one year old?
The shocks that went through, do you remember
those?
Nope. They're gone.
So, the pain and suffering in tests will be
something that is simple and will go fast.
It will be forgotten, and you'll be restored.
Other questions?
David?
You look like you wanna ask a question. Ok. Sura 91 is entitled "The Sun."
Dr. Sabahi: I have a comment that (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Go ahead. We missed you for a few weeks. How was Italy, anyway?
Dr. Sabahi: (unintelligible)
One thing that (unintelligible)
It's amazing (unintelligible) but
it is a clear indication of how religion (unintelligible) but
I was thinking of how many people died because (unintelligible).
So, I think it's a clear example of (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: You've seen the statue of Jesus where the foot
is all worn down from touching it?
You see that one, the main building of the
Vatican, and you walk
about 50 yards to the right, they have a statue of Jesus, and people touch the foot of it, and it's worn down.
Half the foot has got dropped, right?
Just from touching it, it's worn down.
And they're proud of that, actually. They show it off.
Have you seen it, Philip? You went to the Vatican.
That's, you know, an amazing demonstration of idol worship.
And then they have the tombs of some saints
in the basement.
Did you go to those, Mahmoud?
In the basement of the Vatican, they have
some tombs of Peter and some other saints.
You ran away fast.
I investigated the whole thing. It was just repulsive, just as repulsive as the Prophet's Mosque in Medina.
Go ahead.
Dr. Sabahi: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's beautiful, yes. Yes.
Dr. Sabahi: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, very good point, Mã Shã Allãh.
Don't be a slave of your job, your spouse,
your children or...
Be a slave of God alone.
Okay, we're ready for Sura number 91.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[91:1]  By the sun and its brightness.
[91:2]  The moon that follows it.
[91:3]  The day that reveals.
[91:4]  The night that covers.
[91:5]  The sky and Him who built it.
[91:6]  The earth and Him who sustains it.
[91:7]  The soul and Him who created it.
[91:8]  Then showed it what is evil and what is good.
[91:9]  Successful is one who redeems it.
[91:10]  Failing is one who neglects it.
[91:11]  Thamoud's disbelief caused them to transgress.
[91:12]  They followed the worst among them.
[91:13]  GOD's messenger said to them, "This is GOD's camel; let her drink."
[91:14]  They disbelieved him and slaughtered her. Their Lord then requited them for their sin and annihilated them.
[91:15]  Yet, those who came after them remain heedless.
Again, we see in the first verses, some of
God's profound signs that remind us of God's greatness.
And why we should be worshipping God alone.
[91:1]  By the sun and its brightness.
Do you have any idea how hot the sun is? How bright it is?
93 million miles away.
And you go out at noon there, and with a lens
you can actually burn anything.
You can put a piece of paper in the lens,
in the focal point, you can burn the paper.
It's very bright and very hot.
And Muhammad or Jesus had nothing to do with
creating that sun.
Saint Jude had nothing to do with creating
that sun,
or adding a single atom to it.
Yet, the people thank him for their successful
operations.
[91:1]  By the sun and its brightness.
[91:2]  The moon that follows it.
What is the moon?
It's something hanging in space.
That we flew to the moon and we went around
it.
Something that's hanging in space.
And synchronized the movement with the earth.
So, you see only one side of the moon.
These are the profound signs that God gives
us to remind us of His greatness.
[91:2]  The moon that follows it.
[91:3]  The day that reveals.
You can see everything during the daylight.
[91:4]  The night that covers.
The night and the day are other profound signs
of God.
In fact, last night, I saw that phenomenon of
the night rolling over the day and the day rolling over the night.
I left St. Louis about 8 o'clock at night.
And I watched the part of the... If you travel after sunset, you can see it.
You can look in the window in this area and
there is light and that area it's pitch black. It's very dark.
And you can see the night rolling over the
day.
And you can imagine the earth turning.
The sun set and the night overtaking the day. These are profound signs of God.
And the miraculous things in the Quran and
the infallibility of the Quran is manifested in the fact
that God says "when the world ends
half will be at night and half will be in the day.
God says "our command will come to it during
the day or the night."
Cause half the earth will be daylight and half
the earth will be at night.
If it was a human written book, they would
have made a stupid mistake.
"Our command will come at 12 noon."
Well, 12 noon New York time or Tucson time.
It's an infallible book.
Another profound sign number 5,
[91:5]  The sky and Him who built it.
Trillions, decillions of heavenly bodies in
precise orbits, never crashing with one another.
By the way, you opened, we opened the... Ihsan Ramadan, I was in her house the day before yesterday.
And we got the newspaper to see what time
is sunrise, what time is sunset, the Washington Post.
You can get the Washington Post here, even
the library.
And as it turns out, they give you the rise
and set of every member of the solar system,
Venus and Mars and Jupiter, the moon, the
sun.
They give you the sunrise and moon and sunset.
The moon rise and moon set, everyday.
The Mars rise and the Mars set.
The Venus rise and the Venus set.
We know it by fractions of minutes.
And the dummies in Saudi Arabia still want
to watch the moon to fast Ramadan.
They have to see the moon to fast Ramadan.
Every morning in the Washington Post, you
can just check it in the library.
They give you the sunrise, the moon rise,
the Venus rise, the Mars rise, the Jupiter, Saturn.
It's under the list called the solar system. Rise and set.
That's how precise God's system is.
And we're just talking about the solar system, which is a minute mote in our universe, within the Milky Way galaxy.
There are billions of suns in our Milky Way
galaxy, and ours is one of the tiny ones.
[91:5]  The sky and Him who built it.
Muhammad or Jesus or Mary had nothing to do
with the Mars rise and Mars set, every day.
Number 6,
[91:6]  The earth and Him who sustains it.
Have you seen the big trees in the Redwood
National Park, North California?
Those are fantastic creatures that God sustains.
Was it 1,500 years, the big tree? Edip. What was it?
You didn't set the camera right, so we don't
have the picture.
of the big tree.
Was it 1,500 years?
Oh,
A little older than your grandfather.
1,500 years.
Yes, that's another one.
(unintelligible) Yes.
A man: Interestingly enough, the oldest, you know, living organism (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes.
A man: (unintelligible) years. I mean, 10,000 years (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Wow.
Dr. Khalifa: That's older than America, isn't it?
A man: That's older than everything.
Dr. Khalifa: That big tree in the Redwood National Park,
1,500 years. So, that's 1,300 years before America was born,
when that tree started. And it's huge.
We tried to make Lisa surround the tree with
her arms.
Even if we put Frank next to the tree, he
will look like a tiny person there.
It's the amazing creature that God sustains.
[91:6]  The earth and Him who sustains it.
Number 7,
[91:7]  The soul and Him who created it.
God created the soul and made it invisible.
Number 8, again the message.
[91:8]  Then showed it what is evil and what is good.
What is evil is idol worship and what is good
is worshiping God alone. It's as simple as that.
[91:9]  Successful is one who redeems it.
That's the objective of our life, right there.
Number 9, redeem your soul by feeding it every day, Five Prayers, being charitable, being righteous.
Never lie, cheat, be a person of your word.
You must be an ideal, exemplary person of
moral behavior.
In every respect.
[91:9]  Successful is one who redeems it.
[91:10]  Failing is one who neglects it.
See, it's mostly neglect. Most people out there in the street, they're
neglecting their soul.
They can be the nicest people in the world,
but they're neglecting to feed their souls.
They have to worship God alone to grow and
develop.
And then we're given examples from 11, 12, 13, 14 and 15 of Thamoud and how they didn't listen to God's messenger and they ended up incurring retribution.
And number 15 tells us to learn from those examples and thank you very much and God bless you. We're gonna have the children sing for us.
Unless you have any questions about Sura 91 and let's see who's gonna give the Quranic next time and the Jumu'ah.
You're gonna be stuck with it. Catherine, you wanna give the Quranic study next week?
And the Jumu'ah prayer, Douglas, you wanna give the Jumu'ah Khutba? Ok. This is all set.
Where is Sarah? Is Sarah here?
And where is Alia? Where is Alia? Is she here?
Come here. Come here. Come here. You're birthday girl. You wanna sit here?
Sarah, you wanna sit there? Because we're gonna give you a big prayer.
These two girls are having birthdays this
week. When was your birthday?
Dr. Khalifa: Yesterday?
A girl: Yesterday.
Dr. Khalifa: Yesterday was your birthday. Yours is Monday?
Mã Shã Allãh. You're growing so fast. Slow down.
Mã Shã Allãh. We're gonna read Al-Fãtehah for these two beautiful girls because of their birthdays that God gives them a very happy year coming up
and every year will be happier than the previous year, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Al-Fãtehah
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)
Arrahman Arraheem (1:3)
Maliki Yawm Eddeen (1:4)
Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Ehdina Al-Serata Al-Mustaqeem (1:6)
Serata Al-Lazeena An’amta ‘Alayhim Ghayri Al-Maghdoobi ‘Alayhim Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
Congratulations. You're gonna eat the first cupcakes, Ok?
Ok. You wanna call the kids and we're gonna listen to them.
A woman: We have four new songs and we're gonna
do a couple of the old ones also for the conference.
We have a couple of old ones and (unintelligible).
Edip: Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
[82:1]  When the heaven is shattered.
[82:2]  The planets are scattered.
[82:3]  The oceans are exploded.
[82:4]  The graves are opened.
[82:5]  Every soul will find out what caused it to advance, and what caused it to regress.
[82:6]  O you human being, what diverted you from your Lord, Most Honorable?
[82:7]  The One who created you, designed you, and perfected you.
[82:8]  In whatever design He chose, He constructed it.
[82:9]  Indeed, you disbelieve in the religion.
[82:10]  Oblivious to the fact that there are (invisible) keepers around you.
[82:11]  They are honest recorders.
[82:12]  They record everything you do.
[82:13]  Surely, the pious have deserved bliss.
[82:14]  While the wicked have deserved Hell.
[82:15]  Will incur it on the Day of Judgment.
[82:16]  They never leave it.
[82:17]  Awesome is the Day of Judgment.
[82:18]  What a day; the Day of Judgment!
[82:19]  That is the day when no soul can help another soul, and all decisions, on that day, will belong to GOD.
Also, this chapter starts with a description
of ending of the world and the resurrection.
And then asks a question in the verse 6, asks a
question about diversion of people and then inform us
recorders that record every action, our
every speech, every word, then in verse 9 and
15, we find the same word but in different
meaning where the DIN (دِّينِ) in Arabic in the verse 9
it is in the...its meaning is "religion" but in verse 15,
we find it as the Day of Judgment Yawm Al-Din (يَوْمَ ٱلدِّينِ).
And the description of Yawm al-Din excludes all,
excludes all intercession, all kind of intercession.
That day, the dominion, everything will be... the
decision will belong to God. Nobody will help each other.
It is the only chapter that ends with word "God." The word "God"
only here is the last word and it is in 19th, in the verse 19.
And from the end, it is also the
19th word of "God."
(unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Can I explain that?
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Can you explain that?
Edip: Here, this chapter is the only chapter that
ends with "Allah", with word "Allah." You can find near 19 word "Allah."
And this is the 19th verse, the verse number is 19, and if you
count from the end of the Quran, the word "Allah",
and you will come here this... you find this, this is the 19th word "Allah" from the end.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you have any question?
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The word "God"?
Dr. Khalifa: It's a piece of information.
This is the only Sura that ends with the word "God."
And this happens to be in verse 19
and it ends with the 19th word "God" from the of the Quran.
This is on top of the last 19 words "God" in the Quran. If you count from here to the end of the Quran, the word "God",
you'll find 19 of them. And this is also verse 19.
So, there's a a unique... there's something special.
Yes. Is this a human design?
Dr. Khalifa: Is it possible that a human being designed
it this way?
So, the significance is that this is a super human design. In other words, you know that God is speaking to you, not Muhammad or somebody trying to pull your leg
So, it just meshes in with the interlocking of this mathematical system.
If you look at the bottom of the page, you see the number 1 on the left and 2680 on the right.
This is the....there's only one word God on this page and this is recorded on the left side. The total, up to this page, is 2680.
And you know, at the end, the total is 2698. So, if
you count this word "God" as one, the last one will be 19.
And this is verse 19. So, who made this design? This is the significance of it. That it is a super human design. It could not possibly be Muhammad who designed it this way.
Edip: And I want to point out something. About Yawm Al-Din, we see in Sura, chapter, Fãtehah that we always reciting our Prayers,
we say "Maliki Yawm Eddeen", the king of the Day
of Judgment and here Quran explains the
"Ywam Al-Din" Day of Judgment, Quran explains the
terms and expressions in Quran that never used before.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, Sura 83.
A woman: You know, (unintelligible) This is English phrase. (unintelligble).
Dr. Khalifa: Because it doesn't mean "religion."
A woman: For DIN?
Dr. Khalifa: DAYN. How about DAYN? What does DAYN mean?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Edip: Double meaning. DIN.
Dr. Khalifa: What is DAYN?
You know what DAYN is?
No, DAYN, not DIN. DAYN.
A woman: Debt.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right.
Edip: Right. Mã Shã Allãh.
What is debt?
This is the day where you pay your debt, or you get paid.
It's the day you get paid.
Yawm Al-Dayn or Yawm Al-Din.
It's all related.
It's the Day of Religion, the Day of Debt,
where you pay your debt, so you get paid for
your...
A woman: The Day of Judgement before...
Dr. Khalifa: Where you open your PRA book.
A woman: Right? The Day of Judgement is basically what you could thinking toward the Bible which is described (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: There's nothing wrong with that. It's the same Author.
A woman: Right. No, no, I realize....
Dr. Khalifa: But Dayn is... Dayn is debt.
Some people look at it this way.
So, this is a hybrid between Dayn and Din. Yawm Al-Deen.
I mean, "religion" means Din, but also means "judgment."
Edip: Day of judgment is a very good (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: There are others specific, using this same
word, and it's much more specific.
I can find it for you.
Edip: For what?
Dr. Khalifa: ...throughout the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: For Judgment. Day of Judgment.
Edip: Is it Yawm Al-Haq?
Dr. Khalifa: No, Yawm Al-Din.
Edip: Yawm Al-Talaq?
Dr. Khalifa: Yawm Al-Din.
A woman: Just the word "judgement."
Dr. Khalifa: Din.
In the Quran, yeah.
A woman: But in the language you were talking about,
the judgment.
Dr. Khalifa: But that will be not the context of the Day
of Judgment, even in the Bible.
Judgment in the Bible, most of the word, the
usage of the word Judgment in the Bible means punishment.
In the Bible.
It's not a day of punishment.
It's a day of receiving recompense, or paying
for your sins, either way.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but the Day of Judgment in the Bible is
not the same way as the word "judgment" throughout the Bible.
We have two usages of the word judgment in
the Bible.
But I'm for using the same terms in the Bible. I'm trying to harmonize the Bible and the Quran.
Not the other way around.
What would the day of religion mean?
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) if you use the...
No, that's not what it says, no.
Would you like tea/tee?
You do?
You play golf a lot?
So, why do you like it, then?
I'm talking about golf.
Tee.
You tee off in golf?
That's it?
Well, I'm asking you. I'm asking you.
I used the same word.
A woman: You said "do you like to tee off?"
A woman: I would have understood exactly what you meant.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I was deliberately vague.
A woman: No, I get your meaning that there are...
Dr. Khalifa: You never play golf, yet tee/tea is okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Let me think of something else.
A woman: No, no, I know what you mean. Ambiguity of language, certainly, or double meaning.
Dr. Khalifa: Multiple meanings. Yes.
A woman: Yeah, but it just seems to me that this particular
word, in Arabic, is the only time that means judgement in both expressions of the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: No, that's not true, yeah.
This is what I'm saying.
There are places in the Quran where it is
clear. I'll find them for you.
But I wanna find the English expressions that
are in multiple meanings.
A woman: In Arabic language, the only place where this word is translated as judgement is in this expression.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but the Quran is the Arabic language.
A man: But you can play also that (unintelligible) Day of Judgement.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the Day of Reckoning.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: The Day of Reckoning.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's different.
(Unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, what does the Day of Religion mean?
Edip: It has no meaning.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: Yes, it has no meaning.
See. So, therefore, this is not... if you say "I drink... I tea off at the golf", meaning you put a cup of tea on the thing and you hit it with a club,
Dr. Khalifa: you know, that would be the wrong usage.
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if you say the Day of Religion, it would
be like that.
A woman: ...It means you disbelieve in the religion. The day of the religion, the day when your religion (unintelligible) is (unintelligible). I mean, I can understand (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: So, why don't you use the Day of Judgement?
Dr. Khalifa: So, why not use the Day of Judgement?
A woman: Because it is not an accurate translation.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it is. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: It is not accurate to say Day of Religion.
A man: I don't know Arabic, but you know Arabic, right?
A man: But when you read that, it's probably (unintelligible).
If you understand the Arabic so when you say that you translated it literally, for example
(unintelligible) because you also know the Arabic, but we don't know the Arabic
If you put something, when you're making a translation, if you put it literally, okay, we may not get the meaning in the other languages.
But you can because you also know the original.
A man: I don't know if you actually get the...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, this is true in some other places.
But this happens to be the literal translation
of Yawm Al-Din is the Day of Judgement.
I'm still thinking of English equivalents.
Huh?
Yeah, what does...
A man: Separate meanings.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Okay.
Let's find simpler words.
Think of multiple-meaning English words.
That's a good one. This is a good one.
Come on, Lydia.
Give us multiple-meaning English words.
Like tea/tee.
Lydia: Read/Red
Lydia: Read a book.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Read/Red.
Edip: Sea/See, Rashad.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, very good. Red/Read.
A woman: Sea, like the ocean
Dr. Khalifa: Sea/See. Sea, the ocean and see with your...
Edip: In translation.
A man: (unintelligible). Those are spelled differently. You know like, See/Sea is S E E and S E A.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Read/Read/Red is spelled differenly.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. No, I want words that spell exactly the same way.
A man: Read and Read.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: But they're a bit ambiguous in a sense since one of them is noun and one of them is verb.
A man: Well, to an extent, there's a word like (unintelligible).
A woman: It doesn't matter. I didn't mean... I don't dare to...
How about meet? Okay, meet.
Dr. Khalifa: Is there a word that meet a judgment?
A man: Yes. "Meet" means fair or just. It also means, you know, to meet, to encounter.
Dr. Khalifa: Is it M-E-E-T, both of them?
A man: Yes, they're both M-E.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
A man: Although MEET is equitable to fair is not used anymore.
A woman: It's very archaic. That's very archaic.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is 1,400 years old Arabic.
A man: Okay.
Edip: I'm going on, people.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Chapter 83.
The Cheaters
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
[83:1]  Woe to the cheaters.
[83:2]  Who demand full measure when receiving from the people.
[83:3]  But when giving them the measures or weights, they cheat.
[83:4]  Do they not know that they will be resurrected?
[83:5]  On a tremendous day?
[83:6]  That is the day when all people will stand before the Lord of the universe.
[83:7]  Indeed, the book of the wicked is in Sijjeen.
[83:8]  Do you know what Sijjeen is?
[83:9]  A numerically structured book.
[83:10]  Woe on that day to the rejectors.
[83:11]  They do not believe in the Day of Judgment.
[83:12]  None disbelieves therein except the transgressor, the sinful.
[83:13]  When our revelations are recited to him, he says, "Tales from the past!"
[83:14]  Indeed, their hearts have become shielded by their sins.
[83:15]  Indeed, they will be isolated, on that day, from their Lord.
[83:16]  Then they will be thrown into Hell.
[83:17]  They will be told, "This is what you used to deny."
Here, God blames those people who cheat people
and this is an example of cheating, but you can,
you can, from this example, you can derive many
other examples.
And God reminds them the Day of Resurrection
because they will be (unintelligible) from their every minute acts.
And that day, the Lord of the universe
only be the Judge.
And in verse 9, we see a description of Sijjeen,
a book of the wicked people that's called Sijjeen.
It's a numerically structured book.
And God says "whenever they hear the revelations
or the signs or the miracles recited to them,
they say, "Tales from the past."
It's noteworthy that for the miracle 19, in Turkey, they published a book that they criticized. They object (to) this miracle.
The name of the book was "Tales from the past."
The name of the book.
And "19; Tales from the past."
AFSANE
Do you know word AFSANE?
Yes. And they just use the same expression that's
described in Quran.
In Turkey, we have many words to condemn miracle
19.
They have many words.
But they're stuck just in this unique expression
that's prophesied in Quran.
It's a prophecy of Quran.
I think in verse 13, "When our revelations", instead of "revelation", if a word that has double meaning used would be better.
Edip: Because in Quran, in original text, word AYAT has been used, which means either miracle and revelations, both of them.
Dr. Khalifa: Miracles.
Edip: include miracle and also revelations, but in English, it becomes narrow.
And let's go. There is
an interesting difference between
righteous people and wicked people on the Day of Judgment
in connection with the books, Sijjeen or Elleyyeen.
Let's go on. I'm verse 18.
[83:18]  Indeed, the book of the righteous will be in 'Elleyyeen.
[83:19]  Do you know what 'Elleyyeen is?
[83:20]  A numerically structured book.
It is the same book.
The description is the same, Elleyyeen or Sijjeen, but it's different.
For the wicked people, a book called Sijjeen.
But God says "what is Sijjeen?"
[83:9]  A numerically structured book.
And for the righteous people also, there is a book called "Elleyyeen." The name is only different, but the description is the same.
[83:20]  A numerically structured book.
(83:20) كِتَـٰبٌۭ مَّرْقُومٌۭ
Let's go on to find an answer to our question.
[83:21]  To be witnessed by those close to Me.
[83:22]  The righteous have deserved bliss.
[83:23]  On luxurious furnishings they watch.
[83:24]  You recognize in their faces the joy of bliss.
[83:25]  Their drinks will be spiced with nectar.
[83:26]  Its spice is like musk. This is what the competitors should compete for.
[83:27]  Mixed into it will be special flavors.
[83:28]  From a spring that is reserved for those close to Me.
[83:29]  The wicked used to laugh at those who believed.
[83:30]  When they passed by them, they used to poke fun.
[83:31]  When they got together with their people, they used to joke.
[83:32]  Whenever they saw them, they said, "These people are far astray!
[83:33]  "They have no such thing as (invisible) guards."
[83:34]  Today, those who believed are laughing at the disbelievers.
[83:35]  On luxurious furnishings they watch.
[83:36]  Most assuredly, the disbelievers are requited for what they did.
And now I'm going back on verse 19 and 20.
And I repeat my question to you.
Can you notice the difference between Elleyyeen or Sijjeen that's described in verse 7?
What is difference?
Excuse me?
Yes.
What? Where? Where?
Oh.
Why do you add three of them? You can add four or...
The description is the same.
Yes.
A man: One interpretation is probably (unintelligible) talking, to be spoken to hear it one sense of (unintelligible) in terms of doing business.
In one sense, a very structured book is a person
keeping records of what sort of money he'd
be taking in and what he'd be paying out,
and things like that. He'd certainly be an idol.
In his entire life, he'd be worshipped.
But in another sense, Elleyyeen, of course, refer to miracles God.
We know He exists today.
Or in another sense, it's just a literal application
of the individual person.
Edip: Thank you.
Edip: I have a comment on this, or understanding.
In verse 20 to 21, Allah, God describes the difference.
The difference is, righteous people could read Elleyyeen, their book, their numerically structured book. They can read.
[83:21]  To be witnessed by those close to Me.
But wicked people, they cannot understand.
They cannot read numerically structured book.
Their book will be written in numerical code.
Their deeds will be recorded in numerical
code. They are not familiar with this.
In this world, they always deny, used to deny,
to object this numerical code.
But believers, they are familiar, they can
read.
And this is the only difference here.
Dr. Khalifa: I thought you'll say something else.
I thought you were gonna say something
else. So, I will say it.
I think the numerically structured book is
the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: But the wicked will call it "tales from the
past", and the righteous will be able to see it.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God uses the same word as the elite
of the elite.
Al-Muqarrabun (ٱلْمُقَرَّبُونَ), those who are close to Me.
He said "only those, only the elite of the
elite, will be permitted to see the miracle of the Quran.
It's right here.
Only the elite of the elite will be able to
see it.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a physical miracle.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh. Yes.
Edip: It is Quran, Rashad.
Dr. Khalifa: But the definition
in 9 and in 20, same,
same description. "A numerically structured book."
The wicked will call it "tales from the past",
and the righteous will witness it.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: You agree, eh?
Edip: Good.
Edip: Just wonderful. Mã Shã Allãh. Yes.
Edip: It solves all things, Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: It's the same book, but also this ties in with the verses that you know, where it says that the Quran increases their wickedness.
Or in other places, the Quran causes them
to plunge deeper in disbelief.
Edip: Their book, they record also in Quran, Rashad. Quran describes all offenses and their punishment.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: This is their book, our book, also. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, go ahead.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: But it necessarily refers to the Quran.
Edip: No, no, necessarily refers to Quran, yes.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh. Yes. Good.
Because there is difference. Only difference, righteous people can understand this. The other will say "tales from the past."
Dr. Khalifa: You know how the disbelievers say "the Quran
is full of Hell and fire and brimstone?"
Well, that's what they see.
But it is, as you know, half and half. So, it depends on which half you see.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, we better quit.
Edip: And let's go on. I have another....
Edip: No, no, no.
Edip: On this Sura, verse 29, they used to laugh
at believers, but now, do they laugh at us, Rashad?
Dr. Khalifa: Sure do.
Edip: They must be more crazy. They do not laugh too much.
It is interesting.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, they do laugh at the believers.
Edip: Ok. Let's go.
Dr. Khalifa: But we will laugh at them for eternity.
Dr. Khalifa: Thank you very much. God bless you. Good job.