The messenger: In God the believers shall trust. In other words, if you're a believer,
you must trust that God will take care of you. God guarantees it for you.
And if something appears to be bad,
you must know that there's a good reason for it.
[9:52] Say, "you can only expect for us
one of two good things in war (victory
or martyrdom) while we expect for you condemnation from GOD and retribution from Him,
at our hands... or at our hands. Therefore, wait, and we will wait along with you.”
[9:53] Say, “Spend, willingly or unwillingly.
Nothing will be accepted from you, for you are evil people.”
Rejectors of God's messenger observe the Salat prayers.
[9:54] What prevented the acceptance of their spending is that they disbelieved in GOD and His messenger, and when they observed the Contact Prayers (Salat), they observed them lazily, and when they gave to charity, they did so grudgingly.
This is an important verse. You should remember it, 9:54. Remember it. When the people tell you that "we
think that Salat began with Muhammad. We think there was no Salat before the Prophet Muhammad.
You should remind them with this verse. These
are people who rejected the Prophet.
They disbelieved in God, but they were doing the 5 contact prayers. The word Salat is very specific.
Because Salat existed before the prophet. Just at the time, it had been... they had been corrupted
by idol worship.
Exactly. Same thing today.
9:54 is another proof that the contact prayers (Salat) existed before the Quran.
Yes, this is a good point because this, this verse was revealed probably less than a year before the prophet's death.
And this is my chance to give Parivash a public apology because I misunderstood
her question yesterday. She was saying that
the the verse is at the end of Sura 15,
they are people who accept the Quran partially could not possibly be applicable to the the time of
the prophet because the Quran itself was being revealed. So, it was not in existence really.
Even when the Prophet died, they left the Quran in the
chronological sequence with instructions in
the side was... is not organized at all into a Quran. Now, we have the Quran. This is the Quran
the format that God wants, and did not exist until 20 years after the prophet's death. They decided to put it together.
Parivash: This is very... this only one verse is very very strong. It says proclaim to whom... proclaim the messenger... if messenger... that I'm messenger and after that...
The Messenger:
(15:89) وَقُلْ إِنِّىٓ أَنَا ٱلنَّذِيرُ ٱلْمُبِينُ
And say I am the...
Parivash: One verse is enough to know that after Muhammad, a messenger comes.
The Messenger: Mã Shã Allãh. Yeah, I misunderstood the question.
The Messenger: 196, at the top, 55 says "Do not be impressed by their money, or their children. GOD turns these into means of retribution for them in this life, and their souls depart while they are disbelievers.
This is a common thing that you may come across "Look at those people. They are not believers but they
are happy and rich and this and that." But they are not happy. You have to take that word out. Because God says "He
will cause the money and the children to be to be the source of misery for them."
Then, after all this misery, they leave the world as disbelievers.
56, They swear by GOD that they belong with you, while they do not belong with you; they are divisive people.
They will create division. They'll create confusion because the statements that come out of their mouth is disbelief.
[9:57] If they could find [any] refuge, or caves, or a hiding place, they would go to it, rushing.
[9:58] Some of them criticize your distribution of the charities; if they are given therefrom, they become satisfied, but if they are not given therefrom, they become objectors.
[9:59] They should be satisfied with what GOD and His messenger have given them. They should have said, “GOD suffices us. GOD will provide for us from His bounties, [through] His messenger. We are seeking only GOD.”
And here's the distribution system
for charities other than ZAKAT. Those apply to ZAKAT.
[9:60] Charities shall go to the poor
So, on ZAKAT, it says your parents first. They have to be poor. If they are not poor, then you go to the next line which is relatives, cousins, aunts, nephews, nieces, uncles.
[9:60] Charities shall go to the poor, the needy, the workers who collect them, the new converts, to free the slaves, to those burdened by sudden expenses, in the cause of GOD, and to the traveling alien. Such is GOD’s commandment. GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
[9:61] Some of them hurt the prophet by saying, “He is all ears!” Say, “It is better for you that he listens to you. He believes in GOD, and trusts the believers. He is a mercy for those among you who believe.” Those who hurt GOD’s messenger have incurred a painful retribution.
62, They swear by GOD to you, to please you, when GOD and His messenger are more worthy of pleasing, if they are really believers.
Retribution for Opposing God and His Messenger
63, Did they not know that anyone who opposes GOD and His messenger has incurred the fire of Hell forever? This is the worst humiliation.
[9:64] The hypocrites worry that a sura may be revealed exposing what is inside their hearts. Say, “Go ahead and mock. GOD will [bring out] what you are [worried about].”
[9:65] If you ask them, they would say, “We were only [joking and playing].” Say, “Do you realize that you are mocking GOD, and His revelations, and His messenger?”
[9:66] Do not apologize. You have disbelieved after having believed. If we pardon some of you, we will punish others among you, as a consequence of their [transgressions].
[9:67] The hypocrite men and the hypocrite women belong with each other − they advocate evil and prohibit righteousness, and they are stingy. They forgot GOD, so He forgot them. The hypocrites are truly wicked.
[9:68] GOD promises the hypocrite men and the hypocrite women, as well as the disbelievers, the fire of Hell, they abide [therein] forever. It suffices them. GOD has condemned them; they have incurred an [unending] retribution.
So, here we read four pages,
most of the them about the hypocrites because they sit, sit with us and they... we look on them as believers and then
they talk to some of us and people listen
to them and what comes out, they cause doubt in the hearts of them
in the heart of the believers. But God reserves the lowest pit of Hell for them because of this.
Because they look like believers, act like believers. We have to be...we have to be aware as we grow. Just because
we're all here at the same rung doesn't mean we have to be perfect in our religion. This is a test
for all of us.
They could be very very loving
friendly people and, you know, they are with us and...
Then, they stab you.
Yes, in fact, there are many examples of this. They are with us and very strong. We became very close and very friendly but now we know they are not believers.
Cause things are happening progressively and there's a drop-out point for some people. So, even though they believe
when the messengership point came, for example, they couldn't take it. But they continue to come
with us and talk with us.
You know a few of them.
OK. We'll have 5 minutes of discussion.
Charity is something that don't stop. Storm could come and destroy San Francisco and the people on the street hungry and... you don't even know their names. You help them.
Right. Because it's limited by you and me by not being too extravagant. Go ahead.
Yes, give the ZAKAT to the relatives first
unless...unless he's fighting you. He's just disbelieving and has made a decision he doesn't know but he's not fighting
you actively when you have to give the ZAKAT to the relatives first. God says that.
Because your cousin who's not fighting you, maybe next
week, he reads the Quran, discover God and becomes
better than you and me, right? And maybe when you
help him, this will cause him to believe.
He says "wow, this is a good statement that believers are charitable." So, God tells us to consider them potential believers.
IN SHAA ALLAH.
He got the message from another source?
Oh, I see.
Well, if the circumstances come up, we're supposed
to give the message, any way, when the circumstances come up.
God will create the circumstances for us to  deliver the message but we must strive. We need to strive. We need to do something.
You know, as it is the majority of people
believe in God alone, worship the Quran alone,
worship God alone. And that's it. They're believers. They're good. They're going to Heaven. But they are not the same as
people who strive who are just aflame. Hey, look who's here. The Turners are here. Come on in. Come on in. Mã Shã Allãh.
You left Omnia home.
ʿAlaykumu Al-Salam
Kid sleep here in Tucson? Oh, OK. I know how it is.
Mã Shã Allãh.
Written down? If... if in your mind, you don't care if she keeps the money
and you never get it back, then it's okay.
But if you want it to be repaid, God tells us
to write it down, so you don't forget how much you give her and she doesn't forget how much she borrows.
If you don't care if she ever pays it, then it's okay.
This... this you write it down if you expect it
to be paid back because I'm telling you you'll
forget. You may give her $500 and then after a
month, you'll be absolutely positive you had given her 1000. Sometimes Satan will see to it.
The person who's giving the loan is in control. So, it is the person's right.
But the person who's taking the loan is the one who dictates the terms or writes down, writes down "I received."
"I received $500 from Roxana and I promise to pay it
$50 a month gradually and finish
the payments on a certain date." This is... God gives us the details of what to write. Because it'll be written in the hands of the borrower.
And then you have two witnesses. This is why there'll be no
confusion at all. Subhan Allah. I mean, this was... this came down at an age when there were no accountants.
Yeah, this is true in all countries and seems here also. No, but this is a specific situation talking about the community of believers. And we've seen it also within the
community of believers.
We live... we are living the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what's your first question, Naghmeh?
Naghmeh: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: As much as you can.
We're talking about believers who believe in God, the Hereafter, follow the Quran alone and worship God alone, but that's the extent of it.
They're good people. They're going to Heaven but they're not at the same
rank, as far as God is concerned, like the people who, who strive.
Right. Yeah, right. You have to see all circumstances and how it is working, but God says
لَّا يَسْتَوِى ٱلْقَـٰعِدُونَ مِنَ ٱلْمُؤْمِنِينَ غَيْرُ أُو۟لِى ٱلضَّرَرِ وَٱلْمُجَـٰهِدُونَ فِى سَبِيلِ ٱللَّهِ بِأَمْوَٰلِهِمْ وَأَنفُسِهِمْ ۚ فَضَّلَ ٱللَّهُ
(4:95) ٱلْمُجَـٰهِدِينَ بِأَمْوَٰلِهِمْ وَأَنفُسِهِمْ عَلَى ٱلْقَـٰعِدِينَ دَرَجَةًۭ
God raises the strivers.
So, I don't, I don't push unless this comes from the people who care.
Yeah. Yeah, you're gonna see to it that the message is delivered in the best possible and the most effective manner. It all depends on the circumstances. Again,
(16:125) ٱدْعُ إِلَىٰ سَبِيلِ رَبِّكَ بِٱلْحِكْمَةِ وَٱلْمَوْعِظَةِ ٱلْحَسَنَةِ
Invite to the path of God with wisdom and great diplomacy.
You're gonna do it so you don't chase him away and you don't.... keep the door open. If they are not going to believe now, you keep the door open for them.
So, you're right. Yeah.
Mã Shã Allãh. So, is it good? Good. Alhamdu Lillah
But there's a point of... where God asked us to
give up and then the question in Sura 13
so "is it not time for the believers
to give up on the disbelievers and realize
that God guides whomever He wills?"
Usually they catch it if God wants it one day. Somebody's gonna believe this.
That's it. They see it. You can tell if they're blind and deaf or if there's a concrete wall around them or if they are wide open to the message.
I don't know. It's been rare to see somebody who's completely blocked and
then all of a sudden they, they could see.
Well, Lisa and Susan go to work. Don't go through this door.
I think Parivash finished cooking so you can have some breakfast. You're gonna go help them? Yeah.
Ok. Wait. Stay, stay where you are, stay, stay just one minute.
Lisa and Susan have to go to work soon. So, just wait. Wait a minute.
Lisa:
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيْمِ
Lisa: As Rashad said we're starting with verse 75
Lisa: In Sura 56 verse 75
Lisa: The honorable Quran
[56:75] I swear by the positions of the stars.
[56:76] [And it] is an [awesome] oath, if you only knew
Lisa: We could talk about that all night.
Lisa: We know now, though it was not known 1500... 1400 years ago, how awesome an oath this truly is.
1400 years ago, they could see the stars and looking up in the sky being awed by them as we are today. But for us, having the knowledge that we have
we know that what you can see in the night sky is the minutest fraction of the stars there.
I'd like to read a little bit of passage, talking
about how big our galaxy and the universe
really is. I don't wanna go too far with
it, but to give us a little bit of a feel
again on how awesome an oath this truly is because it
is a more awesome oath than we could really
comprehend. Even though intellectually we
can try, it's beyond our comprehension.
Our sun is only one of perhaps a million stars
within our galaxy, Milky Way. The stars of the
Milky Way is awesome. It would take us a hundred
thousand years at the speed of light to cross it from one end
to the other bearing in mind that the sun's
light travels 93 million miles in 4 minutes.
We can appreciate the vastness of the Milky Way, the hundred thousand light years across.
From the outer limit of our galaxy how significant the
planet Earth of the solar system is? Our next-door gal... neighbor
galaxy, the closest galaxy to our Milky Way
is 2 million light years away. These are all
established scientific facts that a civilized
and highly educated generation is fortunate to
know. If we go to the center of our neighbor galaxy, can you visualize the planet Earth of the
Milky Way galaxy? How significant is it at that
distance? By moving away from our galaxy to the
nearest galaxy close to us, we are already
talking about incredible distances, millions
of light years. Yet our universe contains a
great number of galaxies. Back in the 1950s
(unintelligible) drew the first map of the universe
and its galaxies. One thousand galaxies were surveyed then.
And since then, scientists have discovered
1 billion galaxies, more than a million times
what was known 30 years ago. Can you imagine the
vastness of our universe with its billion galaxies
and billion trillion stars? We are now talking
about billions of light years within our universe.
Have you lost track of our planet Earth?
How significant is our planet Earth?
It is very important to keep this size and
our significance or perspective in order to
appreciate the significance or insignificance
of teeny creatures who inhabited this planet for
brief period of time. And then we have one of the psalms. This is psalm... from psalm 8. "when I behold your
heavens, the work of your fingers, the moon and
stars which you set in place, what is man that You
should be mindful of him or the Son of Man that You
should care for him."
And yet we get up in the morning and we think (unintelligible). This is truly an awesome oath and God is swearing.
[56:75] I swear by the positions of the stars.
[56:76] [And it] is an [awesome] oath, if you only knew.
[56:77]  This is an honorable Quran.
[56:78]  In a [perfectly preserved] book.
[56:79]  None can [touch] it except the [righteous].
[56:80] [It is] A revelation from the Lord of the universe.
We have in our hand the only thing that we need. God
has blessed us with this incredible blessing.
This is our roadmap back to God. And we know that it is, it is an
honorable Quran and it has been perfectly preserved.
We, in this mosque, know that better than any people on
earth or we've been incredibly what? incredibly...
The miracles continue to come, flooding us, absolutely flooding us, showing with no uncertain... in no uncertain terms that this book is perfectly preserved.
And that not only is it perfectly preserved, but it is so incredibly coded that there is no way that
any human being could have even approached the slightest... to the slightest degree approached writing it even more thoroughly.
It's beyond, beyond us and truly great. And
we know now also that none can touch it except
the righteous. What does that mean? I mean, that doesn't
mean physically touch it, but it means that no
one can get from this Quran unless they are righteous. Unless they... Unless they're truly thinking of God. And beyond that
and more importantly for us to this point, we know
that no one could discover this miracle, not being righteous.
There is no way. This miracle is at off limits of anything we can imagine. God has already sworn by the position of the stars that this is an honorable Quran.
This Quran is honorable and it's perfectly preserved and that
is... that... it's overwhelming, massive and overwhelming. So, we know first
of all, we know that this Quran has been preserved. We're also given very clear, very... the strongest of proofs that the discoverer of this code is indeed righteous which is something that obviously all of us realize
because (unintelligible)
But we know very clearly and that this miracle and the revelation itself has come from God.
There is no way, there's no way we could... we could have
made it up or it could have been tricked from God
that anyone could even trick God to discover the miracle any more than they could have tricked God to....(unintelligible)
Verse 81, [56:81] Are you [then evading] this [message]?
[56:82] Do you make it your [share] that you [reject it]?
[56:83] [you soul will reach your throat someday]
[56:84]  [then] you will look around.
[56:85]  We are closer to it than you are, but you [can] not see.
[56:86] [If you do have any power, you should reclaim your soul]
[56:87] if you are truthful?
Look at how many people are fighting, fighting these verses.
These verses, to me, are... are specifically directed
to them as well as obviously to those who reject the Quran.
"Are you... are you evading this message?" God has already said that the Quran is perfectly preserved that none can touch it except the righteous,
and yet there are those who say that they
are Muslim and say that they study the
Quran and yet they reject the miracle and they do it out of ego. They don't like what we do. We're just worshipping God alone, removing all additions, all of the falsehood, all of the garbage and coming back to the very simple truth.
It is very simple. It's not easy and until you
make it easy, until you allow it to be easy.
It's very simple.
And it's very straightforward and clear-cut.
Those who are evading
this message and that's truly what it is. I mean,
anyone who reads this, reads this Quran have to, have to evade it or follow it. If you follow it,
there's no way you can, can follow Hadith and Sunnah. There's no way you can accept all the other garbage if you're
following the Quran. So, if you're reading it and you're
still following Hadith and Sunnah, you're evading the Quran.
[56:82]  Do you make it your [share] that you [reject it]?
Well, they take the very... it takes a lot of work
I think on some level not to accept the truth. You have to... you have to work at rejecting the truth.
When you intend to do that or when you do that, then you become a
fanatic person. I think that's a lot of what we've seen.
And it's very clear from the next verses that
none of us can help our lives. None of us can
stop death when it comes. God is closer to
us than our jugular vein. He stands between us
and our hearts. We know that God is in control of
every... the minutest detail in the universe. He controls every
atom, every subatomic particle within our body, within the rest of the universe. That power is so
awesome and so incomprehensible to us that it's
probably easier for all people to ignore it because
it's too scary to realize that there is a powerful....
And yet we're here to come back to that realization.
We're here because we did not remember that when we were in God's Heavenly plain and we're here again, as Laurie so beautifully
expressed. We're here again to try and come back within a second chance. Should I... can I stop here? Are there any questions or comments?
I'm sorry. Thank you. Excuse me
The footnote: the Quran is by no
means a regular book. Only the sincerest seekers of
the truth will be allowed to understand it (see 41:44).
The insincere will be prevented from acquiring any
knowledge from the Quran. In fact, those who are prevented by God from learning the Quran. Plainly, this verse means
that no one can physically touch the Quran unless he satisfies certain ablution requirements.
Obviously, this distortion is a clear Satanic plot to prevent people from studying God's message to them.
Our salvation is in reading, studying, and heeding the Quran.
The messenger: It's not really "touch", the English word. The Arabic word does not mean "touch." And we have to find another word, but still in English, you can say that.
The messenger: It means that nobody can derive anything out of the Quran unless they are sincere.
But in Arabic the word is
يَمَسُّهُ
And it's different from يلمس
یلمس is physical touch but يَمَسُّهُ is touch in this meaning that they cannot take, derive, understand anything from letters they see.
Cause your teacher is God. When you read this book, you're directly being taught by God as we read in Sura 55. It's not a regular book.
This is why you read it over and over a thousand times and you still find new things every time, unlike a novel. You read a novel and that's it.
(unintelligible)
Cause every time you look in it, God gives you new information.
This is.... in verse 77, the Quran in Arabic is described as KARIM. In other places, it is called Quran 'AZIM. And in Sura 50, it is described as Quran MAJEED,
Glorious, 'AZIM, Great, KARIM, honorable. So, these are actually a sequence of God's names. I mean, this is awesome to describe the Quran with the same names of God.
'AZIM, MAJEED, KARIM tell you how great this book is. Your salvation is in this book. And we're really... we're really fortunate to be
studying it every week. I mean, the Quran study. Hopefully, you're reading it everyday, at least one verse every day. Make it a duty upon yourself.
Cause it... you know, it's a blessing.
None can touch it except the righteous. And we have... we have an international
observation to prove this in the... the miracle of Quran that is
coming up in this mosque that it is... it is a miracle that
is like the Quran, ranges from the very simple
to the very complex. Yet, nobody was allowed to
make any discovery in this miracle except those
who are connected with with us, connected with...
to believers, only believers who believe like we do. They believe in worshipping God alone and upholding the word of
God alone. Just look at the people made discoveries. I wanna pass this around. Just do it very
fast. Just take one and pass on to the next.... This is a summary of the miracle in one page. When you look on the back and there are other
features of the miracle, you'll see that the first verse is 19 letters. The number of Suras is 114, 19 x 6.
Is this simple enough? The first verse is 19 letters. The number of Suras is a multiple of 19. Rachel, the first revelation was 19 words.
The last revelation 19 words. These are famous first revelations and famous last revelations.
And they are very simple. They don't require a computer. But not a
single person outside the fold of believers
was allowed to touch it. It's a monopoly. You look at the
people who made major discoveries, Abdullah,
Mahmud, Ihsan, Lisa, many others, Feroz, Ismail. These are the people that we know. And they are all... Gatut.... they're
all people who firmly believe like we do. And for a long time, I was surprised why doesn't
anybody else find these things, you know? Because
I needed some support. That's very simple.
When you look at the back, you see how simple it is. From the missing BISMILLAH to  the extra BISMILLAH
19 Suras. Is this difficult? I mean, the consistency in repetition of the number 19, it's so simple.
Yet, nobody, a billion Muslims in the world but none of
them was allowed to find these very simple facts
unless they upheld the Quran alone. They believed in Hadith and Sunnah and mentioned other names
in their prayer. They are not permitted to touch it. This is verse
77. By the way on the wall, you'll see a very
complex miracle, in the circle. This was, it's no
longer the biggest number in the world because this is
already obsolete. Abdullah, on his birthday
yesterday, made it obsolete. In this circle,
the number begins with the first verse in the Quran, 1. So, if you look on the left, there's an asterisk on the left
side of the circle and you see right... you start by 1 2 3 4 5 6 7. these are the
verses in the first Sura. 7 verses followed by
the total number of verses in the Sura which is 7.
Then, you move on to the next Sura, 1 2 3 4 5 6 all the way to 286,
the number of verses in Sura 2. When you put the total number
of verses in Sura two, 286 and you do this all the way to the
end of the Quran. When you get to the end of the Quran, if you look on the right side, you see this big
arrow that says "total number of verses in the Quran", you put that. Now, you have a very long number that is... I like
it in the (unintelligible). It is 1 kilometer long. And it consists of 12,696 digits. And it is a multiple of 19.
If you go on, if you see now, if you look on the right
side of the circle in the middle of it with
the big arrow that says "total number of verses in the Quran." After the asterisk comes the total number of
verses in the first Sura which is 7. And next to it is the
seven verses 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
Then, you put the total number of verses in Sura
number 2 and so on. So, what we're doing in
the lower half is we are reversing the position of
the total number of verses (unintelligible) at the end of
every Sura. We're putting this in the beginning of every Sura. And brothers and sisters, the number is divisible and go to
the end. So, now this is a circle and connect the
two numbers. We have what was until yesterday,
the day before yesterday, the longest number in the world, 25388
digits. And that's a multiple 19. Now, what
Abdullah did to make this number obsolete,
he added the number of ever Sura. Okay, let's go now
to the asterisk from the left side in the circle.
It begins with the numbers in the first Sura, 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
followed by the total number of verses in this Sura which is 7. Now, between the two 7s there, he put the
number of the Sura, 1. And he did this with every Sura and you get this, the number is still divisible.
It's just incredible. And there's more. If you put
the number of the Sura at the beginning or at the
end or in the middle, it's still divisible. So, this
would be in the Ramadan issue. In the Muslim Perspective, you're gonna
get more, more of the details. So, now I don't know
how many digits there are from the first Sura to the last Sura, the numbers.
1 2 3 4, you counted the digits? 114. Sura 1, Sura 2, Sura 3, Sura 4, all the way to Sura 114. How many digits? 472, you add that...
OK. This... there's a by-the-way miracle, you know.
1 2 3 4 all the way to the end of the Quran 114, and you put the digits next to each other. 474 digits
and it's a multiple of 19. So, you... you put that, you add this to this number which is 25698 digits,
you add 474, now you have the biggest number
in the world. It came out of this Quran. 2 4 25 388 plus 1... about. 25800 numbers, digits and that is divisible.
In the middle meaning between the last verse
and the total number of verses. If you look on
the left side of the circle, you see the asterisk
and above it, you see the number of verses in Sura Al-Fãtehah,
number one. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 followed by the total number of verses
in the Sura which is another set. So, he put the 1 between the two 7s that you see there.
That's the number of the Sura and you do this in all the Suras, it's divisible. If you move the
number of the Sura, put it at the beginning, so you have 1 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 7
that's divisible. And if you put the total number
of verses at the beginning, so you have 1 7 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
you still have a divisible number. So, it is.... it sounds like almost a
physical impossibility but it locks...  it locks
every verse... somebody called today and said
"how do you know it's only the two verses in Sura 9?" You notice the Sura 9
is mentioned here. If you look in the upper right corner
of the circle, it says total number of verses in Sura 9.
It has to be 127. This fellow was calling from Louisville, Kentucky and he said "how do you know it's know only
the two verses in Sura 9 that violate
the code?" So, I thought it was every single verse what we see
here is every single verse in Quran is authenticated as Divine from God, every single one, except these two.
So, it's just it is fitting to mention why God
swears by the position of the stars
that this is a.... this is a Quran KARIM. By the way, AL-QURAN AL-KARIM has a gematrical value that is 684, a multiple of 19,
the numerical value of this... the official name of the Quran, AL-QURAN AL-KARIM.
Just to change the subject to make it a little bit lighter. You know how they count the stars? Just some of you do. But any way, they go out
in the night and take a picture of the sky, just take a picture and they put in the computer and
they count... the computer will count the number of the stars in that area in the picture and there's a formula that tells you what the circumference
from the inside of a circle is and then you can... you
can tell from this picture how many are in the
whole circumference of the whole sky and you do
this a hundred times and then you take the average of
a hundred times and you have exactly, almost
exactly, the number of stars, a billion trillion of them.
And these are the ones that we see. Because of this... our Sun is in the next galaxy, you will not be able to see it because it is one of the dim stars.
What we're seeing are only
the bright stars. This is... this is how we counted them.
[56:75]  I swear by the positions of the stars.
Because they are in perfect positioning, perfect orbits. They don't crash into one another.
There was something else also I wanted... the notes are here.
Are there any questions?
Right, right. We have two halves that are divisible by 19. So, what I'm doing here is just making them into a circle. Well, the upper half is a multiple of 19 and you have the
total number of verses at the end of each Sura. The lower half is a multiple of 19 and connecting them has nothing to do with
anything, but in the lower half,
you have the number of verses at the beginning
of every Sura. If you look on the right side of
the circle. Look at the right side of the circle at the big
arrow that says "total number of verses in the Quran." We know that you see Sura Al-Fãtehah with the total number of verses which is 7 at
the beginning, not at the end. So, you have 7 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 instead of
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 7. Both of
them are independently divisible by 19. And I just
put them next to each other. And this because the
upper half was a discovery by Feroz Karmally.
And he put... he ended up... he ended up putting the total number of verses in the Quran at the end of the number.
The lower half is Abdullah's discovery and the total number of the verses comes ahead of the Suras. So, the total number of verses in
the Quran fits right there, ahead of the whole Quran. This circle is now obsolete, great but obsolete. We have better circles made. Any other questions? Back to Lisa and verse number? What?
Lisa: Verse number 88.
[56:88]  [Thereafter] If he is one close to Me—
[56:89]  then [happiness], flowers, and gardens of bliss.
[56:90]  And if he [belongs with those on] the right—
[56:91]  [then] peace [to you from] those on the right.
[56:92]  But if he is one of the [rejectors], the strayers—
[56:93]  then an abode of [retribution]—
[56:94]  and burning Hell.
[56:95]  This is the [inevitable] truth.
[56:96]  You shall glorify the name of your Lord, the Great.
Verse 88 and 89, actually all of these verses, refer back to the beginning
verses of this Quran...this Sura where it talks about the High Heaven, the Lower Heaven and Hell. And we see
again in 88 how beautiful the Highest Heaven is.
We know, of course, that these are all allegorical
descriptions. That God uses allegory because
there's no way that we in our present states can
even begin to understand really what is in store
for us. But we know from, from the allegory of the
Highest Heaven that it is truly blessed and that
it is wonderful beyond our dreams. God says that
anything we wish for, anything those who are in the Highest Heaven, IN SHAA ALLAH we'll be there, anything they wish
for and even more. So, God's grace is even greater
than anything we can comprehend or, or desire, wish for.
And then those on the right, those in the Lower
Heaven, for them also, it's incredibly beautiful
and it's peace. Peace to you from those on the
right, an incredible incredible triumph to be
among those on the right. But if he is one of
the rejectors strayers, then the retribution
and burning Hell. We know again that we can't
comprehend really the awfulness of Hell.
We have a slight idea because we are... it's far from
God as anything in the universe at this point
and we know how hellish this world and how
awful it is particularly when you step out
of God's kingdom. We're incredibly blessed
to be in God's kingdom, IN SHAA ALLAH, but as soon as you
step out, you know how, what an incredible hell
that is and that is nothing compared to the ultimate Hell.
[56:95]  This is the [inevitable] truth.
[56:96]  You shall glorify the name of your Lord, the Great.
Mã Shã Allãh.