Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Raheem.
Qul a'udhu bi-Rabbi al-Falaq, Min sharri ma khalaq, Wa min sharri ghasiqin idha waqab, Wa min sharri an-naffathati fi al-'uqad, Wa min sharri hasidin idha hasad.
Surah Al-Fatihah.
Ihdinas-sirat al-mustaqim, Sirat alladhina an'amta 'alayhim,
ghayri al-maghdubi 'alayhim wa la ad-dallin.
Sadaqa Allahu al-Azim.
We have a short meditation for all of you now.
Let us begin.
Once again we'll try to close our eyes, concentrate, and travel across billions of galaxies, across seven universes,
universes, and move to the 7th Heaven and announce to the angels that we, as humans, are present,
and that there is no doubt that there is no god but God.
Jalla wa 'Ala.
La ilaha illallah.
La ilaha illallah. La ilaha illallah.
La ilaha illallah, La ilaha illallah...
La ilaha illallah.
La ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah,
la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha
illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha illallah, la ilaha
As we whisper La ilaha illallah, try again to let the soul go close to its source in Heaven.
Let us continue.
Amen.
La ilaha illallah.
Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah...
Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah. Allah.
Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah,
Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah, Allah,
Allahu, Allahu, Allahu, Allahu, Allahu, Allahu, Allahu.
Allahu, Allahu, Allahu, Allahu.
Allahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar. La ilaha illallah. Allahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar. Wa lillahil hamd.
Subhanallah.
Surah Al-Baqarah, Surah An-Naml, Surah Al-Baqarah.
Surah Al-Baqarah, Surah An-Naml, Surah An-Nas.
Subhanallah. Subhanallah.
Subhanallah.
Allahu Akbar.
Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah...
Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah...