Alhamdulillah, wa ashadu an la ilaha illallah wahdahu la sharika lah. As you see I have an assistant today.
As you know I'm working on gathering all the evidence and the proofs that show that if you go to any source other than Quran, it means you're setting up another god beside God.
and the book is evolving and changing and I keep showing you the slides as the
book evolves, and then I expect to have it printed insha'Allah in a couple of months.
But you bear with me, some of these slides may be repetitious as far as you
are concerned, but this would help me because I do get comments on correcting
this, or changing that, and insha'Allah this will lead to perfection of the book. But
before we get to the slides, I'm going to read one verse in Surah 9, because a lot
of people sometimes are concerned about the feelings of others, like if you meet
somebody who believes in hadith for example, and you worry that you might
hurt their feelings. This verse deals with that, because when it comes to the
truth, especially about God, God wants people to be completely sold on him
without, absolutely, with no hesitation whatsoever.
So the verses in Surah 9, it's number 120,
and it reads, I'm going to read it for you.
Neither the dwellers of the city nor the nomads should seek to stay behind the
messenger of God when he mobilizes for war, nor should they place their lives
ahead of his life. This is because, this is what I wanted to read for you, this
part of the verse. No thirst afflicts them or any effort or any hardship in
the cause of God, nor do they make a single step that discourages the
disbelievers, nor do they strike at an enemy without having this credited to them as
a righteous work. God never fails to reward the righteous. Okay let me put it in
plain English, you can see that I have to improve the translation, but part of
this verse says they do not do anything that enrages the disbelievers without
having this written to them as a credit. So don't worry about the feelings of
people who are not completely sold on God. And a lot of
people who compromise their own convictions just to please others or
afraid that they may hurt the feelings of others. Actually you're not hurting
the feelings, you are serving them, you're helping them. And we shouldn't forget the
verse that says you should invite to the path of God with wisdom and nice
admonitions. But the Quran deals with all situations. There are situations where you
cannot compromise your convictions, and you have to be solid on the side of God.
and you don't worry about, if the person deserves to be enraged, then this will be written to you as a credit.
Could we separate these two?
If you keep them apart they will not make noise.
Okay, now we get to the slides.
This is the latest edition of the book, and I'm going to rely on your opinions and help to modify this.
I'm going to turn it a bit, just to push it a little bit.
This is the new title. Quran times, our titles are becoming mathematical now.
Quran times hadith equals zero. Because if you get the Quran, and you uphold it,
and you follow it, but then you seek any other source besides Quran,
then you might have zero, you have nothing.
Also when you multiply anything by zero, the result is zero.
Now there is no salvation without obeying the messenger, and these are the verses.
So when they tell you, we must obey the messenger, you agree with them and you go even farther
than that.
You say, yeah you must obey the messenger, furthermore you do not obey the messenger.
These are the verses, and we're going to have it printed for you, someday.
When delivering God's messages, messengers do not speak on their own initiative.
and we see this documented in the previous scriptures in the Bible, the Old
Testament, the New Testament.
And the Prophet Muhammad is represented by Quran alone. This verse, these verses
here from Surah 5, verses 48 to 50. These verses keep repeating that
The whole message is given from God. Yes. We keep repeating that we reveal to you, we send
down to you this book, that is the Quran, and you shall judge among
them according to what is revealed to you, which is the book, and be
aware of them lest they pressure you into deviating from the book, etc.
So the Prophet is represented 100% by the Quran. Now these verses are very,
these verses are very clear: Muhammad is forbidden from uttering any religious
instructions other than Quran. See, see this part here? Had he ever uttered, let me go back.
This Quran is the utterance of an honorable messenger. It is not the
utterance of a poet; rarely do you believe. Nor is it the utterance of a
soothsayer; rarely do you take heed. A revelation from the Lord of the universe.
This is an expression that is specific for the Quran: Tanzilun min Rabbil 'alameen.
Had he ever uttered any other religious utterances attributed to us, we would
have punished him severely, then we would have stopped the revelation to him.
In other words, we would have fired him. None of you could have protected him against us.
Therefore the Prophet did not utter any religious instructions other than the Quran.
Otherwise he would have been fired as a messenger. This is very clear, I mean very
harsh actually, not just clear.
Also, this is the utterance of an honorable messenger.
Some people will tell you, the Quran says obey God and obey the Messenger.
They tell you God is represented by Quran, the Messenger is represented by Hadith.
But we didn't get Quran from God personally.
God didn't give us the Quran directly to me or to you.
I mean the Quran came through Muhammad.
So the Messenger is uttering the words of the Quran, the words of God.
And there is a verse that you will see that says when you obey the Messenger, you are obeying God.
Obviously the messenger is not God, but when he's uttering the words of God,
that is the Quran, then he absolutely makes no mistake and we must absolutely
obey him, that is the Quran. Muhammad was ordered never to deviate from the Quran.
Deviation meant severe retribution. This is in Surah 17, verses 73 to 75, and it
says here, "They almost diverted you, Muhammad, from our revelations to you.
They wanted you to fabricate something else, to consider you a friend.
If it were not that we strengthened you, you almost leaned towards them a little bit."
In Arabic, "a little bit."
"Had you done it, we would have doubled the punishment for you in this life and after death,
and no one could have protected you against us."
Very, very harsh words.
There is absolutely no deviation from the Quran.
And Muhammad was ordered to deliver the Quran alone, without the least alteration, and
never to fabricate anything else. Now these verses speak of the Quran
specifically. It says, "When our verses are recited for them, those who do not expect
to meet us would say, 'Bring a Quran other than this, or change it.' Say, 'I cannot
change it on my own initiative. I simply follow what is revealed to me. I fear if
I disobey my Lord the retribution of a terrible day.'" Who is more wicked than one
who invents lies about God or rejects His revelations?" When we go to Hadith,
we commit falsehoods. We reject God's revelations that state that the Quran is
complete and perfect, as we will see. And we follow
the invention of lies against God.
and rejecting His revelation. Inventing lies and rejecting His revelation, the two things.
I'm trying to rush but I'm slowing myself down, let me make haste slowly. One God, one
source. Our Almighty Creator commands us, commands that Quran, specifically Quran,
shall be the only source of religious teachings. Furthermore we are told that
the acceptance of any other sources for religious guidance equals the setting up
of other gods besides God. This is verse 19 of surah 6 and it says, say O
Muhammad whose testimony is greater. God is the witness between me and you that
this Quran by name was given to me to preach it to you and to whomever it
reaches. However you certainly bear witness that you set up other gods
besides God by upholding, this is parenthesis, by upholding other sources
besides Quran. It's obvious from the flow of the words. Say I will never do what
you are doing, I disown your idol worship. So this verse is very clear and we're
going to see more. There is one God, one source. In the strictest possible language
we are commanded to uphold Quran, the whole Quran, and nothing but Quran. I should
qualify this by saying that the Quran implies also referring to the previous
scriptures. In other words, scripture. Repeatedly we are commanded to uphold
Quran as the only source of religious guidance. Again and again we are reminded
that the following of any other source besides Quran equals the setting up of
other gods besides God. This verse in 17:39 says, this is now after a long list of
commandments in surah 17, this verse comes and says this is some of the wisdom
revealed to you in this Quran and you shall not set up any other god beside
God by following any other source besides this source.
Quran, an extraordinary book. Despite the clear commandments, why do the followers of
Hadith and Sunnah fail to uphold Quran alone? The answer is provided in the same
surah following the commandment shown on page 8, previous page. Verses 45 and 46 of
surah 17 inform us that those who refuse to believe God and heed His commandment
to uphold Quran alone, are deliberately isolated from Quran. And this verse
speaks of the Quran alone.
When you preach your Lord in the Quran alone, they run away in aversion. They just
shut up. And you probably experienced that before. Sometimes people walk into
this mosque by mistake. You know you see the word mosque. And they come in here, and
as soon as I mentioned to them the Quran alone, they literally run.
Just like the verse says, they can't stand to talk about the Quran alone.
But this verse says here, says when you read Quran, we place an invisible barrier
between you and those who do not believe in the Hereafter.
And we put shields on their hearts to prevent them from understanding Quran
and deafness in their ears.
And when you mention your Lord alone, now alone here follows the Quran.
When you mention your Lord alone in the Quran alone, the word alone came after Quran.
Quran, the only Quran, the only Quran.
Do you believe God or not? This is verse 38 of surah 6 that says we didn't leave anything out of this book.
And in this verse 114 of surah 6 says God revealed the book to you fully detailed.
I got a letter from Egypt from a hadithist; he was asking me if the Quran is, and he used this word,
he said if the Quran is fully detailed as you say, where do we find the prayer? We're going to deal with this question later on.
So I returned the letter to him and I told him to refer to this verse, because he used the very word
that God uses in the Quran, Mufassalan, meaning fully detailed. This verse says, shall I seek
other than God as a source of wisdom, when He revealed to you this book fully
detailed?
Now the people at the time of the Prophet for example, I'll give you a
question. And have you imagined this? What did they think about the Sun, for example?
Was a new Sun coming out every morning? But they didn't know about the Earth and
the sun and the moon, the information that we know today.
How much knowledge did they have, including the Prophet himself?
What do you think they thought in their mind about every morning the sun comes
from the east and goes in the west? Where is it coming from?
Is it a new sun every morning? Or
what's going on here? Now God created the sun
and the moon and the Earth and the solar system. Did you look at the moon last night?
Did you see the two eyes, the nose and the mouth? Did you see it? Now that's God's sense of humor.
And it provided a lot of poetry for the Arabs across many centuries.
Now, people can think of God as running the world like, now I want you to think of God
when He was designing the moon. Now think, just to bring it to our mind, think of a chairman
of the board sitting at a desk, and this chairman of the board was designing the
moon. The chairman of the board said, let us give the people of Earth a satellite, a
moon that will light their nights at certain times and help them calculate the months.
Because you can calculate exactly the day of the month by looking at the moon,
at the lunar year. And let's put two eyes and a nose and a mouth in this thing.
But the physics of this matter, the moon has to turn around. The moon rotates around itself.
Right? But now how do we make it so the people of the Earth will always see one
side of the moon, that is the face, with the two eyes, the nose and the mouth. So let
us make the rotation of the moon exactly the same speed as the rotation around the Earth.
And I give that demonstration to most of you, as to why we see one side
of the moon. This makes us think of the greatness of God and how He
designed the creation of the heavens and the Earth, and how much wisdom that the
people of that time, of the Prophet Muhammad, how much wisdom did they have?
So we seek that wisdom. I see some of you need a demonstration. Let's make that
demonstration again for those of you who didn't see it.
It's going to go around one time. Let's say this is the side of the moon that you see
every time, all the time. We only see one side of the moon, even though it rotates around
itself. This is the Earth right here, and this is the moon. Now this thing is
going to go around itself exactly one time. But at the same time it's going to go
around the Earth, right? However, because this rotation around itself is exactly
to the second equal to the rotation around the Earth, the people of the Earth
will always see one side. So watch this, here's the moon going around the Earth,
it's a satellite. Now it is going around itself, and going around the Earth
at the same time. See that? So when I did this, here I am in the same place,
and the people of Earth see only one side, the two eyes, the nose, and the mouth.
At the same time, the moon went around itself one time.
Did you see this? Everybody see it?
See right now, I was facing this way, and when I was over there by Barakt,
it was facing that way, and when I went by Miriam, it was facing this way,
when I came to Dr. Mahmoud, it was facing this way, and then it was facing this way.
So it made a complete circle around itself.
We just have to think
of this very minute component in the universe, how God designed the moon for
us. And how He put in two eyes, a nose and a mouth, and the very enigmatic expression
on the moon. You can see the mood, and if you want to see it sad, you see it sad. You want to see
it smiling, you see it smiling. It has a neutral expression. So whatever mood you have,
the moral proof will help you. And this is God's design. So this verse here is
saying, shall I seek other than God as a lawgiver? When He revealed to you this book
fully detailed? So all the wisdom we need is in the Quran. And it would be just stupid to
to go for wisdom, especially to people in the old times. Think of your own grandfather.
I'm not insulting you. Remember how simple he was? And that's our own grandfather.
How much knowledge did he have? Did he have as much as you? Would you go to him for wisdom?
your own grandfather, each one of you has a grandfather.
So let alone going back 1400 years, seeking other than God's wisdom.
This is why God didn't invent all these advances in technology and computers
and airplanes and things until the final scripture came.
So we cannot seek any wisdom from those people, who didn't know much.
Just what did they think of the sun coming out every morning? Can you imagine all the
superstitions, all the stories, the speculations, they had no school. Shall I
seek other than God as a lawgiver when He revealed to you this book fully detailed?
And this verse says the word of the Lord is complete in truth and justice. The
the word in Arabic is tammat, it puts a stamp on it.
It doesn't mean anything else, it cannot be interpreted.
It can only be translated, meaning complete, the word of the Lord is complete
in truth and justice.
So the question here is, do you believe God or not? It's as simple as that.
And God says, if you decide that you don't want to believe me, I'm going to block you out.
This is what the Quran says, we've seen it in the last page I think, yeah.
I'm going to put an invisible barrier.
There's no wall, you don't see it, it's invisible. For the people who decide they
don't want to believe God. That's not enough, God says I'm going to put shields on
their hearts. And in case you miss the meaning of the shield, it says to prevent
them from understanding the Quran. And deafness in their ears, a total block-out.
So the question is, do you believe God or not? This is what you tell them. And not
believing God is disastrous, as you will see.
The consequence of not believing God is that those who refuse to believe my
revelations and are too arrogant to accept them, the gates of heaven will
never open for them nor will they ever enter paradise until the camel goes
through the needle's eye. Now what was the biggest needle you've ever seen?
I guess Diana can tell us about that, she's got lots of needles in her shop.
The biggest needle will not pass a ladybug, a ladybug, just a ladybug, let alone a camel.
So God is saying it's a physical impossibility for people,
it's a physical impossibility for people who refuse to believe God's revelation that the gates of heaven
or the gates of the sky will open for them.
There are more consequences than that.
An important criterion of divine revelation. Some people will tell you Hadith is also
divine revelation, like the Quran. You've probably heard it before. But God gave us a
criterion in Surah 15 verse 9, it says, my message, my final message will be perfectly
preserved. And by their own admissions, the vast majority of Hadith and Sunnah are
false fabrications. They'll admit that, especially if it doesn't agree with them.
Hadith and Sunnah are 100% conjecture.
This verse says, shall I seek other than God as a lawgiver,
when He revealed to you this book fully detailed?
Even the recipients of previous scriptures recognize it as coming from your Lord.
The word of your Lord is complete in truth and justice.
And then it says at the end, if you obey the majority,
they will take you away from the path of God because they follow conjecture.
put an asterisk on it. By their own admission, Hadith and Sunnah are conjecture. They think the
Prophet said that. And we say even if the Prophet said that, we follow only the
wisdom of God. Obeying the messenger is conditional, and this is in the Quran, this
verse here says, O Prophet, if the believing women come to you and pledge
that they will not idolize anything besides God, nor steal, nor commit adultery, nor
kill their children, nor produce any falsehood, nor disobey you when
you are right. Now this is a condition and it's a
negative of disobeying, which means they should disobey when you are not right.
So the Quran is very clear that obeying the Prophet or the messenger is in what
he uttered as Quran, nothing else. Obeying the messenger is conditional or
conditioned. I like this word, but I looked it up in the dictionary and it said
condition equals conditional. So I left it there. This verse says anything good
that happens to you, Muhammad, is from God. And anything bad that happens to you is
from you. So the personal opinion of the Prophet may be bad, and may cause bad
things to happen. On the other hand, Muhammad the messenger
utters only the Quran.
And here is a good example where we are told that the Prophet
fears the people instead of fearing God.
And certainly God doesn't hate the Prophet. Why is He scandalizing him all over the
world through the Quran? Why? God is not scandalizing the Prophet; He is telling us
that he has his actions and his words, and these are his opinions, and he can be
right or wrong. And he is right only if he agrees with the Quran. Therefore you
people take from him only the Quran.
Otherwise, what's the purpose of a verse like this?
Here is a famous example.
Obeying the messenger is conditional.
Now this example is where the Prophet neglected the poor man,
the poor blind person,
and gave his attention to the rich man.
Is this something we're supposed to do?
That's what Sunnah means.
I mean it's not anything that the Prophet would want us to do.
One complete surah illustrates the fact that we are to obey Muhammad only in his Quranic
utterances and not in his personal utterances or personal behavior.
This rules out the so-called Hadith or Sunnah as a legitimate source of religious guidance.
Why is the whole surah, the whole surah is entitled, "He Frowned?"
The whole surah is telling us that he made a mistake.
Why?
He's telling us, don't follow his personal actions.
By the way, at the end it says, "Indeed this is a reminder for those who wish, a reminder
for those who choose to remember."
A reminder of what?
That his personal actions and words may be right, may be wrong.
The idolization of Muhammad.
Well, I think we're running out of time, but this verse says that Muhammad is a human
being like you, and at the end of the verse says do not fall in idol worship.
This is another verse that says Muhammad is a human being like you, and at the end of
the verse says do not fall in idol worship. What a coincidence, both verses
end up saying do not fall in idol worship. Muhammad is a human being like you, do not fall in idol worship. Both of them.
The abuse of the Quran.
This verse here,
إِنَّ اللَّهَ وَمَلَائِكَتَهُ يُصَلُّونَ عَلَى النَّبِيِّ ۚ يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا صَلُّوا عَلَيْهِ وَسَلِّمُوا تَسْلِيمًا
God and His angels encourage the Prophet.
O you who believe, you too shall encourage him and support him completely.
This needs a lot of explanation which I will do later.
But they use this to praise the glory of the Prophet day and night.
And they forget that the word Prophet, the word Nabi in the Quran, almost refers to
the Prophet during his lifetime, when he was alive, not after his death. And then
we're told 13 verses before this that God and His angels make Salat on the
believers, every single one, you and me, if you are believers. God and His angels will
make Salat on us, to take us out of darkness into the light. So I get to this
level, but I have to quit. Also this verse, I just don't know where to quit, but I better quit here,
and maybe when we have enough votes tonight, maybe we can finish this whole
whole thing and explain it in detail and then eventually inshallah we're going to have it
written down in print. So let us turn to God and ask Him to encourage us to stick to His
word alone and to be satisfied with the wisdom of God alone. SubhanAllah.
Alhamdulillah, wa ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah, wahdahu la sharika lah.
Hopefully this book will give you the evidence that you can show anybody.
We're supporting the idea that the program