Alhamdulillah. Ashhadu an la ilaha illa Allah, Wahdahu la sharika lah, wa usalli wa sallim
Last week, and the week before, we went over time, and some of the brothers and sisters were having to catch classes at 1 o'clock, we were a little late, they had to leave.
So I plan to finish by a quarter to 1, inshallah. However, I'm already 5 minutes late. I cheated myself out of 5 minutes.
So, I will try to compress everything in the next half hour.
The problem with most people is unawareness of God, or underestimating the greatness of God.
So, the subject today is awareness.
You look at the people in the streets, see how they are going about their lives, unaware of their Creator.
So we're going to look at a few verses in here to see the importance of being aware.
The first one is in Surah 7, verse 179, page 117, it says,
"We have committed to Hell multitudes of jinn and humans.
They are the ones who have hearts, have minds, but they're minds
that do not understand, eyes that do not see, and ears that do not hear. They are
like animals; no, they're even worse. They are the unaware."
So the people who are unaware are assigned to Hell. They have minds with
which they do not think, they have eyes with which they do not see, and they have
ears with which they do not hear. The next verse is in Surah 10, verse 7.
It says, "Indeed, those who do not expect to meet us, are satisfied and content with
this life, and are heedless of our revelations.
These have deserved Hell as a consequence of their work."
Now, "heedless" or "unaware," it is the same Arabic word, which means they are unaware.
And you notice they are content with this life.
So you look at the majority of people out there on the street,
and they are unaware of their Creator, unaware of the Hereafter,
accountability, and they are busy with this life.
The next verse, 16, 106.
It says,
"Anyone who disbelieves in God after having believed—except for one who is forced while the heart is content with faith—
but whoever willingly opens his heart to disbelief, has incurred wrath from God..."