Latifah, you want to take the line to two?
There's only one Latifah here.
Don't look around.
If you were to obey most of those on earth,
they would divert you from the path of God.
They follow nothing but conjecture,
and they only guess.
They said, "We hear, and we disobey."
Their hearts were filled with adoration of the calf, as a consequence of their disbelief.
disbelief.
Say, "Miserable indeed is what your belief commands you, if you are believers!"
Say, "If the abode of the Hereafter with God is exclusively for you, and not for other people, then long for death, if you are truthful."
But they will never long for it, because of what their hands have sent forth.
God is fully aware of the wrongdoers.
In fact, you will find them the most covetous of life; even more so than the polytheists.
One of them wishes to live a thousand years.
But this will never save him from the retribution,
even if he lives that long. God is Seer of everything they do.
Is what you're saying now right?
Yeah, it is right.
Okay, what I, my only plan here is to make it to the United States.
But I was busy there, so I couldn't make it.
But I was the one who said, "I'm not going to promote it."
I'm going to teach a proof that's going to make it.
But yet, there are some people who disobeyed me.
And yet, um, they feel that what they themselves have done is their own life.
They're already getting down to defeat.
They feel that this here is closer to what they had.
You know, but then they covered up the Word, you know, and some people did it because of gain.
And yet, they got so many followers.
Of course, all of this is because of Satan's trickery itself.
And the man, or people themselves, fell into this trick.
And a lot of them, like the Christians and whatever, they idolize others besides God: the Jews, the Catholics, the Orthodox.
They think that they're going to get into Heaven.
But they're not going to get into Heaven.
They're going to get into Hell, because, um,
Is this what God wanted them to do?
He wanted us to talk to them, and they denied what we said.
And if we talk to them, and if they are really stubborn,
we're supposed to tell them and show them the truth.
To show that what we stand for is real.
You can also let them know, too, that you can see it, because if they were really children of God,
they would learn from that.
Because they want to live forever and ever.
Their silver, and their gold, and their Bible chapters, and their scriptures,
and they want to keep their faith in the grace of God.
Whereas, it's not.
And like us, the messengers, we're all the same.
But I'm talking to people, you know, we long for that.
You know, because we know that the appointed day is coming.
And we know, right now, that we have the truth.
And yet, we couldn't dare tell anybody else that he is going to go.
Even though we know we have the truth.
And this is the proof of the mission.
And yet, they're running from it.
And they come to you and give you excuses.
They lie to me and they try to attack me.
That's my understanding.
That's beautiful. You touched on a very important point of proof, you know.
When people come to you and say anything,
you make a statement, Jesus is the Son of God.
Why do you say that? Do you have proof? Are you sure?
If you prove it to me, I'd be glad to believe it.
But the difference is that we have proof.
That's a big difference.
And then too, like you said though, a lot of times, like,
you know, I try to give out as much as possible, even more than that.
But then, when I talk to people, I find that a lot of times they doubt it.
They try to knock it and debate it. You know, they say, oh, yeah.
You know, a lot of times, that's scary.
I get excited because I know that it's not just people talking to each other.
You know, it could be one of the jinn that take over.
They talk to each other. I can hear it. I can hear it in my brain.
I can't tell it's people. That's what I'm saying.
And so therefore, you know, when I related it,
they go, wow, yeah, you know. And I would think a lot of people would still come to me
and see a lot of people cry. And then when it comes down to
Okay, I'm back in my conviction.
Okay, what's it going to do?
You know how it is in the air?
You know what I'm saying?
So, like, you know, they're putting the message out.
They're going to send it on the air.
They're going to send it.
Everything else, the stuff that's in the soul,
comes to the god of the air.
The air is actually doing it.
And they're going to go home and sell it.
It comes to the god of the air.
Okay, we did the job, yeah?
And then God knows whether they deserve to be guided or not.
Yeah.
Okay then, that's that.
Two, ninety-seven.
Say, anyone who opposes Gabriel
should know that he revealed the scripture
confirming the previous scriptures,
and a guidance and good news
for the believers.
Anyone who opposes God, his angels, his messengers,
Gabriel and Michael,
should know that God opposes the unbelievers.
We have revealed to you profound revelations, and only the wicked reject them.
Was it not a fact that whenever they made a covenant, some of them would violate it?
Indeed, most of them do not believe.
And when a messenger came to them from God confirming their own scripture,
some of those who were given the previous scriptures disregarded this new scripture,
as if they did not know.
So, that's an important piece of information.
Why do I feel like I just skipped a part of it?
I guess I don't understand the difference between the whole thing.
So Jibreel is... It means, you know, Christ's helper?
You mean who Gabriel is, then?
Yeah.
He came to Mary.
Right.
He told her about the coming of Christ.
Yeah.
Right.
Thank you.
So this tells us that Gabriel's function is to mediate revelations between God and the Messengers.
And this happened since Adam.
This is the one who carried revelations to Adam, to Noah, to Mary, to Jesus, to Moses.
Well, God spoke directly with Moses.
But there are instances where Gabriel also was involved.
This is his job.
I was just wondering,
you know,
maybe a rebellion
or something.
You think,
right,
Gabriel took
Azrael's place there,
right?
Yes,
you know.
No,
not necessarily.
Repeat that.
No,
I was saying like,
okay,
how do you say that
Azrael's not
The archangel?
Okay,
but there were
many archangels.
Also,
Satan was kicked out
before the
revelations, before the human
beings were on earth.
Right?
So, that was not one of his functions.
Okay, but it was my understanding,
was he the only one?
I was thinking he was the only one
who defied.
No, no, no. It was many.
There were millions.
Probably millions. Billions.
Okay.
Yeah.
Did the angels then reveal the scripture on their own initiative or was it an order from God?
It's an order from God, and it was just transmitted, because it's one of the transmission methods of the message, the Quran.
Moses is the only one that God spoke to directly, I mean, the only one mentioned as spoken to in the Quran, anyway.
But these are the words of God. The Quran is the word of God, and Gabriel is
told to go and release them from Muhammad's heart.
But Muhammad was summoned to the highest horizon, and the Quran was in his heart.
Like you and I, everybody, each one of us has in his heart, or her heart, the knowledge
that God is the Master, the Lord. Satan is the renegade.
We all met God, all of us, before we were born.
But because of this body, we don't remember.
And the same way, Muhammad had the Quran in his heart,
exactly the same way.
But he needed God to come and release it to his mouth
from inside.
So for that knowledge that you have about meeting God
to come to the surface,
you need the test to have ended,
or you need to die, get rid of the body.
So, Gabriel was just transmitting the words of God, orders from God, letter by letter.
Why don't we remember that?
Because the body obscures that knowledge.
Do you remember your meeting with God?
That initial one, at the creation of the heavens and the earth, where God said,
"Am I not your Lord?"
And we all said, "Yes, we bear witness."
And God said, "Now you cannot claim on the Day of Judgment that you never heard of me."
That's what the Quran said.
But we don't remember that because of this body.
And the Quran was in Muhammad's heart in the same way.
So, Gabriel's function was to release the Quran.
So, what we just read there is a piece of information telling us that Gabriel mediated the release of the Quran.
We have a whole bunch of angels with us, each one of us. We have two of them, at least.
Two of them that stay on the right and on the left side. What do you think they are used for then?
Oh, they do all kinds of things.
They'll wake you up for Fajr prayer, don't they?
You know, I don't know.
They'll do all kinds of things when they really get familiar with you.
They pinch you to wake you up. I mean pinch.
They push you off the bed sometimes.
They will speak to you, they will knock on your door.
She's shaking her head.
They'll knock on the door.
When she gets out of bed, opens the door, there's nobody there.
But it's time for Fajr prayer.
They'll speak to you.
They did it to me once. I was sleeping in bed and I always sleep with the radio on next to me. I always like to have the radio on.
And then the Fajr prayer time came, and I got up very sleepy and very tired. I was really especially tired that night.
So after I stood up next to bed I said, oh I'm going to sleep again for maybe a half hour.
Just as I was going to sit down, in an Egyptian accent, a purely Egyptian, the word was
"Ew'a," means, "Don't you dare." "Ew'a terga' tani?" Ew'a. Ew'a. "Don't you go back again?" You know, I really wanted to, so I looked around.
And I thought maybe the radio was on. It was saying one word, but it was off.
It was very clear, loud and clear, "don't you go back to sleep."
You can imagine what happened after that.
And then whenever they do it, you're never afraid, you're never scared, it's very nice.
Doesn't matter what they do, you're never scared.
It is never a frightening experience, if anything, it's an exalting experience.
I'm sure quite a few of you, somehow, open up their eyes just at Fajr time, right? And
they're given the impression this is the time to pray.
That, I urge you to do that.
We go to surah 13, this will talk about this subject.
I'll give you the verse number, right?
I know, it's here.
Surah Thirteen?
Surah Thirteen.
Yeah, the angels take turns.
Is it 11?
Right, there we go.
Yeah, verse 11, each of you, that's you and me, each of you has a succession of angels
in front of you and behind you, who guard you in accordance with God's decision.
So you have angels around you who make sure that nothing happens to you except exactly
what is to happen to you.
It is just amazing, what is supposed to happen to you has to happen. And yet, it all
depends on your decisions and what you do.
And I have to tell you this story, it shows you exactly how it happened.
I had a friend who was talking about marijuana.
Marijuana.
I don't know how we got on the subject.
Oh, I was walking down the alley there and I saw high school kids at the corner there.
They were smoking.
And marijuana. Smoking.
And I smelled it. It's not cigarettes.
So I came near. Not that way. I didn't sniff that hard.
So I mentioned to my friend that it smells nice. And the friend said, yeah, that stuff is good.
Or something like that, something that is false.
So I said, well, expect a sting.
And if God doesn't like it, He says it's toxic, it's haram, it's prohibited.
And if God doesn't like it, you're not supposed to like it, or even praise it, or say anything
nice about it.
So you have to expect a sting.
And I wasn't, I felt like preaching.
You know, I took a lesson about this, that I held back.
That was my, it was a mistake on my part.
I felt that I was not doing justice to the subject, when I really should have.
Now, then that same day, the two of us, same two people, were starting a heater in one of the apartments.
I couldn't. And I was lighting the pilot. The pilot was not lighting, but all of a sudden
I heard the hissing of the gas. The hissing of the gas came in. Now, I'm not boasting,
but I'm not really dumb, you know. I know that if I strike a match, there's going to be
an explosion. But it was as if I was completely hypnotized. And I lit the match anyway.