The root is ra'a. You see, it's 'to see' in some way, because when you are watching
sheep, you are also seeing, isn't it?
For instance, that has been done deliberately, you see. But there are a few occasions mentioned, even in
the history of Islam, the Jews used to make fun of the Muslims; they would get some Arabic
word used by the Muslims and then pronounce it in such a way that it becomes bad, the
opposite.
It happens to us, I think, you know, when we speak another language and so on.
It's like, I remember out in Indonesia, because sometimes you use a word you think is good, but it is not a good word at all.
If you say it there, then they would laugh, you know, in Yogyakarta. It means something very, very
bad. Then they would laugh. And I let it go.
But yeah, that happens.
That happens.
Some word has a good meaning in one language, but a bad meaning in another language.
Especially if not pronounced well and so on. And this is a moral scripture;
you are not supposed to fool around with these terms.
And the second word, it doesn't...
The second word, yeah, go ahead.
I don't know what the issue is, because, you know, you can read that in the phrase.
phrase.
It's vicious.
Because we're saying that.
But this is not a black and white issue.
So it's more like, you know, can we actually walk up to Jews and Christians and say...
Yeah, I think I have that because it's pointing to 4:46, the footnote.
4:46. There is a footnote in there
that
Ra'ina sounded like a lewd word
in the Hebrew language.
And some Hebrew speakers
believe in that.
You know,
she's saying what I'm saying,
and all I asked was,
when I'm doing my personal prayers,
can I use
the word
Unthurna
in English?
Oh, that's...
That's all right.
Watch out.
That's okay.
That's because it's here.
And it's not here.
And you're asking, "Why can't I do that?"
So, you understand the point I'm making.
I think, well, she's gone.
She's going home.
Yes, you are relating 105 with 101; 101 refers to the Jews.
Because their concept of being "the chosen people" was very exclusive, and they denied the idea that others would also receive revelation. But then God says He specifies His mercy for whomever He wills, and God is Possessor of Infinite Bounty.
That is "Dhu al-Fadl al-'Adhim," and this is explained in this part, that He specifies His
mercy; He chooses whom He desires to help, and so on.
106 is a very delicate verse.
There is a long history to this, because there have been two groups of people.
And the enemies of the Qur'an have interpreted one of the extremes to mean that this abrogation
is abrogation of Qur'anic verses.
Now I have to be very careful about this.
This is the theory of an-Nasikh wal-Mansukh; naskh, to abrogate, and mansukh, that some verses of
the Qur'an abrogate other verses of the Qur'an.
Now, this runs against the idea from the Qur'an that the Qur'an is consistent, contains no
crookedness, and so on.
Now, if we accept that the Qur'an is consistent, then you cannot have a verse that corrects
another verse.
Therefore, the meaning of this would be the following, the second which I think is the
more reliable meaning: that the Qur'an supersedes the former scriptures.
For example, where there was a prohibition on something in the old scriptures, the Qur'an says
it is now permitted. For example, the prohibition of certain foods among the Jews.
The Qur'an, you know, says, "Forget that."
The idea of intercourse
at night during the
month of Ramadan; in the old days,
that was prohibited,
and now it is allowed.
So, in that sense,
the Qur'an has verses
which supersede
former verses,
or rather, it supersedes verses
of former scriptures.
I think that is the only
possible
meaning.
It is not one verse of the Qur'an correcting another verse, but it is a verse of the Qur'an
superseding the provisions of former scriptures.
Because the Qur'an is consistent; there is no error in it, and so on.
So if one wants to remain a Christian, and on some issue, he has to follow the Bible, right?
And he follows those verses that are found in the Bible.
And if he follows the way of the Bible on that matter,
it is applicable or right for him, right?
It is no sin. Yes. No, no. It is Christian.
Christian. Yeah, that is considered the Christian way.
Yeah, in that sense.
But if you want to remain a Christian or follow the Bible...
The answer is in 5:48.
Five?
Do you want to hear the quote?
We are proceeding. Do you want to hear?
5:48 says,
"Then We revealed to you this scripture truthfully, confirming all the previous scriptures,
and superseding them.
You shall judge among them in accordance with this scripture,
and follow not their opinions instead of the truth that has come to you.
We have decreed statutes and methods for each of you. If God had willed,
He would have made you one congregation. So, if this person wants to
remain a Christian, he's supposed to follow the laws of Christianity. If he wants to remain a Jew,
he has to follow the laws of the Jews. And it's quite clear in the Arabic text; I hope it is as clear in English.
The point here is, We have decreed statutes and methods—method means method for prayer, method for worship, method for dieting—for each of you."
If this Christian would now follow this Quran, which is superseding, then he would become a Muslim.
Right.
And that is what is happening in this country.
Yeah.
This is how millions have become Muslims.
That's right.
I'm sure there are a lot of systems that are really prescribed for the Jews themselves.
So one of them is the law of Tabernacles as a law, right?
About,
for example,
they don't have to make a hut, right?
Not that I know of,
but if they go into the hut,
what happens?
They have to see through the roof.
They have to make a hut.
And they,
they don't have to do the Friday prayer.
It is a religion.
I think you may, you might find some basis
if you go back to the Old Testament,
because that, as you know,
when the Temple was built,
everybody from all over the country, all the Jews had to go there once a year.
It was part of the ritual that was established during the time of Solomon and David.
There's a verse in the Quran that says there was a pilgrimage in the older religions.
When Moses wanted to marry a daughter of this man, he said, "You can marry her; the dowry is that you work for me for eight pilgrimages (Hajj)."
Meaning eight years, because the pilgrimage (Hajj) happens at a specific time every year.
I mean, because there are
parables in there about
wine. But I mean, if you look
at it, you know, you know,
in the Quran, once you read that parable, you'll
see that it's really a parable.
And they take it literally. You know, just like they tell us here that we will drink wine
in Paradise. But the Bible says specifically that wine is not good. Yeah, but I mean, what they're
taking is a parable that's in the text. You can't take it literally. Then you see here, Jesus said...
Yeah, but it's the, you know, wine is not the only intoxicant.
It didn't say only wine!
Take the case of pork. The Christians nowadays, they don't follow the Mosaic law about not eating pork.
But they claim it's abrogated by a particular statement in the New Testament itself.
Yeah, they claim. They eat it.
The Bible also prohibits pork. And they use it.
I don't know of any worse
to prohibit
well it's
it just
yeah
you can understand it then
you know but
I mean it's not stated directly
whereas there is a parenthetical statement
that says you know
something that Jesus said
I can't remember the precise one
what goes into the mouth
is not what's unclean but what comes out
of it is unclean
and then parenthetically, in all the Bibles
I've seen, the statement is put in parentheses
explaining that by this
statement, he made all food
permissible.
I mean, it's in there. I mean, you pick up any Bible
and it's in parentheses.
And people take that as a little
part of the scripture.
That's an editorial bit.
But this is in the New Testament where he cast
the demons into the herd.
I mean, because if the pigs were permissible, why would he destroy
some of these private properties?
The pigs belonged to somebody.
They ruined something, economically, when they were all drowned.
We were reading what it says about racing with people in righteous works.
What does that mean?
Well, people like us.
Okay.
Outdoing each other in religious works?
Outdoing each other?
Well, even with them, that's what we're doing.
It's the kind of competition that increases the good relation, the affection instead of
hatred.
I think Karim has still a few videos.
Yeah, there you go.
Well, they always had demands. You know, for instance, when they were told to sacrifice a heifer,
they said what kind, what color, this and that, and then when they moved to Sinai, they
said, "We don't like manna and quail, we need onions and lentils and beans."
They always had demands.
Yeah, remember that's why they worshipped the calf.
Yes, in fact they said, "Make an idol for us, make a god for us like these people have done."
Yeah, so maybe this is the kind of demand that is a lesson for us.
A good example of this is the Senate, the Arizona Senate that wants to introduce a bill
He was talking about teaching creation in Arizona schools, and he was very enthusiastic and was having a lot of news conferences.
And then I sent him my booklet on creation, which had the physical evidence from the computer.
And after he received that, he sent me a thank-you note, and then that was the last we ever heard of his attempt to talk about creation,
because they don't want non-Christian teachings.
This is just the way people believe.
So, it's like Samson.
You know, "Upon me and upon my enemies."
So he doesn't want his creation bill to go through,
because this may let the people know about this faith.
Jim Cooper, you know.
So, they would rather see us go back to become pagans,
It bothers them when the people watch it in the dark, you know.
And then we tell them, we're not watching it in the dark, we're watching it in the deep.
So, it's a formidable sign.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt you.
No, please go on, my friend.
Oh.
Please, please start explaining.
Oh, oh, oh, excuse me.
Please go ahead.
What?
What? What do you want me to do?
I don't know if you can hear it or not, but I think it's going to be the voice of God in a few minutes.
And that's the message that's going to come out today.
It's going to show you that we are not alone.
We are blessed to know that God can help you out of this.
And I want to make sure that you can hear that.
And I want to make sure that you can imagine that God can help you out of this.
Thank you.
Yes.
We'll take the Quran.
We're at 2:111.
Do you want me to take over?
Yeah.
We will go to Submission.
We will start with this.
They said, "No one will enter Heaven
unless he is Jewish or Christian."
Such is their wishful thinking.
Say, "Show us your proof
if you are truthful."
I think we are the lucky generation
that
This is the end of the era of religion where we have no physical proof.
And this is what we have from now on, we have to apply this principle,
It's a commandment: Say, produce your proof.
You say Jesus is God? What? Show me your proof.
You say Jesus is the Son of God, what is your proof?
I have physical proof that Jesus did not die.
The true identity of Jesus happens to be in Surah 19, which has the most powerful code.
It has five letters in front of it. You want to go look at Surah 19? Look at the beginning of Surah 19.
See the first verse, page 206, K.H.Y.'A.S.
And when you add up these letters in this chapter, their total is 798, which is divisible by 19.
And this is the chapter, in fact, that describes the true identity of Jesus, who he is.
And we have, inshallah, our next book will be based on this chapter, in fact, Jesus and the Truth.
And we're going to describe Jesus, his miracles, his life, and the story of the crucifixion.
Because he was not crucified.
So in February or March or so, now we have the visual presentation of the miracles.
And we're going to have a book, Quran, Hadith, and Islam.
The Arabic version of the visual presentation of the Quran came to the community in Arabic.
And the Arabic book also. And then, the next project will be Jesus and the Truth.
So in that book, we will be able to present proof to them of the identity of Jesus.
so they said no one will enter heaven
unless they are Jewish or Christian.
Like we said repeatedly before,
if you go to any group of
any religion and they tell you this is the only group
that's going to heaven,
you better leave right away. It's a fraud.
Because God will not
will not restrict
His mercy to a group of
Muslims,
or Christians, or Jews, Hindus, or what?
God's mercy will encompass anyone who worships God alone.
Who recognizes God.
The One who created the heavens and the earth.
Now people say, I believe in God, and in their mind, God is Jesus.
Then they are wrong.
Because Jesus did not create the heavens and the earth.
So when they worship God alone,
they have in mind the omnipotent, omniscient creator of the universe.
The one who runs every minute detail in the universe.
And that's not Jesus, or Mary, or Muhammad, or any of the others.
So God says here, "Say, show us your proof, if you are truthful."
Indeed, whoever submits to God.
Notice it doesn't say any Muslim who submits to God.
It says, whoever submits to God.
You can be a Buddhist, for all that you know. A Buddhist who grew up as a Buddhist,
and then he came to a conclusion that the only one to be worshipped is God, who
created this universe. If that person submits to God, and he will be taken care of, God
will inspire him to make Ruku' and Sujud, on their own, by instinct. God will
teach them to make prostrations, and to be righteous. Whoever submits to God while leading
a righteous life, have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
And the Jews said, the Christians have no basis, and the Christians said, the Jews
have no basis, though both of them read the scripture. Those who possess no knowledge
have uttered similar utterances. God will judge them on the Day of Resurrection
regarding their dispute. Who is more evil than one who forbids others from attending
the mosques of God wherein His name is commemorated, and seeks to have them deserted?
These ought not to enter therein except fearfully.
These have deserved humiliation in this life, and terrible retribution in the hereafter.
Now, every time you see the word God here, you should bear in mind that it is God alone.
If you remember the first commandment in Submission, is to believe in God.
And this means believing God alone.
That only He is to be worshiped.
To God belong the East and the West.
Now this is verse 114, it is very important, we must encourage rather than discourage attending the mosques.
There are many commandments in Quran that tell us to stick together,
because God inspires us as a group, through one of us, and we learn a lot.
And verse 114 shows that who is more evil than one who forbids others from attending the mosques of God.
That's the maximum evilness.
So this is all we do here in this mosque.
We commemorate the name of God.
We study His word.
because we want to follow what God wants
so now who is more evil
than forbidding them?
Now, verse 115,
we touched
on this before.
Wherever you turn,
there is the face of God.
God is Omnipresent, Omniscient.
They said, "God has begotten a son!"
Glory be to Him.
Nay, to Him belongs everything in the heavens and the earth;
all are subservient to Him.
He is the Initiator of the heavens and the earth.
Whenever He decrees a matter,
He only says to it, "Be," and it is.
Those who do not know
said, "If only God could speak to us,
or a miracle come to us, we would then believe."
Thus did those before them say
the same utterances; their hearts are similar.
We have made the revelations clear for people who have attained
certainty. We have sent you with the truth as a
bearer of good news and a warner. You are not
answerable for the dwellers of Hell. Neither the Jews nor the Christians will accept you
unless you follow their religion. Say, "God's guidance is the true guidance." And if you
ever acquiesce to their wishes, after the knowledge has come to you, you will find no one to help
you against God. Those to whom we have given the scripture and read it as it should be read, will believe in it.
As for those who disbelieve in it, they are the losers.
O Children of Israel, remember the blessings I bestowed upon you, and that I set you apart from all the worlds.
Be aware of the Day when no soul can avail another, no ransom will be accepted, nor will any intercession be useful.
Well, my understanding is already that God is everywhere, but then when He says "to the East and
the West." And I know there's the East and West. And then somewhere else where God says, "I'm the God of the
two Easts and the two Wests." You know, that's kind of... but it doesn't make a difference, you know.
You know that in a new work, they have the, you know, some of the people move on to explaining with graphs for people.
As to the two Easts, there's one interpretation, that is that the two Easts
are the east of the sun and the east of the moon.
The moonrise and the sunrise, and the moonset and the sunset.
Because in Arabic, the place of sunrise is also called the East.
I don't know why they call it the East.
Yeah.
Well that's a
not acceptable interpretation,
that's it.
But wherever you may turn,
you are in the presence of God.
Wherever you turn, it is up to
the presence of Him, and God is everywhere.
That He is omnipresent is the essence of our submission.
Can you put this in the form of a question?
No, I was going to say, as you said
in all of these translations, you said
if the sun rises at a point, and then at the winter solstice it rises at a different point, so in between those points, that's what he has in his footnotes, that's what he's saying, that's what it appears to be.
The sun's rising point varies from one...
Actually, the sun rises from a different point every day.
Well, he's saying in between all of that. I think that's what he was saying.
There is another verse where it is "Lord of the East and West," and "Lord of the two Easts and the Lord of the two Wests."
That's what he's saying in those verses.
Yeah.
Yeah, there are other verses.
There are also East and West all over the universe.
If you are, when you go to the moon, there's an earthrise.
Did you take a picture of the earthrise yet?
Yeah, I haven't seen it yet.
I don't know.
Can you send this kind of message to her?
No.
You can keep those two girls apart.
Let's keep them apart
so we can have a conversation.
Verse 116.
They said, "God has begotten a son."
Glory be to Him.
That right there is the greatest blasphemy.
And then the Christians, or whoever believes in Jesus Christ being the son of God, they
also give glory to him, which is a praise that they should be giving to God.
And I hear God saying, "Nay," which is no. "To Him belongs all, everything in the heavens and on
earth, and all are in service to Him," saying that everything in the heavens and the earth
and everything between them belongs to God alone, and all are in service to
Him, and to Him alone. And if you find anybody else or a spirit or anything else that's a partner
with Him, then you are out of it. And that's it. And also, you can ask yourself, when Christians
and other people who believe that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, if they would just ask
themselves this couple of questions, as to, you know, where was God? You know?
So he was once a baby, helpless, you see, and who made the earth and all that kind of stuff? He was a baby. What was he then?
First of all, they say
He had to give His son for our sins, which means He is unable to forgive. That's a
blasphemy in itself.
If God wants to forgive the world, why can't He forgive the world? Why does He have to
give up His son?
Second, they see Him as a helpless father. Any one of us would hate to see it when somebody
tortures their son or their children.
.
So they see God as a helpless
entity.
And all of these ideas are so blasphemous
that again, at the end of Surah 19,
I will request you again
to go back to that Surah
about Mary and Jesus,
Surah 19 at the end.
This is the most
descriptive,
the most descriptive verses about the sonship
of Jesus,
on the great blasphemy.
They say,
"The Most Gracious has begotten a son." Indeed, you have uttered a gross blasphemy.
The heavens are about to shatter, the earth is about to burst, and the mountains are about to crumble upon hearing such a claim.
It is not befitting for the Most Gracious that He should take a son.
Every single one in the heavens and the earth is no more than a servant of the Most Gracious.
He has counted every single one of them, and each will come before Him as an
individual on the Day of Resurrection. So you can see how the description of the blasphemy is,
the mountains are about to crumble apart, just blow up in the air, from a statement like that.
That's why every time the Quran repeats this claim, it is followed by Subhanallah.
to come and love the Lord Jesus Christ.
What's your love for the Lord Jesus Christ?
Okay, so
being there like me,
we talk to people, I can ask them all
stuff, you know,
questions like that.
So, you know,
sometimes we can even
ask
if he needed a
perfect man or
a servant of God
and not God himself.
And if God wanted to have
what he did, as a lot of
Christians and a lot of people say that Jesus Christ
in the name of
Jesus Christ,
he didn't say he was going to
be reborn
and do all kinds of things.
Again, that's saying that
God himself can't do it by
himself. If he needed someone
that's a disgrace.
He's a little proud man.
And they make it like he can do all the work.
Where he really, you know, they put him up with God.
And a lot of people are saying that, and it's not giving God any credit.
And then they really look at it as, you know, God is all powerful, which they know that.
You know, you can say it's big.
And it is.
But then, you know, like they did with Jesus. You know, He said, 'Be,' and it was. And people overlook all those signs and things because they take this life as the only life that they're going to ever have.
And so everything that they hear, and everything that comes by, they take it as truth.
When it's not.
It makes you realize that this is a time for us to try to get with God and recognize Him and submit to Him fully.
Without becoming best friends to the devil, where all he wants is to prey on you, and his promise is to doom you.
And this is not the real life.
I mean, you know, a lot of people, when they come into a belief, and one of these is believing in God, like you said, they interpret different interpretations, because to me, God is God. But to other people, God may be Jesus Christ, or God may be Mary, or God may be their mother, or father, or husband, or their children, you know. They interpret it as different things.
And so when you come into dealing with God, you've got to commit totally to Him if you want things to be for you and then He wants to take care of you in the real life.
So you can't go around believing that Jesus Christ is God.
And you can't go around believing that Jesus Christ is God because he has no part.
The only part he played was to come and deliver the message and show people what they can do if they believe and worship God alone.
And this is why my understanding is, that in the end, God don't need nobody.
He's not God, and that's all he was, Jesus Christ. Even though we all love him and respect him for what he did.
He's dead and he's gone. And he's gotta worry about his case, and we all have to worry about ours.
You only need to visualize what will happen at the Day of Resurrection where people will actually go to Jesus.
I tell you, you mean you're not going to save us?
What are you talking about? I have to answer for myself.
I'm with you, you know, we're all in this crowd, we're all here for God.
So, you have a question?
They say that Jesus saw God.
Good question. A very good question.
The people, you know, when they hear things like that,
they need to ask themselves,
you know, like the story that Jesus Christ went through a wall, appeared in a small room, and sat down there.
I mean, and you know that everything from the moon, the stars, the birds, the powerful forces, all the different colors of our skins, are signs and proofs.
And then Jesus Christ was the only one who saw Him? When the mountain crumbled to dust and all that?
And Jesus Christ, who couldn't, you know, stand watch for an hour or so at this time, and yet he can see God?
Even if He saw God, if He was the most perfect creature, He's still a creature, He's still a man.
And if He did see God, it's only because of God's grace that God allowed Him to see Him.
And this doesn't make him any different from any one of us.
We must believe that we are all capable of being like him, or better than him.
We have that capability.
Yeah, but we didn't. I mean, we don't want to go away from the truth.
The fact is that the Quran doesn't mention any of his sins or any mistakes, so he could have been sinless.
Or maybe the Quran just didn't mention any of his sins, if he did sin.
Whether he was sinless, whether he was perfect, whether he saw God, or he didn't see God,
it all doesn't make any difference.
But the truth is, there's only one God, and one true God.
And we mustn't think that Jesus is God.
He is a human, a frail man, and he is dead.
So if he's dead,
then he can't help anybody.
We must forget about anyone else
as a helper. Muhammad or Jesus
or Mary or a saint or anyone.
We must forget them.
It's what they want. It's what God wants.
It's the only way we can
be saved. And Satan's
job is to inject
other names besides God.
We need it.
Yeah? I have a question about
when you show us a proof
from the scripture on Jesus,
after the crucifixion.
And...
And, when you talk about the story of Jesus, the main point that they make is that he was resurrected, that he didn't die. So, how do I answer that he was not resurrected?
What is the proof?
Well, they will show you the Bible and say that's the proof.
You cannot hang your salvation on a story. You have to have proof.
But there's nothing in the Quran about a resurrection of Jesus.
There is something about him being raised; he was raised to God before the crucifixion, but there
is no resurrection of the body.
The body was left on the cross and was buried, the body doesn't belong to you anymore, once
you leave it, it's like you took off a shirt and threw it away.
But what about that part in the Bible about him rising up and going and seeing the disciples afterwards?
that's you know the scholars say that's added on to the scripture because originally all the gospels
only went up to the fact that the stone was gone from the from the grave and then there's the
the one that's added on in some of the Bibles, put it, you know, like in italics, because
it's the, you know, there's, you know, they admit it, but they don't know that that's
part of the effect.
Not only, I mean, this is, this can be considered a divine sense of humor, because every time
they play in the Bible, there's a scandalous exposure of that play. For example, when they
they played with Abraham's son, who was being supposed to be sacrificed, they
made him Isaac instead of Ishmael. But you see the contradiction very deeply,
when it says Ishmael was born to Abraham, and 14 years later
Isaac was born to Abraham. And then they say, God said to Abraham, take your only
son, and then they inserted Isaac, and sacrificed him. But Isaac was never the
only son. So it's a very clear mistake. And the same thing happened with this resurrection
business. They said he stayed in the grave how long?
Three days.
Three days. But when you look, when you read the details, it's really 48 hours.
Not even that much.
Not even 48 hours.
It's about 6 o'clock on Saturday.
Friday.
Oh, Friday.
Did they crucify him on Friday?
Yeah, okay, but it went down at sunset before the Sabbath, right?
Right.
Okay, yeah.
Okay, so 6 o'clock on the Friday night till before 6 o'clock on Sunday night.
Which makes it less than 48 hours.
18 hours.
No.
24, 30 hours.
I can't, man.
Get the calculator.
Anyway, it's nowhere near the three days that they are making, they don't correct it.
I mean, even now in the 20th century, enlightened priests and ministers will stand in the pulpit
and say, and he stayed in the grave three days and three nights.
But if you read the Bible, you'll find out it's not even two days.
And this is always the case, because the people who played in the Bible were great, great,
great-great-grandparents of ours, who, I'm not insulting you when I say, think of your
own grandfather, you know, and how simple-minded he was. All of them. Those grandparents who
Look at what happened with 19, because in the last 50 years, there was an information explosion.