Alhamdulillah, wa ashhadu an la ilaha illa Allah, wahdahu la sharika lah. This first khutbah will link up with the khutbahs that Din Mahmoud has been giving us and before I start I would like to draw your attention to something that you probably take for granted and that is
here is a mosque that advocates the worship of God alone. I know that God
sent Moses to preach La ilaha illa Allah as we know in Surah 21, and not to preach
the glorification of Moses. And God sent Jesus to preach the worship of God alone,
La ilaha illa Allah, and not to preach the glorification of Jesus. And God sent
Muhammad to preach the worship of God alone, and not to preach the
glorification of Muhammad or anyone else, just worshipping God alone. In this mosque we
advocate the worship of God alone, and we follow the Quran to the letter. We came
to call this mosque the University of God, because it is the most important
education, and we have been very fortunate in seeing the truth of the
Quran and sticking to every letter of it. The University of God, the most important
education, lacked official professorship. So you can see from God's vantage point
he said, "Well, these people are advocating the worship of me alone, God alone, and
they need a professor. So let's send them a professor." So God appoints a couple of
angels to go and hunt for the best professor on earth. And he gets us not
only a professor, but a dean of the Islamic Institute in the Philippines.
Now he doesn't know why he is here in Tucson.
All he knows is, he sat down in Tucson, he got stuck to the Masjid
and he's teaching us, bless his heart, and he's been teaching us about Adam and Eve
and the sin of Adam and Eve. And we've been enjoying his teaching, so we have an
official, not just any professor, the dean himself. So an official school, so we
don't lack officials. What Din Mahmoud has been teaching us the last few khutbahs
was about the sin of Adam and Eve. What was the sin of Adam and Eve? They
ate from the tree, that's what they did. And because they ate from the tree, they
do not qualify to continue in Jannah, in heaven, paradise, the kingdom of God.
Because they ate from the tree, they committed one sin. What does this teach
us? What do we learn from this important lesson? We learn that you cannot go to
Jannah with one sin. If you have one sin in your record, you do not qualify to go to Jannah.
Sounds difficult, but for the people who worship God alone, it is not difficult at all, because
there are two ways of wiping out the sins from your record. And this means nobody will
see them, you will not see them in the record, if you fulfill these two requirements. But
the thing we must learn from Din Mahmoud's lessons in the past, that Adam's and Eve's
sin is they ate from the tree, they were kicked out, because they committed one sin.
Therefore we learn from this that we cannot go to heaven with one sin on our record, not
one.
If you commit one sin and you have it in your record, then you die, you cannot go to heaven.
You must be absolutely sinless. Because when Adam and Eve ate from the tree, they
didn't commit murder, they ate from the tree. That's all they did. God told them you go
in heaven and eat from anything you want but not this one tree. They ate from the
tree and they were kicked out. And this is exactly what we're doing here on
this earth. We are here to be tested and to end this life without a single sin in
your record, otherwise you do not qualify to join the Kingdom of God, you do not
qualify to enter Jannah. Now how do we, what are the ways of erasing sin from
your record? This is one thing you must remember, you must never forget, that our goal is to end
this life without a single sin.
How can we do that?
The first method of erasing sin is tawbah, repentance.
That's one thing.
You turn to God and you say, I'm sorry I made a mistake, I will never do it again, I pledge,
I will never do it again, I repent.
repent, I'm sorry, I apologize, all the words of apology that you can muster, and you
pledge solemnly that you will not do it again, that's one way. What if your
repentance is not accepted? There comes the second way, the second way is to pay for it.
The first way to erase sins is Tawbah, repentance, the second way is to pay for
them here in this world, and they are very expensive, I'm telling you. I would
like to put a dollar value on the sins, and how you pay for them here in this
world. Now as a believer you will pay in material things, thank God, you don't pay
with your arm or your leg, just look around this mosque, you don't see anyone with one arm or one leg,
Alhamdulillah. You have to say Alhamdulillah every time. But, you will, when I put
material values on it, it seems like the punishment is out of proportion for the
sin. But you have to pay for it, unless you want it on your record. If you
have one sin on your record, you cannot go to Jannah.
People go and commit adultery, and they think it's a simple matter, when marriage is really
a simple matter, if you have a relationship with another person, you might as well want
to suggest marriage.
Very simply, two witnesses, you call Allah, you declare that you're married, but if you
fall into adultery, my dollar value on it is $10,000. You have to pay, in misery or
if you don't have the $10,000 it will be a problem. The payment for sins seems to be
out of proportion in this world, but really it isn't, it's a tremendous mercy.
So the believers are the only people who enjoy certain problems in this world
because they know they are paying for, and wiping out certain sins. The
believer does not get away with sins in this world, he has to pay for them. The
disbeliever doesn't either, except with the disbeliever the punishment continues
in the Hereafter. With the disbeliever, the punishment also comes in this world,
but he or she cannot make the connection. He will appear to
get away with sin. And then after years, months, after a time where the
person cannot connect the punishment to the sin, bang! They get hit. So the two
ways to erase sins are repentance and paying for them. These are the only two ways.
There's one sin, not sin, it's not even a sin, there's one offense that cannot be
forgiven. The only unforgivable offense, I will let you open the Quran, now reach
for your Quran, and get Surah 39 verse 53, no excuse me, I made a mistake, 4, 48, not even
4, 17. 4, 17 is page 53. Alright, this is the order God wants us to see. This is not
the one that we meant to see, but it deals with repentance. Page 53, verse 17 says,
Repentance is accepted by God from those who fall in sin due to ignorance
then repent immediately. God redeems these and God is Knower, Wise. So this is
how repentance is accepted. Let's go on. But repentance is not acceptable
from those who continue to commit sins until death comes to them then say now I
repent. Nor is it acceptable from those who die as disbelievers. We have prepared
for them a painful retribution. So repentance, there are conditions for
accepting Tawbah, for accepting repentance. That you fall in sin due to ignorance.
Let's say you don't know that wine is haram. And you go drink wine, then you
find out in Quran that wine, liquor, alcohol is haram. Then you repent. And you
pledge you'll never do it again, you made a mistake, you'll never do it again, then your
repentance is accepted. But if you know that wine, liquor, whiskey, marijuana, or any of
those is haram, and you go deliberately and you do it, you cannot repent from that, you
have to pay. And the price is very high, either here or there. If you know that
adultery is haram, and you go commit it, you cannot repent from that, there's no
repentance there, you have to pay. And the pay is very expensive, ten thousand dollars,
you know the prostitutes are $50, $100. But the price that you pay according to
God's law is, I put a figure on it, just roughly, $10,000. In misery or problems or
whatever. So this is the condition for repentance. You can repent only if you
fall into sin due to ignorance and then repent immediately. You can't linger. In
the right way you say, I'm sorry God, I made a mistake.
These are the conditions for repentance.
Also, let's go to 39:53.
Because when I say you cannot go to heaven with one sin,
it sounds terrible, doesn't it?
Not one sin, because Adam and Eve ate from the tree, committed one sin.
39:53.
page 319, page 319, verse number is 65, no, that's not the one, 53, excuse me, it's on
the same page anyway, 53, it says, "Say: 'O my servants who have transgressed against themselves, never
despair of God's mercy.' God forgives all sins, for He is the Forgiver, the Most Merciful."
Now the Arabic is even a lot stronger,
قُلْ يَا عِبَادِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسْرَفُوا عَلَىٰ أَنفُسِهِمْ لَا تَقْنَطُوا مِن رَّحْمَةِ اللَّهِ
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يَغْفِرُ الذُّنُوبَ جَمِيعًا
All sins. God forgives all sins. Moses committed murder. He was forgiven.
If you remember the Quran, Moses immediately turned to God and said, "This is the work of the devil,
please God forgive me." He repented immediately, didn't he? And he didn't
intend to kill the man either. But he was forgiven right there in the same prayer.
The same verse of the Quran. So God forgives all sins. The instruction here
for us is never to despair from God's mercy. There is one unforgivable offense.
Now that's the one in 4:48. Let's go to 4:48.
Down at the bottom of the page, it says idol worship, the only unforgivable offense.
God never forgives the idolization of anything besides Him, and He forgives all
lesser offenses for whomever He wills. Anyone who sets up any idol besides God
has forged a gross offense. Therefore the only unforgivable offense is idol
worship. And this is why we are very careful in this masjid not to idolize
anyone, not Mary, not Jesus, not Muhammad, not Moses, not any saint, not anyone, not
anything. Our motto is God alone. And the criterion is in the Quran.
When you talk about God alone, they don't like it, that's the sign, but we love it.
We talk about God alone, because idol worship is the only unforgivable offense.
Let's go in the same, in the same surah, verse 116, 116, this is page 63, again at
the bottom of the page, it says, God does not forgive the idolization of anything
besides Him, and He forgives all lesser offenses for whomever He wills. Anyone
who idolizes any idol besides God has gone far astray. So now we know that
there's only one unforgivable offense and that is idol worship, to idolize
anyone or anything. It's just the one that is not forgiven. Because the whole idea of
creating us in this world is to worship God alone. And this is why we are told
throughout the Quran, that the prophets have no power to benefit you or harm you, have
no power to benefit themselves or harm themselves. Why is God saying that? Why?
Because the people have a tendency to idolize their leaders, their saints, their
prophets. Christians idolize Jesus, the Muslims idolize Muhammad, the Shia idolize
the Imams. It's a plague, it's a plague that Satan set up for the Jews, the Christians,
and the Muslims, and people fall in it. And we find it reflected in the Quran, a statement of fact.
وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِاللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
The majority of believers fall into idol worship.
وَمَا أَكْثَرُ النَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
The majority of people will not believe to start with, and the majority of the minority will fall
into idol worship. This is why you must be absolutely positive and careful that you
are idolizing no one. That you are worshiping Allah alone. That you're following the
Quran alone. The words of Allah alone. You don't accept any instructions from anyone
because God is the wisest.
So with this in mind, we know that all sins are forgivable. The only unforgivable offense
is idol worship. And we know that we cannot go to heaven with one sin, we must erase all
sins. When we die we mustn't have one sin in our record, otherwise you don't go to heaven.
We are here in this world to prepare for entering heaven, that's what we want, the
real life, the eternal life. So this life is zero. So in order to qualify, you have to
erase all the sins. You can erase by tawbah, repentance, and by paying for them.
Therefore I propose that we go out of these doors
absolutely sinless. We're going to walk out of these doors without a single sin
on our record, because we're going to repent right now.
We're going to turn to God and we're going to declare tawbah, we're going to pledge that we will never
break God's law, that we will follow His commandments as stated here, and that we
will never offend God in any way. Idol worship is out of the question. We did
that a long time ago. But we're going to turn to God and sincerely pledge we're
going to repent of all the past sins and offenses. We're going to say that we
are sorry that we fell into those mistakes. We will apologize and we will pledge, this is
most important, that we will never again commit a sin. You have to mean it.
You may fall in sin again, which you will, but God says in the Quran that He loves,
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ التَّوَّابِينَ
Those who continuously repent. He didn't say إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ التَّائِبِينَ
He said التَّوَّابِينَ because you continuously repent, you have to repent every day.
But as far as we're concerned at this moment, we're going to walk out of these doors absolutely
sinless. So turn to God and repent, do dua to Allah. Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah, Alhamdulillah.
When you repent, you wipe out all the sins in your record, and you qualify, if you die right
now at this moment, you're going to heaven straight, because you're going to have no sin.
and remember the conditions for repentance in the future when you reach
for a cup of whiskey or wine or something you know it is wrong and you
know you're gonna pay for it dearly. It's very expensive. I remember one time I was
in Libya at the time and I was buying a donut from this fellow and he had a bottle of
whiskey next to him, he was a cashier, and he was drinking away, and I said, "You know
this is very expensive." He said, "Yeah, I paid a few pounds for this." I said, "No, that's not
what I mean. This is going to cost you a lot." Because it's very expensive, you're breaking
God's law. As far as Adam and Eve are concerned, it cost them heaven. Heaven is God's grace.
You get anything you want. God says you get anything you wish, and He has more.
He has more than you wish. Because God has things that we cannot even imagine in order to wish.
You know, how can you wish for something you cannot imagine? Pleasures and joy that you cannot imagine.
God says, I have more than what you wish for.
And now that you are sinless, try to maintain this condition.
If you're about to commit a sin, be prepared to pay for it, dearly, expensively.
You know what is worse with sins, is if they really become too much, then there's a sheath
that builds up with every sin, and if there's too much of that around you, people cannot
penetrate that sheath. But never despair from God's mercy. You must repent
immediately, whether you know it or not. If you fall in sin knowingly or unknowingly,
repent anyway, immediately, and be prepared for the price. And you pay the
price happily. Any time God says you shall not, you shall not. No matter how
simple it seems. The second khutbah is about the importance of the Arabic
language. This is the second khutbah. Because we started the Arabic language
lessons recently, and I'm going to summarize the whole khutbah in one word.
Let me make it two words. Not important at all. That's four words.
Not important at all. Arabic is not important at all.
Because we learn from Surah 41. Let's look at 41:44.
Most of you are familiar with this.
41:44 is in page 332.
It says, had we made it a non-Arabic Quran, they would have said, why did it come down in that language?
Whether it is non-Arabic or Arabic, say, for those who believe, it is a beacon and a healing, regardless of their language.
As for those who do not believe, they will be deaf and blind to it, as if they are being called from afar.
So language is absolutely immaterial. If you're a believer, you're a sincere Muslim,
then God will put everything in your heart, the whole Quran in your heart.
I've seen people quote the Quran without ever reading it, because they're sincere Muslims.
They haven't read it all yet, they're working on it.
At the same time, if you're a professor of Arabic linguistics at the Mecca University or whatever,
and you are not a sincere believer, you cannot get one Arabic word from the Quran,
even though you are a professor of Arabic language.
Because God says, as for those who do not believe, they will be blind to it.
You cannot get one word out of it.
At the same time, a Japanese, a French, a Swede,
or one who does not know one letter in the Arabic language,
God will put the Quran in his heart.
Otherwise it will not be fair, because the Quran is for the whole world,
for everybody, and it will not be fair to restrict it to those who can read and write
Arabic. As you see from this verse, the title of the surah is Fussilat, elucidating.
God made the Quran available to every believer, and also the Quran is very
special, the Quran is never available to those who are not believers.
But the Arabic, the Arabic helps, just like mathematics or physics or chemistry, it helps.
And this is why we have the Arabic lessons.
I'm going to give you one example of how the Arabic helps. I wrote it
out there. Because the Muslim Ummah is trapped in a satanic plot, where they do not believe God when he says that the Quran is complete and
perfect. They have to go to other sources.
They have five sources of Sharia. They have the Quran, the Hadith,
the Ijma', unanimity, Qiyas, that is analogy, and all kinds of other sources.
And God says if you go to any other source besides Quran, you are
setting up a god beside God.
I'm going to read the verse for you, it happens to be verse 19 of Surah 6.
قُلْ أَيُّ شَيْءٍ أَكْبَرُ شَهَادَةً
قُلِ اللَّهُ شَهِيدٌ بَيْنِي وَبَيْنَكُمْ
وَأُوحِيَ إِلَيَّ هَٰذَا الْقُرْآنُ
لِأُنذِرَكُم بِهِ وَمَن بَلَغَ
So the people set up other sources beside Quran, other gods beside God, against the will of God and the will of the Prophet.
And they think that they are guided.
One perfect example of the Arabic language is this verse here.
It says, it's Surah 17, verse 45. It says,
when you read the Quran, we place between you and those who do not believe in the
Hereafter an invisible barrier. And we put shields on their hearts to prevent
them from understanding Quran and deafness in their ears. And when you
mention your Lord, when you preach your Lord in the Quran alone, God put the word
alone after Quran. They turn away, they run. They don't like it. They run. And we have seen
this, you have seen people who will come here and you tell them the Quran alone and they
run. They can't stand it. Just like the Quran says,
Now, because of the general trap that the Muslim Ummah fell in,
they refused to translate this the way it is. They say when you preach your Lord
alone in the Quran, you just pick up any translation of the Quran, and you'll find
that they move the word وَحْدَهُ after your Lord. And this is why in our translation
we put وَحْدَهُ after the Quran, because God put it after the Quran in Arabic.
This sentence would have been perfectly, perfectly perfect if you say
وَإِذَا ذَكَرْتَ رَبَّكَ وَحْدَهُ فِي الْقُرْآنِ
But God deliberately put the word وَحْدَهُ after al-Qur'an. So if you know Arabic, it will help you
distinguish and understand that the majority of people are plagued with idol worship.
وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِاللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
And they are plagued to the extent that they refuse to believe the Quran.
They refuse to translate the truth of the Quran.
They cannot stand when you say the Quran alone.
God is not enough for them.
They have to have Hadith and Sunnah and Qiyas and Ijma and all these other sources
that were invented centuries after the Prophet, including the hadiths in Syria.
So this is an example of the importance of the Arabic language.
And we have here the expression
الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ
Those who do not believe in the Hereafter.
Let us look at them consistently in the Quran.
We find first of all, Surah 16, verse 22.
16:22. 16:22 says, your God is one God. But those who do not believe in the Hereafter,
their hearts are denying, and they are arrogant. Your God is one God, but
those who do not believe in the Hereafter will set up other gods beside
God. That's what it means. You see, you people are fortunate, most of you were
born in a non-Muslim house, and they will get double the reward. This will be
another khutbah. You get twice as much as me, the person who grew up in a Muslim
house. The Quran says that those who grew up in a non-Muslim house and they became
Muslim and accepted the Quran as their book, they get double the reward. So I grew up
in a Muslim house, my parents said if you are a good person you have to be a
Muslim, you must believe in God, you must be a Muslim, you must believe in God, and so
so forth. So, I grew up saying, I'm a Muslim, I believe in God, I'm a Muslim, I
believe in God, you know, because my parents taught me so.
They talk about the Hereafter, that they will be resurrected after death, but they really don't believe it; they just say it
because their parents taught them to say that. So those who do not believe in the
Hereafter, their hearts are in denial. How do we distinguish? This is the verse that I
wanted to share next, that those who do not believe in the Hereafter, how will
God show them on the Day of Judgment that their hearts were
in denial? By this criterion here, when you tell them the Quran alone they run. This
is the criterion, this is the sign that will show them on the Day of Judgment that
they were saying with their mouth, I am a Muslim, la ilaha illallah, but their hearts
inside were denying it, they didn't know it.
So this is the sign.
Another verse about those who do not believe in the Hereafter is in surah 6, verse 112.
6:112 shows us the hadith and sunnah test, where people do not believe God when He says the
Quran is complete and perfect.
They don't believe that, because their hearts inside are denying.
So when you read 112 it says, And thus we have appointed for every prophet enemies
from among the human devils and jinn devils, who invent and narrate to each other fancy
words in order to deceive.
Had your Lord willed, they would not have done it.
So you shall disregard them and their inventions. Go on to 113, this is God's way, in order
that the minds of those who do not really believe in the Hereafter, see, it's the same
expression, it's the same expression, because the heart and
sight are denied. And we see that, those who do not believe in the Hereafter,
consistently, they will run away from the Quran alone, they will be attracted to
the fabrications against the Prophet that they call hadith and sunnah, and this will
show them on the Day of Judgment that their hearts were denied, that they were not satisfied
with the word of God alone.
alone.
39:45.
39:45 is the great criterion that tells you if you, or anyone you are speaking with, talking
to, is really a believer or a false believer.
It says, when God alone is advocated, the hearts of those who do not believe in the
Hereafter shrink with aversion, but when idols are mentioned besides Him, they rejoice, they
become happy.
When you speak about God alone, they don't like it.
وَإِذَا ذُكِرَ اللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ اشْمَأَزَّتْ قُلُوبُ الَّذِينَ
لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ
Again, those who do not believe in the Hereafter, the same expression, they don't like it.
You have to mention besides God Mary or Jesus or Muhammad or Ali or somebody.
So, you cannot speak about God alone to them; they will not be happy. But
when you mention someone else, they'll be happy. So this is a sign that they do not
believe in the Hereafter. That's the sign, the great criterion for you, me, anyone you
talk to, and this is why I have it at the beginning of the translation, because it
is the great criterion, it tells you exactly if your heart is denying or not, if you are a
Muslim or you're deceiving yourself, you tell yourself, "I'm a Muslim, I'm a Muslim,"
when you really are not. These are the signs.
Finally, let's look up the same surah 39, verse 65.
Prophet Muhammad is our example, and his example is to uphold the Quran, the whole Quran,
nothing but the Quran. And here is a statement directed to the Prophet, it says,
"It has been revealed to you, Muhammad, and to those before you, that if you ever fall
into idol worship, all your works will be nullified and you will be a loser."
After all the work he did, after all the suffering he went through, after being
banished from his hometown,
if he ever fell into idol worship, all his works would have been nullified.
It doesn't matter what a nice guy you are.
It doesn't matter how nice you are, how honest,
and truthful,
and beloved,
and benevolent, and charitable.
It doesn't matter. If you idolize anyone or anything,
all your work is in vain.
Because we exist in this world to worship God alone.
This is the whole idea.
Because Satan wanted to be a god with God.
So God created us to show Satan and to show the angels that we will worship God without
putting anything beside Him.
If we put Muhammad next to God, or Jesus next to God, or Mary next to God, then
we'll prove Satan's point.
We prove that God needs a partner, God needs Muhammad in order to be worshipped, or God
needs Jesus to be worshipped, or God needs Moses, or Mary, or something to be worshipped.
We are here to prove that God can be worshipped alone, without anything with Him.
This is the whole idea of the Quran.
This is why it is the only unforgivable sin.
Another final statement is in another verse, in Surah 40.
Verse 10, we're going to start with 10.
40, 10.
I'm going to close with this, I promise.
At the bottom of the page, page 321.
321, at the bottom, it says, 'Worship God alone.'
It says, "Those who disbelieve will be told, 'God's abhorrence
towards you is even greater than your own abhorrence towards yourselves, because you
were invited to believe but you chose to disbelieve.'"
Verse 11 says, they will say, "Our Lord, You have given us two deaths and two lives, and now we
confess our sins. Is there any way out?'" The answer in verse 12 says,
"This is because when God ALONE was advocated, you disbelieved, but when
partners were associated with Him, you believed. Therefore, God's judgment has been issued;
He is the Most High, the Great.'" So to give this subject, this verse is
very important. To give the verse its justice, we'll read it in Arabic.
[Arabic recitation of Quran 40:10-12]
The idea of someone paying for the sins of the world—that is a wrong concept about sin.
Let's listen to this question and answer; maybe we will all benefit from that.
Regarding the concept that we are all sinners: we do go through stages where we do not follow the commandments exactly.
But you can be sinless.
But hopefully, before you die, you reach a stage where you are absolutely sinless.
You don't have any sins from the past.
Alhamdulillah, if you regret them, you are sinless right now.
Now, it is in your hand to commit a sin or not, as of this moment.
Now, if you fall into sin due to ignorance, and then you repent, you know what to do.
But it is absolutely in your hand to follow the Quran exactly to the letter.
Does this make sense?
We do not have to be sinners.
It is not true that we are all sinners.
You can get rid of all your sins. And therefore, from that time on, you have a perfect life.
That's what God says. You have a perfect life, absolutely no problems.
No traffic tickets, no headache, no stomach ache, no sickness.
You're guaranteed, absolutely guaranteed, health, wealth, peace of mind, perfect happiness.
That's what God says in the Quran. Surah 24, verse 55.
And you better believe it, because God promises that.
Yeah?
It gets to the point where no one can benefit or harm you.
It's a very common belief, I think in Morocco, that there are things like the evil eye
and amulets.
Right.
That people can look at you in a certain way and cause you to be ill or something like
this.
I'm afraid of this.
This is not how it works.
Right.
If you are afraid of anything, someone points a gun to your head and you get scared.
You don't know how it works.
You shouldn't be. I mean, I'm giving you an extreme.
Because that gun will not work unless it is in accordance with God's will.
And if it is God's will to die at that moment, there is nothing anyone in the whole world can do about it.
Because the method and time of your death is already written down.
And you cannot die except with a personal decree from God. Personal decree.
It is a written decree. God must sign your death certificate.
Therefore, a person comes with a gun, can do nothing to you.
Because they have to have a signed certificate of your death from God, personally.
No one knows when you will die, no one. This is what the Quran says, the end of Sura 31.
Not even the angels know God's laws.
The authority comes from Allah.
SubhanAllah.
You had a question?
Yeah, you said earlier that
they would receive a double reward
if they were to convert to
Submission. And
it's stated before that
everybody has to stay in caste.
So I don't know
if there's any kind of contradiction
for them to get a double reward
if they're facing the same caste hurdles.
No, they have additional hurdles
that they have to move across.
Because their clerics told them Jesus is God, he's the son of God, the trinity, this kind of thing.
And they had to overcome this.
Besides, if God wants to be generous with them, there's nothing anyone can do.
And God says that if you grow up under difficult circumstances and you come to the Quran,
you will, you will receive double the reward.
So that's more guidance.
Yeah, that's more guidance.
But it doesn't mean anything.
Maybe it doesn't.
Maybe not.
The end, for example, the end of Surah Al-Baqarah, and they all quote the end of Surah Al-Baqarah.
I will give a quote on that topic.
That's all.
Congratulations.
Abdullah.