Okay, I think we are at 2:196, verse 196. This is Christmas Eve and it seems like a lot of people are having a family reunion.
Do you want to come see me?
You're welcome.
Is there football in the future?
No.
It's about to start, isn't it?
Mary from New York.
Verse 2:196, Hajj and Umrah.
Here is a commandment. You shall complete the Hajj and Umrah for God.
If you are prevented, then offer a sacrifice, and do not shave your heads until your offering has reached its destination.
But if you are ill or suffering some head injury, then you may shave your head and expiate
by fasting or giving charity or sacrifice.
During the normal time of Hajj, you break the state of sanctity between Umrah and Hajj,
then expiate by offering a sacrifice.
Okay, all this sounds complicated, but it has to do with the Hajj rituals.
When you go for Hajj, you start out with Umrah.
There are two things you have to do.
Umrah and then the Hajj.
Umrah consists of putting on the unsewn clothes.
then you go around the Ka'bah seven times, then you run between Safa and Marwah.
So, if you decide to break the state of sanctity between Umrah
and Hajj, see, as soon as you enter into that state of sanctity, you don't do any vanity,
you don't make up your face, you don't cut your hair.
It's another form of making the body know its place.
You're telling your body, I'm not going to beautify you and make you look pretty or anything.
I'm just casting you off.
Women care, the men don't care.
You don't shave hair, you don't use perfume, you can shower, but maybe simply.
But you don't wear clothes that distinguish the rich from the poor.
You wear very simple clothes, and for the men it's just two pieces.
So in fact, there are people involved, and you cannot tell who is rich and who is poor.
And they all look the same, and they are all neighbors, and all that.
So, all the practices in this state, being the boss over your body,
come out the first thing you have is the charity.
So, let me go over this sentence, the verse now.
You shall complete the Hajj and the Umrah for God.
So, this is something you have to do, as soon as, whenever you can.
You plan on it, and when you can, God will make you able to go and do it.
Of course, the first person to announce that was Abraham, and this is in Surah 22,
I think it is verse 27, which is going to...