Commit no error, like the verse says, you see that? Commit no error, and that is stated in the Book, of course. Of course. So I didn't translate it this way for nothing. God is saying you commit no error by following it, in certain ways, but it is not how it works, and it is similar to God's command to the angels. The Quran says before that, they will not harm you; they will obey God,
The only prohibition is visiting the Prophet's tomb, that is idolatry, visiting the Prophet's tomb,
uh...
well it was a lot of work.
We are taught what we are supposed to do, and we are commanded to sacrifice sheep for the poor and the needy, like it says here.
You are commended for it by the way you are doing it, and I am very proud of what you are doing.
This is not in Hadith. That is what I was referring to before on this topic.
That's why I said it's pure, it's called Submission.
It's not a sacrifice.
Right.
.
During the rites of Hajj and `Umrah, you enter the state of sanctity
between `Umrah and Hajj, and you expiate by offering a sacrifice.
Those who cannot afford it, shall fast three days during Hajj,
and seven when they return home.
This makes a complete ten, provided they do not live at the Sacred Masjid.
Now this means seven days when you go back. But if you live there, you're not going back.
Again, the Quran's language is perfectly clear. You shall observe God, and know that God
is strict, of course, in retribution.
197 tells you that Hajj is to be observed. Remember I said, on the eighth day, you have to be there?
because there are specified days.
Hajj shall be observed during the specified months.
Thus, whoever sets out to observe Hajj
shall abstain from sexual intercourse,
misconduct, or arguments throughout Hajj.
So, this is really self-control. You cannot say a word of gossip or anything.
You don't say any bad words. You only say the right amount.
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Whatever good you do, God is fully aware thereof.
As you take provisions for the journey, remember that the best provision is righteousness.
and you shall observe Me, O you who possess intelligence.
Okay, any questions on that?
Yeah, one of the main things, all in all, is that the start must be marked for the rites of the Hajj.
Two days in Mina, or three days?
One day?
Yes.
The first day is the 8th. This is the Day of Tarwiyah. The 9th is Arafat, and so on.
Then on the 9th, you must be on Arafat.
So there's the second day coming up.
It's coming up at two or three in the morning.
Oh, in Mina you're stoning Satan, the stoning of Satan ceremony, in Mina.
No, I just remembered.
At Mina, you see Satan was trying to talk Abraham out of sacrificing his son.
He said, "Some god has got you to kill your son?"
So, in throwing stones, it is a symbol of rejecting Satan's temptation to disobey God.
And it is done at three pillars, with seven stones at each one,
on the first day, second day, and third day.
And all the people must be there. So we have one million people in Mina.
Now they made it easy by building bridges. So there are actually two stories for people.
My parents couldn't do it, so I did it on their behalf.
So it's just too much of a problem.
While I was sitting there,
so I collected,
let me see,
for myself, for my father, for my mother.
There are seven stones each.
So I put them in my hand.
I was throwing for four people.
Then we had
one at a time saying,
Allahu Akbar,
Allahu Akbar.
You have somebody who likes to make an imprint on stones.
Because nobody sees who is throwing what.
Aim at his head, you know.
It's funny some people get carried away in that situation, because their guide is telling them,
"Just think of that as Satan. And you are throwing stones at Satan."
Some of them get carried away and they throw their shoes.
Honestly, there are so many shoes on that thing.
Thank you.
Yeah, we can.
Yeah.
[silence]
Another story is how God ordered Abraham to sacrifice his son, and he was about to sacrifice his son.
But Satan came to Abraham, who thought God ordered him to sacrifice his son, and Abraham was going on that assumption that he's obeying God.
So Satan's idea was to make him disobey God, as Abraham was convinced that God wants him to kill his son.
Of course, this whole thing is absurd, that's a fact.
But the fact is, God did not order him to do this.
And obviously did not want him to do this, because God intervened and saved him.
So, on the two days in Mina that we commemorate the event, we will be...
is going to...
seven stones.
Seven...
eight.
I don't know, I don't see the reference for what was said about it.
See, the Quran mentions seven heavens, but hereafter there will be eight angels.
The eight bearing the throne of God.
Verse 198: You commit no sin by seeking commercial benefits during Hajj.
When you depart from Arafat... okay, now we're going to stop at this sentence.
This says you're allowed to take advantage of being a Hajji,
and buy wholesale a box of merchandise.
We'll bring them here for trade, and we'll sell them to the locals.
We'll use this trade, and we'll make a lot of money.
You commit no sin by seeking commercial benefits from your Lord.
When you depart from Arafat, that's on the evening of the ninth day,
you shall commemorate God at the Sacred Monument, Muzdalifah.
This is where you collect the stones, the pebbles.
You pray, you pray the Maghrib and Isha
as well.
...
uh...
while they may not have a good goal,
but still, for the believers, this is what we stand for.
They could let them go back to their camp,
and then the people who were with them go over there.
...
I remind you of the Day of Judgment.
People are equal, there is no rich, no poor,
and there is a crowd, a great number of people,
one million people, you can't even move about in it.
The Day of Judgment will be like this,
all past, present, future generations
will be gathered at the same time, on this earth.
It will be very crowded.
They will not reserve a special place in the hereafter for Ronald Reagan, just because he was president.
A president is not special. There's no such thing.
But I tell you,
he's going to be in deep trouble.
he is from the pit.
But if he then becomes a Muslim,
and he decides to do so from the heart,
then the Most Forgiving will create the greatest opening for him.
Exactly.
Oh yeah, you get the benefit.
Two hundred: Once you complete your rites of worship, you shall continue to remember God, just as you remember your own parents or even better.
Some people may say, "Our Lord, give us of this world," while they have no share in the Hereafter.
Others would say, "Our Lord, grant us righteousness in this life, and righteousness in the Hereafter, and spare us the agony of the Fire."
Each of these will receive a share for their work.
And God is most efficient in reckoning.
Like I said, some people spend their life here,
seeking the materials of this world,
concerned about this brief life,
forgetting the eternal life.
Now, verse 203 concerns the specified days of Hajj.
You shall commemorate God during the specified days.
These can be two or three days. Thus, if you complete this in two days, you commit no error.
And if you stay longer, you commit no error, so long as you maintain righteousness.
You see here the openness? Because sometimes it's impossible for you to leave,
you know, when you want with so many people, and only with a few buses.
This flexibility, however, is not to be abused.
Because when God says, for example, "seven laps," then it must be seven laps.
But when He says it's okay to do it in two days, then it is okay to do it in two days.
So the Quran is very careful and takes all circumstances into consideration.
You shall observe God and know that you will be gathered before Him.
I know he is here, but I can't really see him, it's too crowded.
Can you read a couple of verses?
I was looking for him to start.
Let's continue.
Verse 204.
Among the people,
there is one whose utterances concerning this life may impress you.
He may even call upon God to witness his innermost thoughts, while he is a most ardent opponent.
As soon as he leaves, he roams the earth corruptingly,
destroying properties and lives.
God does not love corruption.
And when he is told, "Observe God," he becomes arrogantly indignant.
Consequently, Hell will be his deserving lot; what a miserable destiny.
Then,
O you who believe, you shall embrace total Submission; do not follow the steps of Satan.
He is your most ardent enemy.
If you backslide, after the clear proofs have come to you, then know that God is Almighty, Most Wise.
Are they waiting for God Himself to come to them in dense clouds, together with the angels?
The opportunity is to study.
I hope that I can do that.
I hope so.
You tell them that they are not following what God says,
that they are making up things, but they can't do it right.
You see, they are not following.
You show them the Quran and you say,
this is what the Quran says about Wudu.
This is how we derive the ablution.
Is this how we do the ablution? They say, "No."
And then, sinful pride of excess, and they say, "What is wrong with having more?"
And when you say, "Just obey God," they say, "You are not following what God says."
But you can see this, they attend their rites, and they call God to witness,
they're talking about God, and worshipping God, and really they are not.
How can they be worshipping God and not following His commandments?
And then when you're doing it the right way, some authority will tell you to do more.
Yeah.
I think that happened in the last world war.
Oh yeah.
And they are so righteous, you know.
"Oh, you're not doing it completely right."
No, no, no.
You don't have to add more.
Sorry.
Okay then.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Now, we will note this example of submission to God. We will commit ourselves to God.
This is what God says, this is what you do.
And I have a question in practice,
when God tells you to press this button or that button, what do you do?
You just strictly adhere to what God is saying.
You do not believe yet,
when God says do this, and you want
to do something extra.
Then you have a god beside God,
telling you to do nine steps of wudu, not four.
You know, in fact, it's just, it's, um, I see that as far as, you know, the change
that we've lost a lot in our society, but also as a society, I think going to more
steps, everything will be more clear.
What will we do?
What will we do for that?
And it's kind of like a double-edged sword.
It's a test for them.
It's like, you know, who's going to do it and who's not going to do it?
I don't think he likes this criminal action that he's doing now.
Yeah. It's the message of the day, guys.
Yeah, and I know why he's doing it.
He's dressed straight up as a criminal.
He's got a gun.
He's got himself a gun.
No, don't get involved with them.
Sad.
No.
Don't get involved with them.
Yeah, what more do they want?
And God parted the sea for them to walk across the Red Sea. Walk, no bridge, there is no bridge, walk across the Red Sea. And then Pharaoh and his army followed, and God drowned Pharaoh and his army, right before their eyes.
And they still wait for God to come down. And so this is the question. And we are the same people.
That's even more profound. We showed them that the Quran is from God. What more can you do to prove to them that this is from God?
No, but some people are not satisfied. They would like to, they would like a lot of help.
Exactly.
Because it says here, 2:210 is connected with 2:211. It is the verse.
Because as we know, the Jews have asked Moses,
"Show us God. We want to see God. We want to see Him."
They want to see Allah.
And yet, they were given so many things, so many favors from Allah,
and they were not satisfied.
And now, as you say, there are so many things in the Quran,
and so many wonders, and still people are not satisfied.
It's as if they want Allah to come down,
It's a form of ingratitude, I think. It's a form of kufr, or ungratefulness, for this life.
I don't know why I'm telling this to you guys here, because I'm too old to do this kind of stuff.
Well, this is what it looks like.
So I do want to talk to you about my job, which is to help you grow.
That's my job. That's my job.
So I don't just tell you to do this.
I help you to do it.
But you can try to do more than just do it.
It helps you to believe in God. That's a problem we all face.
I don't think that faith has a form like this.
It was a blessing.
What? What? Really?
The way he was, did he hold you up?
You know what I'm talking about?
I believe he was telling you what God meant.
Yeah, I think this is one way to reduce self-doubt about it.
Yeah.
I'm talking about that Day coming in the morning,
Well, what about mentioning He told him seven heavens, and he couldn't even count how many?
I think there is a procession of people outside, isn't there?
People praying in the background.
Yes.
Have you ever heard the first words of Joseph to the king?
The dream of the king.
This verse is opening the eyes of the people,
so that they will be shown the truth.
However, the unrighteous will not heed a book
that will be read by the righteous.
The eyes of the people will be opened wide.
The people used to be one single community,
so God sent His prophets as bringers of good tidings and as warners,
and sent down with them the scripture with the truth.
Ironically, none disputed it except those who received the scripture,
out of jealousy among themselves,
after the clear proofs had come to them.
Then God guided those who believed.
died before they could receive it, and for them the reward from God.
That's why I told her, school doesn't do real estate like that.
So, the verse I quote, you know, it describes some people saying, you know, you only want one.
and people definitely want to take that to school and go to school
and do all the other things they want to do
because they know that they are going to go to school
and do school,
but
when you see the Hereafter,
well,
you know.
It is only a matter of time, but what is time?
It is a matter of time, but what is time?
because we really are being persecuted for adhering to the Quran, you know.
I was discussing today with one fellow. The one person was telling me what he knew.
I knew him. I was just talking about him. I was talking about what he can do, you know.
He said to me, you know, I haven't basically read it in such a long time.
I left my little bit of brain to talk about this topic, and I know you all talked about this topic in the week I have been here.
The list of believers was something we talked about.
You can see what is said in Hajj, that people are on an edge; once a trial befalls them, they turn back.
Okay, are there any questions?
No questions.
Fatiha.
I don't care for the fake, that's what I'm trying to do.
What are you trying to do?
The refutation is here.