Ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah, wahdahu la sharika lah, lahul-mulk wa lahul-hamd, wa ilayhil-masir.
I'm going to start this khutbah
from the Bible.
It may be strange, but God says in the beginning of the Quran
that you must believe in the previous scriptures.
And the Bible is 90% truth, 10% distortion.
And unfortunately, most of that 10% distortion is the doctrine of the church.
So, we have the Quran as the criterion to correct any deviation.
A reading from Genesis 6:11 says,
"In the eyes of God the earth was corrupt and full of lawlessness.
When God saw how corrupt the earth had become,
since all mortals led astray lives on earth,
He said to Noah,
'I have decided to put an end to all mortals on earth.
The earth is full of lawlessness because of them.
So I will destroy them and all life on earth.
Make yourself an ark.'"
So the idea is, when there is too much lawlessness on earth,
disobedience of God, and non-adherence to the oneness of God, God destroys the earth.
And I want to use this to point out to you, that you probably saved the earth.
You, because you are people who believe in God alone, you do not idolize Muhammad,
or Jesus, or Mary, or any saint, or anyone, or anything.
You, because you have reached the conviction that God alone is king,
and God alone rules the world, and rules your life, every minute detail in it.
Nobody controls your life. You have come to this conviction.
You know that your boss has no authority over you.
God controls the minds and hearts of everybody, including the people around you.
Your boss, your spouse, your children, your parents, everybody. You've come to that conclusion.
Back in 1977, did we start the mosque in '77 or '78? '78? '78.
This mosque was established because we came to the conclusion that
the Quran, as God says, is the only source.
This is why this mosque started.
But before that, we want to look together at the earth.
Now God looked at the earth in Noah's time and He said,
"Nobody believes in God alone, and there is too much lawlessness.
So I'm going to destroy the earth and wipe out everybody."
That's what God said. We have it in the Quran and we have it in the Bible.
Now, of all the millions of Christians you see on earth, how many believe in God alone?
How many believe that Jesus is a human being who has no power to do anything?
A helpless, dead person. How many of the Christians believe that?
And I worship God alone. Of all the millions, of all the millions of Muslims
on earth, how many believe God when He says Quran alone? How many? How many
mosques on earth say, "ash-hadu an la ilaha illa Allah" without any other names in the Adhan?
How many? None. And you very probably saved the earth, because everybody was
corrupt. How many Jews adhere to the Book of God alone, and do not follow Hadith and
Sunnah? How many? None. They all follow Hadith and Sunnah. They don't follow
the Torah.
Exactly the words, Hadith and Sunnah.
In their language it is called
Mishnah, which is oral law.
or Hadith.
And Gemara, which means tradition.
So it is called Mishnah and Gemara.
It is called the Mishnah and Gemara.
It is not part of the Torah.
So these are the people who believe in God.
And they were all corrupt.
They are all too corrupt. It probably was a blessing from God that I worked for
the United Nations and traveled to every Muslim country. And everywhere I dug up the most
religious in every country, and I have not seen one place that does not praise and worship
Muhammad day and night, besides God. I mean they worship God, and they pray the five prayers
exactly to God, but they insert names of Muhammad and Ibrahim in their faith.
I haven't seen one place on earth that worships God alone.
When corruption takes over the earth, there is no need for the earth to exist.
The end of the world will come because there will be no one who worships God alone.
But it has been in God's knowledge and predestination that the Masjid of Tucson will come to be.
The people will worship God alone.
This is the only masjid on earth that says, "Ash-hadu an la ilaha illallah."
Without any other name.
By the way, we have three people here.
Earlier, you saw me discuss things with them, and they were angry because in our Adhan,
Hussein, for instance. Guess why they were angry? Can anybody make a guess?
Who said that? Yeah, because they didn't say Muhammad? You're wrong. No.
Because we don't mention the name of Ali in the Adhan.
They happen to be Shiites.
We don't say, "ash-hadu anna Aliyyan waliyyullah."
To each his idol, you know.
What I mean, what they didn't like about our Adhan, I was just like Fatima, I thought, yeah,
well, he mentioned the name of Allah alone.
But they went on to indicate it was because Ali's name was not there.
But this is the only mosque in the world that mentions the name of Allah alone.
In our Salah, in our Zikr, I challenge anyone on any spot on earth.
There isn't any faith that has only the name of God.
And when corruption spreads in this way, God destroys the earth.
I want you to look at, in the Quran, at Surah Ar-Rum, verse 41, that is page 278.
Verse 41 says, "Corruption has prevailed throughout the land and sea due to the people's work."
In my new translation it will have "misery" instead of "corruption." Misery.
Therefore He makes them suffer, well it's self-explanatory, He makes them suffer in
the consequences of their works that they may return.
It's very, very possible that you saved the earth.
Do you hear what's happening in California?
Did you see what happened to Malibu beach?
All those mansions turned into strips.
This is God. God is angry at California.
This is California from border to border.
From Mexico to Oregon, it's being slammed, hit. Unbelievable, the pictures that you saw.
It is believable of course. God is angry at California.
As we see in the Bible, in the Quran, and God's law never changes.
Back in 1977, there was no one on earth that I know of anyway, that worshipped
God alone. They always had idols beside them. You look at the Christians, the Jews, the...
Muslims. And it is an unfortunate fact of life, what we want to show you in this slide.
This is a statement in the Quran, that the majority of people, no matter what you do,
will not believe, are not believers.
This statement here says that of the believers, the majority of them will not believe in God alone.
And then you take the minority, that is the believers, and God says a statement of fact
that is assured by a double negative. That the majority of the minority, the
majority of the believers are idol worshippers. What's it called? Idol worshippers.
They worship God, but they also idolize Muhammad, or Jesus, or Mary, or somebody, or
something. They just cannot come all the way to La ilaha illa Allah, to worshiping God alone.
So if you are with the majority, you will be in trouble. Even if you are with the majority of the minority.
If you are with the minority of believers, you have to find out are you in the majority of this minority or are you in the minority of the minority.
You are elite of the elite. And that's very difficult.
The problem is, these people who are believers but they fell into idol worship, they think they are righteous.
They sincerely think they are righteous. As we see out here. They think that they are rightly guided.
They think that they are rightly guided. They think they are rightly guided. Repeated in the Quran.
And here, this is a verse that you are familiar with, on the Day of Judgment,
where they say, "By God our Lord, we were not idol-worshippers."
On the Day of Judgment, that's what they'll say.
And these words, "we were not idol-worshippers."
We're still on the same page, 30:41.
I am going to go on to page 278.
Say, travel the earth and see the consequences for those before you.
Or look at California.
The majority of them were idolatrous.
Therefore, you shall devote yourself to the perfect religion
before a day comes that is inevitable.
On that day, the people will be shocked.
Whoever disbelieves does so to his own detriment, and those who work righteousness do so for their own good.
God bestows His grace upon those who believe and work righteousness. He does not love the disbelievers.
When you come to La ilaha illa Allah, you come all the way to La ilaha illa Allah, you deserve
what you're tested with.
Because as you see, you are a very small minority of the minority.
You are a very special person when you come to La ilaha illa Allah, and Satan will concentrate
all his forces on you, he does not want you to make it, because when you make it, making
it means kingship on earth, sovereignty on earth, and ruling all your surroundings, perfect
happiness in this world and in the hereafter. But that's nothing easy. I mean to
qualify for a job, you go to the university and work your head off for
four years to qualify for a job. So to qualify for kingship on earth, what do you
expect? It's very difficult. And this is why
Alright, let's look at 29:2, Surah 29, page 270.
Do the people think they will be left to say, "we believe,"
without being put to the test?
We have tested the generations before them,
for God must distinguish those who are truthful
from those who are liars.
You cannot be left, you will not be left alone to say, "I believe."
You have to be put to the test, and it is a severe test.
Because there is too much at stake.
There is kingship on earth at stake, there is perfect happiness.
So you have to be put to the test, because God wants to
show you to the angels, and to tell them
look at my creature, under any circumstances he believes in me.
Look at Surah 12, 38, let's start at 38, Surah 12, 38, page 158, this is Joseph speaking,
I follow the religion of my fathers Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, we never worship anything
anything beside God. This is but grace from God upon us and upon the people, but
most people are not appreciative. Now, verse 39, O my prison companions, is it
better to have several lords, or God, the One, the Supreme? You worship nothing
beside God but names that you made up, you and your parents. God never authorized
any power in them. Kingship belongs only to God. He commanded that you shall not
worship except Him. This is the perfect religion but most people do not know.
Now here is Joseph preaching one God and worshiping one God and where is he? In prison.
He is a prophet of God in prison. Because God wants to show the angels and Satan
that look at my servant Joseph, look at my creature Joseph. Doesn't matter what
condition he's in, he knows I am the King, and he worships me alone. Look at 42, he
then said to the one to be saved, "Remember me to your lord, the king." But the devil
made him forget the remembrance of his Lord, and Joseph remained in prison a few
more years. A prophet of God, Joseph, who preaches the one God. And just like that,
a few more years in prison. Some people come to me and say, I've been a Submitter two weeks,
why am I having all these problems? Patience. You have to have patience. Here is Joseph
in prison, and the man who was supposed to remember him, he forgot, so Joseph stays in prison
a few more years. But listen, you're guaranteed kingship on earth. Let us go on to verse 90
of the same surah of Joseph. What does 90 say? Page 162. They said, "Are you indeed Joseph?"
it's his brothers. He said, "I am Joseph, and this is my brother. God has been gracious
to us, if anyone works righteousness and steadfastly perseveres." This is required, patience, steadfastness,
You can't come to Submission for six months and then demand kingship on earth. You must
steadfastly persevere. You must prove that you really believe under any
circumstance. You have to be put to the test. But you are in God's eyes throughout the
test. He may push you to the brink, but He will always watch over you. You will
never fall. Because if you fall, He will hold you back. But you will be on the brink, because
God wants to be proud of you, and He wants to tell Satan and the angels, "Look
at my creature, it doesn't matter what condition he is in."
Now look at 110 of the same surah, page 164.
When the messengers reached the point of despair and thought that they had been lied to,
our victory came to them.
We then save whomever we wish, while the guilty can never evade our retribution.
So when you reach the point of despair, you are a believer in God alone, nothing
changes the conviction, then comes kingship on earth. Joseph was a king on
earth, and he was controlling the provisions for the whole Middle East. His
brothers came from Palestine all the way to Egypt to beg for grain, and he was giving
them a camel-load per person. He decided that. He was in command of that. He was a king
on earth. His brothers and his parents, they fell prostrate before him. This is what is
guaranteed for you. But you have to steadfastly persevere, you have to prove yourself.
What happens in the test, it is an agreement that God has with Satan. He says,
"You go and do anything you want, and if you can take them, they are yours." Now here we are,
Satan is our most ardent enemy, and when you come to La ilaha illallah, he will come
and tempt you with your most urgent needs. If you need money, he will tempt you with money.
If you need sex, he will tempt you with sex. Whatever is your most urgent need, He will
tempt you with that. He will take you away from La ilaha illallah.
And if you fall, his bait is delicious and powerful. The bait for the fish must be the best.
When you go fishing, you pick out the best bait. Salmon eggs.
We'll just find something better. Worms, whatever.
The bait must be fantastic for the fish.
But as soon as you catch the fish, what do you do to it?
You cut its head and you fry it in oil. You take its intestines out.
This is what Satan will do to you.
Once he has you. Because he's our enemy.
See, the test is very powerful. This is why Job said the following in Surah 38,
look at Surah 38, verse 41.
Surah 38, verse 41, page 312.
Recall our servant Job. He called his Lord, saying,
the devil has afflicted me with disease and suffering. It's not God who really afflicts.
See what happened as we learn from the story of Job, is that God was proud of Job.
And he was telling the angels and Satan, look at my servant Job, he worships me alone. You
know, they are very rare people. The people who worship God alone are very rare. And God
was proud of Job at the time, and he was telling the angels, look at my servant Job.
And Satan said, well look at him, he is rich, he has a family, he is not under any pressure,
so why shouldn't he worship you? And God said, okay, I'm going to lend you Job for a while.
Now remember Job is always in God's eye, and Satan has limits where he can go.
So, Satan started to work on Job.
And this is why you see, recall our servant Job, he called his Lord saying, the devil
has afflicted me with disease and suffering.
He knows.
Job knows.
And so, God may lend you to Satan for a while.
And if Satan gets you in his hands, just like when you catch a fish, he's going to gut you.
You must steadfastly persevere, and you cannot flunk a test.
And when you flunk a test, you regress, you start again at square one, square zero.
So, we have to turn to God right now and do two things, first, thank Him for saving the
planet earth because of us, thank Him for guiding us, whatever led our steps to this
place, me and you, this is the greatest blessing that ever happened to you, and we have to
thank God for it.
then we're going to ask God to keep us on the path
steadfast, to persevere, no matter what happens
Steadfast, to persevere, la ilaha illallah
nothing will take us away
Natoobu ilallah.
I have been talking in the last khutbahs about situations in the hereafter, actual situations
in the hereafter.
And in my last khutbah I talked to you about the verse that you saw here, where God gathers
people and asks them, Where are your idols to help you?, and they say, by God our Lord we
were not idol worshipers.
It's an actual situation where people are not aware now, they swear to you they are
not idol worshippers.
And they swear then on the Day of Judgment that they are not idol worshippers, they are
not aware.
And I went through the signs of idol worship, that they cannot stand to talk about God
alone, they cannot quote the Quran alone, 17:45, and they cannot accept what God says
in the Quran.
When He said Muhammad was astray and was guided, I have read the translation for you.
Incredible wasn't it? They changed his straying into a virtue.
He was lost in love for this world, for its people, whatever the great distraction was.
And I will connect that situation with a specific situation in the hereafter.
This was a human being. This was a human being.
Someday I'm going to look like this.
Someday you'll look like this.
Just imagine handsome Abdullah is going to look like this someday.
Beautiful Rahimah will look like this, someday.
For some people, like myself, this is an improvement.
This person had beautiful teeth.
This was a person that lived on earth, just like we are now.
And you can imagine how much time was spent just for this eating.
And this happens to be a female, and can you imagine how many times she chewed food?
You can look, you can see the teeth, how much food this person had to eat.
She probably worked, she had a boss, she had lots of friends.
She drove a car, maybe.
She had fights with her friends, and relatives.
She had plans.
She made love.
Look down. See, I don't know how many miles she walked. This was a person. You're going to be
like this. Your body will be like this. Now, I want to draw your attention to God's design.
Imagine God designing the human skull, just the skull. Imagine, just for the sake of understanding,
Imagine God as a great architect, chairman of the board at a big desk, designing the human skull.
And God says, "I'm going to leave two openings for the eyes, because this human being will have two eyes."
And there has to be an opening in here for the nose, to breathe.
Here and here. Now, the eyes go in these holes, so God said, "I'm going to make these eye sockets."
And if you look in there, you see very tiny holes inside for the optic nerve to go through to the brain.
And if you look in here, you see the sinus passages.
And the teeth are something else, the design of the teeth, the cutters and the grinders.
An opening for the ear, you see the small opening on the side?
From the ear hole here, it leads to the auditory nerve, on to the brain.
And this is very hard, you know, to protect the brain.
God put the brain inside this case.
Now, God didn't put these things on there, the strings. Those have been put there.
My goodness, see, this is very tough. It's made of a number of layers, you can see the layers.
This was a human being, look what we're doing with her.
The brain is protected in fluid, which is very important.
I can see the opening at the bottom of the skull, for the spine.
Everything in the body is controlled from here.
Now I want to move on to a situation in the hereafter.
This person, this was the garment.
This person was buried. But the person herself is asleep. She doesn't know that she died.
Then this person, let us say she is an average Christian, or an average Muslim, or an average
Jew, who fell into idolatry, when she gets up, she would rise then.
Resurrection. All the people who ever existed on earth will be up on this earth,
resurrected.
And this Methodist says, "My God, it's true! Wow, everything we heard is true! We see the
resurrection."
I didn't pay attention to this day.
Look at that big person over there.
See? They have a small sign.
And she would go to this great person and she would say, how did you get like that?
And he would say, "Well, for one thing, I never missed breakfast."
It never fails.
And she would say, "Well, I didn't miss breakfast either.
You know, eggs and bread."
And the other fellow was saying, "Yeah, but were you purifying your garment? You didn't keep..."
How was my acting, by the way?
Not bad, either.
I should have also the voice tone, you know.
"Oh, what made you do that?"
"I don't know."
Well.
Just don't call Hollywood.
I'm not in a position to do that.
I don't want the director bugging me, you know.
But this is an actual situation where people will be in different, different sizes.
And then she will ask, "What is going to happen now?"
He will say, "Well, the next thing that will happen is God will come to this earth.
And the energy associated with God is equivalent to millions of hydrogen bombs.
If you imagine this earth with a million hydrogen bombs falling on it, what would happen?
See, this is why God taught us nuclear science.
This is why God let us invent hydrogen bombs.
So we can understand what happens when heat comes.
This is what the Quran says."
And the big person will go on and say, "When God comes, you cannot stand the Lord.
The energy associated with God is equivalent to millions of hydrogen bombs.
And when God comes, this whole earth is going to shatter into pieces.
Like a million hydrogen bombs hit it.
The stars will crash and disintegrate,
and you are going to be in bad trouble.
You cannot stand the presence of God.
So, child, then what will you do?"
I say, "I'm going to feed on that energy.
I'm going to enjoy it immensely.
And as soon as God comes,
we're going to be stratified
into ranks.
You will have to run away
to Hell."
This will be actual conversation.
And she will say, "Well, I'm going to run to Jesus and see if he can help me.
Because I believe in Jesus."
And she may go up to Jesus, and he would say, "I'm in deep trouble myself.
I have my own troubles.
You know, all that has happened right now is the initial resurrection has taken place.
I can't help you.
God is the one who created you, God is the one who provided for you, God is the one who
terminated your life, God is the one who resurrected you, and God is the one who will hold you
to account, hold you to account."
If this person were a "Muslim," he would say, "I am going to run to Muhammad; he is my shafi'."
he is my intercessor.
You have to believe in God alone.
That day is going to come. See, this person leaves here on earth and forgets everything
he was doing. Now, and you are going to be like this person someday.
You may not look this good by the way, but you do look very good, if you have this much
faith.
So you must, in order to stay on the path, you must... you must remember those awful situations that we will be in there.
situations that we will be in.
And this is why God puts belief in the Hereafter next to belief in Him.
Therefore, if you fall short, you cannot make it.
You cannot just believe in God, or you will go to hell.
You saw the slide.
The majority of people who believe in God are going to hell.
You must believe in God and the Hereafter.
You must never neglect to feed your soul.
Because this is what the battle is about, right?
And people like myself, we've been grappling with it.
Even, you know, that somebody in there might shout from there, "You know, I don't care for it, it's a garment that they throw away!"
Remember your old clothes? You throw them away. What can you do with them now?
Your body is just like that, old clothes, old garments.
So, if you neglect to clean your clothes, it's your own fault.
The five prayers are useless if you idolize anyone else besides God.
God must be the only one, not number one.
Because number one needs to have a number two.
God must be the only one in your life.
Allahummaghfir lil-mu'minina wal-mu'minat, wal-muslimina wal-muslimat, al-ahya'i minhum wal-amwat.