The biggest problem in the world today
is not war.
It is not disease, cancer, AIDS, and so on.
It is not children starving in Africa or
in some other parts of the world. It is
not poverty, and it is not crime.
The biggest problem in the world today is
that people do not know who they are.
And consequently, they got their priorities
all mixed up. You ask the average person,
who are you, and they will look in the
mirror and they will say, this is me.
And they are wrong. When you look in the
mirror you do not see your "self" -
you see your body, and your
body is simply a garment that you are
wearing for fifty or a hundred years.
Then you shed it.
You know, it is a matter of common sense.
There is a difference between a living
body and a dead body. The living body is
full of vitality and spark, and when it
dies, the spark is gone and becomes stiff -
just like a piece of wood. And we know
that something is gone, the person is
gone. So we can easily agree that
a person consists of a body and a soul,
and the soul is the real person. And this
is where the people fail to recognize
who they are. If they knew that the body
is not them - they will rearrange their
priorities, and they will pay more
attention to themselves - their selves - not
their bodies. A person goes to school
for many many years, works hard, takes
examinations, and even after school
he gets a job to make some money, and so on.
All this to care for the body, a vanishing
entity that will become stiff
dead someday. And when that day comes
almost everyone would look at that
lifeless body and say: for this thing I
went to school, I worked hard, I took
examinations, I earned a lot of
money and I spent it all to care for
this thing, this vanishing stiff part of
me, what did I do for myself? There is
something that we must do, and this what
life is all about. We have to rearrange
our priorities and this cannot
result without knowing that I am a body
and the soul, and I must put the body in
the service of the soul.
To drive the point home, just take an
average person and ask him or her - what
did you feed your self today, what did you
feed your soul today?
Let's start with the question - what did
you feed your body today? And they will
tell you - I gave my body breakfast,
lunch, dinner, numerous snacks - but they
gave nothing to the real person,
to themselves. What did they feed themselves?
We nourish the babies -  when we are born,
we give the baby milk and so on.
And then the baby grows,
becomes a child, and we give them
potatoes and meat and rice, and the body
grows to five or six feet. But what did
we do for the real person? This is the
major question that we're addressing
right now. This is what life is all about.
People are giving attention to the
vanishing entity and totally ignoring
the real person. There is such a thing as
food for the soul, nourishment for the
real person. And now, the new thing that I
have for you, is tangible evidence that
there is food and nutrition for the real
person. And the strange thing that is not
known yet - is not commonly known anyway
- is that just as the body grows, the real
person or the soul, grows in leaps and bounds. Maybe the body grows to
five or six feet, but the soul the real person, grows to immense sizes.
I don't want to confuse you right now but
the size of the soul can be as big as
the City of Tucson. I'm not exaggerating.
We now have
tangible evidence that the soul can grow
from a very small size like a cat to a
huge size. And this makes it even more
important to nourish and feed the real person.
Now what is the food for the
soul? This tangible evidence that we just
obtained, tells us - the evidence by the
way comes from the Creator, from God
himself - and He tells us that we must
make contact with God every day, to cause
this nutrition and nourishment of the
soul, because the soul is literally a
piece of God, and God says if you have
anything to do with Me, with God, your
soul will grow. If you remember - and the
Bible at the beginning God said He
breathed into Adam the breath of life. So
the soul is part of God's breath. And
if we have anything to do with God
we grow, however there is a specific set
of nutrition that we can offer to
ourselves.
Another question that illustrates this
biggest problem in the world, namely that
the people do not know who they are, is
that you ask the average person: how old
are you? and he or she will give you a
number somewhere between 15 and 85 years old.
Wrong, again.
Any person, the real person, is a few
billion years old. And this is the new
information that we obtained from this
new tangible evidence.
You can easily see the problem if we
illustrate a little bit how the human
being
consists of two entities.
One entity is the body, let us represent it by this dot right here.
and the eternal person, and this is an
infinite entity, it will never die, it
just goes on forever and ever. So here we
have a body that lasts a period of time
somewhere between fifty and a hundred
years, we know that we all exist - we are
all under death sentence.
And this period - when you divide any number by infinity
it equals zero. If you live 1,000 years,
you divide this by infinity and it
equals zero. This is just plain
mathematics. So the body that is going to
live for a zero - for all practical
purposes - zero period of time, is taking
all our attention. We spend
24 hours a day taking care of this
insignificant entity, the vanishing
entity. And the question is how much are
we doing for this eternal entity, the
real me, what am I doing for it.
Now that we agree that we must rearrange our
priorities and give more attention to
the real person, the soul, instead of
wasting all our life taking care of the
vanishing entity. Now what specifically are you
supposed to do. You know there are so
many people who are talking in vague
terms about capturing the heavenly light
and dissolving it into your whole being
and - all this doesn't mean a thing you
know, all these things. It is much more
practical than that, it is much more
specific than that, and God has been
sending to us the exact methodology of
developing our person, our real self,
since Adam - since the first human being.
It came down to us in the Bible, in the
Old Testament, in the Psalms of David, in
the gospel of Jesus, in the Quran. And now
we have specific methods of developing
the person, the soul, and exactly what
to do and when, and the most efficient
ways and the least efficient ways. We now
possess this valuable information, and
we are told that you must make contact
with God, your Creator, five times a day.
This contact - you can think of ropes
coming down from the Creator and keeping
us out of this sizzling pan called the
world.
At the same time we develop and we
nourish our self, the real self, the soul,
by making these contacts five times a
day. We are given exactly the
combination - actually it is a numerical secret
combination that anyone can obtain - and
through this secret mathematical
combination you can make contact with
God and nourish and develop your real
self. Five times a day, you are given the
combination, you are giving the method, how to do it, when to do it, and this is
the way to provide for yourself. Everyone
takes breakfast, lunch, dinner, snacks and
so on, and dresses nicely, and buys
a nice home, and has a beautiful spouse
or a handsome spouse as the case may be,
and all this to take care of the
vanishing entity, the body. The big
question is: what are you doing for you,
the real person? and you can agree with
me now that this is the biggest problem
in the world, not knowing who we are.
You notice I mentioned making
contact with God, and this is - I'm talking
about a specific methodology - I'm not
talking about prayer, prayer is fine and
it will contribute to the growth and
nourishment of the person's soul, the real
person. You know, millions of children
grow up - we grew up knowing that we must
say grace before we eat and say a short
prayer: God is good, God is great, please,
thank you for our food, and all that.
Millions of people pray - I mean they utter
supplications, ask God for favors and all
this is fine, God loves that. But I am
talking about a practical - a real meal
for the real person, we have this
physical evidence telling us exactly
what to say, what sounds to utter, it is
like the combination of a safe. You have
this combination, a knob on a safe - where
there is a treasure - and you have to
turn it this way a certain number of
times and then this way to another
number and so on and then you open the
safe and you have the treasure, it is
very similar to that, a numerical
combination - a combination
of sounds that you must utter,
a combination of movements that you must
do. And this is common to all religions.
It came to us, like I said, in the older
scriptures, and the latest scriptures, and
in this new discovery of a tangible
mathematically coded method. And if you
contact me at the telephone numbers
shown at the end of this program, I can
discuss this specific method with you.
And the contact with God is not the only
way to develop the soul, there
are many other methods, but the daily
contact with God is the most efficient,
this is the steak of the soul food.
But, for example, there is a method
of fasting, where you dictate on the body
exactly when the body is going to eat or
drink, and there is even a specific
time of the year for that. So God told us
exactly what to do to nourish our soul.
And if this becomes known to you or to
any other person you can ask them: what
did you do for your self today? and they
will not say zero or nothing, like most
people would say now.
The person would answer: I gave my body
breakfast, lunch and dinner, and I gave
my self five good meals by contacting
my Creator five times today.
There will be a big difference.
There will be the proper arrangement of
priorities. Right now the priorities are
all reversed, people are spending 99% of
their time caring for the vanishing entity
and totally unaware, totally neglecting
the real self, the real person. And it is a
big shame because when the time comes
and we shed the body, we will really
regret that we didn't give the real
person, the soul, the proper attention.
You know it is very well and finally
established now - that money, fame, beauty
and so on, do not bring happiness, there
is always something missing.
Did you see the Barbara Hutton story
that was shown on TV the other day?
I was listening to a special - a Barbara
Walters special, she was interviewing
Eddie Murphy, he is a movie star who has
got everything. He has two Rolls Royces,
Mercedes, a Corvette.
He has got a palatial estate in New Jersey,
his family - yet he told Barber Walters
there is something missing.
We have to develop the real self in
order to be happy. If you have a body
that has everything, money, fame,
everything it wants, everything the body
wants - but the soul is not nourished
happiness will be missing. And this, now
you can appreciate that this is the
biggest problem in the world.
And I know what you're thinking,
you're probably saying: what is the catch?
how much do I have to pay for this?
Ironically, this very precious knowledge
is free. It is just yours for the asking.
And like I said it is there is no
mincing of words, there is no vague ideas
I am talking about specifics.
Happiness has been the most elusive goal
for everybody and now we know that
material success, money, fame, and all this
does not bring happiness. Now we have a
concrete tangible method - actually the secret of happiness,
this most elusive of our goals, has been
unveiled.
You ask all the philosophers, and people
who have a lot of experience in life, and
they will tell you, readily, that material
success does not bring happiness.
Money, fame, success - all this does not
bring happiness, and I mentioned to you
Eddie Murphy as an example in his
interview with Barbara Walters. But now
we have a concrete method with a track
record that tells us that this most
elusive of our goals, happiness, is
actually attainable. And the secret is in
developing and nourishing the real person.
The people are unaware - they're going
about their life, totally unaware totally
neglecting the real self. And if they
only develop and nourish the real person,
and put their priorities in perspective,
happiness will be readily theirs.
I'm not talking about something over
there in heaven somewhere, where you have
to die first, stay in the grave millions
of years, and then get resurrected in
order to be in paradise and all that.
I'm talking about happiness, victory, success,
the real thing, here, in this world.
Just like I mentioned earlier, like
the combination, you turn that
combination to the right, left, and so on
in the correct numbers and you open it
and you have the treasure now.
You do the specific procedure, just
like a cookbook recipe, it's just as
simple as that, I'm not exaggerating. God
told us exactly how to do it, what to do
and what to say and the combination is
very specific. You do it and you get the
results.
As you see, it's been all common sense
and this is why you ought to believe me.
Why should you believe me by the way? let
me ask that question, why should you
believe me? You should believe me because
when you discuss this matter with me, if
we meet in person,
I'll show you tangible evidence and you
will see that we have a mathematically
coded message from God. You will see
the physical evidence, if you don't see
it just leave, I mean you don't have
to take it. You look at the evidence, you
see it is tangible, concrete, and you see
the results. And you visualize the whole
thing, I mean it will be in-front of you.
There is no imagination, or speculation,
or conjecture - this is the real thing.
And from the beginning of this program
to the end it is all common sense isn't
it.
Now who would be the most authoritative
source to give you this kind of
information? the Creator, the one who
created your soul, the one who breathed
into Adam from his breath - your soul is a
piece of God, and the source of all this
information is God. And you will see it
supported by physical evidence. This is a
new stage in human history and you can
be one of the pioneers to discover this.
The discovery, by the way, is very recent.
And maybe 50 years from now everybody
will know about it. But right now only a
select few - the elite of the elite knows
it, and you can be one of those. God
willing it will be known in a shorter
time than 50 years. But you can grasp
this opportunity now, you live in this
world only one life and then we move on to a new stage, the
eternal real life. Where everyone is
assigned a rank and a position depending
on how much you nourished your real self.
Can you hire a child as a pilot or
an engineer? you can't. Therefore you have
to develop the real person and grow, and
nourish, in order to be strong enough for
the eternal real life that will come
after this world. And then you will be
assigned a prominent rank.
And like I said, you don't have to wait
for that - happiness, real happiness and
the consequences of nourishing your soul
begins right here. God's promises have to
be a fact. And God says He promises those
among you who believe and lead a
righteous life that they will be
sovereigns on earth, kings and queens on
earth. And when God says that He promises
- it is done
What I told you is a very condensed
summary of this major historical event.
Needless to say there is a lot of
detail that anyone can come and see me,
and talk about it and discuss it.
They can demand the proof, where is the
physical evidence, the concrete tangible
evidence you're talking about, they can
come and ask me that. And I will show it
to them. And then they can make the
decision themselves. They have got
nothing to lose, and this is all free, I
never asked for a penny.
So they can come and see me in Tucson
at 739 East 6th Street, or better yet
call and make an appointment and then I
will sit with them and show them the proof.
The telephone number should be shown at
the end of this program, it is seven nine
one three nine eight nine, and it could
be the most important step they have
made in their life, and it results from
the realization that we are not just
walking zombies, were not just bodies
walking around with nothing in them.
al hamdulillah, we praise God. wa ashadu anna la elaha ella allah wahdahu shareeka lah,
and we bear witness that there is
no God except the One God.
It is very important for any person to
know who God is, to really appreciate why
millions of people fall into idol worship.
Why do they leave God and idolize
Muhammad, or Jesus, or Mary, or San Francis, or Saint Jude, or some helpless creature.
And the main reason is that the people
do not know who God is, they do not
appreciate the greatness of God. So my
purpose in this sermon is to share with
you some idea about the greatness of God.
And to appreciate the greatness of God
we we have to think of this universe
that we are living in.
Our planet Earth is part of the solar
system, as you all know. And by the way
I'm going to talk to you strictly about
scientific facts, established scientific
facts.
This earth is part of the solar system.
It is the only planet in the solar
system that has life. We went to the moon
and we didn't see a single tree there, or
a mouse, nothing. We sent cameras to
Mars and we didn't see a creature there,
unless those rocks are creatures, as we
saw in one of the cartoons. There is no
life in the solar system except here on
the planet Earth.
Our sun, the center of this solar system,
is 93 million miles away - now I want you
to watch these distances - 93 million miles
away from us, the Sun. And the light comes
to us from the Sun in four minutes, so
remember this relationship, the light
travels from the Sun to the Earth;
93 million miles in four minutes.
The solar system itself spans a distance
of two billion to four billion miles.
This is our solar system. So when you go
to the edge of our solar system - if you
travel two billion (with a B) - two
billion miles away,
how big is the planet Earth from that
point?
It would seem small.
Okay let us now go a little further, let
us talk about the galaxy, our galaxy.
As you know it is called the Milky Way
galaxy. And the solar system is one - the
Sun of the solar system is one of one
billion suns, of stars, in our Milky Way
galaxy.
It will take four minutes for the light
to travel from the Sun to the planet
Earth, 93 million miles. Do you know how long it will take to cross the Milky Way
galaxy? If you travel at the speed of
light you will cross the Milky Way
galaxy, our galaxy, in a hundred thousand
years. Not four minutes, or ten minutes, or
one hour, or ten hours, or ten days, or 10
years.
It will take you a hundred thousand
years to travel across the Milky Way
galaxy, our galaxy.
Now, so if you go to the border, the edge
of the Milky Way galaxy and try to find
the planet Earth, where is it?
it is minute isn't it? Just a tiny mote,
you know when you look at the sunlight
and see these little things flying? Those
are called motes, and the Earth is not even
that within the Milky Way galaxy.
Well let us travel - let us go on a little bit further, let us go to our
next-door galaxy, our neighbor.
You know how far it is? our neighbor
galaxy?
Two million light years away.
So if you're cooking something and you
want to borrow some salt or some sugar
from your neighbors, don't go to the
next-door galaxy, it will take you two
million years going at the speed of
light, and two million years coming at
the speed of light and your cooker will
be all gone.
So 2 million light-years, from our galaxy
to the next-door galaxy.
Now, so if you go to the next-door
galaxy and try to find the planet Earth
in the Milky Way, what are your
chances of seeing the planet Earth using
the strongest possible imaginable
telescope, can you find the planet Earth?
how about your house? or you? or any human being like Jesus or Muhammad?
Can you see that from that galaxy? our
next door galaxy?
Shall we move a little further?
There are 1 billion galaxies in our
universe.
This is one billion (with a B).
A billion trillion stars in our galaxy -
in our universe, excuse me. There are 1
billion galaxies in our universe.
A billion trillion stars in our universe.
Our universe now has distances of
10-15 up to 26 billion light-years,
distances within our universe.
And you can easily imagine this now. If
our next-door galaxy - and these are all, I
remind you, these are all scientific
established scientific facts.
26 billion light years within our
universe.
You have to agree with me that
when you go to the edge of our universe
it is hopeless to try to find the planet
Earth, it is such an insignificant speck
in God's kingdom.
It was an established physical fact that
when you go, if you go to the edge of our
universe you cannot possibly see the
planet Earth, you cannot possibly see the
Sun of our solar system, let alone the planet
Earth. So that's our universe. Before we leave
our universe - that's the next step - I
would like to remind you that -
in fact I will do a calculation thing with you right now.
Let us say the number of stars in our
universe is not a billion trillion,
let us take a smaller number;
quintillion, quintillion that's a smaller
number of stars in our universe. And let
us count from one to quintillion.
Taking one second per count, it's like, let
us say we're counting the stars 1 2 3 4
1 second per count. So we take 1
quintillion, divided by 60, you'll get the
number of minutes it will take you to
count from 1 to quintillion. Then you take
this number and divide by 60 again, you
get the number of hours it will take us
to count from 1 to quintillion. Now you take
this last product and divide by 24 and
you get the number of days it will take
you to count
from one to quintillion.
These are physical facts as you see, it is
just a simple dividing by the seconds,
the minutes, the hours, and the days.
Divide by seven you get the number of weeks then you divide by four you get the number of
months, you divide by 12 you get the
number of years it will take you to
count, just count, a quintillion stars. Do you
know how long it will take you? how many
years? this is a mathematical physical
fact - it will take you 32 billion (with a B)
32 billion years just to count a quintillion stars in our
universe.
And God created them.
God didn't just count them, God created
them. And we are talking only about
stars in our universe, we are not talking
about the planets that go with those stars.
We're not talking about the
uncountable gazillions of heavenly
bodies and meteorites that are in our
universe, we are talking only about stars.
The Sun is one of the stars, our Sun. By
the way, it is one of the dim stars.
The bright stars - the definition of a bright star is it must be at least 1
million times as bright as our Sun. Look
outside and see how bright the Sun is.
A bright star has to be a million times
as bright as this, as our Sun.
We had a conference here at the
University of Arizona that dealt with
bright stars only, and the Sun was not one
of them because by definition a bright
star is a million times as bright as our
Sun.
So it will take you 32 billion
years just to count, not to create - just
to count a quintillion of the billion
trillion stars we have in our universe.
That's our universe. Now prepare for a chock.
This universe, our universe - vast as we
can imagine - is only one of seven
universes.
And it is the smallest and innermost
of the seven universes. This is a fact
that is in the Quran, proven by the Quran's
mathematical code.
We are all now familiar with the
mathematical code of the Quran that
proves that every word is from God. That
it is not written by a human being. That it
is God's word, God's message to the world
and this mathematically proven
statements say that our universe, with its billion
trillion stars, a billion galaxies, 26
billion light year distances, is the
smallest and innermost of seven
universes.
Can you imagine how big the second
universe is if our universe is 26
billion light years across? The second
universe, can you imagine how big it is?
How about the third universe? The fourth that is around these? You can imagine seven
balls inside each other. The fifth
universe I don't think you can imagine the
size of the fifth universe.
How about the sixth universe and the
seventh?
I can tell you right now there is no
number in the world that can describe or
measure the circumference of the seventh
universe - actually the first universe, we
are the seventh universe, the inner most
of the seven universes.
There is no number that will describe
the circumference
of the first universe. Now prepare for
another shock. Most of you are familiar
with that statement in the Quran in sura
39, where God says he is holding the seven
universes within the fist of His hand.
In Arabic in the Quran; wassamaawaatu
matwiyyaatum biyameenih
God was not holding the seven universes
like this in two hands. God is holding the
seven universes in one hand and this is
allegorical description
to give us an idea about the
greatness of God and who God is.
It's an allegorical idea to make us
appreciate the greatness of God.
And to make us appreciate and realize
the blasphemy of saying that such great
God has a human son on the tiny tiny
speck called the planet Earth.
I mean how can that be?
We are a fortunate generation, in that
with the established scientific facts we
can appreciate the greatness of God.
And God tells us who He is and His
message to the world, the Quran.
And with the sciences we now accomplished we appreciate that greatness.
And therefore we can appreciate the
grossness, the blasphemy of saying that
God had a wife or a mother or a son.
We can appreciate - we can realize how
blasphemous, how terrible it is to
say that God has a partner, another God
with him.
How can we idolize Muhammad the tiny
human being who existed on a tiny planet
called Earth in a tiny solar system.
What was Muhammad's role in deciding the
speed of rotation of the moon
for example.
The moon rotates around itself and
around the Earth, yet we always see one
side of the moon, the same side of the
Moon.
Because of the perfect synchronized
movement of the moon around itself and
around the Earth we see only one side.
And if that movement was off by one
second we would see the other side of
the moon.
This precision in God's creation - what
was the role of Muhammad or Jesus or
Mary or son Francis
in deciding that speed of rotation of
the moon, this elaborate system,
everything going in its orbit precisely.
We know exactly what time the Sun will
rise in the year 2025, July 4 2025.
We know exactly, in Tucson Arizona for
example, we know exactly what time
the Sun rise and from what spot,
because the Sun follows God's laws, God's
creation, and follows the exact orbit.
God is holding the seven universes in
His hand.
That's who God is.
Man has always believed in some kind of
a god.
This need to believe in a supernatural
and omnipotent being led many to search
for a god, start wars in the name of a
god, even create a god if they had to.
Hello my name is Bill Buck. In this
report we are going to present to you what
we call the ultimate miracle.
You see, when man chose to believe in
gods most of these gods had one thing
in common, it was required that they be
feared worshiped served and revered.
Numerous religions sprang up to serve
these gods.
Some of the oldest religions still exist
today namely Buddhism, Hinduism, and
Shintoism. Some of these religions believe
in many gods, for example a god of fire,
a god of water, a god of love, a god of
prosperity and so on.
Then came the monotheistic religions,
those that believe in one god. All of
which are considered major influences in
global history and affairs.
These are Judaism, Christianity, and Islam.
And significantly they share a common
belief in one global history and affairs.
These are Judaism, Christianity, and Islam.
And significantly they share a common
belief in one supreme god. Perhaps the
best way to portray these is to look at
Jerusalem where all three religions
mingle. We have a historical account of
biblical and other prophets and the
miracles that they are credited with
having performed. There was Moses who we are
told talked to God and led the Jews out
of bondage and brought them the Ten
Commandments. He even parted the Red Sea
when pursued by Pharaoh and his troops.
According to the Bible there was Jesus
Christ who is the son of the Living God
to Christians, through him Christians
entered into a new covenant with their
creator.
Lastly, there was Muhammad. Muslim history
tells us that in Mecca God revealed to
him the Quran, the Muslim holy book. Which
is recited fervently and followed by
one-fifth of the world's population.
For many centuries and in spite of man's
experience with religion, there still
remained many mysteries. The most
baffling and complex mystery of all
remains the identity and the concept of
this god that man has never seen and yet
believes in so religiously. This sea of
religious confusion has been swelling
all the time, many religions all claiming
to be right began to break into sects.
During all this time man was advancing
economically, socially, militarily, and
intellectually. Man continued to advance
technologically at an unprecedented pace.
But in terms of religion he was still in
this sea of confusion, often misled by
tricksters and deeply disappointed with
his unanswered prayers to this unseen
God. Disappointment and confusion led
many to lose their belief. Agnosticism
and atheism have become widespread. Many now openly reject or at least question
the existence of this god who has been
so popular throughout the ages. The
theory of Darwin became the accepted
opinion of many scientists and scholars
who were able to draw supportable
conclusions from the proof and arguments
presented. But now most scientific and
religious thinkers realized that there
are deeper questions. So where does that
leave us, are there any real solutions to
this religious dilemma? On the one hand
the man cannot accept the illogical
practices that religion dictates to him.
Yet, by denying God man still doesn't
find the answers to some of his most
burning questions, such as; Who am I? why
am I here? is there a god? what is
purpose of life? Just when man's tolerance
to manual labor reached a limit and the
Industrial Revolution lay around the
corner,
now an intellectually enlightening
revolution seems to be around the corner.
Previous generations were converted to
believe in God by means of miracles,
however, modern man cannot believe in God
because of these, he has watched men walk
on the moon. He is presented daily with
the latest technological marvel, he has
come across too many false claims, fake
miracles, and fake promises. He has become
very cynical - especially when it comes to
ancient myths and beliefs. With some
arrogance he believes that he knows more
than his forefathers, let alone those
ancient reporters of fantastic events. He
wonders what they would have thought of
some of today's miracles. Today's man
needs something substantial,
he needs an ultimate miracle. All the
miracles that were supposed to have
converted man over the ages were limited
to a particular geographical location or
a time period. By definition, an ultimate
miracle would be something that is
perpetual not limited to a certain
century or a geographical location. It
would be for all of the people to see,
all of the time. It would be something
that is physical, touchable, examinable,
verifiable and irrefutable. A few years
ago noted scientists and television
personality Carl Sagan in his
best-selling novel talked about a
mathematically coded message from outer
space, on page 431 the author states "my
fondest hope for this book is that it
will be made obsolete by the pace of
real scientific discovery" well it seems
that Carl Sagan's fondest hope has come
true. Research over the past few years
has uncovered just such a mathematical
code in a document that is over 1,400
years old. There are other miraculous
aspects to this document.
For instance, only in the past 20 years
has science been able to witness the
development of the fetus in the very
early stages, however, 1,400 years ago the
development of the fetus and the first
28 days had already been documented and
with such graphic accuracy that it left
Dr. Moore - chairman of the anatomy
department of the University of Toronto -
utterly amazed, for at this stage the
embryo is only about one tenth of a
millimeter long and would appear like a
dot to the human eye. To discern its
shape would require a powerful
microscope, however, microscopes were not developed
until the 17th century and yet 1,400
years ago we find the following:
"thereafter we created of the drop a
thing which clings, a leech like
structure" - Dr. Moore confirmed that the
embryo does in fact cling to the wall of
the uterus. Another passage describes the
stages of fetus development: "God makes
you in the wombs of your mothers in
stages one after another
within three veils of darkness" - Dr. Moore
confirmed the accuracy of this
description also, he explained that the
three veils could reasonably be
interpreted to mean the mother's
abdominal wall, the wall of the uterus
and the amino chorionic membrane. It goes
on. We've all heard about the big bang
theory but who would expect to find an
account about the Big Bang Theory 1,400
years ago but there it is:
d"o the disbelievers not realize that the
heavens and the earth used to be one
entity then we parted them" - the
separation process resulted in the
formation of multiple worlds. The mention
of these worlds has made several times
in the document, also it would seem that
the modern discovery of bridges of
matter which are present outside
organized astronomical systems is
referenced in the verse which reads: "God
is the one who created the heavens the
earth and what is between them today we
will only preserve your body to set you
up as a sign for subsequent generations
indeed most people are heedless of our
signs" - miraculously it seems that the
Egyptians were exclusively gifted with
the science of mummification. In 1898
Laurier discovered the mummified body of
Ramses ii of Thebes in the Valley of
Kings, where it had lain untouched for
three thousand years.
He had it transported to Cairo where it
may be seen to this day. The medical
study of the mummy of Merneptah, Pharaoh of the exodus, has yielded further useful
information on the possible cause of
this pharaohs death.
The lack of signs of deterioration of
the body proves that the body did not
stay in water for a prolonged period of
time. And in the heavens, for many
centuries it was believed that the moon
had its own light - science discovered not
too long ago, that the moon really did
not generate its own light, but acted
only as a reflector of the Sun's rays.
"God is the one who made the Sun
luminescent and the moon alight, and he
designed its phases to provide you with
a timing device. God did not create all
this in vain.
God is the one who created the night, the
day, the Sun, and the moon, each one is
travelling in an orbit with its own
motion". Today it is known how the
celestial organization is balanced by
the position of stars in a defined orbit,
and how the interplay of gravitational
forces is related to their mass and
speed of movement each with its own
motion. Sir Francis Drake proved the
Earth to be round when he sailed around
it in 1597. "Are you more difficult to
create than the heaven that He built? He
raised its masses and perfected it. He
made its night dark and it's morning
visible. Thereafter He made the Earth
egg-shaped" - that was written almost a
thousand years before Columbus. We know
now that the Earth's atmosphere acts as
a filter to prevent harmful radiations
from reaching the surface. Short
wavelengths like x-rays and ultraviolet
rays are filtered out at high altitudes.
Protection from these rays is vital to
the existence of life on Earth. "And we
made the sky a protected ceiling".
Then there is the affirmation of the
modern idea that the origin of life is a
aquatic. "And we made water a requisite for
every living thing". Water is the simplest
chemical compound of importance to all
living things. Most organisms consist
of 50 to 95 percent water. Scientists know
that absolutely every living entity
known to man requires water for its
existence. Many properties of water make
it essential to life's processes. Its
ability to dissolve a great variety of
substances is vital because most
chemical reactions within organisms can
occur only in a water solution. Take the
field honeybee, busy bringing in nectar
from flowers, on entering the hive with a
full honey sac - which is an enlargement of
the esophagus - the field bee regurgitates
the contents into the mouths of young
workers called house or nurse bees. These in turn deposit nectar in a cell and carry
out the tasks necessary to convert the
nectar to honey. This we have known for
about 80 years. "And your Lord inspired
the bee, build homes in the mountains
and the trees and what the people build
for you and then eat from all kinds of
crops and obediently follow the designs
of your Lord, out of their bellies comes
a liquid of various colors wherein there
is healing for the people this should be
a sign for those who reflect."
Remember, this statement was made 1,400
years ago. How in the world could
somebody have known 1400 years ago that
honey came from the belly of the bee.
This document also claims that there is
a healing property in honey, honey does
in fact have mild antiseptic properties.
The Russians used honey to cover their
wounds in World War two, the wounds
retained an amount of moisture and left
very little scar tissue. Because of its
density no fungus or bacteria could grow
in the wound. It is also known that if a
person suffering from allergies from a
certain plant is given honey produced
from that plant, that person builds up
certain resistance to the algae. 1,000
years before the discovery of the
circulation of blood and roughly 13
centuries before it was known what
happens in the intestine to ensure that
the organs are nourished by the process
of digestive absorption we find a verse
in the document: "from between the urine and the blood comes pure, delicious milk."
Only recently was it found that
from what the cow eats there is a
separation of nutrients into the blood
and the urine and the remainder ends up
as milk. Progress in botany 1400 years
ago was nowhere advanced enough for it
to establish as a rule that plants have
both male and female parts, nevertheless
we read in the document:
"God is the one who sent water down from
the sky and thereby
brought forth pairs of plants, each separate from
the other". Today we know that fruit comes
from plants that have sexual
characteristics, even when it comes from
unfertilized fruits like bananas. "Of all
fruits God placed on the Earth two of a pair". This document stated to early man
the remarkable premise that mountains
move like the clouds, we know this to be
true now since the Earth rotates around
its axis and around the Sun, but to an
ancient, what could be more contradictory
to the obvious than that mountains move
and yet: "When you look at the mountains
you may think that they are standing
still. But they are moving in the same manner as the clouds. Such is the creation of God."
We know now of continental drift, a
folding which forms mountain ranges. The
Earth's crust is like a solid shell on
which we can live while the deeper
layers are hot and fluid. "Have we not
made the Earth an expanse and the
mountains stakes." The stake like
stability of the mountains is linked to
the folding phenomenon in that the folds
provide the foundations for the reliefs
that form the mountains.
From this aspect they are indeed like
tent stakes driven deep into the
ground. "He makes his chest straightened
like one who climbs towards the sky".
Fingerprinting became a scientific
method of identification in the 1880s
with the research of Sir Francis Dalton.
Dalton calculated mathematically that no
two persons could have exactly the same
fingerprint patterns. "We can even
reconstruct the tip of his finger." All of these scientific
phenomena have been taken from the same
book, other examples contain infinitely
more precious data which directly relate
to facts discovered by modern science,
but it took modern computers to discover
them. It is only now that the numerous
verses of this text have finally become
comprehensible. dr. Maurice Bucaille,
an eminent french scientist, says that
it is impossible to explain how a text
produced 1400 years ago could have
contained ideas that have only been
discovered in modern times. Many other
scientific phenomena; the barrier between
salt and freshwater, the branch-like
progression of combustion, all were
mentioned 1,400 years ago. In a notable
recent experiment conducted by Nova, it
was found that at the exact moment of
death there is a slight weight loss in
humans, but not animals. This document
states that at the moment of death God
takes the soul away and now we come to
the most incredible significance of
these discoveries. remember we said that
modern man needs an ultimate miracle to
release himself from the bondage of
religious frustration and confusion
about his creator. Well it so happens
that this ultimate miracle does exist in
this document, the identity of which we
are about to reveal. This ultimate
miracle exists in the form of a
scientifically proven mathematical code
that is touchable, examinable, verifiable,
and utterly irrefutable.
Not only does it prove that the author
of this divine document is God Almighty,
but it also serves as the first physical
evidence for the very existence of God.
And it serves as a means for
preservation for the document itself, so
that the reader knows that every word,
indeed every letter is from God Almighty.
This document is correct and the
ultimate miracle is the perfect and
unchallengeable mathematical code. This
mathematical code, this signature of the
Creator, has always been here in the
Quran for all to see. But only recently
was it revealed and then only with the
help of a modern computer by dr. Rashad
Khalifa, the Imam or minister of the
mosque of Tucson. Briefly let me explain,
the Quran consists of 114 chapters, 29 of
these chapters are prefixed with letters
that remained mysterious for 1,400 years,
nobody knew what they meant until now.
Before we go into details of this let us
look at a simple example that will allow
us to realize the magnitude of this
miracle. Take a simple sentence like "Jack
and Jill went up the hill" there are
7 words and 24 letters in
this sentence and this is called the
simple mathematical structure of this
sentence. Now let us try and change this
mathematical structure but still try and
convey a specific meaning in good
English. Let us say we want to convey the
same meaning with a sentence containing
7 words and 26 letters.
We must pad 2 letters in "Jack and Jill
went up the hill", in trying to do this we
soon see that the word "Jack" and the word
"Jill" cannot be changed. The word "over"
cannot be substituted for "up" because it
conveys a separate meaning. Similarly the
word "tha" cannot be replaced by "a" because a hill refers to any hill. In other words,
it becomes pretty difficult to change
the mathematical structure of a simple
sentence and still have an accurate and
acceptable statement in English. Now how
about if we try and group sentences
that conveys specific meanings into a
mathematical pattern, not only
controlling the count of total letters,
but also the count of specific letters
within words. Suppose we want to take
"Jack and Jill went up the hill to fetch
a pail of water" and change the total
number of "A" plus the total number of
"I" to 9 instead of 8. There are
7 words containing the letters "A" and
"I" that make perfect English and cannot
be changed so we can only try and change
the rest of the words, but this will
again convey a different meaning to the
sentence. It quickly becomes apparent
that changing this structure to fit a
pattern is almost impossible for just
one sentence. Prepare for the shock, the
document, the Quran contains an
exquisitely sophisticated control of
letters across chapters, within chapters,
in combination of letters, between words,
in total number of sentences, in total
number of words, all interlocking with
one another -
rendering it impossible to duplicate
even with the most powerful computers.
Yet it remains very simple to understand,
for example 29 chapters roughly 160,000
letters are prefixed by mysterious
letters. Chapter 50 starts with just Q.
Chapter 2 has ALM. Chapter 19 has 5
letters as a prefix KHYAS. Please note
that we have chosen English equivalents
of the Arabic letters for simplicity of
illustration. It was found that the
letter Q occurs in chapter 50 exactly 57
times or 19 times 3. The "A" "L" &amp; "M"
in chapter 2 occur a total of
9899 times and so on, without a single exception in
all the initialed chapters, with the
occurrences in multiples of the number
19.
At the same time that the "A" "L" &amp; "M"
are controlled in 7 chapters that
have ALM as a prefix, the A's and the
"L" are part of the Arabic word for God,
the occurrence of which is also being
controlled as you will soon see. At once
we realize that there is a deliberate
superhuman design that binds the book's
chapters, verses, words, even letters, for
if one letter was changed, deleted, or
added, the whole system collapses. And the
fact that this system was discovered
1,400 years after its
creation proves that it has been
perfectly preserved. The foundation of
this mathematical code is the opening
statement: "In the name of God most
gracious most merciful" that this
contains exactly 38 alphabets or 19
times 2. In the language of the Quran,
Arabic, it contains exactly 19 alphabets
and 4 words, these 4 words - namely
"name" "God" "most gracious" and "most
merciful" appear in the whole book 19,
2698, 57, and 114 times
respectively - all these are multiples of
19. The total number of verses are 6346,
the total chapters are 114 - again,
multiples of 19. We are beginning to see
that this unique code must have been
pretty difficult to construct. "On it are
19 -  indeed by the moon, by the night as
it passes, by the morning as it shines,
this is one of the greatest miracles."
Greatest miracle indeed, and now we
realize that 19 is the creator's
signature on everything He created, for
example - you and I have 209 bones in our
bodies 19 times 11, a full-term fetus
remains in the mother's womb 266 days 19
times 14, the Sun the Moon the Earth
line up in the same position every 19
years, and on and on and on.
The viewer may wonder: why 19? well using our ancestral
system of numerology the Arabic and
Hebrew word for one has a value of 19.
And this is what the message of Quran is -
one, one God, and one Brotherhood of
Nations under God. The Quran was written
under God's direction. One thing is clear,
no human being could have written such a
complicated and perfectly mathematically
coded text, not then, not now - even with
the aid of computers. One of the most
important functions of the Qurans
mathematical code is that it proves and
authenticates by physical evidence all
the miracles of the previous prophets
and messengers. Moses parted the Red Sea,
Jesus revived the dead and healed the
hopelessly blind and the lepers and so
on. Now these miracles are mathematically
composed within the Quran and proven by
this code to be true, God was the witness.
His words are divine and what He has
proven by means of the ultimate miracle,
is that the Quran is indeed His word,
the Word of God. Therefore let us look to
it to answer some of our most crucial
questions such as why are there famines,
disasters, and diseases, and what is the
overall purpose and meaning of life, and
what of peace, that elusive dream of the
righteous universal man. Given now that
the message of the Quran is one, one God,
one Brotherhood - Think of it.
All the power and love in the universe
in one Supreme Being who has assured us
that He not only exists but communicates
without question to those who believe
and seek out the truth. His laws and
commitment. Imagine what can be achieved
by following his laws and directions.