[Music]
in the name of God the most gracious the
most merciful
we are recording this program in January
of 1986
a couple of months ago around November
1985 a book appeared in bookstores
across the nation that soon became a
best-seller
the book is a fictitious novel narrating
the arrival monitoring of a coded
message from outer space
that proved the existence of a super
intelligence out there trying to contact
us on earth
the message was decoded by computers
and the novel this fictitious novel even
supports all time religions belief in
God
the novel is contact
you probably saw this book
contact by Carl Sagan
and there are only four quotations that
I would like to share with you in this
book the first quotation appears on the
front flap of the book and it says
in contact Carl Sagan who's cosmos
enthralled millions of readers and
television viewers has brilliantly
employed the freedom of fiction to
imagine the greatest adventure of all
humanity's first encounter with other
intelligent beings
the second quotation appears on page 219
and it describes the computer decoding
of this message as
this is though this is only the most
amazing discovery in the history of the
world
let me repeat this quotation it
describes the computer decoding of the
message like this this is only the most
amazing discovery in the history of the
world
the third quotation that I would like to
share with you appears at the end of the
novel page 430
where we find the conclusion of the
whole novel
and here it is there is and intelligence
that antedates the universe in other
words the novel is trying to say that
there is God out there
there is an intelligence that antedates
the universe the last quotation that I
wish to share with you
is NaN fictitious it is not fiction I
thought it is Carl Sagan's notes at the
end of the book
Carl Sagan says in his in the author's
note my fondest hope for this book is
that it will be made obsolete by the
pace of real scientific discovery
well ladies and gentlemen Carl Sagan's
fondest hope has just come through
in the next 50 minutes or so I will
share with you the real scientific
discovery of a coded message from outer
space from deep space and the message
will represent the first physical
evidence ever for the existence of God
we have been talking about God and those
who believe in God have been presenting
circumstantial evidence but now we are
going to witness a miracle we are going
to witness
physical evidence the first
incontrovertible evidence that God
exists and we are going to see this
proof through
the real scientific discovery of a coded
message that came to us and could never
be human-made
before I get to the historical
development of this message and the
monitoring and decoding of it I would
like to make a couple of statements that
I consider very important
the first statement is that every
utterance you are going to hear in this
program
is a proven scientific fact
every statement you are going to hear is
proven by means of a mathematical code
that gives us provides us with physical
evidence that every statement is correct
it is very important that you have full
confidence that every statement here
is proven
by physical evidence
the reason I'm saying this is that some
of the statements you are going to hear
have in the past
provoked ridicule or snickering or some
laughter this will no longer be the case
you see the message came to this world
in many parts and the first part came to
us through the first man Adam Adam was
created by God and he knew about God and
when he came to this world he
transmitted the first portion of the
message
the purpose of the message as you will
see is to tell us where we came from why
we are here where we are going the
purpose of our existence
so Adam taught his children and
grandchildren about God and everything
he knew about the creation of Adam the
creation of the human being the creation
of his wife Eve and how he came from up
there to the planet Earth that is a very
important part of the message the
message
afterwards came to us through every
messenger of God Noah Abraham Moses
Jesus Mohammed and I will go through the
stages of development of the message and
show you the mathematical code that was
embedded in these messages
[Music]
what happened was that God picked out
from every generation a human being
through whom God sent part of the
message we are talking about one and the
same message
Abraham Moses David Solomon Jesus
Muhammad all these people received parts
of one and the same message and as a
proof of authenticity as it turns out
and as you will witness in this program
God incorporated in his message to us an
intricate mathematical code intricate
beyond human ability just to prove that
this message is not fabricated by any
human being
contributed a good portion of that
message
and you know
you probably watch the movie the Ten
Commandments
you know that Moses was walking in the
desert when he saw the burning bush and
God communicated with Moses
God communicated part of that message it
was a very significant part part that we
call today the Torah
you saw in the movie and you read in the
Bible how the tablets were were written
were recorded that the scripture was
recorded on the tablet that scripture in
the language of Moses was mathematically
coded beyond the human ability and this
is what this program is all about the
discovery of a mathematical code
embedded within God's message to us
through his messengers
the first hint let me go back to Moses
when he carried the tablet with the
message on them the letters on that on
those tablets were counted according to
an intricate mathematical code the same
mathematical code that was discovered in
all the scriptures
the message given to Jesus in his
language Aramaic was also mathematically
coded in that language the alphabet
letters of that message were counted and
carefully placed
the whole message in aramaic was
composed according to a mathematical
pattern and this is the pattern that was
consistent through every part of the
message from Adam to Abraham Noah before
that Moses David Solomon Jesus Muhammad
the same mathematical code the letters
the words the verses everything was
calculated and carefully placed to prove
that the message is from God
the first hint of the discovery of a
mathematical code was at least what we
know of was announced about 10,000 years
ago and this was printed recently in a
book called studies in Jewish mysticism
studies in Jewish mysticism and I will
am going to read for you a quotation
from that book no change can be
tolerated in the text of the prayers not
even on my note one because every change
even of one letter
would destroy the numerical harmony
inherent in the text that was the first
hint of a mathematical code in God's
message to the world
here's another quotation from my the
same book and this quotation also was
written about 900 years ago
according to Rabbi Judah and the
Ashkenazi Hasidic school in general
there can be nothing accidental in the
Bible not even the forms of letters the
punctuation the vocalization and
especially in the numerical structures
how do you like that 900 years ago marks
the first discovery of a mathematical
code in the scriptures
and I will go through the details of
this amazing mathematical code and how
it penetrates and encodes the complete
scripture of God of course I'm talking
about the original scripture not edit
translation we are talking about the
original words of God in the languages
of God's messengers Adam Abraham Moses
David Solomon many many others
Jesus Muhammad and the original
scripture was coded according to this
very intricate miraculous system
[Music]
how in the world are we going to study
the original scriptures given to Abraham
Moses David Jesus and Muhammad
the mathematical code that God put in
his message to the world
is in the original scripture the
original words letters verses that were
written by God Almighty in those
scriptures in Abraham scripture in his
original language Moses scripture in his
original language and so on
how are we going to study the original
scripture given to Jesus in Aramaic his
language
well there is only one scripture in the
world today that is original and still
intact and that is the Quran back in the
year 610 ad God picked out a man named
Mohammed and communicated with us
through him by giving him the Quran and
Quran today is the only original intact
scripture in the original language as
written by God Almighty
the Quran represents the latest edition
of the scripture remember we are talking
about one and the same message
and the mathematical code that I will
share with you today
was through out the whole message
Tora in the Gospel of Jesus in the Quran
in the Psalms and the as I meant I
mentioned to you glimpses of the
mathematical code that were written
about about the thousand years ago
back in 1968 I noticed that the Quran
had
mysterious letters at the beginning of
certain chapters for example chapter 2
begins the first verses only three
letters a LM what is a LM I want them
29 chapters in Quran have these
mysterious letters chapter 50 is
entitled q let's set Q and this prefix
to the letter Q nothing else q
chapter 68 is prefixed with the letter N
chapter 36 is prefixed with the letter
letters Y s and so on these letters
remained mysterious for 1,400 years in
610 ad
when curiosity led me to put the Quran
in the computer just to find out what
these letters represent so I wrote the
Quran in the computer of course the
Quran in the original language is Arabic
remember and the computers when back in
1968 they didn't have Arabic computers
so what I did I took every Arabic letter
in the Quran and the I use an English
letter to represent the Arabic letter
and I put the whole scripture the final
edition of God's message to the world
in the computer then I asked the
computer for a number of mathematical
characteristics the number of every
little in every chapter the number of
numbers of words and the all kinds of
questions I had no idea what to expect
and when the computer was true and
answering my questions a very intricate
mathematical pattern emerged and fit
with the older findings of mathematical
codes in the original scriptures of
Moses Jesus David and and so on
the mathematical code that emerged
provides
the first physical evidence for the
existence of God
in fact
once you did you study this mathematical
pattern in detail and understand it you
will no longer believe in God you will
know that God exists you'llyou'll you
need faith no longer so that's how
intricate and how miraculous this met
this mathematical code is
[Music]
as it turns out these mysterious letters
have specific counts in their chapters
and there was one common denominator in
the whole scripture that is common to
all these letters we're talking about
exactly half the Quran the Quran is
about 500 pages of the regular-sized
pages and the mysterious letters prefix
29 chapters that represent in size
about half the Quran the Quran consists
of 114 chapters many of them are short
chapters but these mysterious letters
prefix about half the Quran and it
turned out that every single set of
these mysterious letters is found in
each chapter in multiples of 19 without
a single exception in other words the
letters are distributed within Quran
according to this intricate mathematical
pattern that is way beyond the human
ability
if you when you study it in detail you
will have no doubt whatsoever that there
is a mathematical system proving the
authenticity of Quran as God's message
to the world to be more accurate as God
final edition of the scripture his
message to the world so now let me give
you a few examples to demonstrate the
miraculous nature of this mathematical
code a chapter 50 for example in Quran
is entitled the Q as I mentioned before
and is prefixed with the letter Q when
you count the letter Q in that chapter
you will find 57 Q's in the whole
chapter that is 19 times 3 it's a
multiple of 19 and as I said every
single one of these mysterious letters
is found in its chapter and multiples of
19 there is another chapter in Quran one
other chapter that is also prefixed with
the letter Q and that is chapter 42 and
guess what even though chapter 42 of
Quran is more than twice as long as
chapter 50 it has the same number of Q
in it 57
so in 57 is 19 equals 3 so the only two
chapters in Quran that are prefixed with
the letter Q have exactly the same
number 57 and 57 and Q we are taught in
chapter 50 represents Quran Quran is
spelled with the heavy K in the Arabic
language which is represented by the
letter Q
only two chapters 57 and 57 the total is
114 and guess what this is the number of
chapters in Quran 114 19 times 6 the
letter n prefix is chapter 68 and when
we count the letter n in that chapter we
find 133 these as you notice are
physical facts it is not guesswork I am
NOT saying in my opinion chapter 68
contains 133 ends this is a physical
fact the chapter is initial with the
letter n prefixed with the initial N and
it contains 133 ends 133 is a multiple
of 19 it equals 19 times 7
chapter 36 for example is prefixed with
the letters Y s and when you count the
letters Y and s in this chapter the
total is 285 or 19 times 15 how do you
like that this means every letter Y
every letter s and this chapter is
counted calculated and harmonized with
the other initial chapters
there is also an interlocking
relationship between these letters
because you find these letters in a
number of chapters and they interlock
with each other
and all of them give you totals that are
multiples of 19 we will find out why 19
before the end of this program but at
this point I would like to quote for you
from Rabbi Judah the pious his writings
of about a thousand years ago and it
demonstrates the common denominator in
all the scriptures one and the same
message the Quran the gospel of Jesus
the Torah of Moses the Psalms of David
let me quote for you from rabbis Yuda
the pious when we find that the number
19 is the common denominator in all the
scriptures
here's what revised you that said nine
hundred years ago the people the Jews in
France made it a custom to add in the
morning prayer the words ASHRAE TV may
Derek
which means blessed are those who walk
the right righteous way and our rabbi
the pious of blessed memory wrote that
they were completely and utterly wrong
it is all gross falsehood because there
are only 19 times here it is
there are only 19 times that the holy
name is mentioned in that person of the
morning prayer and similarly you find
the word Elohim 19 times similarly you
find that Israel were called sons 19
times and there are many other examples
all these sets of 1919 here we go
our intricate intricately intertwined
and they contain many secrets and
esoteric meanings which are contained in
northern eight large volumes so this
this just to give you an idea that the
number 19 is the common denominator in
all portions of the message God's
message to the world
[Music]
[Laughter]
ladies and gentlemen it is impossible
statistically impossible to write a book
with this kind of mathematical
composition where every letter every
word is calculated and carefully placed
according to a mathematical pattern that
is clearly beyond human ability we find
this mathematical pattern in God's
Scripture the one and the same message
in Quran and in previous scriptures I
just gave you the example of from the
Torah as written by Rabbi Judah the
pious
[Music]
and now we come to the big question why
19 in the older scripture as well as in
the Quran why is 19 the common
denominator of God's message to the
world from the time of Adam until now
and why did it have to wait you see when
the rabbi Judah discovered the number 19
in the older of scriptures he didn't
know who I 19 as you recall when I
quoted him he said there is a secret and
the great esoteric meaning to the number
19 but he didn't know who I because this
question had to wait until the
completion of God's message to the world
by revealing the final edition the Quran
in the Arabic language
you see 19
is the numerical value of the word one
in Arabic and this is the whole essence
of the scripture that there is one God
that we shall worship only the one God
in Arabic the world 1
is little like this it is pronounced
wah-wah and at the time of Revelation of
Quran there were no numbers as we know
them today they use the alphabet letters
as numbers
so the numbers would not existent this
is a relatively recent invention the
numbers so let us go through this word
in Arabic the world one overhead and see
how the numerical value equals 19 the
first letter in this world
y course was 6 in those days it was the
letter Y and also the number 6 this is
the letter A and it represents the
numeral 1
this is the letter half which
represented the numeral eight finally
the letter B where ahead a letter D was
four and if you add the total six plus
one is seven 7 plus 8 is 15 15 plus 4 is
19 so there is the total the numerical
value of the word one in Arabic and now
with the completion of the Scriptures
through the revelation of Quran we know
why 1919 they common denominator of the
mathematical code throughout the
Scriptures means one God is one
what is more important that the
mathematical code is the content of the
message itself
because the message being from our
Creator tells us who we are where we
came from where we are going and why we
are here what is the purpose of our life
these are the most important questions
as far as any human being is concerned
and now we have the answers from the
most authoritative source the Creator
himself
naturally we cannot discuss all the
contents of the message in one program
hopefully in a series of programs we
will present to you the contents of the
message but for now let me deal with
just one question
who is God
who is the one who created you and me
there is a specific one who created you
and me and the whole universe there is a
certain one that we should know who is
the omnipotent omnipresent omniscient
God who runs this universe who is he
the Quran describes God as following
you see this planet Earth is part of the
Milky Way galaxy and the Milky Way
galaxy is so huge that it takes 30,000
light years if you travel at the speed
of light it will take you thirty
thousand years to reach the outer limit
of the Milky Way galaxy our galaxy
and our universe contains 1 billion
galaxies like the Milky Way a billion
trillion stars these numbers are actual
scientific numbers the astronomers the
scientists stopped counting at 1 billion
galaxies in our universe and the billion
trillion stars that's how big our
universe is
we now measure 26 billion light years
within our universe twenty-six thousand
millions of light years within our
universe
and the Quran God tells us in Quran that
there are seven universes
the billion trillion stars
they're 1 billion galaxies the 26
billion light years are only within the
smallest and innermost of seven
universes this is how God describes the
universes you can imagine seven balls
inside each other and we live in the
smallest and innermost of the seven
universes
can you imagine the size of the second
universe
how about the third universe
the fourth the fifth the sixth and the
seventh universe how can we describe the
circumference of the seventh universe
infinity will be the most accurate
description of this the length of the
circumference of the seventh universe
and you know what
Quran describes God as holding the seven
universes in his right hand
that's who God is
God is holding the seven universes in
one hand it makes a difference whether
you are holding something in both hands
like this or within the fists of one
hand and in chapter 39 of Quran God
describes himself as holding the seven
universes in his right hand and this
tells you who God is
God is the one who created the Sun the
Moon the Stars the galaxies in the
extreme accuracy that you see the Sun
will rise tomorrow exactly at the
specific time from the specific place
because God designed it this way and he
is the only one who controls it
no other entity human or non-human
designed this universe so this is just
an example of the contents of the
message the message the goes on and
tells you exactly why you are here and
how to fulfill the purpose of your life
but we will get into these topics in the
future God willing and I hope you will
follow this series of programs meanwhile
if you have any questions please write
to me or call our address is seven three
nine East sixth Street Tucson Arizona
eight five seven one nine the telephone
is area code 602 seven nine one three
nine eight nine
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen my name is Rashad
Khalifa and what I'm about to share with
you is the most important news in the
history of the world because this is the
most important news
it comes with something unique something
never witnessed before a built-in
irrefutable proof of authenticity the
world's leaders are invited as well as
each and every one of you invited to
examine the evidence then take action in
accordance with this news here are the
headlines this year 1986 is the last
year to experience the world as we know
it today a new worldwide era or
worldwide system will begin sometime
between September 6 1986 and August 25th
1987 we are recording this bulletin on
May 15 1986 the new era will last 303
lunar years which is equivalent to two
hundred ninety four regular years after
which the world will come to an end in
other words after 300 years of a new era
the world will end in the year 2000 280
[Music]
up until now the world has served as the
testing ground for Satan's claim that he
can be a god besides God up until now
the world has been Satan's domain
Satan's incompetence as a God has been
proven by the abundance of misery
disease famine divorce oppression and
Wars in this world in the new era Satan
will throw up his arms and declare his
failure for thousands of years Satan has
been trying very hard to make his domain
the planet Earth a perfect place where
everyone enjoys perfect health
perfect wealth and perfect peace but he
just couldn't do it
while Satan's Kingdom is plagued with
misery disease famine poverty oppression
and Wars the upcoming era of God's
kingdom is characterized by perfect
health
perfect wealth and perfect peace and joy
to become a member in the upcoming
kingdom of God you must satisfy three
minimum requirements first you must
believe in the one true God as the
omnipotent omniscient and omnipresent
creator and sustainer of the universe
you must believe in the one true God the
specific one who actually created you
you must believe in the one true God
alone without idolization of any
creature of God such as Jesus or Mary or
Buddha or Muhammad or the saints the
definition of idol worship is believing
that anyone or anything other than God
can benefit you the second requirement
for membership and the upcoming kingdom
of God is to believe in the hereafter
resurrection after death heaven and hell
the third requirement is to lead a
righteous life and this means that you
are a person who is honest truthful nice
one who never hurts anyone
[Music]
Oh
so these are the three minimum
requirements for membership in God's
kingdom first to believe in God alone
without setting up any idols second to
believe in the Hereafter third to lead a
righteous life
this news bulletin confirms the
conclusions of the outstanding Christian
scholars who thoroughly researched the
Bible then concluded that Jesus is
neither God nor the Son of God
but a great teacher and the messenger of
God they published their findings in the
famous book the myth of God incarnates
[Music]
the next headline is actually an
invitation and a challenge to the
world's leaders to examine the evidence
the incontrovertible physical evidence
that comes through the world built into
this message I invite them to examine
the evidence then take whatever action
they deem necessary to save their own
necks and the necks of millions of
people who follow them
I invite Billy Graham to examine the
evidence then repent and save himself
and his millions of followers one of dr.
Graham's favorite statements is I know I
am going to heaven
well I have news for dr. Graham he will
see heaven only if he repents and
reverses the mobilisation of millions of
people against Jesus Christ and the
teachings of Jesus Christ I have no
doubt about the sincerity of dr. Graham
but I can show him physical evidence
proving that he has been used by Satan
to oppose Jesus Christ
I invite Billy Graham Pat Robertson
Jerry Falwell Robert Schuller Oral
Roberts Jimmy Swaggart and all
evangelists to joy in God's kingdom by
upholding the teachings of Jesus Christ
and by abstaining from offending Jesus
by calling him God or son of God
I invite the Pope to joy in God's
kingdom before it's too late
I call on Pope John Paul the second to
examine the evidence then lead his 1
billion followers out of Satan's grip
and into God's upcoming kingdom the Pope
is in contempt of God so long as he
idolizes Jesus Mary and the Saints
against their will
[Music]
robbery kushnir of boston has published
their book entitled when bad things
happen to good people this book exposed
Rabbi Kushner's denial of God's
omnipotence and revealed the reason why
Satan had victimized Rabbi Kushner and
his late son
I invite rabbi Kushner to break away
from his persecutor Satan and to joy in
God's kingdom by professing God's
omnipotence and by taking whatever
action necessary to retract his
blasphemies against God
[Music]
this bulletin declares that the Muslim
world has been in Satan's camp for 1,200
years the Muslims en masse have
abandoned the Word of God in favor of
man-made fabrications I invite the
leaders of the Islamic world to stop
misleading their 1 billion followers and
to joy in God's upcoming kingdom by
upholding the Word of God and nothing
but the words of God I must point out
that no one should ever think that I am
judging anyone only God is judged what I
uttered in this bulletin was God's
judgment not my judgment and God's
judgment is supported by its built-in
proof of authenticity that anyone can
examine and verify may God guide us all
towards membership in his eternal
Kingdom
[Music]