How this mathematical miracle of the
Quran was discovered? When I came to this
country, the United States, in 1968, I read
the English translations of the Quran
and I didn't like any of them. I read
them all, Yusuf Ali, Muhammad Ali,
Pickthall, Arberry, N. J. Dawood, and so
on. All of them, even as far back as
George Sale's translation. Some of them
actually distorted the basic doctrines
of the Quran and that was serious enough
to encourage me to translate the Quran
myself, for my own children. I did it just
for local consumption. However, because
I'm a chemist and not a professional
religionist,
I decided not to move from one verse to
the next unless I knew exactly what
every word and every verse meant. I made
a pledge to God that I will not move
from one verse to the next unless I know
exactly what it meant. So, I started the
translation and I finished the first
Surah, Al-Fãtehah
in seven days. Then, I moved on to the
next verse, the first verse of Sura
number two, Al-Baqarah.
And I found that it consisted of only
three letters:
ا ل م  = A.L.M. Of course, I knew this
all along since I was a young child, but
now I'm trying to translate it.
I wanted to know exactly what the
significance of A.L.M. is. I looked up all
the Tafseers, interpretations, and all
the books written about these letters
and everybody, all the scholars said "we
do not know what these letters mean." So, I
started my own research and after many
attempts and many failures, I decided to
put the whole Quran in the computer. I
didn't know what to look for. So, I had
the computer count every letter in every
Sura, and the objective was to look for
any mathematical connections or any
mathematical pattern between... that
involves these letters. There are 29
Suras in the Quran prefixed with these
initials, different sets of initials, 14 sets of
initials to be exact:
ا ل م,  نون, ص, ق, ط س م
ی س, ط ح, and so on, 14 of them. And sure enough, after 4 years of research
a mathematical pattern emerged
with a common denominator binding
all these initials without a single
exception. And the common denominator was
19. As it turned out, and as you will see
in this program, every element of the
Quran: the number of verses, the numbers
assigned to the Suras, numbers of words,
the letters, every letter in the Quran is
mathematically
composed beyond human capability. And the common denominator
that binds all these mathematical
physical facts is the number 19.
So, let us get down to business and look at the Quran itself. And I would like to remind
you that all the items you're going to
see are factual observations. They're all
physical facts in the Quran. So, here is a
big Quran that we can see together
and the first item of this miracle is that
the first verse in the Quran:
"Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem" consists of
19 Arabic letters. Here they are: 1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 19 letters. And the whole Quran has 114
Suras. As we see here, the last Sura is
number 114, and 114 is a multiple of 19,
19 times 6. And it consists of six verses, by the way.
So, 19 times 6 gives us the total
number of Suras in the Quran, 114.
Now, if we count from this Sura towards the other Suras, here is 1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18 and 19.
We find that number 19 is the first revelation in Quran, Sura number 96 and it says
(96:1) ٱقْرَأْ بِٱسْمِ رَبِّكَ ٱلَّذِى خَلَقَ
the first revelation. So, the first Sura revealed is
positioned, in the Quran, atop the last
19 Suras in the Quran. You also notice
that this Sura consists of 19 verses.
The first revelation was 19 words
exactly. Here they are: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9,
10, then go to the next page, 11, 12, 13, 14,
15, 16, 17, 18, 19. This was the first
revelation through the Prophet Muhammad,
and it consisted of 19 words. If you
count the letters in these 19 words, you
find that the total is 76, 19 times 4.
And if you count the letters in the whole Sura, the first
Sura revealed, you find that the total
is 285 letters, or 19 times 15.
The last Sura revealed was Sura number
110 and it consists also of 19 words.
Here they are: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19. So, the last
revelation and the first revelation
consisted of 19 words. Now, if you go back
to the very beginning, the first verse
in the Quran, as you heard before
the first verse of the Quran "Bism Allah
Arrahman Arraheem" consists of 19
letters. Every word, there are four words
here, and every word is mentioned in the
Quran a number of times which is
consistently a multiple of 19. The word
"ism" which means name is mentioned in the Quran 19 times, exactly.
If you wish to use the word "Bism", it
is mentioned three times, but if you add
the numbers assigned to the verses and
Suras where the 3 times of "Bism" occur, the
total is 114, 19 times 6. The second word
"Allah" is mentioned in the whole book
2698 times, or 19 times 142. The third word
"Arrahman" is mentioned in the whole
Quran 57 times, or 19 times 3.
The last word "Arraheem" is mentioned in the whole
book 114 times, or 19 times 6.
As you see, Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem,
the first verse in the Quran is very
important. And you will see it at the
beginning of every Sura in the Quran.
Every Sura has this "Bism Allah
Arrahman Arraheem" at the beginning except one.
However, only the first verse of the first
Sura is numbered. It has number one.
When you go to the other Suras, you
find that this opening statement has no
number. This is why we take only the
first opening statement to represent
all the Bismillahs in the Quran, all the
opening statements of the Quran. If you
go to Sura 9, you will notice that this
Sura does not have a Basmalah. It says
here that this Sura does not have Bismillah.
Now, since the Quran has 114 Suras, and
this one does not have an opening
statement, this will mean that we have
only 113 Basmalahs in the Quran, and this
number is not divisible by 19. But we
find that this missing Bismillah is made
up in Sura number 27. So, if you go to
surah number 27,
you will see that we have two "Bismillahs."
This is Sura number 27, and there is one
"Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem" at the
beginning, like every other surah except
Sura 9 and there is an extra one
in the middle of the Sura. Right here in
verse 30, you'll see another
"Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem." So, this Sura
contains two of them, two of the opening
statement or "Basmalahs", one at the
beginning and one in verse 30.
And this restores the number of this
important opening statement to 114
or 19 times 6.
Also, if you count the Suras from the
missing Bismillah of Sura 9... see, there's
the missing Bismillah of Sura 9.
And then we count the Suras from here to
the place where we find the extra
Bismillah. Here is one. This is number 1.
2 Suras, 3 Suras,
4, 5, 6, we are counting from the
missing Bismillah to the extra
Bismillah, this will be 7, 8, 9, 10, 11,
12,
13,
14, 15, 16, and 17,
we didn't get to Sura 27 yet. This is 25
which is the 17th Sura from the missing
Bismillah. Here is 18, and you'll find
that the Sura that has two Bismillahs,
Sura number 27, is Sura number 19. From
the missing "Bismillah" to the extra
"Bismillah", from Sura 9 to Sura 27, we
find exactly 19 Suras, inclusive.
This is the Sura that has two "Bismillahs" and it
is Sura number 19 after the missing
"Bismillah" of Sura 9. From the missing
"Bismillah" in Sura 9 to the extra
"Bismillah" in Sura 27, there are 19 Suras.
So, when you count the Suras from the
missing "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem" of
Sura 9 to the extra "Bismillah" in Sura
27, you find 19 Suras. Now, watch this:
if you add the numbers of the Suras, the
numbers assigned to the Suras, from 9
to 27, from the missing Bismillah to the
extra Bismillah, that is 9 plus 10
plus 11 plus 12 plus 13 all the way to
plus 26 plus 27,
the total is 342 which is a multiple of
19. It is 19 times 18. And this is half the
story. You add the numbers of the Suras
from the missing Bismillah to the extra
Bismillah 9 + 10 + 11 all the way to 27
the total, 342, is exactly the number of
words between the two Bismillahs of
Sura 27, the number of words, as you see
here. This total, 342, is exactly the
number of words between this Bismillah
in Sura 27, and the second Bismillah
of Sura 27. You count these words.
You count all these words and
you'll find that the total, up to this
word here, before the second Bismillah,
up to this word, the total is 342, which
equals the total of the numbers of Suras
from the missing Bismillah to this extra
Bismillah.
The number of verses "Ayat" in the Quran,
from the beginning, from the first AYA
or verse, to the very end,
to the last AYA is 6346, which is a
multiple of 19. The total number of
AYAT, verses, in the Quran
6346, or 19 times 334.
As I mentioned before, there are 29 Suras in Quran that are initialed with these Quranic
initials. And the first initial in the
Quran is in Sura number two, the first
verse:
(الم) A.L.M. The last initial is the
initial NuN (نون) in Sura number 68, which
is right here.
This initial here is the last initial.
This here is the first initial and this
is the last initial. The number of AYAT
or verses in this section here, from the
first initial to the last initial, is
5263 AYAT or verses, 19 times 277. You just
start at الم (A.L.M.), the first
Quranic initial, and you count all the
verses in here up to this verse in Sura
68, and you'll find that the total
is 5263, or 19 times 277.
Also, if you count the word "Allah"
in this section between the first
initial and the last initial, you'll
find that the total of the word "Allah"
here is 2641
which is a multiple of 19,
19 times 139. And of course,
if you count the word "Allah" outside of
this section, that will be here
and before الم (A.L.M.), the word "Allah" is
57 times, is found 57 times
or 19 times 3.
In the section from the first initial, الم (A.L.M.) to the last initial, NuN (نون),
there are exactly 38 Suras without
initials. The un-initialed Suras here are 38
which is a multiple of 19, 19 times 2. So,
this is another physical fact.
Now, I mentioned that outside of this section,
there are 57 word "Allah." That's outside
the initialed section of the Quran, in this
part and this part to the end. There are
57 words "Allah." If you add the numbers of
the Suras, the numbers assigned to the
Suras, like this number here, and the
numbers assigned to the verses, the total
is 2432, or 19 times 128. Now, I'm talking
about the numbers assigned to the Suras
and verses where you find the word "Allah"
outside of the initialed section. You add
these numbers assigned to the Suras and
to the verses wherever you find the
word "Allah", and the total is a multiple
of 19. Well, this proves that the numbers
assigned to the Suras and the numbers
assigned to the verses are from God,
not from humans.
The word "Al-Quran" is mentioned in
the Quran 57 times. That is 19 times 3.
Isn't that profound? And if you add the
numbers of the Suras and the numbers
of verses, where the word the Quran is found,
the total is 2660, which is 19 times
140. I'm talking about the numbers - for
example, this word here, Al-Quran, is in
Sura 17. See the Sura number is 17,
and the verse number is 45 as you see
here. You take these numbers, the 57 times
where the word Quran is found in the
Quran, and you add the numbers of the
verses and the numbers of the Suras,
altogether, the total is
2660, or 19 times 140.
There are other grammatical forms of
this word "Al-Quran" like "Al-Quranan" and "Al-Quranahu" and if you add all the
Suras and all the verses, the numbers of
the verses and the numbers of the Suras,
where these forms, different forms of the
word "Quran" is found, the grand total
is 3363, or 19 times 177. Of course, the word
"Quran" is very special and this is why it
is so intricately composed within the Quran.
The first pillar of Islam, mainly that
God is one, is mentioned in the Quran
exactly 19 times, that "Allah Wahid." God is
one, is mention in the Quran exactly
19 times. Now, there's also the word "Wahdahu", worship God alone.
This commandment to worship God alone "Wahdahu" is mentioned in the Quran five
times, and if you add the numbers of the
verses and the numbers of Suras where
the word "Wahdahu" worship God alone
occurs, the total is 361, or 19 times 19.
So, this emphasizes the importance of
worshiping God alone. The word "Wahid"
referring to God as one, is mentioned in the
Quran 19 times and the word "Wahdahu"
is mentioned 5 times, but when you add
the verses and Suras' numbers where this
word "Wahdahu" is found, the total is 361, 19 times 19.
For example, this word "Wahdahu" happens in verse 12
of Sura number 40. So, you take this
number 40 and the number of the
verse 12, and you do this every
time you see the word "Wahdahu" in the
Quran and the total is 361, 19 times 19.
The other 4 pillars of Islam, the Salat,
the Zakat, the Hajj and Siyam,
are mentioned in the Quran 114 times,
or 19 times 6.
Now, when you take the word "Salat" for
example, which happens in the Quran 67
times, and you take the numbers of verses
and the numbers of the Suras where
every time you see this word "Salat"
and you add them up, the total
is a multiple of 19. It is 4674, or 19
times 246, the word "Salat" throughout the
Quran. You add the verses and the numbers of the verses and the
numbers of Suras where the word "Salat" occurs, and the total is
4674, or 19 times 246.
If you go to the word "Zakat", you
find that "Zakat" and "Hajj", you add the
numbers of the verses and the numbers of
Suras where "Zakat" and "Hajj" are found,
and the total is 2888,
or 19 times 19 times 8. This is "Zakat" and
"Hajj" together. You add the numbers of the
verses and the numbers of the Suras
throughout the Quran where you see "Zakat" and "Hajj." When you look at the word
"Siyam" in the Quran, the whole Quran, the
fasting of Ramadan, you'll see that it
occurs 6 times. And if you add the
numbers of the verses to the numbers
of the Suras, every time you see this word
"Siyam" in all its forms, the total is
1387, or 19 times 37.
So, the basic pillars of Islam, the
numbers assigned to the Suras and
verses where these words are found,
all these numbers are multiples of 19.
The Sura entitled "Q" is also initialed with
the letter "Q." And when you count this
letter "Q", every time you see it, you
count it, in the Quran, in this Sura,
you'll find that the total of the letter
"Q" in this Sura is 57, or 19 times 3.
Also, the only other Sura initialed
with "Q", which is surah number 42 - there's
the letter "Q", as an initial - contains
the exact same number of "Q" as the
other Sura. So, you count this "Q"
and then you go and find this "Q" and
count it, and so on, this is a physical
fact. The total occurrence of the letter
"Q" in this Q-initialed Sura is also
57, 19 times 3. Now, when you go back to
Sura "Q" here, you notice that "Q"
is a symbol, or stands for Quran. "Q" stands
for Quran or "Q" here stands for Quran.
And if you add the 57 "Q" of
this Sura number 50, plus the 57 "Qaf"
or "Q" in Sura number 42, also 57,
57 plus 57 is 114, which is exactly the same
number as the Suras of Quran. 57 plus 57
equals 114, the number of Suras in Quran.
You notice that the Sura "Q"
is number 50 and it consists of 45
verses. If you add the number of the
Sura which is 50 to the number of verses
in the Sura which is 45, the total is 95
or 19 times 5. Well, this is half the
story. If you go to the only other Sura
initialed with "Q" which is Sura number 42,
you see that the number of verses is 53.
And if you add the number of the Sura
to the number of the verses, you get
exactly the same total as Sura "Q",
which is 95. 42 plus 53 is 95, or 19 times 5.
And with Sura "Q", 50, the number of
the Sura, plus the number of verses 45,
50 plus 45 is 95, or 19 times 5. In this
Sura, the Quran is described as "Majeed."
(50:1) قٓ ۚ وَٱلْقُرْءَانِ ٱلْمَجِيدِ
And this word "Majeed" has its numerical value is 57,
which is the number of the letter "Q"
in this Sura. "Majeed", the M is 30, the
Jeem is 3, the Ya is 10, and the Daal is 4,
and you add these numbers, 30, plus 3,
plus 10, plus 4 - the total is 57, 19 times
3. When the Quran was revealed, there were
no numbers. These letters were used as
numbers. So, you can look at the "Meem" as
the letter "Meem" or M, and also as the
numeral 30. The same with the other
letters. So, this is a universal
established system of... where the alphabet
letters are used as numbers. When we go
to Sura 68, which is initialed with the
letter "NuN", N, if you count the letter
N wherever you see it in this Sura,
you find that the total is 133,
19 times 7. In the Quran, there are three
Suras initialed with the letter "Saad." The
first one is Sura number 7.
It is initialed with the letters: Alef Lam Meem Saad (A.L.M.S.). The second Sura that's initialed
with this letter is Sura number 19,
Sura Maryam, which has five initials:
Kaf Ha Ya 'Ayn Saad. So, this is the
second Sura where we see the initial,
the letter Saad as an initial.
The third Sura initialed with this letter is Sura number 38, which is also entitled
Saad. The name of the Sura is Saad, and
the initial is Saad. So, these are three
Suras initialed with the letter Saad, and
when you count the letter Saad in the
three Suras, the total comes to 152, or
19 times 8.
There is one Sura in the Quran
initialed with the letters
Ya Seen, two letters, Ya and Seen.
It is Sura number 36. See, the first verse is
the two letters Ya and Seen. And if you count these two letters, Ya and Seen in the
whole Sura, the total is 285, or 19 times
15. So, you see that consistently, the
Suras contain a number of their
initials that is consistently a multiple
of 19. There are 7 Suras initialed
with the letters Ha and Meem, 7
consecutive Suras, beginning at Sura
number 40. See, there is Sura number
40, initialed with the letters Ha
Meem. The whole verse consists of just
the two letters, Ha Meem, 7
consecutive Suras. This is the last one,
Sura number 46. It is initialed with the letters Ha Meem.
And you count these distinctive unique
letters, Ha and Meem, in the seven
Suras. And you find that the total is
2147, the total of Ha plus Meem in the
7 Suras. This is 19 times 113,
2147. This means if only one letter Ha or one
letter Meem was lost or added in the
last 1400 years, the whole mathematical
system collapses. But as it is, you count
them right now in any Quran anywhere in
the world and you find that Ha and Meem
in the 7 Ha Meem initialed Suras
totals 2147, or 19 times 113.
Sura number 42 has two sets of initials. As you have just
seen, it has the initials Ha Meem in verse
one, and verse two of this Sura has the
initials 'Ayn Seen Qaf, three letters, 'Ayn
Seen and Qaf. And if you count these
three distinct letters in this Sura, 'Ayn
plus Seen plus Qaf, the total is 209
or 19 times 11.
Sura number 19 has the largest or the
biggest set of initials. It has five letters. This is Sura number
19, and it is initialed with five letters:
Kaf Ha Ya 'Ayn Saad. And you add, you
count these letters in this Sura,
the five letters total: 798, or 19 times 42.
Now, I wish to remind you that the
letter Saad, for example, interacts or is
interlocking with the other Saad
initialed Suras, Sura number seven and
Surah number 38.
You remember that this letter Saad
in the three Saad-initialed Suras is 152,
or 19 times 8, but it also
is intricately intertwined with these
letters in this Sura to give us a total
of 798, or 19 times 42. So, you can see
that this mathematical system is far
beyond human capability.
There are six Suras in the Quran
initialed with these letters:
Alef Laam Meem, A.L.M. They are Suras
number 2, 3, 29, 30, 31, and 32. This happens
to be Sura number 32. And every single
one of the six Suras contains a total
of these letters which is a multiple of
19, every, every one. For example, Sura
number 2 contains 9899 of these letters
and that's a multiple 19, 19 times 521.
Sura number 3 also contains a multiple
of 19 of these letters:
Alef Laam Meem, and so on. Every one of
the six Suras contains a total of Alef
plus Laam plus Meem which is a multiple of 19.
There are six... there are five...
There are five Suras in the Quran initialed with
these three letters: Alef Laam Ra, A.L.R.
And every single one of the five Suras
contains a total of Alef plus Laam plus Ra, which is a multiple of 19, every one.
Sura number seven is initialed with the
four letters: Alef Laam Meem Saad,
as you see here. And when you count these
letters Alef plus Laam plus Meem plus Saad,
in this Sura, the total comes to 5320
which is 19 times 280. And again, I wish
to remind you that this letter Saad
interlocks between this Sura and the
other Saad-initialed Suras, Sura number 19 and Sura number 38, and every time
within the Sura, and also with its
sister Suras where the letter Saad is
found, the totals are consistently a
multiple of 19.
Sura number 13 is initialed with the
letters Alef Laam Meem Ra, four initials,
Alef Laam Meem Ra. When you count these letters Alef plus Laam, plus Meem, plus Ra
in this Sura, you find that the total is
1482, 19 times 78. There are five Suras
in the Quran initialed with the letters
Ha, as we see in Sura 19 here, there's
the letter Ha, one of the five initials
in Sura 19. And then in Sura "Ta Ha" there it is, Ta Ha.
And the initials Ta Seen Meem in Sura number 26 right here, Ta Seen Meem.
And in Sura 27, it is the initials
Ta Seen, right here. And Ta Seen Meem
in Sura number 28, Ta Seen Meem. You
count these letters in the 5 Suras
and you find that the total is 1767, or 19
times 93.
People keep asking why 19? Why did
God choose the number 19 as the
common denominator throughout the Quran to
prove every element of the Quran?
The numbers of verses, the number of Suras,
the numbers of words from a certain
root, the numbers of letters, the
initials as you have seen, and we find
the number 19 in the Quran in Sura
number 74 verse number 30. We find
the number 19, and we find it
connected with the proof that the Quran
is not human-made. Some people say the
Quran is human-made.
إِنْ هَـٰذَآ إِلَّا قَوْلُ ٱلْبَشَرِ (74:25)
as it says in Sura number 74
verse 25. And God says the answer to
these people is the number 19, as we see
in verse 30 of Sura 74. Now, why 19?
It turns out that 19 is God's signature
on everything He created. As to the
answer to the question "why 19?", we
discovered that 19 is the basic message
of the Quran. Because 19 is the numerical
value of the Arabic word ONE. So, the whole
message of the Quran is God alone, God is
one, worship God alone. And 19 is the
numerical value of the word "WAHD" (one) in Arabic. When the Quran was revealed, there were
no numbers. The alphabet letters were
used as numbers, and the letter "Wow"
also served as the numeral 6. The
letter "Alef" was 1. The letter "Ha" was 8.
And the letter "Daal" was 4. "WAHD" 6
plus 1 plus 8 plus 4, the total is 19.
And this is why 19 is the common denominator
throughout the Quran, proving every
aspect, every element of the Quran.