In the name of God, the Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
This is the second in a series of programs.
And in the last program, I presented to you physical
evidence that the scripture is God's
message to the world, the physical
evidence was in the form of a
mathematical code that pervades the
whole scripture and I am talking about the Bible
the Old Testament, the New Testament, and Quran. This mathematical system
teaches us that every letter, every word
is mathematically composed in the
scripture beyond human ability, far
beyond human ability, and this
gives us... gives you confidence that every
statement you are going to hear is a
proven scientific fact. Every letter,
every word in the scripture was written
by God, and now we have this physical
proof, the mathematical code that was
discovered by computers recently, to let
us know that every statement is a proven
fact. We now have full confidence in
every statement. That program was very
important and I hope you watched it because
it will let you know that every statement
you heard and every statement you will
hear in this series of programs is a
proven scientific fact.
It is very important to have this confidence
because many items that we will share
with you deal with matter that has been
confusing in the past. Now, it has become
very clear and proven by physical evidence.
We are going to deal with the matter of
God's love.
You heard me open this program by saying "in the name of God, the Most Gracious, the
Most Merciful.
And we read in the scripture the proven
word of God, that God is love,
that God is peace, that He is the Most
Compassionate, the Most Merciful.
Yet, when we look around us in this world,
we see a lot of misery, a lot of war,
oppression. The vast majority of people
in the world are suffering from poverty,
diseases, starvation,
cancer, and the question, the inevitable question that arises is why?
If God is Loving, Compassionate and Merciful
as we read in the scripture, if God is in
full control, why do we see all these
problems, the earthquakes, the miseries? Why?
So, as you see, we are dealing with
some very heavy material.
In this episode, I want to illustrate for
you the answer to the question "who is
God?" And remember now that every
statement is supported by physical evidence.
Let us start with the solar system.
If this is the Sun, the planets
are orbiting the Sun in the solar system,
and so on. Now, in this position, our
planet Earth
is orbiting the Sun and the distance
from the Sun to our planet is 93 million miles,
93 million miles. The light travels
from the Sun to the planet Earth in four
minutes. That's the speed of light.
Now, the whole
solar system has distances within the
solar system of four billion miles.
Four billion miles within our solar system. You can imagine the planet Earth when
you are four billion miles away. It will
look real tiny. Now, let us consider the
solar system within our galaxy, the Milky
Way galaxy. So, I'm going to erase this.
Okay, this is the solar system and the
planet Earth is in there somewhere.
So, the planet Earth can be represented by a dot. Now, the Milky Way galaxy has
millions of stars, and remembering that
the light travels from the Sun to the
earth in four minutes, 93 million miles,
imagine this from here to the edge of
the Milky Way galaxy, the light will take
not four minutes, not a year, not a
thousand years, it will take 30,000 years
at the speed of light to go to the edge.
So, here's the planet Earth and if we go
to the edge of our Milky Way galaxy,
it will take us thirty thousand years, excuse me,
at the speed of life to get
to the edge of the Milky Way galaxy. Can you imagine? Now, if you are at the
border of the Milky Way galaxy, how big
is the planet Earth?
Rather how tiny is it? It will be
submicroscopic, real tiny, relatively.
So, let us now look, let us erase this and
look at the Milky Way galaxy. Let us make
it real tiny. This is the Milky Way galaxy,
right here, and somewhere in there,
this dot is actually, this dot right here
is actually too big for the solar system
because we're talking about
30,000 light years across. This distance here, remembering that the light
comes to us from the Sun, 93 million
miles, in four minutes. So, if we say this
is the solar system, you can imagine the
planet Earth in there somewhere.
So, this is the Milky Way galaxy now,
and our universe contains
one billion of these galaxies,
one thousand millions like the Milky Way
within our universe.
So, the distances within our universe reach
up to 26 billion light-years, 26 billion
light-years within our universe.
From the Sun to the earth, we have 93
million miles and the light takes four
minutes to get to us from the Sun. Can
you imagine distances of 26 billion
light-years? Where are the four minutes
within this distance, the four light-minutes?
These are 26,000 millions of light-years
within our universe.
So, now let me erase this and
draw our universe.
Okay, here is the Earth, the solar system, the Milky Way galaxy, our universe. This is all, of
course, distorted because we don't have
enough board, but when you are at the edge
of the Milky Way galaxy, the planet Earth
is very tiny. And when you go all the way
to the border of our universe, where is
the planet Earth?
Do you remember where the planet Earth is? Very minute.
Well, this universe is the smallest and innermost of seven universes.
Seven universes, not one. And our universe
is the smallest and the innermost of the
seven universes. We have seen how vast
our universe is, with 26 billion
light-years within our universe.
The second universe is much bigger.
The third universe is bigger than the second,
the fourth, the fifth, the sixth,
the seventh universe. Our mind cannot imagine
the size of the seventh universe that
encompasses the other six universes.
This is why in the last program,
we decided that the circumference of the
seventh universe
cannot be described mathematically in
terms of miles or light-years.
Infinity is the best description of the
circumference of the seventh universe.
And now we get to know who God is. This
will correct the concept of God in the
minds of millions of people because God
is holding the seven universes in his hand.
This is what the proven statement
in the scripture says.
In the Quran, chapter 39,
God tells us that He is holding the
seven universes in His hand. How much
space do you have within the fist of your
hand? And God is holding these vast
distances, these vast universes within
his hand. Where is the planet Earth in
there? How significant is it?
It is very important and very relevant to this
program to understand who God is and
how minute and insignificant the whole
planet Earth is within God's kingdom.
This illustration gives us some idea
about the greatness of God and who God
is and I assure you we didn't even come
close, but we do have a better idea
and this corrects the concept of God in
the minds of millions of people.
God is great not only in terms of size
but also in terms of controlling
everything, every atom in the heavens and
the earth, down to subatomic levels,
and this is a direct quotation from Quran.
We learn from the scripture that God is
the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. God
is Love. He loves His creation and you
noticed that I started this program by
saying "in the name of God, the Most
Gracious, the Most Merciful.
And this brings the inevitable question.
When we look around us all over the
world, we see a lot of misery, a lot of
famine, starvation, poverty, accidents, earthquakes, problems, diseases, cancer.
The world is full of problems. The vast
majority of the world is under
dictatorship, oppression and poverty.
So, the inevitable question that pops up
in our minds, justifiably so, is if God is
full of Love and Compassion and Mercy,
why all these problems?
Why does God permit this famine,
starvation, accidents and misery?
It's a legitimate question and this
program will deal with this question.
In order to answer the question "why are we here?
And what is the purpose of our lives?", we had to go back in time to where there
was God and nothing else.
Then, God created the angels
to perform functions where the existence
of God is not necessary, or simply
devastating, as we will learn later on.
The Angels had to possess immense powers,
and just to give you an idea, today, the
angels have to travel billions of
light-years in only a few of our
hours. They have to possess immense
powers, and God gave the angels immense
powers.
We have heard in the last few years
about questions like how many angels can
dance on the tip of a pin. This kind of
silly question. But the exact opposite is
true. Just to give you an idea, one angel
can hold the planet Earth in one hand.
We know these things now after the
discovery of the mathematical code and
the mathematically proven statements in
the scriptures.
One of the angels became infatuated
with his God-given powers. He had so much
power that he thought he can be a god in
his own right. That angel's name was
Lucifer or Satan or the devil or El Diablo.
He has many names.
Let us call him Satan for the purposes
of this program. You can imagine Satan flying in the
universe and saying to himself "I can be a god in my own right. I can
rule part of this universe by myself." That was all in his head
and, of course, his fellow angels had no
idea what Satan was thinking, but God
knew about Satan's supercilious
thoughts, deep in his head.
God knew those thoughts.
And there were two alternatives,
either God can simply wipe out Satan, and
in this case the angels will wonder. They
will be perplexed "why did God do this to
Satan? Satan didn't do anything wrong."
The other alternative was to expose Satan first,
and to do this, God decided to create a
tiny, a minute creature from a lowly
material, mud. You can imagine the size of
the human being compared to the size of
an angel who can hold the planet Earth in his hand.
So, God created a tiny creature from a
lowly material, mud. Then, God ordered the
angels to bow down before Adam, this tiny
creature. They all did, except, you know who, Satan.
And thus Satan was exposed as a rebel.
Now, the angels see for themselves
that Satan is a rebel
who deserves to be banished from God's
Kingdom.
That was the first reason for creating the human race.
It was mercy from God that He decided to
expose Satan first by creating the tiny
creature from mud, then ordering the
angels to fall prostrate, bow down before Adam.
The other reason for creating the human
race is a bit more complicated.
To understand this second reason, we have to go back to
the time when Satan was infatuated with
his power and saying "I can rule part of
this universe by myself. I can be a god
in my own right."
God said to Himself when He knew about
Satan's supercilious thoughts "all right,
you want to be a god? I will make you a
god, and see how good you are. There is
much more to godhood than you think." This
is what God thought to Himself and this
is where the second reason for creating
us comes.
In order to make Satan a god, temporarily,
God decided to give Satan a dominion and
constituents. In order to be a god or a
king, you have to have a dominion and
constituents. To give Satan a dominion,
God went out of His way to show Satan
that the dominion God is giving to Satan
is really tiny, minute. God created this
vast universe, the seven universes that I
described to you. And in this vast
universe, God told Satan "I'm giving you
this tiny tiny planet Earth. This is your
dominion." Okay. So, now that Satan has his
dominion, where will he get his
constituents? That's right, the human race.
God created the human beings and gave
them the freedom of choice.
God told us, you and me and every one
of us,
that if we choose Satan's kingdom, we
belong in Satan's kingdom. And if we
choose God's Kingdom, then we belong in
God's Kingdom.
Now, this choice depends on siding with
Satan's point of view or God's point of view.
God's point of view is that God alone
is Lord of the universes. He has no partners, no other God besides
Him. This is God's point of view. And when
you agree with this point of view,
you belong in God's Kingdom.
Satan's point of view, on the other hand,
is that God alone is not enough. There can be
or there must be another god or gods besides Him.
And Satan wanted to be that other god.
So, the human beings have the freedom of
choice and those among them who side
with Satan's point of view become Satan's
constituents.
So, now Satan has his dominion, the planet
Earth, and his constituents the human
beings who side with his point of view.
And Satan is being tested as a god
and the results are all around us.
Now, you know why the famine, the starvation,
the misery, the accidents, the cancer.
Satan's kingdom is plagued with these problems.
On the other hand, these problems do not
exist in God's Kingdom. When you side
with God's point of view, that is
decide that God alone is Lord of the
universes, without any other idols in your life, you
belong in God's Kingdom and God's
Kingdom has no cancer, no accidents, no
headache, no problems. God's kingdom is
characterized by perfect health,
perfect wealth and perfect peace, perfect happiness.
I know this sounds unbelievable but you
heard me right.
God's Kingdom is characterized by
perfect health, perfect wealth,
perfect happiness and joy. When you
choose God's point of view,
you belong in God's Kingdom, and you will
have no headache, no problems, no traffic
tickets. I'm gonna repeat that, you heard
me right. When you belong in God's
Kingdom, you will have no headache.
You will forget what headaches are.
You will have no financial problems, no
health problems.
God runs the universes, and this is His
law. If you belong in God's Kingdom, there
will be no accidents in your life, no
misery, no marital problems, no problems of any kind.
Unfortunately, the vast majority of
people have sided with Satan's point of view,
that God alone is not enough. They do this
by idolizing, setting up idols like
Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or Saint
Francis or the boss or the dollar. They set up all kinds of idols.
And when they do this, they uphold
Satan's point of view and automatically,
they become Satan's constituents.
Don't get me wrong. Satan is trying very
hard to make his kingdom, the planet
Earth, and his constituents, the people
who choose him and his point of view...
he is trying very hard to make his kingdom
a perfect Kingdom. He wants very badly
his constituents to enjoy perfect health,
perfect wealth and perfect peace and happiness,
but he just can't and this is the whole idea.
Satan is being put to the test with a
dominion and constituents and his
incompetence as a god has been proven
and this is the whole idea of our existence.
Some of you may think that I'm talking
about some kingdom to come after life or
something like that,
but I'm talking about now, you and I.
And some of you may ask "I didn't
want to be in this test. Why am I here, involuntarily?"
And this is a wrong question.
Because we learn from the scripture
that is proven by mathematical
code, by physical evidence to be God's
message to the world, we learn that you
and I and every human being was asked
whether we want the freedom of choice or
not. We met God before the creation of
the heavens and the earth and we bore
witness that He alone is our Lord.
But this knowledge is obscured with this
body. We cannot remember it now.
We will remember it when we get rid of
this body, this garment and become free again.
I'm talking about now. Every
human being you see is either a
constituent of God or a constituent of
Satan, and as I mentioned constituents of
God enjoy perfect health,
perfect wealth and perfect happiness and
joy now, in this world.
Satan's constituents are plagued with
problems, financial, marital, health. They
have all kinds of problems and I know
this sounds unbelievable but this is why
I am repeating it. And I must repeat now
that these statements are proven by
physical evidence, by the mathematical
code that I explained to you in the last
episode. It is very important to realize
that I'm not talking from the top of my
head, that this is
proven material by physical evidence
that anyone can examine and verify.
When you are in God's kingdom, when you side
with God's point of view that God alone
is Lord without any idols, without
Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or the Saints
or the boss or the dollar, you belong in God's Kingdom and you enjoy perfect life.
When you side with Satan's point of view,
here in this world, you suffer the consequences.
What you see around the world is the consequence of Satan's incompetence as a god.
God gave him this planet Earth and gave
us the freedom to choose him and become
his constituents.
You know the scripture tells us that if
God wills, He can make all the people
believers, which is true. If God wills, He
can make all the people on Earth believers.
The question is why doesn't He? And the answer in the scriptures is
"if God made all the people believers, where
will Satan get his constituents to
prove Satan's incompetence as a god?" See, we are here to provide Satan with constituents.
Those among us, with our freedom of choice, who choose Satan become his constituents
by their choice.
So, this is happening here and now. Any
human being you look at belongs either
in God's Kingdom or in Satan's kingdom.
Whether they know it or not, there is no
other choice. You either belong in God's
Kingdom or in Satan's kingdom. How can you tell? If you have any problems whatsoever,
if you have headaches, financial
problems, health problems,
marital problems, any kind of problems,
this will be your hint that you have
made the choice to side with Satan's kingdom, somehow. You will have to examine your own life.
That is the difference between Satan's
kingdom and God's Kingdom.
God's Kingdom is characterized
by perfect health, perfect wealth and peace of mind.
If you look into your life and find
that your life is full of problems
or has some problems,
if you come to the conclusion that you
have been victimized by Satan or duped by
Satan into joining his kingdom, what is the way out?
How can you join God's Kingdom? How can I
join God's Kingdom?
This is a very easy matter. At the same
time, it is not so easy for the reasons
that I'm going to explain to you.
First of all, you have to come to a solid unshakable conclusion that God alone is
Lord of the universe, that no one besides God can help you or harm you.
You have to come to this solid conclusion.
So, let us say you claim that you came to
this conclusion, that you believe that
God alone is Lord of the universe.
The scripture tells us, in Quran, chapter 29
verse 2, I'm going to quote it now.
"Do the people think that they will be left
to say we believe without being put to
the test? We will surely put them to
the test to distinguish those who are
telling the truth from the liars."
Therefore, when you make this claim that
you believe that God alone is Lord of
the universe, you will have to be put to
the test to show that you're not just
offering lip service, that this is a deep
solid unshakable conviction.
We read in the Bible that Job was put to the test.
Satan inflicted a lot of harm upon Job,
and this is my chance to tell you that
any problems, any diseases, any accidents, any misery is inflicted only by Satan.
God does not inflict any harm on His
creation.
There are four kinds of disasters. The first kind is the admission tests,
what I call admission tests. When you
or I claim that we believe that God
alone is Lord of the universe without
any idols, we must be put to the test.
These admission tests are designed to show
that we uphold this conviction solidly,
unshakably under all circumstances,
rich or poor, health or sickness. And admission tests are characterized by
the fact that they do not leave
permanent damage. They test you thoroughly.
Then, you are admitted into God's Kingdom. That is the first kind of disaster.
The second kind of disaster is called educational disaster. This is designed to bring us back into
God's Kingdom if we sway out of God's
Kingdom.
If we make a mistake and step out of
God's Kingdom, this is exactly what
happens. You step out of God's Kingdom
and Satan captures you, smites you, gives
you a problem, a disaster. And this will be your attention getter.
You'll be alerted that you have stepped out of
God's Kingdom and you will come back
fast. That is called educational disaster.
And as you see, admission tests and
educational disasters are inflicted by Satan.
The third kind is called blessings in disguise. And these appear to be disasters but
when they are passed, you look back on
them and you discover that they were
actually good for you. You go apply
for a job or something and you don't get it,
you flunk in the interview and you're
very upset because you wanted that job,
but later on you discover that with time,
you obtained a better job and that... had you
succeeded in getting that job, it would
have been much worse for you. So, that is
a blessing in disguise.
The fourth kind of disaster is retributive disaster.
And it happens when a society
or an individual reaches the point of
corruption where there is no reform, the
point of no reform. A good example in the
Bible and the Quran, in the scriptures, is
Sodom and Gomorrah. The people of Sodom
and Gomorrah were corrupted beyond
reform.
They became hopelessly trapped
in their corruption.
And God decided to inflict the
retributive disaster that they deserved
And this is the only kind
that you may attribute to God, but
actually it is... this ended their life. It was the final blow.
And death is a fact of life, as you know. Everyone dies. So, it is not really a
disaster since it is the final act.
Death is a fact of life. We all die.
And that is not a disaster.
So, these are the four kinds of disaster.
I remember a story that was told by a
famous preacher about two men, one
believed in God and the other did not.
The man who believed in God was telling
his friend "well, listen if you don't
believe in God, then if there is a Day of
Judgment, you will be in deep trouble. But
you see, if you believe in God and then
if there is a Day of Judgment and you
face God, you've got nothing to lose.
If you don't believe in God, you're in
trouble. But if you believe in God and
there is no Day of Judgement and there is
no God, you've got nothing to lose."
Now, this argument the preacher said
makes sense. It makes sense that you
believe in God. But actually, I am here to
tell you that it doesn't work that way.
See, you cannot believe in God just in
case there is a God. The only way is to
reach deep solid unshakable conviction
about God, not only that God exists, but
also that God is the Only Lord of the
universe, that there is no idol, no other
god besides Him.
And as I told you, it is very easy to
make the switch from Satan's kingdom to
God's Kingdom.
All you need to do is to reach this deep
conviction. You have many years to study,
look around, research, think, reflect and
make a decision.
And if you are fortunate to make a
decision
to join God's Kingdom by believing that
God alone is Lord of the universe,
then you will be put to the test
to show that you mean it, that it is
not only lip service or just in case as
in that story.
Your decision to join God's Kingdom
based on deep unshakable conviction must
be accompanied by repentance, remorse for
the wrong things you have done in the
past. You simply say to God "I'm sorry, I
did those things. I'm sorry, I did not
side with Your point of view, that I fell
into idol worship.
I committed certain sins. I will never do
them again. I repent to You."
This repentance wipes out all your sins. You
become like a newborn baby, no sins whatsoever.
Better yet, we learn from the scripture
that all your sins of the past will be
transformed into credits. That's right,
credits in your record. And credits means
growth and development and strengthening
of your soul. So, on the day of judgment,
you will be strong and able to withstand
the Energy of God, being close to God
Himself.
A lot of people ask the question "why the
children are suffering?
Why the innocent children are suffering?" In the last few years, we have been
watching in our living rooms on the TV
children starving and dying in Africa.
And a lot of people are justified in
asking "why the children?"
It is very important to point out that
when we side with Satan's point of view,
we move ourselves and our families out
of God's Kingdom into Satan's kingdom.
We and our families become constituents in
Satan's kingdom and subject to Satan's
incompetence as a temporary god. This is
why the children are suffering.
On the other hand, the suffering and death of
those children is actually a blessing in
disguise. When we study the scripture
carefully, we realize that these children
are going straight to Heaven. And it is
indeed a blessing for them. They actually
do not die. They move on from this life
to a much better life.
The chances of those children growing up
and making the right choice, siding with
God's point of view, the chance is very
nil that they will do that.
And it is far better for those children to die
now and go to Heaven than to suffer for
a long time and then end up not making
it and ending up in an eternal Hell.
This brings us to a very important item
in this episode, the unforgivable sin.
You see, at the end of our term in this
world, at the time of death,
murder is forgivable,
adultery is forgivable, stealing is forgivable,
lying, cheating, all these are
forgivable sins. There is only one
unforgivable sin when maintained
until the time of death.
This one unforgivable sin is idol-worship.
We fully appreciate now why idol worship
is the only unforgivable offense.
Because now we realize that the whole idea
behind our existence, the whole idea
behind creating us is to provide Satan
with the constituents who agree with his
point of view, that God alone is not
enough,
that there can be other gods, other idols besides God.
The grossness of idol-worship
can be appreciated when you
remember what I mentioned earlier in
this program, that this planet Earth is a
tiny tiny component in God's Kingdom.
Remember when I mentioned that the
planet Earth
is 93 million miles from the Sun, that the
light from the Sun to the planet Earth
takes four minutes to reach us? 93
million miles from the Sun to the Earth.
And this is a very tiny distance when we
think of the whole solar system being
something like 4 billion miles across. And you can see the planet Earth
diminishing in these vast distances. Now, the light comes to us from the Sun
in four minutes,
but from the edge of our galaxy, the
Milky Way galaxy, the light takes not
four minutes, not four days, not four
years, not four centuries, and not four
thousand years even, it takes 30,000
years for the light to travel
from the planet Earth to the edge of our
galaxy, the Milky Way galaxy. Can you
imagine how tiny the planet Earth is
in the Milky Way galaxy? And I mentioned
that before. Our universe contains one
billion galaxies like the Milky Way, and
distances up to 26 billion light years.
From the Sun to the planet Earth, the
light takes four minutes. If you travel
at the speed of light, you reach the Sun
in four minutes. You reach the outer
limit of the Milky Way galaxy in 30,000
years. You reach the outer limit of our
universe in 26,000 millions years at the
speed of light. So, where is the planet
Earth in our universe? It is almost nothing.
Now, our universe, as I mentioned, is one of seven universes. The other six are much larger universes,
if you can imagine that. So, the planet Earth is terribly insignificant.
Now, on this tiny insignificant planet
Earth, a man named Muhammad walked for 63
years.
All his life from birth to death was 63
years. On this tiny insignificant planet
Earth, there was this human being,
Muhammad. And millions of people around
the world idolize him against his will. Can you imagine the grossness of this
idol worship? On this tiny minute
insignificant planet Earth, a man named
Jesus, a creature of God, walked on the earth for 33 years.
So, how significant is he? How significant is Muhammad?
And you can imagine, you can appreciate
the grossness of idol worship when
people idolize
creatures of God like Muhammad or Jesus
or Mary or the Saints who walked on this
Earth for a limited period of time. And
this planet Earth, as you see, the whole
planet Earth, is terribly insignificant.
So, now with the study of the scriptures and the
physical evidence supporting it, we come
to appreciate that the only unforgivable
offense is idol worship.
God is holding the seven universes in
His hand and we see now that our purpose
in life to be successful is to side
with God's point of view that He alone
is enough. God describes His greatness in
the scriptures for us to appreciate God
and to see that He alone is Lord and
to see and appreciate the
grossness of idolizing anyone else. The
definition of idol worship, by the way, is that
if you believe that anyone other than
the One who created you can benefit you. Then, you have fallen into idol worship.
This is the definition of idol worship.
If you believe that anyone other than
the One True God, the One, the specific
One who created you, if you believe that
anyone other than God can benefit you,
then you have fallen into idol worship.
I am sure you realize that we cannot
cover these heavy subjects in such a short time.
I have shared with you the
ideas about the king of chaos. We know
now who the king of chaos is. We know why
the world is full of miseries, famine,
wars, oppression, disasters, accidents, cancer, etc.
And we dealt with the most important
question in anyone's life, the purpose of
our life. Why are we here? Why were we
created?
And because these subjects are so heavy,
I am sure I raised more questions than
answered, and this is why I hope you will
get on the phone and call me with your
questions. Don't hesitate to ask. My phone
number is area code 602 791
(www.submission.ws)
3989. I am going to put
the address and the telephone number on
(www.submission.ws)
the screen for you. So, please write or
call. My address is 739 East
(www.submission.ws)
sixth Street, Tucson, Arizona 85719 and the telephone is area
code 602 791 3989
(www.submission.ws)
Thank you and God bless you.