One God
LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH
(There is no god, except the One God)
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is great).
One God
LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH
(There is no god, except the One God)
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is great).
ALHAMDULILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
We continue to record these KHTUBAs because they are very
important.
Now, I know what I'm going to talk about.
About, in fact, exactly 19 years ago,
I started the research on the Quran. I put
it in the computer
and you know the rest of the story. Now
after that, there was tremendous
publicity for the miracle of the Quran.
We had not reached the
the conclusion that is causing all kinds
of problems for the disbelievers that we
shall worship "God Alone", that we shall
devote ourselves to "Allah Alone"
and that we must uphold the Quran, the
whole Quran and nothing but the Quran.
Until this conclusion appeared about 1976,
there was tremendous publicity for the
miracle of Quran and the putting the
Quran in the computer
and it was a very popular issue. The
leaflet was distributed by the millions
throughout the Muslim world
and was translated to all languages of the
world, French and Japanese.
And the biblical scholars apparently
became jealous and they wanted to do the
same thing. So, they did organize
a very
sanctioned study at the Hebrew University
in Jerusalem.
A fellow by the name of Cats
put the Bible in the computer, "the
Torah", the five books of Moses I guess,
and what he did was to first, let's say
I'm gonna put the English but they used the original, the oldest text they could get hold of
"In the beginning,..."
This is how the book of Genesis begins.
What they did was take every second
letter.
I think they started with every seventh
letter: one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven. So, they took every seventh letter,
put all these letters together and tried to
get meaningful words or sentences out of
them. That didn't work. So, they took
every eighth letter and that didn't work.
And they kept going on until they got to
some number and they found the word
"Torah" and they became very excited and
they said "God is saying that this is the
Torah" and so on.
They found words like: Elohim, Jerusalem
Holocaust, but these words were born from
the letters that they extracted from the text -
the original text of the Bible. Last night,
Larry King had a professor at the
University of California San Diego, his
name was Richard Elliott Friedman.
His book is now in the market and
they're making a big noise about it. The
book is entitled "who wrote the Bible?"
and in the question and answer by
telephone, somebody asked him if he's familiar
with the computer work that was done in
Israel. And I'm going to let you hear the
answer.
Then I will comment from there on.
Don't worry; you're going to hear it.
...computer without them to prove that it was written by different people in different times.
...that they discovered by using the computer, but the chances of the Bible being written by mortal man is only one
chance out of 1,300,000.
"Sure. I'm familiar. There've been two these computer studies in recent years that supposedly prove that the Bible is all by God
or all by one person and so on."
"These are non-sense. They are bogus. They are a disgrace to statistics. In simplest terms, what their system was
they counted every seventh letter of the Bible to see if
it spelled out any words. It didn't
work. So, they tried every eighth letter and
so on and finally on a certain number, I think, it was
every 17th letter came out every now
and then spelling the word. As it happens
the word they got was "Torah." Three of the
four letters of Torah are the three most
common letters in the Hebrew language.
And so they said so statistically, my God, how
could this have happened that it keeps out
spelling "Torah?" It is nonsense. You
can do this with any book, the same
process. You count every 14th letter of the
Bible and it will spell out "Paul McCartney is
dead."
Okay. This is true, I mean. As you see now, what
I'm trying to tell you in this
KHUTBA is that we have the real thing.
These people tried. They put the Bible in the
computer and they tried all kinds of
things. Now, they're taking every 7th
letter, every 8th letter and so on. In
the Quran, the discovery that came out
of this mosque, we have no choice. We
cannot manipulate the data. We have two
verses initialed with the letter "Q." We didn't
choose "Q."
The author of the Quran, Almighty Allah,
chose
"Q" and there are two chapters
initialed with "Q." One is chapter 42, another
Chapter 50. You count the letter "Q" which
is dictated on us, we did not choose it.
In chapter 42, and you have 57 Q's, 19 times 3.
You count the letter "Q" in chapter 50
which is half as long as 42
and you also get the same number, 57,
which is 19 times 3.
There is one chapter initialed with the
letter "N." We didn't choose the letter "N."
There is no chance of manipulating or
haphazardly looking for anything
and you count the letters in this
chapter. The letter "N" in this chapter and
you have 133. 19 x 7.
There are three chapters initialed with the
letter "S", the heavy "S" a guttural "S." Saad.
And you count this letter. There's no
question about the letter "Q" or "N" or "S",
they're very clear letters. And in the
chapters initialed with "S", you count this
letter and you'll find 152 S's which is
19 times 8.
There is no manipulation here. We
have the real thing. We have proof that
every letter in Quran, every word was
mathematically composed beyond human
intelligence. This is a supernatural
composition. I wanted initially to
give you a report on my visit to
San Diego. We had a very nice meeting last
Saturday and
I find out that Apamea's aunt and
uncle were there.
I presented to them, we discussed with them
the miracle of Quran and there was one
person, an objector, who came from some
other camp.
And I pointed out these things to him
that we have no chance of manipulating
the Quran because we did not choose the "Q" or the "S" or the "N."
And I asked him to explain
how come all these are consistently
multiples of 19? We have seven chapters
initialed with "H. M,"
seven chapters.
And you count these initials in the seven
chapters and you have 2147 or
19 times 113.
2147, these seven chapters are almost one tenth of the Quran and if you have one
extra "H" or one extra "M",
this will not be a multiple of 19.
It's an extremely sensitive mathematical
composition.
"ALM" in chapter 2, 9899 of them, you count
the letter "A", the letter "L" and letter "M",
and the total is 9899. We did not choose "ALM",
like they skipped every seventh letter,
every eight letter, and then they took
the letters out and tried to make words
out of them.
Like Dr. Friedman said "you can do it with any
book."
Some of the critics say "you can do this
with any book." But it's not true.
I tell them "fine." They said "you can do it to any number, not the same 19."
I say "please let us see some other numbers." You know,
"we'd like to see
a miraculous composition of the Quran
using any number." And they they haven't
shown us anything yet.
19 years until now and we challenged
them to prove any mistake here. There isn't any.
Notice this is 9899,
it sounds like the price of a used car,
9899 and 99 cents. But this is a
multiple of 19.
19 times 521.
One A, one letter A, if it's added or
lost becomes 9898 and that will not be
a multiple of 19.
If you add one "L" or one "M" in chapter two, a huge
chapter, just one letter,
lost or added and you have 9900 which is
a nice round number,
but it's not a multiple of 19.
We have a chapter initialed with "KHY'AS", the heavy "S."
This happens to be chapter 19 and it has to do
with the story of Mary and Jesus,
the virgin birth, the miracles of Jesus,
things that are normally unbelievable and
this is why God is strengthening this
chapter with 5 initials. And you
count them. These are distinct letters
that I have in the book, the visual
presentation book, with every one
of these letters marked with a star. So,
they can see for themselves. I mean, you're
feeding them the miracle with a spoon.
The first book was just tables and numbers and
they said "how do we know
you're not lying? How do we know these
numbers are correct?" So, I printed the
second book for them with every letter. I said "all you need to do is show me one
letter without a star, one of these letters
without a star, or show
me a star under a letter that is not
one of these." There are 798
of these. This is 19 times 42.
Consistently, every single one of them
without exceptions, 29 chapters initialed.
And we have no choice. This "KHY'AS" have
been in the Quran for 1400 years.
There is no chance for manipulating or
playing around.
And after the conclusion came that we
shall worship "God Alone" and uphold the
"Quran Alone," you know how popular I am.
They are dying to find a mistake.
It's a blessing from God
that I'm not that popular.
Just received a death threat the other day.
Somebody said "the Saudi's gonna
assassinate you almost
three days ago. That's how
popular I am. So, you can imagine how
eager they are to find mistakes and you
can be sure if they find one mistake
because one mistake means the whole
thing collapses and this is what I'm telling
them. I said "I'll forget the whole thing if you
find one mistake because God is
perfect and His system is perfect.
There are other initials: "ALMR",
"ALMS", "ALR", "TSM",
"TS", "YS."
"YS" is a SURA entitled "YS", SURA number 36.
You count the "Y" and the "S," in this
chapter, they are 285. 19 times 15.
Strange things happen in the Quran. There
is a letter Y. This letter is
questionable in many many SURAs. There're
many words
like for example: یتوفکم "Yatawafakum" is
written with a "Y" in the word that is
obscure "Y." It's kind of a questionable
"Y." You do not find a single
questionable word in this SURA. They're
all straightforward "Y." YA SEEN. 285.
I don't know what other letters I forgot but
every single one in their chapters
is a multiple of 19.
No wonder God calls this "One of the Greatest
Miracles."
And we are the lucky generation that
witnesses this miracle.
The consequences of this Miracle
certainly are fantastic and they have evolved
to the ultimate conclusion
that I've been telling you about.
"God is doing everything." This is the
ultimate conclusion.
This ultimate conclusion explains why
the majority of believers are going to
Hell.
Because there are lots of people who
believe in God but they don't believe
that He's doing everything.
It's a very crucial conclusion, the ultimate
conclusion.
The one that leads us to Heaven and you
can understand why it is rare
that people go to Heaven. People who are going to
Heaven are rare and we find this in
the Bible consistently, the Bible and the
Quran. "Narrow, straitened is the road to
Heaven. Wide and spacious
is the road to Hell" says the Bible.
The Quran says the same thing.
TUBU ILLA ALLAH. Repent.
ALHAMDULILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
Praise be to God. I bear witness that there is no god except the One God who is doing everything.
God is doing everything.
And some people added a few things; Lisa, the other day, was telling me she added "and I
wholeheartedly submit to Him" makes that
another complete sentence. God is doing
everything and I wholeheartedly submit
to Him. Because this ultimate conclusion
that God is doing everything sheds a
whole new light
on the idea of submission to God.
Because from now on you will not be an
objector. You will not be unhappy with
anything.
If you're unhappy with anything, you're
an objector.
If there's anything that causes
unhappiness, you have to find out what it
is and eliminate it. Look for the non-Quranic
situations in your life.
Eliminate them.
You must live, you must be sure that
everything in your life is Quranic. Quranic
means the word of God.
In the meeting in San Diego, the one
fellow over there, the objecting fellow,
was saying that
out of this research came
the dating for the end of the world.
The first book, the Computer Speaks, as
you remember,
I said that the end of the world, God
says, that the end of the world is 2280 AD,
or 1710 AH,
both of them multiples of 19. Okay. He
said that this is a very dangerous thing
to say.
Now, why is it dangerous, whether it is
correct or wrong? Why is it dangerous? First
of all, we're not gonna live until that time.
Second of all, if it is wrong, I mean, why is it...
it's a piece of information.
I must mention here that the three minimum
requirements in the Quran, in SURA 2
verse 62, and also the same thing is
repeated in SURA 5.
It says the minimum requirements are (1) believe
in God,
(2) believe in the Hereafter (3) lead a righteous life.
These are the three minimum requirements.
You'll make it to Heaven if you believe in God
Alone,
believe in the Hereafter, and lead a
righteous life. There is nothing about
Moses and Jesus and Muhammad. You don't have
to believe in them.
There's nothing about the Quran or the
Bible or the Gospel. You don't have to
believe in them. There's nothing in
there about anything. There's nothing about the angels.
You believe in the angels? Of course,
you believe in the angels, but it is not a
requirement. It's a piece of information.
It's an additional piece of
information. There's a difference between
the knowledgeable person and the ignorant
person. And all of them, if they satisfy
these three requirements, they make it to
Heaven. But to believe in the angels,
the messengers, the scriptures,
all these are additional pieces of
information, valuable pieces of
information, and one of the valuable pieces of
information is that God put in the Quran
the end of the world. So, I'm going... this KHUTBA will be devoted to this.
First of all, the Quran is God's
final message to the world.
God is the only One who knows when the
world will end and God wants to tell
the world
about the end of the world
and when it will be. And God put it in the
in the final message to the world. So, it
is not me who is saying or predicting
the end of the world. It is the All
Knowledgeable, God Almighty, that is
saying in the Quran when it will end
and it goes like this. In SURA 20, verse
15, God says "I will not keep the end of
the world hidden."
And in SURA 15, God says "We have given
you, O Muhammad, the seven pairs."
The seven pairs, 14.
And the letters that I showed you in the
first KHUTBA are 14, fourteen sets.
So, they are, as you see, a fantastic
miracle and God is telling Muhammad what
a blessing it was that God gave him
these seven pairs. Now, when the Quran was
revealed, there were no numbers.
This "ALM", the first verse of SURA 2,
for example, you can look on them as
letters and you can also look on them as
numbers.
This is 71. This was 71 at the time of revelation of
Quran. We did not have these numbers when
the Quran was revealed. "A" is 1, "L" is 30, "M" is 40.
1+30+40. The total is 71.
You add the 14 sets of numbers,
and they give you 1709, total.
So, "We have given you, O, Muhammad",
the verse, when you look at it carefully in view
of all the Quran, that from Muhammad to
the end of the world, or from the Quran to
the end of the world, 1709 years.
After you complete 1709
years, you go into 1710 After Hijra, which is a multiple of 19.
There is one flag goes up, a sign, a confirmation.
The corresponding year AD is 2280 which
is also a multiple of 19. Another flag goes up.
This discovery
happened in the year 1400 AH.
And it said that the end of the world
will be 1709. I mean, the total
number of the letters was
1709. So, how many
years are left? How many complete years because 1710 will not be complete?
Before the end of 1710, the world will end. 309 and immediately a flag goes
up. We find in SURA 18, the people of
the Cave.
God didn't tell us how many there are
in the cave.
And God goes out of His way to tell us
I'm not gonna tell you how many there
are in the cave. Three and people say "four."
Five and people say "six" or seven and
people say "their eighth is the dog."
Say God knows how many there are. So, I'm not gonna
tell you how many, but He tells us how
long they lasted in the cave,
300 increased by 9.
Why? This is a Quranic number and
you look the SURA and it tells you why
God says, told us about the people of
the Cave. It says "to remove all doubt about
the end of the world."
I'm gonna say it in Arabic and the translation
in English. I mean, what is more
straightforward than that? It says
وَكَذَٰلِكَ أَعْثَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ لِيَعْلَمُوٓا۟ أَنَّ وَعْدَ ٱللَّهِ حَقٌّۭ وَأَنَّ ٱلسَّاعَةَ لَا
(18:21) رَيْبَ فِيهَآ
That the end of the world, there is
no doubt about it. In other words, so this is to remove
all doubt concerning the calculations.
This is connected with the end of the
world. "We have given you the seven pairs" is connected with the end of
the world in SURA 15.
The verse before that, before we have
given you 7 pairs, God says that God is the
Omniscient who knows, the Creator, the
Omniscient, who knows everything
and knows when the world will end.
(15:85) وَإِنَّ ٱلسَّاعَةَ لَـَٔاتِيَةٌۭ ۖ فَٱصْفَحِ ٱلصَّفْحَ ٱلْجَمِيلَ
(15:86) إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ ٱلْخَلَّـٰقُ ٱلْعَلِيمُ
"That your Lord is the Creator, the Omniscient who
knows when it will end. We have given you seven pairs
and the great Quran." So, all these signs
together tell us that there is no doubt.
But it is a piece of information, it is
not required
to go to Heaven.
The minimum requirements are (1) believe in
God (2) believe in the Hereafter (3) lead a
righteous life under any name. If you're
a Buddhist or Hindu or Christian or Jewish or
Muslim, under any name, if you worship
God Alone, the Creator of the universe
and believe in the Hereafter, Heaven
And Hell, Resurrection after death,
and lead a righteous life. You can't just
believe in God and the Hereafter and be a
nasty, bad person, liar, cheat and all that.
You have to lead a righteous life. So, these three minimum requirements will
lead you to Heaven. Belief in the
messengers, Muhammad, Jesus, Moses is not
required, the angels is not required.
Believing in the scriptures is not required.
We don't see it in the.. Believing that the
world will end in 1710 or 2280 is not
required, but it is a valuable
piece of information as valuable as knowing
that there are angels
and jinns and messengers
and scriptures.
AQEM AL-SALAT.