ALLAH-O AKBAR (4 times) = God is the greatest
LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH (There is no god except One God)
ALHAMDU LILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
I have been talking to you about the overwhelming,
the blessed explosion in the miracle
of the QURAN in the last few weeks.
And Gatut was supposed to give the KHUTBA today,
but because of the unusual circumstances,
this blessed explosion, I again asked him
to let me give the KHUTBA, today.
So, you have to put up with me one more time.
But when I go back to the basics, as you know the miracle of the QURAN is based... the foundation
is in the first verse BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHEEM.
And these are exactly 19 letters.
Now, we came to know that the meaning of the number
19 is that God is One
because in the old time when the QURAN was
revealed, there were no numbers.
They used the alphabet as numbers.
And this for example served the letter 'WOW'
and also as the number 6.
This was the letter 'ALIF' and the number
1 at the same time.
This was the letter 'HA' and the number 8.
These, every, every alphabet served
double as a number and an alphabet.
The letter 'D' also served as 4.
So, when you add 4 and 8 is 12, 13, and 19.
The total is 19.
So, the reason the number 19 is the common denominator
is that it means that God is One.
This is the basic message of the QURAN.
Do not worship except ALLAH.
So, sometimes I'm surprised at as how much some
of us
here do not know these basic pieces of information.
So now, with this very quick review, the
blessed explosion this time has to do with
the five pillars of Islam.
I'm gonna write... I'm gonna deal with the number 1 which is worshipping God alone.
Okay, what we just found...
I think you probably knew, most of you knew
that the word
'WAHID' in the QURAN is found 25 times,
but 6 of those have nothing to do with God.
They have to do with the children of Israel saying "we cannot tolerate one kind of food."
(2:61) لَنْ نَصْبِرَ عَلَى طَعَامٍ وَاحِدٍ
And Joseph's brother telling his children "do
not enter from one door."
(12:67) لَا تَدْخُلُوا۟ مِنۢ بَابٍۢ وَٰحِدٍۢ and so on.
6 of them have nothing to do with ALLAH. 19 say, that God is One. 19 of them.
So, this keeps with the code but what is new
now is that you take the numbers of the SURAHs
and the numbers of verses where the word 'WAHID'
occurs and the total; One, worship God alone.
The total is 1425 which is 19 x 75.
It's a multiple of 19.
Now, it is not enough to know that God is
One
that "ALLAH WAHID", you must worship God Alone.
And this is something new in the word WAHDAHU, God alone.
This word is mentioned in the QURAN 6 times.
5 times, it has to do with ALLAH and 1 time
with the QURAN.
(17:46) وَإِذَا ذَكَرْتَ رَبَّكَ فِى ٱلْقُرْءَانِ وَحْدَهُۥ وَلَّوْا۟ عَلَىٰٓ أَدْبَـٰرِهِمْ نُفُورًۭا
Has to do with the QURAN.
"If you preach the QURAN alone, they don't like it."
But the 5 times, you take the verses and the
SURAHs again and you add them up
and the total is 361. Watch this now.
361 for the word "Alone".
Worship God alone.
This is 19 x 19.
This is assurance.
It turns out that these numbers have also a
message in them.
Okay. So, this is the first pillar of Islam: Worshipping God Alone.
The other basic pillars, as you know, the famous, five
basic pillars of Islam are what?
SALAT, ZAKAT, SIYAM, fasting and HAJJ.
Now it turns out, you can look at the index of the QURAN and SALAT is mentioned 67 times.
ZAKAT is mentioned, I believe 6
times. No 32 times.
SIYAM is 6 times and HAJJ 9 times.
Where are they?
Yeah.
Let us add these together. These are the numbers of times these basic duties in Islam are mentioned.
7 and 2 is 9, 15, 24. 2 and 6 is 8 and 3 is 11. 114, the same number of SURAHs as the QURAN
or 19 X 6. Okay, this is not the big deal here right.
Well this is, this is profound.
But what is really profound is that you take the
word SALAT, everywhere the word SALAT is found
in the QURAN,
take the number of the SURAH,
and the numbers of the verses.
These are the numbers assigned to the AYAT and you add them up,
and the total for SALAT is 4674.
This is a multiple of 19.
And then you take SIYAM.
I'm gonna take SIYAM first.
And you do the same thing,
you take the numbers of SURAHs
and the numbers assigned to the verses and
add them up
and the total is 1,387 a multiple of 19.
This is 19 x 73.
You take ZAKAT, the 32 of them.
Everywhere the word ZAKAT is found in the QURAN, you take the number of the SURAH and the numbers assigned to the verses
and the total is 2395.
Now, the computer did all this.
Now, this here is NOT a multiple of 19. It is up by 1.
But then, you go to HAJJ and you find that
the total, in the same manner is 645.
This is NOT a multiple of 19. It is down by 1.
So, but when you add all of them together,
the total, of course, is a multiple of 19.
Now, watch the message that this gives us
that SALAT, every Muslim in the world did
SALAT
sometimes during his or her life.
Every Muslim did.
It is the most important duty on every Muslim
SALAT. And the number is a multiple of 19.
Fasting of RAMADAN,
every Muslim in the world before
he or she dies, fasted sometimes during RAMADAN
without exception.
Everyone must fast.
Every Muslim must fast,
rich or poor, they can do it.
Now, ZAKAT,
is only for the Rich.
It is not... not every Muslim pays ZAKAT.
And this is reflected in the fact that this
is not a multiple of 19,
and the same with HAJJ but together
They are divisible. They are multiples.
There's a message in the numbers also. You can see the extreme
intricacies of the numbers and the message that come with them.
Not every Muslim in the world made HAJJ before he or she died,
not everyone but everyone made SALAT, everyone
fasted and only the rich pay ZAKAT.
This (ZAKAT) is up 1 and this (HAJJ) is down 1.
So, these are the five basic pillars of Islam,
that "God is One." I've mentioned it to you. And these four basic pillars.
Okay, there is more that I will have to talk to
you in the second KHUTBAH.
So, turn to ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA  and repent.
TUBU ILLA ALLAH.
ALHAMDU LILLAH. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHAREEKA LAH.
In the continuing research of Ihsan,
she's been holding the index of the QURAN; and adding
the numbers of the SURAHs and the numbers of the verses and
she's coming up with this blessed explosion in the
miracle and also putting us to work.
We are sorry that she's leaving tomorrow
but we're also glad,
No, no.
We're really sorry that she's leaving tomorrow
Because she does put us to work through the telephone anyway.
Look at the SURAH Qaf,
SURAH number 50 initialed with Q.
It's in SURAH 50.
You take... this is very simple. Anybody
can do at home without a computer.
You look at SURAH Qaf and look at the AYAT where the
letter Qaf happens.
You know, we have it in the blue book.
You can see SURAH QAF and the verses.
You add them up, they're 798,
a multiple of 19.
19 means God is One.
Worship God alone.
And this is 19 x 42.
Well, it doesn't stop here.
You know what 42 is.
It's the only other SURAH that is also initialed with Qaf.
SURAH Al-Shoorã: HA MEEM 'AYN SEEN QAF.
So, there is that. This interlocking and intertwined
relationship of the mathematical code is telling
us that this is the only
book in the world, in history, that is mathematically composed,
that is superhuman, that when you read any statement in it, you know this is from your Creator.
You have 100% confidence, this is God speaking to you
and this is the importance of it.
It never happened before in history and will
never happen again.
This is an original idea of ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA' ALLA.
You will not find a book...
you go to the university, how many books do they have, the university libraries?
Millions, not one of them is mathematically
composed.
But the QURAN is.
I was writing yesterday. It's something that
I wrote before but I
wanted to share, I wanna share it with you was... we're writing a book about Jesus,
the truth about Jesus
from the Quran, from the Bible, from the Gospels.
And an interesting fact, very quickly,
is I was writing a chapter "Jesus birth"
and the Quran say that
(3:59) إِنَّ مَثَلَ عِيسَىٰ عِندَ ٱللَّهِ كَمَثَلِ ءَادَمَ
The creation of Jesus as far as God is concerned
is equal to the creation of Adam.
Jesus equals Adam.
In other words, the creation of Jesus is like the creation of Adam.
(3:59) خَلَقَهُۥ مِن تُرَابٍۢ ثُمَّ قَالَ لَهُۥ كُن فَيَكُونُ
God said "be and it is."
He said to Jesus "be in Mary's womb" and he was.
So, it just happens that in the Quran and this is, anybody can look at in the index,
that both Jesus and Adam are mentioned exactly the same number of time, 25.
25 (Adam) and 25 (Jesus).
I believe the name of Jesus is a multiple of
5, when you look at the numerical values of it,
but this will be another KHUTBA, IN SHA ALLAH.
And then, I wanna pass on to you a valuable
experience in all these works with the miracle
of the Quran and the book on Jesus that is
geared to the average American here.
We experienced interferences from Satan that
are very clear.
And we also found out how to chase him away.
And it turns out to be a commandment in the
Quran in SURAH 23
where it says in Arabic... and we tried it and
it works and I want it to work for you.
I want you to do it as my brothers and sisters because it's really effective.
And it is a commandment in the Quran. It says,
(23:97) وَقُل رَّبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ هَمَزَٰتِ ٱلشَّيَـٰطِينِ
QUL means say.
It's a commandment.
My Lord, I seek refuge in You from Satan,
from the suggestions of the devils.
Excuse me,
this is the literal translation.
It will be
wonderful if you can learn in Arabic and
say it just like this because it is a numerical
combination.
The statement is رَّبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ  you
know most of these words anyway.
رَّبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ هَمَزَٰتِ ٱلشَّيَـٰطِينِ
My Lord, I seek refuge in You from the suggestions of the devils.
(23:98) وَأَعُوذُ بِكَ رَبِّ أَن يَحْضُرُونِ
And I seek in You my Lord lest they come near me.
So, I would suggest to you that you study
this in Arabic and say it. I'm
telling you a thousand times a day is not,
is not enough
because the sneaky whisperer ٱلْوَسْوَاسِ ٱلْخَنَّاسِ
will grab any chance and will come to you
and suggest things against ALLAH SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA.
So, this is a very effective commandment and
this is my suggestion. You can call it ZIKR
because you are
making ZIKIR of ALLAH.
رَّبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ هَمَزَٰتِ ٱلشَّيَـٰطِينِ وَأَعُوذُ بِكَ رَبِّ أَن يَحْضُرُونِ
And we'll have to rush through, so
AQEM AL-SALAT.