أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيْمِ
(36:1) يسٓ
(36:2) وَٱلْقُرْءَانِ ٱلْحَكِيمِ
(36:3) إِنَّكَ لَمِنَ ٱلْمُرْسَلِينَ
(36:4) عَلَىٰ صِرَٰطٍ مُّسْتَقِيمٍ
(36:5) تَنزِيلَ ٱلْعَزِيزِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(36:6) لِتُنذِرَ قَوْمًا مَّآ أُنذِرَ ءَابَآؤُهُمْ فَهُمْ غَـٰفِلُونَ
(36:7) لَقَدْ حَقَّ ٱلْقَوْلُ عَلَىٰٓ أَكْثَرِهِمْ فَهُمْ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ
(36:8) إِنَّا جَعَلْنَا فِىٓ أَعْنَـٰقِهِمْ أَغْلَـٰلًا فَهِىَ إِلَى ٱلْأَذْقَانِ فَهُم مُّقْمَحُونَ
وَجَعَلْنَا مِنۢ بَيْنِ أَيْدِيهِمْ سَدًّا وَمِنْ خَلْفِهِمْ سَدًّا فَأَغْشَيْنَـٰهُمْ فَهُمْ
(36:9) لَا يُبْصِرُونَ
(36:10) وَسَوَآءٌ عَلَيْهِمْ ءَأَنذَرْتَهُمْ أَمْ لَمْ تُنذِرْهُمْ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ
إِنَّمَا تُنذِرُ مَنِ ٱتَّبَعَ ٱلذِّكْرَ وَخَشِىَ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنَ بِٱلْغَيْبِ ۖ فَبَشِّرْهُ
(36:11) بِمَغْفِرَةٍ وَأَجْرٍ كَرِيمٍ
إِنَّا نَحْنُ نُحْىِ ٱلْمَوْتَىٰ وَنَكْتُبُ مَا قَدَّمُوا۟ وَءَاثَـٰرَهُمْ ۚ وَكُلَّ شَىْءٍ
(36:12) أَحْصَيْنَـٰهُ فِىٓ إِمَامٍ مُّبِينٍ
But that night, in April, I opened Quran as usual and read the place where usually... the top right. And it said "you're going to hell."
So, I closed it again and said this is Satan telling me, trying to fighting me with giving me bad time. So, I said
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
And please God protect me from Satan. I seek refuge in You. And I said it in many different ways
and then I opened it again at random as usual and it said "you're fired. You will not do the job. You're a chicken. You're not suitable. And you are going to hell."
So, I sought refuge in God again from Satan, from the devil in stronger terms for a longer time. I made SUJUD
Then, I opened the Quran again at random. It said "you're fired. You're going to hell. You're doomed. You're not gonna do it. We'll find somebody else to do the job."
So, I closed it again. It is now defying statistics or coincidence.
So, I turned to God very hard and I said "please, God, let me know if this is coincidence or why is it giving me these bad ideas."
So, I opened and I kept doing this and repeatedly every time, I opened. It said "you're fired. You're no good. You're going to hell. You're doomed."
And it was getting worse. Until I reached the conviction, a real conviction in my heart, that I'm doomed. I'm going to hell.
Then, I started to cry. And I started to repent. And I opened it and as if the Quran had nothing in it except "you're fired. You're going to hell.
You're not gonna do the work. We'll substitute somebody in your place." So, I said this Quran is rigged. Maybe, because I'm using it a lot.
So, I got this one which was brand new. And I opened it. It said "you're fired. You're going to hell. You cannot do the job. You're a chicken. We'll substitute somebody in your place."
So, I closed it again and I opened another place. The Quran had nothing in it except... I got the English Quran and I opened it.
I looked in a neutral spot. "You're fired. You'll not do the job. You're going to hell." So, it is no longer coincidence.
I got this big book, this big Quran, here.
And I opened it this way. I mean, I did all kinds of crazy things to let the Quran open at random and go like this.
And then I opened the Quran and looked in it. And it say "you're going to hell. You're doomed. You cannot do the job. You're fired."
So, with this, I got... Oh, I got a letter opener and I stacked the Qurans
like this and I point. I closed my eyes and pointed the letter opener
and inserted it in one of these pages and opened it
and it tell me the same thing. There was nothing in the Quran that morning except "you're fired. You cannot do the job. Get out of here. You're doomed. I don't need you anymore. I substitute somebody else in your place."
So, I cried and I made SUJUD. And I repented. I sought refuge from Satan and it kept giving me the same message.
So, I became convinced that God is speaking to me through the Quran and I became convinced that I'm no good,
that I'm fired, that I'm going to hell. And I cried as hard as I never did in my life.
I really became convinced that I'm finished and I'm doomed and there is no salvation inside.
I... my SUJUD became longer, my crying was harder. There was nobody in the mosque.
And then one time, I opened the Quran and it said "We forgive you." Oh, I reached the conviction with all this crying that...
now, the message was very clear that I am not coming out with an announcement that I am God's messenger.
I have known it since 1980 and I ignored messages that say... there are verses in Quran that say "say O, people I'm God's messenger to all of you."
And I ignored those. They were very loud and very clear and I ignored them. Obviously, the timing was not right, then. I mean, now in retrospect
I was supposed to have ignored those messages. They got loud and repeated and louder and clearer and I kept ignoring them until this happened. So, there is something that led to this.
I mean, I opened the Quran says "say O, people I'm God's messenger for all of you."
And I became convinced that this is no longer the case. Then, with these repetitions, I reached the decision... in my repentance,
I said "please God accept my repentance. Take me back even if I lose my own children, my friends, if I lose everybody, I will, I will do anything. I will go out and I will make the announcement."
And I really had that conviction cause I said chances are my children will tell me "get out of here. You're a crazy man. What are you talking about?"
So, it became my neck. And there are verses in Quran where it says "the person disowns his own parents, his own children. The children disown their parents" and so on. It became a reality for me.
And here I am doomed, going to hell. And all things are hinging on courage. God doesn’t want a coward to work for him.
It became very obvious.
So, when I really reached the conviction that I will do it at any expense, I got this message that said "you're forgiven. We'll accept your repentance."
And my crying of sadness became crying of joy.
And I still didn’t believe that remark. Maybe, it's a fluke.
So, I did the same thing and there was nothing in the Quran except "We accept your repentance. You're forgiven. Go now and do the job. God is Forgiver, Merciful."
And I did it in the same way. I mean, this defied all statistic and all coincidence.
The background to this...
This is why I'm not... people who around me know that I'm not making any bones about it. I'm not being humble about it and I could not take any chances.
And I believe if it happens again, I will be really fired and be sent to Hell. And I'm not gonna do it. So, this is why I have been bold.
And it really has nothing to do with humbleness or modesty. If we understand a few basic things in the Quran. One thing is that a messenger is no big deal.
That it is a big deal only if we idolize the messengers. We get the picture in our mind...
...and this is the typical response with all the believers.
The people who were averse from the beginning, they just continued to be averse or maybe a little bit worse.
Except their harsh attacks had a little bit of reverence in, as if in the background, it said "what if he is?"
I get this telephone calls on the machine and in the past, they used to call me bad names and all that but
now they say... they read Quran. And they read the verses that says "fear God."
And then they add "come back to Islam." This kind of thing. But you can sense the kind of respect they have at the back of their mind.
This is the difference that happened with the opponents.
And this is because of their reverence for RASOOL ALLAH. This word, they made it so big and put it next to God.
And this is why it's a big deal for them. But if we understand the Quran, we'll find out that it is not a big deal
because the Quran teaches us that a messenger is not necessarily better than anyone in the world, in the generation, or anyone around him.
We have this lesson in SURA 18 where Moses, one of the big messengers of God met someone who's described as one of God's servants. "one of Our servants" God says.
And this one of God's servants began teaching Moses a few lessons and Moses turned out to be a lousy student.
So, this is teaching us that the messenger, the biggest ones, are not any better than anyone around them. I mean, not necessarily better than people around them.
The Quran teaches that say "I'm a human being like you." And this is about the prophet Muhammad, for example.
The Quran teaches that the criterion for closeness to God is righteousness, not being a messenger or not being the most knowledgeable or the richest or the tallest
or anything else. Righteousness. Nothing else. So, and anyone can be more righteous than the messenger or anybody else.
There is also a verse in SURA 39 that says that "being a messenger of God does not even guarantee Heaven." It is no guarantee.
It says. I'm quoting the Quran, now. It says "that's what We revealed to you and to those before you that if you ever fall in idol worship, in idolatry, all your work will be nullified and you'll be a loser."
So, if people understand this, they won't make a big deal out of being a messenger of God. I called Atef and I told him about this.
and he... logically, he started to discuss the wisdom of making an announcement like this and why is it necessary.
And I found myself him and I talking as if I sat down and decided to make an announcement. Then, it dawned on me it's not really my decision. It was not my decision at all.
Obviously, God wants this announcement to be made for reasons that only God knows.
And we can speculate on.
The first verse in SURA 67 says "God created death and life to test us, to test the people."
Cause before that there was no death. Before the human race came here, there was no death. This is why God says He created death.
mentioned death before life.
The whole purpose is a test. And it turns out and we know now that the road to God is full of traps on the side for people to fall off. They drop out.
And when you hear somebody say "I'm a messenger of God." Some people drop out. And it's part of the sifting process. There are so many traps along the road.
And the matter is decided, really, from the very beginning. I mean, a person who has doubts, who is not a sincere believer will fall off at one of these traps along the road.
The firm believer will keep going, no matter what happens. Because what we're saying is "worship God Alone." We are saying "destroy all idols."
And we are fanatically against building idols.
This reminds me of... I don't know if it's a good joke. I mean, there's nothing bad about the language but...
The Muhammadans insist on putting Muhammad's name next to God and say
لا إله إلا الله محمد رسول الله
In the AZAN they say
So, I'm tempted to ask them how do you like if we follow your method and, you know, we say
لا إله إلا الله
That's it. There is no god except the One God.
This is like the Quran says. Verse 18 of SURA 3, God says
شَهِدَ ٱللَّهُ
God bears witness
أَنَّهُۥ لَآ إِلَـٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ
that there is no god except He. In other words, God's SHAHADA is
لا إله إلا الله
and then the verse goes on and says
وَٱلْمَلَـٰٓئِكَةُ
also the angels
وَأُو۟لُوا۟ ٱلْعِلْمِ
and those who possess knowledge.
This is their SHAHADA.
لا إله إلا الله
So, it's very clear in the Quran that the SHAHADA is
They insist because of idolatry to add the Muhammad's name which violates a good number of commandments in the Quran when you put Muhammad's name next to God
in the so-called SHAHADA, their SHAHADA,
they are violating a good number of commandments. So, the temptation is I wanna tell them "how do you like if we say"
لا إله إلا الله رشاد رسول الله
if we follow your method.
Now that they picked up this opposition to me... the Muhammadans... and to the point that I'm under death sentence in a good number of countries, now.
Saudi Arabia is one of them. Iran is another one. So, now that they hate me so much, how would they like to say
لا إله إلا الله رشاد رسول الله
if I give them enough proof and so on.
Maybe, this will induce them to just say
لا إله إلا الله
So, we are saying
We are, very strongly, starchly against building any idol. And
I don’t know how to convince them that I don’t want any glory or money or fame. And for 8 years, I was really... I was a coward.
I mean, what did this announcement bring to me? Except, I thought "trouble."
but it did not, actually. Their action has been positive so far.
But I would rather go and worship God Alone by myself somewhere very quietly and just eke out and living out of this world and go into the eternal life.
This is what I'd rather do, personally. This is what I wanted to do for 8 years. This is why I was fired in that night.
So, I'm sure I forgot quite a few points that I wanted to tell you about.
The background of this is that I have known since 1980
that I'm God's messenger in the sense that... not in a general sense... in the sense that Abraham was the original messenger of Islam.
He brought all the practices. The NAMAZ, the fasting, the ZAKAT Charity, pilgrimage
and of course the first commandment.
لا إله إلا الله
and Muhammad brought the Quran. And that I am the third of a triangle that I brought the proof... the proof of authenticity of the religion.
The first publication... we just found out this yesterday... The first time the miracle of Quran was published
was in January 1973.
1973, I was 38 years old and I didn’t know anything except that I found this mathematical miracle in the Quran.
And the 7th... the January 73 publication in the most popular magazine in the middle east: آخر الساعة
had to do with the proportion of the initials. Qaf, for example, the letter Q in chapter 50. That chapter had the highest proportion of the letter Q.
SURA Saad had the highest proportion of the letter Saad. SURA NuN had the highest proportion of SURA NuN. Alef Lam Meemm and so on.
Every SURA had the highest proportion of its initials except SURA Ya Seen had the least... the exact opposite. And that was the whole article.
And it didn’t have the computer printouts of the whole Quran which I had written in the computer. And then in 1973, in November
which is exactly my 38th birthday was the first report on the number 19. That was back in 73.
And... but I didn’t know that I am God's messenger in that sense until 1980.
1980 was correspondent to the year 1400, the Islamic year. And
it seems like a new era began at that time, 1400. If you look here
in SURA 47.... SURA 47, verse 38. 38 was very prominent. We were looking at this magazine yesterday
We became curious... We were looking at it on the other page.
They had reports in the magazine 38 years ago. They had a big number 38.
47, the last verse which is 38.
I wrote in bold letters that if you turn away, God will substitute other people in your place and they will not be like you.
This is one of the verses, by the way, about substituting somebody in your place.
But then I wrote this in bold... in big letters and I put a footnote saying here.... at the end of the footnote it says "Islam is being reestablished in the English-speaking world
after being restored to its pristine purity.
So, I wrote here, back in 1980, 1400 that God had forsaken the Arabs. The Arabs meaning in the Arabian peninsula.
There's a certain geographical area where the Arabs are... that defines who the Arabs are.
And now, it's been 8 years and we didn't have... we don't have a single Arab. Of the hundred million Arabs in the world, we don't have a single Arab who could see and appreciate the miracle of Quran
even though it's very clear.
An Arab, from the Arabian peninsula, not from North Africa and not from Egypt.
Sometimes they call me and say "you're an Arab, aren't you?" I say "No, Thank God. I'm Egyptian."
But it's quite a phenomenon that we don’t have a single Arab.
Last Friday, we had like 60 people in the mosque, not a single Arab.
We had the conference in San Francisco, couple of hundred people, not a single Arab except those who came to harass us.
So, there's.... something happened in 1980 after 7 pairs of centuries.
SURA 13... 15 excuse me. SURA 15, verse 87. God is telling Muhammad "I'm giving you 7 pairs."
Among the other meanings, I'm convinced that it means 7 pairs of centuries because of what I've seen and the fact that this verse is at the end of SURA entitled Muhammad.
So, the background is that I have known since 1980 and I have been evading the responsibility of... Actually, we'll just go, just go along and worship God and spread the message.
And what we've been doing was... God has been gracious to us in that He's been showing us what the correct Islam is.
The Muhammadans, throughout the world, the hundred million of them are doing SALAT wrong, they mention
محمد آل محمد. ابراهیم آل ابراهیم
in the SALAT. We know now for sure that this is wrong.
The Quran came out of Muhammad's mouth. It says "you should never mention any other name during the SALAT
besides other than the name of God. That the SALAT must be devoted to God Alone and no one else." So, they did the SALAT wrong. They did the ZAKAT wrong.
They are doing it wrong. And now we have it corrected.
If we look in SURA 6, verse 141, it tells you "when you harvest the fruits or the crops, give the charity, the ZAKAT charity of that crop on the day of harvest."
Now, the ZAKAT as being practiced now in the Muhammadan world is once a year on your savings, above a certain amount.
But the Quran says "give the ZAKAT on the day of harvest."
Now, since we are not farmers, we do not harvest fruits or crops, or anything like that. We harvest paychecks. So, when we get the paycheck, we're supposed to take out
what came to us from IBRAHIM in very clear words
ربع العشر
a quarter of ten. One quarter of one ten. This comes to 2.5 percent.
So, you take 2.5% of your net income when you get it, the day you get it. So, I would... I would go...
I would say it makes sense that we wait like a month to know what our month seems, we get our paychecks, our monthly income. It's a very common thing.
And you, at the end of the month, figure out how much was your net income, 2.5 percent and you give it to people you personally know are in need.
You know them, personally, and you know that they need the assistance. And we are given specific order in the Quran as to who we give the money to.
You give it first to your parents. If they don’t need it, you give it to relatives, cousins, and uncles and aunts and so on. People you know, personally
who are related to you and they need the money or the help. After that, the orphans. You find children who lost one or both parents
for some reason, divorce or abandonment or death and you give them this money. And the fourth category is any poor persons and the last category are traveling aliens
people who sneak into this country from Mexico. They have no jobs. They are hungry. So, you help them. We have a specific order in the Quran.
This is the correct ZAKAT. So, what we did was, we cleaned out the SALAT. We returned it to its pristine purity.
We corrected the ZAKAT. We corrected the fasting. Even the fasting was wrong.
What SURA?
What was wrong with it? Well, they sleep all day and stay up all night and use fasting as an excuse to be nasty and...
You know that. They call names and then say "I am fasting." So, "excuse me, I'm fasting."
And the timing of the moon is always wrong.
I think they're fasting today, still in Egypt. And even though, tonight you can see the moon.
I'd love to go out, but
the computer tells you what time the moon is born, what time it rises, what time it sets
and whether the clouds or not, whether inside or not, whether you are sighted or blind, you can know exactly what the moon is doing.
But they follow the Hadith that says "you fast when you see it, and you break your fast when you don't see it.
and if you cannot see it, you complete the month of Ramadan, 30 days." So, we fasted 29 days this month.
Audience: "Is it 29 days all the time?"
The messenger: No, sometimes 29, sometimes 30.
The Hajj was wrong and we already wrote in the Muslim Perspective to correct... Hajj is wrong by going to Medina.
It turns out that, as it is now done, going to Medina is the most important part of Hajj even though it is not part of Hajj at all in the Quran.
Going to Medina is flagrant idol worship. They go to the prophet's tomb or to Fatimah's tomb and they pray and implore.
"Nothing." I'm quoting the Quran because on the Day of Judgement say "we were worshipping nothing."
So, this is what we've been doing and I was happy that way. So, we were just spreading the message. It has gone all over the world, literally.
This... this translation and the small book, the brown book, Quran, Hadith and Islam and the message of returning Islam to its pristine purity as far as all the practices are concerned.
These places, I never heard of, little islands in the Indian ocean. There's an island called "l'union"? Union Island in English? But it's a French... "l'union."
Ihsan lived in Mauritius. That's another country I never heard of, Mauritius. And we have people there in Mauritius.
l'union? l'union? Close?
Are they close to Mauritius?
It must be.
I went to New Zealand, Australia. I went everywhere and I was happy that way. The message is being spread all over the world.
Exactly what needs to be done. So, why the announcement? That was my justification.
And that's why each one of you asked me "why the announcement? Why is it necessary?"
So, my opinion was the same as yours.
But then, I was...
Pardon?
Right. OK. What do they have?
Obviously, God has a reason. The Quran says "you don't ask God why. We ask."
God is not to be asked about anything He does but we are to be asked about anything we do.
(21:23) لَا يُسْـَٔلُ عَمَّا يَفْعَلُ وَهُمْ يُسْـَٔلُونَ
So, obviously God has a purpose and very good reasons. Now, the Quran says that Muhammad is not the last messenger.
And this could be one the very important reasons. So, if Muhammad is not the last messenger... The statement in the Quran in 33:40 says
مَّا كَانَ مُحَمَّدٌ أَبَآ أَحَدٍ مِّن رِّجَالِكُمْ
Muhammad was not the father of any of your men
وَلَـٰكِن رَّسُولَ ٱللَّه
a messenger of God
وَخَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّـۧنَ
and the final prophet
This expression of
رَّسُولَ ٱللَّه.  وَلَـٰكِن رَّسُولَ ٱللَّه
is not necessary at all for the meaning. If the prophet include the messenger or vice versa.
You can have a perfect sentence saying
مَّا كَانَ مُحَمَّدٌ أَبَآ أَحَدٍ مِّن رِّجَالِكُمْ وَلَـٰكِن خَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّـۧنَ
Muhammad was not the father of any of your men but he was the final prophet.
But of course every letter in the Quran is delivered as we know now, very well. It says
وَلَـٰكِن رَّسُولَ ٱللَّه
a messenger of God
وَخَاتَمَ ٱلنَّبِيِّـۧنَ
and the final prophet
So, there is a verse 35 in SURA 7 says "O, children of Adam when messengers come to you narrating My revelations to you, those of you who believe and lead a righteous life are the successful ones."
Obviously, this is a verse for the people after Muhammad because it's in the Quran. And like Dr. Mansour said "for as long as there are children of Adam on Earth, this verse is valid."
Because it says "O, children of Adam"
In Arabic
يَـٰبَنِىٓ ءَادَمَ إِمَّا يَأْتِيَنَّكُمْ رُسُلٌ مِّنكُمْ يَقُصُّونَ عَلَيْكُمْ ءَايَـٰتِى ۙ
(7:35) فَمَنِ ٱتَّقَىٰ وَأَصْلَحَ فَلَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
35, SURA 7.
So, I mean, what is this verse directed to? Not the people before Muhammad because they've never seen the Quran.
For the people who read the Quran.
The Quran gives us all sorts of example of the human tendency or aversion to the idea of having a messenger of God.
It seems to be a test of ego, a test of ego, you know. This guy is gonna sit here and say "I'm messenger of God." So, he's gonna steal the show. And
he's gonna get all the attention.
And it may be one of the tests, you know, for dropping out. This is something I don't wanna contribute to that. But it's not up to me.
So, the Quran illustrates this by using Joseph. Joseph... this is verse... I believe it's verse 34 in SURA 40.
SURA 40, it says "Joseph had come to you with clear revelations, but you doubted his message. Then, when he died you said he was the last messenger."
Now, look who God picks out. Joseph. Who came after Joseph? The big ones. What are the big ones? David, Solomon, Jesus, Moses, Muhammad.
All these came after Joseph even though the people said "he's the last messenger. Nobody else will come after that." So, they have been saying the same thing about Muhammad
that Mohammad is the last messenger.
The world population today is a thousand times what it was at the time of Muhammad. And you've seen how much advancement the human being achieved.
This is an enlightened generation of humans who are very advanced, computers, and sciences, and technology and video tapes. And it just makes sense that God wants to send a messenger to this generation.
And I can't make any bones about it. I can't. I'm chickened the other way around now. I was a chicken in being afraid to announce and now I'm a chicken not to... I'm a chicken to hold back.
Cause I'm afraid if I'm fired again, there will be no restoration.
So, this verse about Joseph tells us that it's a human tendency. And now the question to turn the table around... the question is why are they averse to this idea?
So, if Muhammad was not the last messenger and somebody is gonna come after Muhammad, messengers after Muhammad. What do they look like?
What are their qualifications? What will they say?
So, if someone comes along and says "worship God Alone.
Uphold the word of God Alone, not the words of men.
Clean out all the practices of worship.
Destroy all idols. Remove all innovations."
What's wrong with that?
I mean, it makes sense that God's messenger will do that, will say that.
Why will I oppose or object to someone who says that?
We'll get along just fine. With any one of us.
This is really the same message from Adam until now. It's one and the same message.
So, I along with you would ask that question, you know. And I put it in the Perspective. They should tell us why shouldn't I be a messenger of God?
I've given them enough proof. I've had lots of, there's a lot of evidence in that.
And it is mathematical. It is physical, tangible.
So, I want them to come up with evidence opposing that that I should not be.
There's one thing that came out. The first thing that came out I'm thinking of some Muslim organization in Oklahoma
and they issued the new magazine. The first issue. I think it was just for that and there was an article in it. said that "my name is not Rashad Khalifa."