WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH
We praise
God and we bear witness that there is no god except He.
The title of this KHUTBA is "who is your God?"
and I bet you anything quite a few of you
will be shocked because the natural answer,
the immediate answer is "what do you mean who is
my God? God is my god, the One who created me."
But the Quran is full of verses that tell us that
millions of people would say that their god is God.
You're familiar with the verses that
say "if you ask them who created the
heavens and the earth? They will
say "God" but they're going to hell."
The verses that say "if you ask them who is
the Lord of the Heavens and the Earth and
the Lord with the great Dominion and
the great throne? They will answer "God."
But they're going to Hell. You ask them "who created
you?" They will say "God." So, these are millions of
people who recognize God as the One who created
the Heavens and the Earth, the One who created
them. The One with the great Authority. The Lord of
the Heavens and the Earth, but they're still going
to Hell. Now, I know this is your answer "who's your
God?" And you're gonna say "God is the One God who created
me." But we have this... this KHUTBA is to examine
this question and for you to examine your answer.
We know that your happiness in this world
and forever depends on knowing who your God
is and worshipping God. God guarantees you
perfect happiness in this world and forever.
And this is repeated in the Quran 23 times. Perfect
health, perfect wealth, perfect peace of mind
guaranteed. God is the One who runs the
universe and is guaranteeing this for you.
No problems whatsoever. "Read my lips" like
Bush says. No problems whatsoever if you are
worshiping God alone, worshipping your God.
And you and I are going to detect flaws in
us as we examine this question: who is your God?
It turns out... I'm gonna give you the answer
first then we'll discuss the specifics... it
turns out that whatever is preoccupying
your mind the majority of the day that is your
god. Whatever you are thinking of in your mind,
this is your god. And the Quran explains this
very clearly in specific terms. If you are
preoccupied with yourself, what you look like
you're shaved, your make-up, your dresses, your hair. If you arepreoccupied with yourself, what the people think
of you, "he is a nice guy, she's a nice lady." If this
is your concern the majority of the day, then you
are your god. You are worshipping your ego and
we see this in SURA 25, verse 43. 25:43 says
"Have noted the one whose god is himself or his desires
or his wishes or literally "his self?" quote, unquote.
Now, the answer that whatever is preoccupying your mind most of the day is
your god is backed up by many many verses
in the Quran. If you are preoccupied with
your job most of the day, that is your god, not God who created you. You can say that
the One who created the Heavens and the
Earth is God but your god is your job.
If your spouse is preoccupying you more than God
then that is your god, your wife or your husband.
If your property or the dollar, the mighty
dollars, preoccupying you. That is your god. Now, let
us look at the Quran and see what backs up
this idea. In SURA 33, verse 41, we say... it says
"O, you who believe commemorate God or remember
God or mention God a lot." Okay. Now, the prayer is
mentioned 5 times, the fasting is one month in
the year, the ZAKAT is two and a half percent
of your income and so on. Everything is limited
but when it comes to commemorating God or mentioning
God or thinking of God, there is no limit. It
says KATHIRAN, a lot. And the following verse says
(33:42) وَسَبِّحُوهُ بُكْرَةً وَأَصِيلًا
and glorify Him
day and night. Remember God or mention God or
think of God a lot. Glorify Him day and night.
And I will discuss with you how to do this
We see in SURA 3, verse 191, a description
of the believers who are going to Heaven.
God says "they are the ones who think of
God or mention God or commemorate God
standing or sitting or on their side." So,
this covers all your positions, standing
up, sitting down or laying down, you think of God.
We see in SURA 2, verse 200 that you
should think of God or mention God
or commemorate God just as you mention
or commemorate or think of your parents,
your own parents, even more. So, you
can see "even more" is an addition.
In SURA 2, verse 165, the believers are described as
loving God the most. You see the comparison? You
can love your spouse, you can love your children, you can
love your job even as long as God is in your mind
the majority of the time. Then, that is... whoever you're
thinking of the majority of the time is your god.
In 64:14, there's a statement that says "your spouses and your children can be your enemies."
How could that be? By becoming
preoccupied with them.
Ironically, if you want a good spouse and good
children, you should give your attention to God
not to them. Cause God is with your kids
as they ride the bicycle in the street, not you.
So, if you are with God, God will be with your
kids and with your spouse. God controls your spouse's
mind and heart. And you can guarantee
a good spouse if you are good with God.
Look at this in SURA 63, verse 9, God is talking to
the believers. Says "O, you who believe do not be
distracted by your money and your children
from commemorating God or mentioning God
or remembering God" The world is ZIKR-O-ALLAH, in Arabic. "Do not be distracted by your
money and your children from commemorating
or mentioning or remembering God." And this is
directed to the believers. In 64:15, we are told
that your children and your spouses are a test
cause you become attached to them.
So, one of the common gods is
yourself, being preoccupied with yourself.
Another common god is your job, your property,
the dollar and we see this in SURA 18.
Let me back up a little bit about worshipping yourself or your self being your
god. In SURA 18, verse 28 we say... there's a
commandment to the believers. "Do not obey
those whose hearts are diverted from
commemorating or mentioning God." Again
the same word ZIKR-O-ALLAH, throughout these verses is ZIKR-O-ALLAH, otherwise, I will... I will tell you
if it is different. It says "do not obey, do
not follow, do not go with, do not mix with
those whose hearts are diverted
from commemorating God
or mentioning God because they will drag you
with them into thinking about something else.
You can already see that God is not
your god seven days a week. Maybe, one
day a week, maybe two or three days a
week, maybe zero. I don't know. You're the judge.
But this is the definition. You just divide
the day into 100 units instead of 24 hours, 100
units, and see how many of these units, you
are thinking of God. Is it more than 50%?
You judge. This comes as a shock
to many of us but it is also a
great blessing cause God wills that we
know because you can fix it right now.
If there is a problem, if I discover that I am... that God is my god one day a week, I
can fix it right now. And I can pledge that
God will be my god every day of the week.
The answer to this question may answer your
common question: why am I having problems.
Also, it will be a good indicator for you
when you have a problem, why am I having a problem.
If you dig deep, you'll find that you didn't
think of God the majority of the day. And I'm
going to discuss with you how if I forget
reminding because I don't have it written here:
how to think of God the majority of the day.
So, speak up if I finish the KHUTBA. Sometimes, I get distracted.
We have to find out how we can
think of God the majority of the day.
Okay. It is now 12:30. I believe everybody's here.So, for those of you who came late, I'm gonna
update this for you very quickly. The subject ofKHUTBA is: "who is your god?" And the answer is
whoever you are thinking of or whatever
you are thinking of the majority of the
day, whatever is in your mind, whateverpreoccupies you. OK. I mentioned "yourself."
In SURA 18, verse 42, we're told that your job, your property, your boss can be your god.
Your boss says "we have an emergency here at
work and you must come here 3 o'clock in the
morning for the next 10 days." Are you gonna go
at 3 o'clock in the morning for the next 10 days?
God tells you to pray the morning prayer
before sunrise. Are you gonna pray the
morning prayer before sunrise? I mean,  these
are... you have to ask yourself these questions.
You don't have... Yes, you have... you have to
pray the morning... every morning before
sunrise. What I wanna say is that
God says you cannot possibly do it
every day because sometimes you're too tired,
sometimes you're sick, sometimes you're traveling
sometimes you have unusual circumstances.
So, unless you have unusual circumstances
if you don't pray the morning before sunrise, God is not your god.You have some other god.
The criterion is very very easy. SURA 18, verse
42, remember the fellow who had two gardens and
he was very boastful and happy, happy with them?"I'm fixed. I won the lottery. I'm fixed for life."
Sure enough a tornado came and wiped out the two
gardens. But we learn from that that... by the way, I'm
gonna interrupt my KHUTBA here and say whatever
you god is other than God, you're gonna lose it,
guaranteed. If you worship your job, you're gonna lose it. If you worship your spouse, you're gonna lose her or him
and so on. It's guaranteed. Whatever you worship other
than God, you're gonna lose it, guaranteed. So...
and we learn from SURA 18, verse 42
because this... this tornado came
and wiped out the two gardens of
this guy who was so... he thought he was fixed for life.
So, if you idolize your job, give it more attention than God, I guarantee you, you're gonna lose it.
In SURA 7, verse 190, we see that the children
clearly can be your god. In this verse, I will
remind you, verse 190 of SURA 7, it says "this couple...
the wife gets pregnant and they pray. Please,
give us a good baby, good healthy baby.
Please, God give us a good baby. And God
gives him a good baby. Then, they make
the baby their god." What does this mean?
It's what the verse says. End of quotation. This means
they gave the baby more attention than God.
The principle holds that whatever preoccupiesyour mind the majority of the day is your god.
Again, to get all these things, to get the good
children, the good job, the good money, the good
health, the good happiness and peace of mind.
You know the answer. I'm gonna remind you again
of the Gospel of Luke 12:29 to 31. "Seek God's
kingship over you and everything else follows."
If God is your god, you're guaranteed all of these things.
TUBU ILLA ALLAH, repent.
ALHAMDULILLAH, we praise God. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH, and I bear witness that there is no god
except the One God. I hope in your repentance,
you pledged that your god will be God, the One
who created you. Because if you had any deficiency
in the past, you had better fixed it right now. With...
with this repentance. And you mean it every day. You
can take account of what you're doing in the day.
OK. Now, we wanna talk about how... how you go about making God your god. The Quran teaches us.
When you see your children, or your car runs nicely,
you say MASHA ALLAH, this is God's blessing. God
gave me this. When you see a beautiful flower
or a beautiful sunset or your own fingers, you
say SUBHAN ALLAH, God be glorified. OK. Let me start
from the beginning. Let me go back, now. You're
asleep and you're getting up in the morning. When
you get up, you get up in the name of God
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM or say it in any language
you want. The minute you open your eyes, you say
BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM, in the name of God,
Most Gracious, Most Merciful. LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH, there
is no god except the One God. This is the firstthing you must say. This is the first thing as I mentioned to you before
that everybody will say on the Day of Resurrection. When they get up, they will say - 99% of them - "Oh, shit!" 99% of them.
99% of the people will say that. It's not a dirty word anymore. So, I allowed myself to say for the first time in the KHUTBAH.
I mean, you can see it on the TV all the time.
99% of the people, they wake up and look at the clock and say "Oh, ...." You have torush to work. and this is exactly what they will say on the Day of Resurrection.
So, I hope this you reminds you that the first thing to say in the morning
is what you're gong to say on the Day of
Resurrection and it must be BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
In the name of God. LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH. So, there's your mentioning God
the first thing you open your eyes. You go do your ablution and do the
morning prayer. Now, the five prayers,
we're told in Quran, the five prayers
are designed for you to remember God. It says
that, says "do the SALAT in order to remember
Me." God says that. And it is the most powerful.
It is concentrated mentioning of God. I believe
of God. I believe that the five minutes of prayer
make up for, maybe, a couple of hours. Don't take
my word for it and don't take any chances. But
you must do the five prayers. You don't do the
five prayers, you're in trouble already. So, you get up
first thing in the morning and you mention God.
There comes breakfast, you say BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. You open... you open the
breakfast. You start before the
first bite. Remember there's a verse
in Quran that says "do not eat from that upon
which the name of God is not mentioned."
"do not eat from that" and the word
"that" covers apples and eggs and bread,
everything. So, mention the name of God.
Don't forget. You'll forget for the
next month or so, but keep blaming yourself
until every time, you eat anything or
drink anything, you say BISMI ALLAH. So,
there and again, you're mentioning God's name.
Then, you're feeling good. You're feeling healthy.
You say ALHAMDULLILLAH. Even if you don't
feel good, even if you don't feel healthy, say ALHAMDULLILLAH. Thank God or praise God. Just... just
find any excuses for heaven sakes, to mentionGod. Think of God. You see your spouse,
you see your children, say MASHA ALLAH, ALHAMDULLILLAH, thank you God. God be glorified. God be praised.
Continuously, just find any excuses to do... the
sunrise and you think of the Earth rotating
and you say "glorify God" , "God be glorified." This is how.
just... just make sure... the Quran teaches you
to mention God in every occasion,
for reason or for no reason.
So, I'm going to end the subject here. I probably
forgot a few things, but we can discuss it tonight
in the Quranic study INSHA ALLAH. But what I
have here now, the table that I have is
I remember specifically Naghmeh came to me and
said "how come I don't get straight A's?" you know.
She's a good believer, ALHAMDULILLAH. And many
other students wonder how come we don't get
straight A's and my answer to them always wasand is that you will get... yes, John, I'm not gonna embarrass you, you know. It's OK.
I'm not gonna mention it.
The answer always is that where it counts,
God will give you the straight A's, when it
counts. And I experienced this in my life, my own
personal life, where it counts. And the example
that we're going to see here is a typical
example. This is the last game of the season.
The last inning, the last out. OK. Two outsin the ninth inning. I believe most of
you understand baseball, understand
baseball and understand the ninth inning
and two outs and two strikes. You know what this means. This means the
game is over, right? Almost. So, this is now... This was
Sammy's finale in this season and it is a typical
story as far as your courses are concerned and
even... even what is happening to you in life is
concerned. This is a typical example of the
believers, what God does with the believers.
I'm...
OK. I'm starting at this point where the second
out in the 9th inning is going to happen. OK.
and that I think it's self-explanatory.
Did you hear the statement? The season rests while Khalifa...
(Sammy) Khalifa
Sammy Khalifa
From the depth of despair
to the high of ecstasy, all in two consecutiveplays
with a base hit by Khalifa
almost... almost done.
special thank you, once again, to all the people who supported us and for you and a very special thank you to our comrade inthe truck.
It's longer than I thought.
So, this is the idea. God will give you victory inthe crucial times.