I see if you couldn't guard from Satan I
have a lot to say I don't know why I get
and this is very important they have a
lot to say those access to to change the
schedule so when we were ahead of
schedule in the morning and channels of
speaking here
I mean we decided to change the schedule
right but this is destiny this decimal
speak now at this time will you certain
people in this in this bowl now we
attempted to check the schedule here
so we have to go back to the original
schedule because it is destiny that the
speeds now when you go to school and
enroll in a course and they find of your
deficient in some information they send
you back to spoon to dip some
prerequisites you Bartek physics or
physical chemistry and then you find the
formulae or formulas that have things
called differentiation and integration
and funny funny science and universe
tends the thing is it all just a
calculus they know so they sent you back
to schools they go take some calculus
and come back and we are this is not
happen to us you are in God's kingdom
and some deficiency was discovered in us
and some kind of greats have suggested
that maybe lunch paid them send them all
to hell and God said I've never said the
back to school given a textbook the
textbook
and then they test them if they make it
they can come back cortex on calculus
and come back after their neck in this
statement and realizing that we are here
in school to attack some additional
forces while receiving a lot of
information and we are going from test
to test I want to congratulate you most
of you for making it because you have
masked the most difficult test the most
difficult test is to have one of us
human being like us claim that he is a
Messenger of God it's a very difficult
fist and I can see now why God calls
them asemu those who are the heat of the
East said before said before the elite
of the elite but it's a very difficult
test and I myself want to do it so I'm
not I'm speaking from experience God
says they are do nothing with a nobody
many from the first generation we have
the first generation but even in an
afternoon a few from the desert in the
race we are the ones who thought that if
the difficult test many would be jumping
from the wagon in the near future and
thousands and millions are going to join
us in the future but they don't deserve
as much credit as you I was taking a
framer
and Amir creating house in San Francisco
a couple of months ago karema an amine
like myself will go up
with the tradition of Islam they told us
what happened with the last prophet last
messenger the perimeter near passed the
test and accepted me as God's messenger
we looked at the evidence and they
believed me they actually believed God
was God said I am a servant of God said
if not conduct this book of mine except
those who are worthy of it and they said
since God revealed American Quran
through this man then he must be you
cannot be a liar and they concluded that
God was telling the truth it's not as
easy as I'm telling you now it's a lift
of this big massive very easy a couple
of days later after is dead with Kareem
and Emil the neighborhood children came
to ask was that mississauga was very man
and Amina children with rocks and this
was deep in our house for the children
for the generation now God says he
promises a person at the uod enjoyment
in heaven for all of the variables but
even a bishop we cannot get the same
creditors very much I mean this our
children are grown up you have no
hangups
they say the concept this is hard to
listen to and we believe it and for them
it's easy and you see the difference so
I congratulate you
the test is very difficult and I said I
I've asked them I mean going through it
I handled that I didn't pass it because
I am NOT you we we are in the same boat
I am required also to believe the
presence of God and it took me eight
years some of your own better than me in
that respect they take you that long to
me half years
and this gives me a chance to make the
talk to some of my most beloved friends
indeed visiting this man is the most
curious creature on earth his little
curious he knows who mother's name by
now you might not know that he knows but
you know he's very curious and he comes
to me and I mean both of the
supermarket's and leaves what the
turbulence of the bulletin board let's
make it easy but interested how does the
revelation talk to you deceive Catherine
what does he tell you what do you tell
him not for and it is very difficult to
convey this to him and I can see the
disappointment in his face he's very
dear to me because he's a be evil the
rules commanded is also very curious
because that will tell you that very few
and he asked me the same question he is
a very very dear to me through sperm
onion the disappoint from his face this
breaks my heart
what do then is I'm proud to tell you
that I see the disappointment of the
deep space and I see from ruin his face
I don't know if I can satisfy that
curiosity or not but they thrive there
is a president of Iran as you know
Gabriel appeared to Naya
we both know he was Gabriel but what did
she say
Cindy out of a real money maker a sickly
person come from you he put that idea so
she assumed that he is Satan or an agent
of Satan something bad and before we
adopt my conclusions I want to set up
some record straight
Gabrielle is a Messenger of God his the
messenger who carries regulations is an
angel God calls him around I mean the
opposite
there are of Revelation Romans I mean
and the lead is will may have human
human visions of Gabrielle I will make
convey on him human characteristics like
you make sure your card messengers let's
say get away from me you said we will
think that he'll get mad and say I'm
telling you you were God's message no it
doesn't his very mind they understand it
very gentle and very respectful and he
never never others to think that we
would utter but I'm telling you you
better do the announcement listen it is
amazing of course God gave a certain
powers the see certain things and they
have their talents understanding the
angels who so they're in the engines the
old engines as we understand it is very
fitting now I went through the test
because that the way they resin comes to
Ruth and they deep is that would not
selling information to us
Garrett seems to just take over my brain
completely and nothing else I can know
nothing else accepts deal with this of
information that was coming so work I
instead it in the perspective one time
that this world has seen first-rate in
academia usury he said that most
assertive you ever told me that in
economics our university applies to you
surely you are one of the messengers and
I try to avoid that because the vendors
it's the best work statement and I grow
up
sabia seen I was even thought that you
see the name of
after my brain is taking over and you
are one of the messages I say going
you're saving which is what Mary said
and then a very wide a very gentle
debate will go on why do you think I'm
Satan's did you if you say I will be
language technology I will actually say
this I see how the name is have another
cheek as if he puts in that when Satan
the rejected and I would say lovely I
will become in him as a society
my lord I seek refuge in you from the
whispers of the devil well I will pick
up the wall and I seek refuge in you my
lord that they come close to me and
their the debate will savor you said
these statements until the improv he'd
protect you
I'm not saying and this is Martin says
said I simply butan guard from you you
said I would look at my linka I see if
abused with the most gracious from you
imported a figure if this means anything
to you otherwise even you will
understand what I'm saying if you are
really rapidly covered appeared to
monumental in the form of a human being
this did not happen in my case my guess
is strictly here so I dismissed the
thought but then I'm I'm totally
incapacitated as far as thinking this
constant or doing anything so I ignore
the songs and they say okay the reason
Quran then I open the Quran and my brain
is taking over
you are not the messenger so I see in
three applies to you so this is I'm
openly satisfies at least some of the
philosophy of if I got to water will
come up to some other question but it
was very difficult I also I think I need
to let a correction also I was never
asked to make the announcement I think
the way I put it down I may not have
expressed myself I was not I was never
altered
until the time that loves me in that 8
years before that I was not older but it
was implied
like I said that the gentleness and
mindedness and the obviously there was
distance there was a certain type of the
announcement but I was as told in this
fashion all the information that you've
got to listen sir and I went on by many
ways saying I would lead the world apart
at all it wasn't oh god oh no don't need
anyone else with the said okay fine okay
I know I've got listened to fine leave
me alone she's kind of things then and
the first conference say that one that
was boiling point that and jump the gun
and do something and Susan Ray kind of
let the cat out of the bag from a few
speculation and then at that time
because this night is here I'm gonna
relive his part
Catherine Colton was just letting me
that would that happen and those a big
promotion she went in the room and she
found the sniper got a cousin Achmed of
Malaysia and mainly and both the rules
conferring about this disaster and his
main paragraph was pacing the room who's
very angry and he made a statement of
turbulent birth his light is here he
said I'm going to ask you point-blank if
he is God's messenger or not he was
whispering by the way
[Laughter]
and he was there and my work as the
Egyptian to ask me point like are you
God's messenger and I was captain simple
as he was watching me and there was very
quiet what she didn't know maybe she
knows now but it was great very hard
please God don't let anybody ask me that
question
I don't need anything like this I'm
gonna place you would alone was for you
alone now what happened is might we have
done San Francisco you knocked down I we
didn't want any new ones see so we
looked through the Quran and to us the
messenger was one who received Scripture
and this guy didn't receive in his
question not as far as we know and if he
says that these receive scripture he's
alive so I deserve a drastic point-blank
and get the thing forward and gathered
my witness I couldn't open my mouth to
have
[Applause]
sometimes interest may litigate like I
can't explain why I was so determined to
ask you and what made me just I didn't
do it so obviously God answered my
prayers
and time went by they had to make that
announcement and I said some of you
maybe I need a permit from me because I
really have a nice dome at that foot but
the simple of bragging how would I tell
my friends brothers and sisters about
this enough how many of them would I do
I love them very much I wanted to go
with me
Israel not to heaven and I'm great at
losing eight of them so I I had a
sleepless night then I go to for the
football Friday and they're very
eloquently and as heavily as I can I
delivered the football and I take them
that idea all the time now is the time
God's messenger then in the Hanuman then
I go to a Catholic open for circle and
there Oh have to work I have to just
bring you or my condition at the time of
it and I'm sweating away what do you
think of this Japanese Hitler I'll put
that on the wall what's the big deal
then I thought the man Tom and Susan and
they said what took you so long to
breath and sweating away
guys knew all along the funniest one was
I went to Laurie also and though these
guys already knew somehow without
announcements just like I knew without
an announcement the funniest one was XM
about which was that same little son was
going for children saying this makes the
misses or mrs. he know this is the
toughest test it is very tough and I
congratulate you
that's why into them also try to take
account of this conference and I have
lost some of my dearest friends because
I was sudden but so I'm not going to be
subtle
the verse that says they are merciful
among themselves and harsh when the
disbelievers I'm not too late
enemies I'm going to be the wreck and
step forward after competitively most of
you there are individuals who I'm afraid
they go to hell if they are kind that
they will love me for say for saying
this they are not going to they would
hit me which doesn't make a difference
so I was standing at the lunch line and
Lydia said how nice and smooth the
compass is going and the Cathy Robinson
to blow it out of my mouth it is not
over yet
so linear almost some please and what do
you mean
so I said yeah it's not over yet what
you hear me so I may cause a lot of
turmoil I need to remember the test
yes the test is very difficult but if
the person is not a believer it is
amazing how flimsy the test can be and
they flow and this happened to some of
my dearest friends because inside their
heart they were not disbelieve they were
not believers claims you my friends here
I give an example this is not what
happened but it's an example they will
learn they will come to the mock to the
nest you look at the very thing they
will read the translation they will
discuss the matter with me say
worshipping God the logos reason about
this what we believe the bottom there
was a part of the Lord is boring this
what we believe then they go out and
they have block away they need somebody
who lives in this but
[Laughter]
us the believers of all parts of us and
then for EMC reason they will flunk the
test but it's a very difficult test but
then it reflects their belief or
disbelief inside we had many people come
to the mosque with nothing to burn they
talked to the Quranic studies they come
to the Friday prayers and they will be
seemingly good believers now this what
actually happens then of course they
have to be tested sort of - the first
ones in line with the people think they
would be left to say we believe
being put to the test we will certainly
test them to distinguish the truth from
the liar
she has to be tested and it isn't my
best effort but I happened upon the hot
water who people easily especially what
they say were believers I was telling
her that Sadie very dear to me
the rules they give to me and I select
you this matter of Revelation even
though it is really impossible to convey
I want to tell you anything I want
everything to be open I don't anything
to be mysterious and I don't want to go
hesitate we've left anything mysterious
[Music]
taboo something them there's no moon
there is no mystery it's a form of
enhanced but what are they do to me
because there are behaviors one of the
best advantages you gain God's
messengers is that I get to know the
believers through believers it says such
a partner because believers are a rare
precious commodity
God said so the Quran that says most
people no matter what you do would not
believe and most of those who believe
with all my devotion so these it isn't
my best interest that people go through
the tests and hypocrites are sifted away
but like I said I happened to fall in
love with these people
so whenever these people come to the
message it appear to be nice both
believers and then the test and sentence
and a man who's very eloquent very
clever and I know who does not blow the
fire is believed to be a Muslim and this
as he sips his whiskey he tells them
that it was bad it's not exactly he
picks his nose but he doesn't keep his
word or his practice is left here
occasionally some flimsy real and
there's all okay they will not
so it reflected if helix means but again
it explains why I congratulate you for
passing the fastest the most difficult
test the test of messengership I don't
miss everything they wrote some notes
like with you here Godzilla
I would like work from my revelation
those who are arrogant and the only
reason people launch this visit but this
is evil and God goes out of his way the
Quran and repeats that say I am a human
being like you I am a human being like
you and you know what you are do you
look perfect
normal is God's messenger whoever he or
retain and human name like you the key
word is life heals but what does God's
messenger is a person through whom God
is sending information and the message
of himself is required to listen to this
information and is required like you to
look at it and believe it or disbeliever
and it's the same difficulty that you're
going through but it is information from
God this way whatever way the messengers
were very dark
this doesn't mean idol worship which is
used frequently to block something you
are advising Michelle we know better
than that we're listening to the
information that is coming from God
there is another burst assist when our
is very strong versus panel Arabica can
say no by your law and our people now
you know they are not believers after
hockey book until the they ask your
judgment he passes on a pylon whatever a
previously dispute so Monica did you
feel it was imperative and then they
find on visitation in that whatsoever
given an adult about you you judgment
where's the diamond s Lehmann very
powerful welcome Selim submit completely
this phenomena quick and I will be no
why would Lord they are not believers
there's the lady from a cohort this is
Christina she stopped me this morning
Christina Christina not sure and she
taught me I believe in God alone also
got the loan I believe the Quran the
Quran alone
I don't believe they're misses of that
what did you say
[Applause]
we had the same incident in Vancouver
privately between her and me she said I
don't believe her Messenger of God and
then when he has said that he came out
public like this and said that believed
our message that is not believed Jesus
was the son of power and that believe me
son what to do
okay I want to 58 says you were not
firing people who believe in God and the
last day depressing ghost of a postcard
and His Messenger even if they were
their parents were the children or the
siblings or their tribal he will not
find people who even God and the last
day befriending those who are both god
and his messenger deliver God's
messenger it's either the contact I am
the way I do know is they don't thank
you well if you give lepers in Vancouver
from all over the world and this is one
problem I'm glad you brought this up
because I remember this satanic
principles of the knobs are okay
let us all be aware of this statement do
not serve this one of the names of this
book is up for fun let's work it were
the which we are those up this is
Satan's most famous principle and you
will hear it every day do not suck by
God we concept because we have the law
resulted by the human law we can justify
God's law when God says that the
disbeliever will go to hell we can slay
the disbelievers
when God says you cannot find people who
believe in God and hereafter regret
those who fought God and His Messenger
and he sees some of the most beloved
friend Greg in this precarious and
constantly associating with with enemies
of God and God's message you have to
worry about them and as I said in the
beginning what I know what I'm about to
say if the people are guided they will
love report but they are not guided do
we have before you know you taught me
this morning there's a lot believe about
the messenger which is I don't care
about this myself was less leaning
against God who God says none can dust
the Quran except those who are sincere
so again the numbers are saying you know
you know what if I'm a liar it means
even the hereafter that something is God
and will be asked why did he do this
what did you say go ahead I made a
mistake or it goes up this is a very
serious this is a very serious matter
so somebody is about to get into the act
this also comes with all the hype of you
possess the people that she knows better
are with me as my translation is wrong
and therefore we we have to have a
presentation of the other side and you
thought this comes down peacefully
we have enough first one second I need a
volunteer to take for zien Fatima and
xeni relief to the airport I know
I want you and I know you connect heaven
you've been in this movement from day
one you can solid but you second is
working for you you know that you know
that you know some enemies of God's
message will be waiting for you I'm
going to very nicely put invite them to
your house when I wasn't back over you
have good of a clue than your house even
though she was less leaving against me
I'm lying to help me
it is this kind of thing you thought it
out of kindness so they are not
attacking you already you
right now who was it this week yeah what
was it this video impressed with Sunni
Islam I said you said I never thought
you welcome and you know she came and
she said that she wanted to see this is
zero is the blue one
that's the way I was in other words with
you
Gus's latter shadow do not leave the vas
who are so
[Music]
the messages on this is already obsolete
was God send his message extensive even
in the original Quran that the Prophet
Muhammad delivered and I have an example
to show you so if you like I said God
says say I'm a human thing like you
which means I'm not perfect just like
you if you see me as a bad person then
it is your tough luck if you see me as a
very good person because that wants to
guide you however the truth is I'm not a
person but every one of you I've got to
do this experience you need somebody and
you're you are really dumb and stupid if
you don't say a thing
to this person who hit you as soon as
the pizza vessel leaves you'll remember
all the verses in the Quran and the
thing that you eat it it's tough luck
for that person that person will leave
taking the tourist human person and many
times will give them some money and you
will be very eloquent and
right you say the right words and it's
because this is a very you I just asked
you because this is a very very
dangerous situation I was the one about
1986 that I swear in front of law that I
am going to bash you up until my last
job and this I mentioned but I am going
to back up the messenger come the
messenger means exactly what this
message is your message is absolutely
untouchable you are the messenger for
that message but the situation is very
dangerous today today I was saying look
in you
plus additional for all new translated
and I found that there was a difference
of 3d and then when I show this to one
person this person said do you know
better than he does exactly what you are
saying that you separate no special
Arabic sand heart this is not the point
because we are human beings we are able
to make mistakes and this if I am
showing it's because this position
should be correct to as you are doing it
now but the person is dangerous because
this person tells me if you are saying
that this is wrong you are an unbeliever
sizing you you are the one who said
first is the Quran and the messenger is
for us we have God says that you have
gone over it means like divided the
homework and this is everybody knows
that you know if you really if you
really sincere and you read to worry
about the message and the messenger you
will come you will come to me and ask me
because I'm the one who wear the change
different men
whatever you was asking showing the
person that they made a mistake or visit
change you will come to me a discussion
with name
[Music]
[Applause]
Monsieur she existed on voyage she
claimed something very strange we had a
discussion here with you as one of your
claim that now I remember
can you hear me one of your play that I
remember now then in the a somebody will
come and strong double plus two now
[Music]
Susan last year we had a discussion and
we discussed a real meeting and also you
make some interpretation on certain rows
like Luca and I have received a letter
from you in Turkey or 1938 you will
claim also I think you playing here I
don't remember exactly but I remember
that you claim that you are very sure at
the end of 80 days
these become I don't know somebody what
is else it will come now I want to
change the subject
I'll ask you what has come if it is so
important I want to give you a chance
I witnessed pressure will give you a
chance what had come at the end of 88
then should have changed supposed to be
changed everything in the earth it isn't
mistake but you made a lot of trouble
the time you will claim and this we
discussed is the only place that we have
the Liberty from God to speak truth and
this is what I have if it is this our
vicious idea if everybody can select an
oven or on video we begin I am sure
[Applause]
[Music]
I think behind anybody's back I want to
break everything Howard and I want you
to know that I love greatness and so be
very much
I know there are believers there are
things I worry about them like ever but
with my rock brother or sister or
parents just just one lemon you know I
love you very much you know I want you
to be in a vanguard of the of the
believers that you see it is also
dangerous because if you sucked in
anything the grass does not want you to
do and you know some of the people
around you who may listen to you
[Applause]
[Music]
I think I better close up the maybe the
energy little questions with the vessel
49 that says first of all I'm not a
popularity seeker
I don't care home by myself this is this
is God's business it's not my business
nothing to do but it was my duty to
share with you this verse that says in
surah 49 in Navajo Bingham he never is
not exclusively let's meet in the only
difference in a man what we know the
only variables and the reason our motto
which I was worthy of those who believed
in God and His Messenger lumen of your
term and then Harvard no doubt
whatsoever this is the definition of the
believers now because of what is
happening in our generation who have a
tremendous responsibility and when if
there is tremendous blessings that will
be flew the sin the idiot of lady was
also tremendous responsibility that
brings the worst disaster if I write
with my assessment of Christine and what
she taught me this more visit and unless
she she is sent by God's mercy she would
be the sorriest person of the day of
judgment because she came so close this
coming very closely big at the same room
with God's message and God's messenger
listening and witnessing and of the
devil you see this in surah 57 and
completeness and quit
I mean having as you ask the question
when you come so close it is very
dangerous
there are only two extremes in this room
only two extreme the extremely
unfortunate over the Mojave
those are fantasticly fortunately and
then there is the worst this video there
is no in-between in this room you're
going to go either to the park go to the
park and it is your neck
the truth is evident and also this
evidence and you make the choice I'm not
interested numbers or popularity or many
vidiians really I mean come here I'm
amazed nobody people believe I'm amazed
and gratified and are very happy
57 something a person contained on that
day when the day of judgment the
hypocrite dependent woman these are
hypocrite hating people who pled to
believe but in their hearts they are not
believe the hypocrite men and women will
say to those who believe you say to the
leaf of the elite please allow us to
absorb some of your life in other words
we need energy we've food we're hungry
give us some of your food some energy
some light it will be safe go back
behind you and seek like a variable will
be set up between them whose get
separates mercy on the inner side from
retribution on the outer Sun they will
call upon them were we not with you
remember that name Oracle who all
sitting at the same meeting home when we
will not wait with you and they would
have some yes you were with us but you
cheated your solos hesitated doubted and
became misled by wishful thing until
God's judgment came you were demented
from God by illusions so either just by
being here it doesn't mean we're gonna
make it today
lady God does not want wishy-washy or
doubtful people at once solid believers
I know them and you know that but
they're people that are not very much
and I want to offer to be a little silly
I want you all to be literal daily I
want to end the speech with a happy note
that in this hole here exists the most
important people on earth and the most
important people in the hereafter for
eternity they did what they did and I
congratulate you from my heart
congratulations whenever there are any
questions of discussions just they will
give it ten minutes this night we have
to admit it a lot of objections
complaints and anything unclear vs.
aliens
you can
[Applause]
[Music]