Ladies and gentlemen. My name is Rashad Khalifa
and what I'm about to share with you is the
most important news in the history of the
world. Because this is the most important
news, it comes with something unique, something
never witnessed before, a built-in irrefutable
proof of authenticity. The world's leaders
are invited as well as each and every one
of you invited to examine the evidence, then take
action in accordance with this news. Here are the
headlines: this year, 1986, is the last year to
experience the world as we know it today. A new
worldwide era or worldwide system will begin
sometime between September, 6, 1986 and August
25th, 1987. We are recording this bulletin on May 15th,
1986. The new era will last 303 lunar years which
is equivalent to 294 regular
years after which the world will come to an end.
In other words, after 300 years of a new
era, the word will end in the year 2280.
Up until now, the world has served
as the testing ground for Satan's
claim that he can be a god besides God. Up
until now, the world has been Satan's domain.
Satan's incompetence as a god has been proven by
the abundance of misery, disease, famine, divorce
oppression and wars in this world. In the new
era, Satan will throw up his arms and declare
his failure. For thousands of years, Satan has
been trying very hard to make his domain, the
planet Earth, a perfect place where everyone
enjoys perfect health, perfect wealth and
perfect peace, but he just couldn't do it. While
Satan's Kingdom is plagued with misery, disease
famine, poverty, oppression and wars, the upcoming
era of God's kingdom is characterized by perfect
health, perfect wealth and perfect peace and joy.To become a member in the upcoming kingdom of
God, you must satisfy three minimum requirements.
First, you must believe in the one true God as
the omnipotent, omniscient and omnipresent Creator
and sustainer of the universe. You must believe in
the one true God the specific one who actually
created you. You must believe in the one true God
alone without idolization of any creature of God
such as Jesus or Mary or Buddha or Muhammad or the
saints. The definition of idol worship is believing
that anyone or anything other than God can benefit
you. The second requirement for membership in
the upcoming kingdom of God is to believe in
the Hereafter, resurrection after death, heaven and
hell. The third requirement is to lead a righteous
life and this means that you are a person who is
honest, truthful, nice, one who never hurts anyone.
So, these are the three minimum requirements
for membership in God's kingdom. First, to
believe in God alone without setting
up any idols. Second, to believe in the
Hereafter. Third, to lead a righteous
life. This news bulletin confirms
the conclusions of the outstanding Christian
scholars who thoroughly researched the Bible
then concluded that Jesus is neither God nor
the son of God, but a great teacher and the
messenger of God. They published their findings
in the famous book "the myth of God incarnates."
The next headline is actually an invitation
and a challenge to the world's leaders to
examine the evidence, the incontrovertible
physical evidence that comes to the world
built into this message. I invite them to examine
the evidence, then take whatever action they deem
necessary to save their own necks and the
necks of millions of people who follow them.
I invite Billy Graham to examine the evidence
then repent and save himself and his millions of
followers. One of Dr. Graham's favorite statements
is "I know I am going to heaven." Well, I have news for Dr.
Graham. He will see heaven only if he repents
and reverses the mobilization of millions of
people against Jesus Christ and the teachings of
Jesus Christ. I have no doubt about the sincerity
of Dr. Graham. But I can show him physical evidence
proving that he has been used by Satan to opposeJesus Christ.
I invite Billy Graham, Pat Robertson,
Jerry Falwell, Robert Schuller, Oral Roberts, Jimmy
Swaggart and all evangelists to join God's
kingdom by upholding the teachings of Jesus
Christ and by abstaining from offending Jesus
by calling him God or son of God. I invite the
Pope to join God's kingdom before it's too late.
I call on Pope John Paul II to examine the
evidence then lead his 1 billion followers out of
Satan's grip and into God's upcoming kingdom. The
Pope is in contempt of God so long as he idolizes
Jesus, Mary and the Saints against their will.
Rabbi Kushner of Boston has published a
book entitled "when bad things happen to good
people." This book exposed Rabbi Kushner's denial
of God's omnipotence and revealed the reason
why Satan had victimized Rabbi Kushner
and his late son. I invite Rabbi Kushner
to break away from his persecutor, Satan
and to jion God's kingdom by professing
God's omnipotence and by taking whatever action
necessary to retract his blasphemies against God.
This bulletin declares that the Muslim world has
been in Satan's camp for 1,200 years. The Muslims
en masse have abandoned the word of God in favor
of man-made fabrications. I invite the leaders of
the Islamic world to stop misleading their 1
billion followers and to join God's upcoming
kingdom by upholding the word of God and nothing
but the word of God.
I must point out that no oneshould ever think that I am judging anyone. OnlyGod is judge. What I uttered in this bulletin was
God's judgment, not my judgment. And God's judgment
is supported by its built-in proof of authenticity
that anyone can examine and verify. May God guide
us all towards membership in his eternal Kingdom.