BISM ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM
Brothers
and sisters AL-SALAM ALAYKOM. This is the lessons
in Arabic language program and it is designed
for beginners who know nothing about the Arabic
language. I will try to cover as much ground
as possible. I want you to know how to read
and write, by the end of this program. So, let
us get to work and I'm going to start with
the alphabet. The first letter is Alef. This
is the letter, just a straight line. The name
of the letter is Alef and it is equivalent to A
in English. The second letter is BA. The name of
the letter is BA and it's equivalent to
the English B. The next letter is Ta. Two
dots. Ta. And it's equivalent to the English
letter T. The next letter has three dots. Tha.
Tha. I want you to look at me now. Tha. You stick
your tongue out. Tha. TH as in think, through. TH.
Tha. TH. As in think. And the name of the letter is
Tha. The next letter is Jeem. Jeem. And it looks
like this, has a dot right here. The name of the
letter is Jeem. It is equivalent to G or J. G as
in go or J as in John. It can be used either way.The next letter looks exactly the same except
it doesn't have a dot and this is the letter Ha. Ha. It's like a loud whisper. Ha. A lot of English
speaking people you have trouble with this letter. They confuse it with the next letter which is the
letter Kh. They pronounce this letter which isHa. They pronounce it Kh. And that is wrong. So,
you have to watch for this. The letter, this letter
is Ha, a loud whisper. And we write it as an H
with the dot under it. So, this is the letter Ha represented by the letter H with a dot under it.
and you can think of it as a loud whisper. The next letter looks exactly the same except it
has a dot on the top. Now this is the letter
Kh. This is the letter Kh, not the other one. The
other one is Ha. The letter before this one isHa. This is Kh. It comes from the throat. The other
one is Ha. This is Kh. It is represented by the
English Kh. Of course, there is no Kh in
English. Maybe, there's some in Scottish where
they say the Loch monster. You know, the Kh. But
there is no English Kh. So, we represent it by
Kh. The next letter is Dal. Looks like this and the
name of the letter is Dal and it is equivalent
to the English D as in David. The next letter is
Dhal. Looks exactly the same except it has a dot
on top of it. This is Dhal. We write it like this.
The name of the letter is Dhal and it is represented by Dh.
It sounds like Th as in then.
This is the letter Dhal. Th as in then, Dh.
The next letter is Ra. Looks like this and
the name of the litter is Ra and the English
equivalent is R. The next letter is exactly the
same except it has a dot on top of it. So, now
you can see that the dots are very important
in the Arabic language, the placing of one dot,
two dots on top of the letter or at the bottom
of the letter is very important. This is the letter
Zein. This is the name of the letter Zein and it's
equivalent to Z in English. The next letter is
Seen and it looks like this. It has three teeth.
Seen. That's the name of the letter.
It's equivalent to S as in Sam. The
next letter looks exactly the same except it
has three dots on top of it and this is Sheen.
The name of the letter is Sheen and it's equivalent
to the English Sh as in show. The next letter is Saad.
We have to move fast because so give you the
maximum Arabic. This is Saad. Now, this is a heavy
S. It is not like the regular S of Sam. This is a
heavy S. There is no Saad, Saad or saw and there is
no English, of course, equivalent to this letter. The
closest would be any word with a heavy S like some.
I don't know. There's no equivalent in the English
language, but it's a heavy S and we represent it by
an S with a dot under it. So, the English equivalent
looks like this, is just a little s with a dot
underneath it. The next letter is, looks exactly
the same except it has a dot on top of it and
this makes it Daad. This is a heavy D and this
is why we represent it by D and a dot under it.
Daad. Daad. As a matter of fact, Arabic is the only
language in the world that has this letter, a
Heavy D. They call the Arabic language, the
language of the Daad because it is the only
language that has this Heavy D. Daad. The next
letter is a heavy T. It is called Ta. Ta. We
represent it with a T and a dot under it. Ta.It's a heavy Ta. T with a dot underneathit.
The next letter is Za. Now, you have to look
at me. It's the same but has a dot on top of
it. Za. You stick your tongue out. See my tongue? Za. Za. It's a heavy Z with sticking your
tongue out. Za. I imagine the English thus would
be the closest thing to it. Za. Thus. Za.
And we represent with a Z and a dot under it, but you
have to stick your tongue out unlike the Z. So,
this is Za. Za. Excuse me, stick your tongue
out. Za. The next letter is 'Ain. Looks like this.
'Ain. And it is represented by an A and
some kind of an apostrophe before it.
This is the English representation. 'Ain. Now, look at
me. 'Ain. It comes from your throat. 'Ain.
The sound... I'm trying to make as much sound
as possible to let you get the feeling of
that letter. 'A from you throat. 'A. And the name
of the letter is 'Ain. It is represented by A and
an inverted comma before it. The next letter
is... oh boy, these are difficult letters... is
the same but with a dot on top of it. Now, this
is Ghain. Oh, you have to look at me again. Gh. Ghain. Gh.
It's like the French R. The closest thing
to it is the French R. You hear the French
saying merci means thank you and this isR that sounds like this letter. Gh. Gh.
It's a gargling sound and it is represented
by Gh. Ghain. The name of the letter is
Ghain and it is represented by Gh. It
sounds like the French R. The French R.
'Ain. Ghain. The next letter is Fa.
Looks like this. The dot is very important.
Fa and of course is equivalent to the English F.
The next letter is Qa, another difficult
one. Qa. It is represented by the English
Q. Qa. It's a heavy K. Qa. Again, from the throat. Qa.
A heavy K. Qaf. The name of the letter is Qaf.
Now, the next letter is Kaf. This is the
regular K here and it looks like this.
the name of the letter is Kaf and it's
equivalent to the English K. Kaf.
The next letter is... the name
of the letter is Lam. This is
Lam, equivalent to the English
L. The name of the letter is Lam.
The next letter is Meem and it looks like this.
Meem is the name of the letter and it's equivalent
to the English M. Meem. The next letter
is Noon. Looks like this with a dot.
and the name of the letter is Noon.
It's equivalent to the English N.
The next letter is... you have to watch
how I write this one. It looks like this.
This is the letter Ha. It's
equivalent to the English H. Ha.
The next letter is Wow. I'm not admiring anything.It's just that's the name of the letter. Wow. Just
like when you like something and you say wow. This
is the name of this letter. Wow. And here is the
name of the letter Wow. It's equivalent to the
English W. Wow. And now the last letter... you didn't
think this will ever end, right? This is Ya. The
last letter is Ya. Sometimes with two dots under it.
Ya. Equivalent to the English Y. So, this is the
alphabet and this is the most important lesson
in this program. So, I want you to memorize
the alphabet. Do not move from this lesson
until you know exactly every letter in the
Arabic alphabet. I'm going to write the whole
alphabet now and pronounce the names of the
letters and the English equivalent so I want
you to pay attention, play the tape back and
forth until you memorize the Arabic alphabet.
Alright? Now, let us do the whole
alphabet from beginning to end.
whoops! There we go. The first letter is Alef.
Ba. Alef is equivalent to the English A.
Ba is equivalent to the English B. Ta.
Equivalent to T. Tha. Equivalent to Th as
in through, think. The next letter is Jeem.
as in G or J. Let me change this, get another
one. Next, Ha. Equivalent to H with a heavy
H. Ha, a loud whisper. The next letter
is Kh. You see the importance of the dots
Alef, Ba, Ta, Tha, Jeem, Ha, Kh. This is the letter Kh. Dal. Equivalent to D as in
David. Dhal equivalent to Th as in then. R. Ra.Equivalent to R. Zein. Equivalent to Z.
Seen. Equivalent to S as in Sam. Sheen
Sh. Saad.A heavy S as in Sam. Daad. A Heavy D
as in David. Ta. A heavy T. Ta. This is Ta. Za.
This is like a heavy Z but you stick
your tongue out. The next letter... I guess
I forgot to tell you that the Arabic
is written from right to left, didn't I?
The Arabic is written from right to left,as you noticed. But so I go now to again
to the right side and start the new line
with the letter... next letter which is 'Ain.
This is 'Ain. 'Ain from the throat. 'A. And this
is Ghain or Gh like the French R. Gh.
Fe. This is equivalent to F as in Frank. Next
letter is Qaf with the two dots. That's a heavy Q
a heavy K. Qaf. Here's the regular K. Kaf. Lam. L. Next
letter is Meem. Meem. This is the equivalent to M
in English as in Mary. The next letter isNoon. Equivalent to N as in Nancy. Next is
this H. Ha. H. H as in Harry. This is the letter Ha.Next, the letter Wow. Just like a large comma
which is equivalent to the English
W and finally the last letter is
Ya. Equivalent to Wow. Let me point at
this again. Where is my pointer? Here, it is.
This is Alef equivalent to A. Ba equivalent toB. Ta equivalent to the English T as Tom.
This is Tha. Th as in think or through. This is Jeem
as in G. George or go or J like J in John also.
This is the letter Ha, a loud whisper. Ha. This
is the letter Kh. It is represented in English
by Kh. Kh. This is Dal. Dal is equivalent
to the English D as in David. This is Dhal.
It is like the Th in then or the. This is Ra. R.Equivalent to the English R. This is Zein.
Equivalent to Z as in zebra and this is Seen
which is equivalent to S as in Sam and this is
Sheen. Sh as in Show and this is Saad, a heavy S. This
is Daad, a heavy D and this is Ta, a heavy T. This is
Za. You stick your tongue out. Za. A heavy Z
with sticking your tongue out. This is the letter
'Ain. 'A. 'Ain. Represented by A'A. 'Ain. This
is Ghain. Gh. The French R. Gh. Ghain. This is Fe or Fa.
Equivalent to the English F as in Frank and this
is Qaf, a heavy K. Qa. Qa. From the throat or Q.
and this is the letter 'Ain. 'Ain. 'A.
It's represented by 'A. 'A. This is the letterGhain. Gh. The French R. Ghain. Gh. And this is the letter Fa.
Represented by F as in Frank. Fa. This isQaf, the heavy heavy K or heavy Q. Qaf. This
is Kaf. The regular K. This is K. The name of
the letter is Kaf. Next, the letter Lam. You
know like... like the animal, the young sheep.
lamb. This is the name of the letter is lamb.
but it represent... represents the English
letter L and this is Meem represented by
M as in Mary. This is Noon. The English
equivalent is N as in Nancy. This is Ha.
Represented by the letter H in English as in
Harry. This is Wow which is equivalent to the
English W. Wow. and this is the last letter
Ya. Equivalent to the letter Y in English.
Now, these are all consonants. There
are no vowels in the Arabic language.
Another surprise. No vowels. Arabic is
written from right to left. Surprise! And
there are no vowels. So, now the next
lesson is the Arabic vowels. How are
the vowels represented? The A, I, O, U. How are they represented in Arabic? How
do you make the letter Ba or
Bu or Bi. We're gonna find out.
Now, this lesson is about the vowels in the
Arabic language and the vowels in Arabic
are simply signs you put on top of the letter or
at the bottom of the letter and this gives the
direction or the vowels for the consonants. So, let
me use the letter Ba, B to illustrate the vowels.
The letter... now, remember I expect you to know now
the alphabet by heart. You play the tape over and
over until you memorize the alphabet, the Arabic.It's very important that you know the alphabet
by heart. In fact, I should give you a test and
tell you what does the letter Sheen look like? Sheen
which is equivalent to Sh in English. Do you know
what it looks like? You should. If not, go back and
study the alphabet. How about the letter Fa. Do
you know what it looks like? If you don't, you go
back and study the alphabet. I want you to know
the alphabet by heart at this point and now let
us move on to the vowels. I will use the letterBa to illustrate the vowels. Of course, you know
that this is what the letter Ba looks
like. It's equivalent to the English B
and to make it sound Ba like in English... the Egnlish Bat or But... to make it... to give it this
vowel, this direction, you simply put a slanteddash on top of the letter and this makes it Ba.
Now, if you want it to have the direction like
Bit or Bet all you do in Arabic is you put the
slanted dash at the bottom of the letter instead
of the top. This makes it Bi instead of Ba. How
about the sound Bu? How do you make it read Buinstead of Ba or Bi as in... as in Boot, for example?
Well, again you use another sign instead of putting
a dash on top or the bottom, you put a small
comma on top of the letter and this makes it
Bu. So, now you have the three directions, Ba, Bi
and Bu. If you use another letter, for example... Let's use the letter Ta. This is Ta and to
make it Ta, you put a dash on top of it. This
is Ta. To make it Ti, you put the dash under it.
To make it Tu, you put a comma on top of
it. Now, do you know what this letter is?
You better because this is Kaf. You better
know what it is. If you don't, go back and
study the alphabet. This is the letter Kaf.
The regular K and to make it pronounced
Ka, you put a dash a slanted dash on top
of it. This makes it Ka. To make it Ku
you put a comma. To make it Ki, you put a
slanted dash under it. So, these are... it's very
easy as you see, the Arabic vowels. Now what if
we have a long vowel like for example in cat
Of course, this is K in Arabic, not C. This
is K in Arabic. So, there's the word Cat
and there is the word Cut. How do you make
a difference between Cut and Cat? Well to
give the K the letter K the direction Ka as
in Cut, you just put the slanted dash, as I told
you, on top of the letter. Now, to make
it a long vowel as we see here in Cat
you simply add the letter Alef after it. This
makes it Kaa. Makes it a long vowel. Kaa not
Ka. So, this makes the difference in Cut and Cat. You
add the letter Alef after the letter with the
slanted dash on top of it. This is Kaa. How about the
direction Kii as in keep, for example. Here's Keep.
and let's say there's a word Kip.
How do you make a distinction between Keep which
is long and Kip which is short? So, as you know
by now, all you need to do to make this
letter pronounced Kii is to put a slanted dash under
it. This makes it Kii. To make it long, you simply
add the letter Ya after it. So, this makes it Kii.
How about Ku? For example, the word Cool.Let me write it here, Cool. It's a long Cool
compared to the word
I can't think of a short Ku. Can
you think of a sort Ku?
Cool is long. We need a short one. Anyway,
to make... Coup d'etat as in Coup d'etat? How do
you spell that? Oh... it's not long. Coo. Okay.
Kool. This is a short Ku and this is a long
Ku. This is an English word, huh? Well, live
and learn. Coo. So, here's the Ku,
the short one. We'll just have a comma on top of it.To make it long as in Kool, you simply add the
letter Wow after it. So, now you should know that
the Alef and the Ya and the Wow can be used
as to lengthen the vowels. So let me erase all
this mess here and clarify the situation for you.
Let us use the letter Fa. This is the consonantFa. To make it Fa, you put a slanted dash on top
of it. To make it Fi, you put a standard dash under it.To make it Fu, you add a... you put a comma
on top of it. Of course, they don't all exist at
the same time. It's either Fa or Fi or Fu.
Now to make this a long Fu,
you just add the letter Wow afterit.
To make it a long Fa, you put an Alef after it. Fa.To make it a along Fi, you put the slanted dash under
it and the letter Ya after it. Fi. This makes it
long. So, to illustrate the vowels, the alphabet
will look like this. A, Ba, Ta, Tha, Ja, Ha, Kha, Da, Dha, Ra, Za, Sa, Sha, Sa, Da, Ta
Za, 'Aa,
Gha
Fa, Qa, Ka, La, Ma,
Na, Ha, Wa, and Ya. Now, this is the alphabet
with a vowel that's equivalent to the English A
or U. A, Ba, Ta, Tha and so on. Now, to
change these sounds from... from A, Ba, Ta, Tha and
so on, you just put this slanted dash under each
letter and they become I, Bi, Ti, Thi, Ji, Hi, Khi and so
on. If you want to change the direction from A
to O or U, you put a comma on top of each letter.
Then, they become U, Bu, Tu, Thu, Ju, Hu and
so on, the whole alphabet. So, I'm not gonna
do that to save time. Now, you get the idea
about the three vowels and the extension
vowels. Once again, very fast the... if this is
the consonant Lam. For example, there is La
and if you put the slanted dash under it
becomes Li. If you put a comma on top of the
letter, it becomes Lu. So, these are the Arabic vowels.
The long vowels, you just add one more letter afterit.
This makes it Luu and if you put the slanteddash on the top and Alef after it, becomes Laa.
and if you put a slanted dash under it with a Ya, then it becomes a long Lii. So, now I
have a question for you. What if the letter does
not have A or E or U, it's just a stop? You stop
on the letter, like in the word stop. The letter
P in stop. You're stopping on the letter. It's
not stoPa or stoPi or stoPu. It is stop.
And this is exactly the next vowel or sign in
Arabic. It is called SUKOON. SUKOON means stop. SUKOON means stop and it looks like a little
circle on top of the letter. So, if this is
the letter Ba. This is Ba. And this is Bi.
This is Bu and a SUKOON or the stop is a
little circle. This means, you stop on this letter.
So, if we use three letters that look like this,what is this? That's right. This is Ba. if you
put an Alef after it, it becomes Baa. If you
put a SUKOON on top of it, you stop. BaB. So, this
becomes BaB and you know something, this is your
first Arabic word. This means door. BaB. See, there
is a FAT-HA. This is called FAT-HA. This is aSUKOON and this is an extension. BaB. BaB means
door. So, there you have it the first Arabic word.Now, I want to give you the names of these vowels.
Let me erase all this.
The letter, again, the letter Ba.
The slanted dash on top of it is called FAT-HA
FAT-HA.
Now, in Arabic, let us write
this word in Arabic. Your second
Arabic word. The letter F, you go to
the right side. Here's the letter F.
To make it Fa, the vowel, you put a slanteddash. Fa. The next letter is T
and you remember from the alphabet, this is
what the Ta looks like. Now, we are making
a stop here FAT. So, you put a circle on
it, makes it FAT-HA. This is the
the letter Ha and it looks like this, as you
know. FAT-HA. FAT-HA. Actually in Arabic, it is spelled FAT-HAH.
So, we write FAT-HA as a short but this is FAT-HA.Because FAT-HA, the other H is this one.
FAT-HA and again a stop on this, a SUKOON ora little circle. So, this is how you write the
name of the slanted dash. FAT-HA. FAT-HA. Now,
of course, in Arabic these are the capital letters
if you... if you may. You can call them capital
letters but there are... when you put the letters
in... connected in a word, they'll be different. Idon't wanna scare you now but I will show you
how these letters are connected in a word. Well,
let me do it now. The Fa connected will look like
this. The Ta will look like this. See? It's not
too difficult. And the Ha will look like
this. FAT-HA. And the Ha will look like this
and I'll have to explain this to you later. But this is
what FAT-HA looks like and we are now talking
about the name of this vowel here. The FAT-HA.
The next vowel is called KASRAH and this
is the one that goes underneath the letter
This is the letter Ba and
to make it sound Bi, you put a
slanted dash under it. This vowel is called KASRAH
KASRAH.
KASRAH. In Arabic, you take the letter Kaf and make
it like this for the vowel, Ka and then the Seen
and you put a SUKOON on it. KASRAH. Here's the
letter Ra and the vowel is a slanted dash on top
of it. KASRAH. And then the Ha and with the SUKOON
on it. A circle. KASRAH. This is the name of this vowel.
The connected words, this Ka, when it is
at the beginning of the letter, the letter looks like
this. We're gonna go through the whole alphabet. The Seenwill look like this, a slanted dash. The
SUKOON, the circle. Then the Ra. KASRAH. and theHa looks like this when connected. KASRAH.
So this is... these are represent the name of
this vowel here. KASRAH. The next vowel is
the the little comma on top of the letter that
makes it Bu and that little comma when you put
it on top of the letter that makes it Bu. The
name of this vowel is DAMMAH. The Heavy D.
DAMMAH.
So, you take this letter and write
it here. It is the heavy the Daad.
Da. And then next M. And this will bring
us to another sign. See? I'm sneaking up on you
with these signs, but there isn't much more. This
is a stress sign like DAMMAH. You're stressing the M and
in Arabic, it is called SHADDAH and it looks like
this, looks like a little W on top of the letter
and this makes it stressed. So, this is DAMMAH. The Ha goes here with a SUKOON on it. DAMMAH.
That's the name. Now, if you connect the
letters, they will look like this. This is
the Da. This is the Ma. This is... You the
put the slanted dash on top of the Da
to make it Da and the SHADDAH on top of
the Meem to make it stressed DAMMAH and the
Ha looks like this. DAMMAH. So, these
are the names of this vowel. The DAMMAH.
The next vowel that I want to explain to you
is the SUKOON. SUKOON meaning stop. And of
course you know by now that it is just a little
circle on top of the letter. It is called SUKOON.
SUKOON. This is N and to write in Arabic the S, ofcourse, you remember looks like this. Seen.
To make it Su, you put a DAMMAH on top of it. SU. And
then the Ka. To make it Ku, you put a DAMMAH on
top of it. SUKOO. SUKOO. But this is long. So, to
make it long, you put a Wow after it, remember?
The long vowel. SUKOON and then the N with a circle
on top of it. SUKOON which is this letter. SUKOON.
This is the name of this vowel. When connected, it will
look like this. This is the Sa. Put a comma on top
of it, makes it a DAMMAH. Makes it SU and this Ka in
the middle the word looks like this with a DAMMAH
on top of it and then the Wow looks like this andthe Noon. SUKOON. So, this is the name of this vowel.
SUKOON. The last sign, may be the one before last,
is the SHADDAH or the stress. It
looks like a little W. Now, this stress
is used in conjunction with the FAT-HA or
the KASRAH or the DAMMAH. It
is used in conjunction with
any of them and you must stress the
letter when you see this little sign
like in Mississippi. You will put a SHADDAH
on the S. Mississippi or Massachusetts. You
put a SHADDAH on the S. Anytime, you
stress a letter, you put this little W. The SHADDAH.
The name of this sign is SHADDAH and in English, it
will be written like this. SHADDAH. Now, in Arabic, to
write it the letter Sheen we'll go to the right
side, will look like this, as you know and to
make it Sha because of this vowel, you put a slanted dash on top of it. The next letter would be this Dal.
and because it is stressed, it's a double letter
in English, you just put this same sign here
SHADDAH in conjunction with the FAT-HA. SHADDAH and then the Ha with a SUKOON on it. SHADDAH.
and when you write it down, it will be like
this. SHADDAH. So, this is the name of this sign. SHADDAH.
Now, there is a little sign that goes
with the letter Alef. It's called HAMZA.
and it really doesn't mean... mean
anything. It's a... but you'll come across
at it. Sometimes, this HAMZA substitutes
for the Alef, if you have two ALEFs
following each other. In Arabic, they usually
substitute the HAMZA for the first Alef.
For example, in the word Quran. Here's
another Arabic word. Quran. The first
letter is Qaf. To make it Qu, you puta DAMMAH on top of it. Qur. The next letter
is Ra. You put a SUKOON on it because you
stop. Qur. Qur. 'A. Then, we use the HAMZA
to substitute for the Alef because there's
an extension. Remember the long vowel? Quran
There's the Nonn. So, this is the
word Quran. That is not connected. When
you connect it. It will look like this. Quran.
So, here you have another Arabic word.
Quran. So, this... I wanted you to know about this
HAMZA which is also found inside the letter Kaf as
part of it but this is not... it's just part of the
letter, doesn't have any... any additional sound to it
And now the fun begins. I'm going to study with
you the way the letters look at the beginning of
the word, in the middle of the word, and at the
end of the word. So we're gonna go through the
alphabet letter by letter and I will show you how
the letter looks at the beginning of the connected
word, at the end and in the middle. There are... before
we start anything, I want to show you six letters
that cannot be connected from the left side. It
can be connected only from one side, the right
side. And fortunately they do not change. The look
does not change. They look exactly the same. These
are the six letters: Alef, Dal, Dhal, Ra, Zein, and
Wow. These six letters are the only letters in the
Arabic alphabet that cannot be connected from
this side, from the left side. They can only be
connected from the right side, connected. to other
letters and they do not change. They look exactly
like this. They look exactly the same. So now let
me go through the whole alphabet letter by letter
and what they look like and again I want you to
memorize this. Once I finish the how the letters
look at the beginning, middle and end of the word,
I want you to memorize everything and do not move
to the next lesson until you know every single
letter. That's right. Every one of them and what they
look like at the beginning of the word, in the
middle of the word and at the end of the word.
Here's the letter Alef. At the beginning
of the word, it looks like this, same way.
unless it is substituted by the HAMZA. This is
why quite often, you'll see the HAMZA on top
of the Alef. So, it either looks like this
or like this at the beginning of the word.
There is one word of Quran
that says Aantom which is
two Alefs. So, they don't write like this. Aantom.
This is a word of Quran. Aantom. But instead of
doing this, they usually substitute the HAMZA for
the first Alef, like I showed you before in the
word Quran or to look like this. Aantom.
Aantom which means "are you" So, this is where
the letter Alef is substituted with the HAMZA.
As I mentioned in the first rule, the Alef can be
connected from the right side. So, it'll be like this
but not from the left side. So, this is how it will
look in the middle of the word or at the end of
the word. So, let's use one word... the letter... the
word Baab. You know the word Baab means "door." Here's
the Ba. There's the Alef and another Ba. Baab. This means door. Baab. And these are connected.
So, the Alef cannot be connected from the left
side as you see here, only from the right side.
OK. Let's move on to the next letter which is
the letter Ba. You already
saw what the Ba looks like.
This is the letter Ba and at the
beginning of the word looks like this.
In the middle, it looks like this. This is it, here.
Because this is a one letter and this is another
letter. At the end of the word, it looks like this.OK? At the beginning, in the middle and the end.
The next letter is Ta and it's exactly the
same as the Ba, except it has the two dots, of
course. In the middle, to look like this. In the
end, it will look like this. The next letter is
the letter Tha. Th as in through. And it's exactly
the same as its sister letters except, of course, it
has the three dots. In the middle, it will be like
this. At the end, it will look like this. Eventually,
I will show you examples of these letters in
words. OK. The next letter is Jeem, as you
know and you know what it looks like. Scratch
your memory now and find out. It looks like this.
Jeem. At the beginning of the word, it looks like this.
In the middle, it looks like this. This is one
other letter and it can be connected from the left
side. At the end of the word, it looks like this.
This is the letter Jeem. The next
letter Ha. Of course, you know
it looks like this. That's exactly the same.
The next letter Kha. At the beginning, it looks like
this. In the mid, it looks like
this. At the end, it looks like this.
Then, we come to one of the six letters
that cannot be connected from the left and
I'm talking about the letter Dal, the next one.
The letter Dal looks like this. At the
beginning of the word, it looks like this
and cannot be connected from the left, as
you know. In the middle, it looks like this.
is connected only from one side and at the
end, it looks exactly the same way. At the
end, it's exactly the same. The letter Dhal, of
course, is exactly the same except it has a dot.
The next letter is Ra. That's also one of the
six letters that cannot be connected from the
left side. At the beginning of the word looks
like this. In the mid, it look like this. At
the end, looks like this, same as the middle.See the looks of the letter do not change
and then the next letter is Zein and
that's also similar except it has
the dot, of course. In the middle
and the end, it looks like this.
And now we get to the letter Seen. The letter,
the capital letter looks like this. Now, at the
beginning of the word, it looks like this. In
the middle... here's one letter coming from the
right side and it connects from both sides. Looks
like this. At the end of the word, it looks like this.
It's connected from the right side. Sheen is
exactly the same way has the three dots. At
the beginning of the word, in the middle... just
be sure you have the three teeth showing in the
middle of the word, anywhere or at the beginning
or at the end. These three teeth indicate the Seen
without the dots or the Sheen with the three
dots. The next letter is Saad and the Saad at
the beginning looks like this. You have to have
this tooth there, otherwise it will be confused
with other letters as you will see. So, you have to
have this tooth. In the middle, it looks like this.
At the end, it looks like this. Again, you have to
have this tooth, here. It's a Saad. The Daad, of course,
is exactly the same except it has the dot on top
of it. At the beginning, it looks like this. In the
middle, it looks like this. Remember this tooth here?
And at the end of the word, it looks like this.
the next letter is Ta.
And you know by now that the Ta looks like
this. At the beginning of the word, it looks like
this. In the middle, it is simply connected from
both sides and at the end looks like this.
Za is exactly the same except it has a dot
at the beginning, looks like this in the middle
looks like this at the end. It looks like
this. Oops, I lost all my colors here! It's
okay. The next letter is very interesting. The letter 'A. 'AYN. You know that it looks like this.
At the beginning of the word, it looks
like this. In the middle... now watch this
looks like this. This is in the middle of
the word. At the end, it looks like this.
This's why I told you it's an interesting letter. Next, the letter Gha. Sounds like the French
R. Gha. At the beginning, it's exactly the same
as the 'A except it has the dot on top of it.
This is the letter 'Ayn and
this is the little Ghain. 'A and Gh.
The next letter is Fa.
You know the Fa looks like this. At the beginning
of the word, it looks like this. In the middle... now
watch this. Now this is a circle, perfect circle. Fa.At the end of the word, it looks like this.
Remember the 'A looked similar to this or the Gha, but it had angles to it. This is the 'A.
This is the Fa. To make it more confusing,
this is the Gh. The Gha would look... will look
will look like this. This is... this is Gha. Ghain. And this is the Fa. See the difference?
There are subtle differences but see now
you're an expert on the Arabic language and
this is why you know these differences. This is
the purpose of this tape. You know what the 'A
or Gha look like and what the Fa looks
like. Now, let us go to the next letter. Qaf.
The letter Qaf looks like this with the two dots. At
the beginning of the word looks like the
Fa except it has two dots. In the middle, it's
exactly like the Fa except it has two dots and
at the end looks like this with the two
dots. It's... it's deeper than the letter Fa.
And now another very interesting letter.
It is so interesting you can call
it crazy letter. The letter Kaf.
The letter Kaf looks like this. Right? But look
what... see what it looks like at the beginning
of the word. What is this? My goodness. Kaf. But
this is what it looks like at the beginning of
the word. This is what it looks like in
the middle connecting from both sides and at the
end, it looks like the parent letter like this,
at the end. So, at the beginning, the middle, the end.
The next letter is Lam. L. Looks like this at
the beginning of the word. Looks like this at
the end of the world... in the middle, excuse me.
The middle of the word. And now we know why
the letter Alef, see down here the letter Alef,
cannot be connected from the left. Otherwise,
you'll confuse the Alef and the Lam. So, the
Lam, L, can be connected from both sides but
not the Alef. At the end of the word, the Lam
looks like this. I'm going to show you examples
of all these letters in the beginning of
the word, in the middle and at the end.
Now let us go to the letter Meem, the next letter. TheMeem looks like this at the beginning of the word,
it's the same. Now in the middle, what's this? Looks like
this, the middle of the word, connected with both
sides. At the end of the word, it looks like this
or like this. Some people give it a tail like that.
So, this is at the beginning, in the middle and
at the end of the word. Either way
is correct. The next letter is Noon.
Noon. N. At the beginning of the word,
looks like this. In the middle looks
like this. Well let me make this a little clearer.
At the end of the word looks like this. It
is the letter Noon. The next letter if
you think the Kaf was a crazy letter, this
letter Ha is the craziest yet. You see the
parent letter looks like this. Ha. So, at
the beginning of the word, it looks like
this. In the middle, and this is where it is crazy.Watch very closely. This is how it looks like.
Let me repeat that. This is what it looks
like in the middle of the word
from both sides. This is the Ha. I told you it
was crazy. Also, sometimes it's written like
this. Ha. In the middle. At the end, it looks
like this. I told you it was a crazy letter. Very
strange. But once you know it, you become
the expert. So, here's the letter Ha. At the
beginning of the word or in the middle,
in the middle of the word or at the end.
It is very easy once you know. You
know, don't let... don't let these
things intimidate you. Things you become
afraid of things when you're ignorant
of them. Ignorance creates fear but
once you know it becomes very easy.
So, this letter and the others will become
very easy for you the next letter is Wow.
And as you remember look down here. It's one of
the six letters that cannot be connected from
the left and it does not change its looks like the
crazy letter Ha. So, at the beginning of the word
looks like this and cannot be connected from this
side. In the middle, it will be connected only from
the right side but not from the left side like
this and at the end, it will look the same like this.
The last letter, thank goodness, is the letterYa which looks like this and sometimes with
two dots at the beginning of the word, it
looks like this, the two dots. In the middle
looks like this with the two dots. At the
end, it looks like this with the two dots.
It's connected from here. So, these are all
the letters of the Arabic alphabet as they
appear at the beginning of the word, the
middle of the word or the end of the word.
Let's take a break and we'll
be back with more lessons.
AL-SALAM ALAYKOM. So, here we are again and I have
a very nice surprise for you and I'm assuming that
you studied the alphabet. You know now every
single letter looks in the beginning of the word
in the middle, at the end. I am hoping that you
have memorized the vowels, the FAT-HA, the KASRAH
the DAMMAH the SHADDAH, the SUKOON. So, you know all
the Arabic alphabet. You know what they look like
at the beginning, middle and end of the word. You
know the vowels and the surprise is now you can
read and write Arabic. That's right. You will not
understand a thing but this you'll have to build
up. You have to build up your vocabulary and the
grammar as you go but right now you're supposed, if you
did what you're supposed to do that is memorize
the alphabet and the vowels, you should be able
to pick up any book and read it. You can pick
up the Quran or any book or any Arabic newspaper
and read it, right now. If not, please go
back and study the alphabet and what they look
like and the vowels. Play the tape over and over
until you memorize the alphabet and I want you
to pick up any Arabic book look in it and read
it. I'm gonna prove it to you. Okay. Here we go.
you know what this letter is?
This is Ba. We put a slanted dash under
it, becomes Bi. We connect it with this letter
that has three teeth. You know what this is? This is the Seen and you put a SUKOON on it, becomes
Bis. So, this is Bis. Bis. See? You can see it
in an Arabic book looking like this and then
the letter Meem that looks like this at the end
of the word and we put a KASRAH under it. This
becomes BISMI. See? BISMI. You should be able
to read it now. You probably even know the meaning
of this word. BISMI. In the name of. The next
word is, here's, ALEF. With the FAT-HA make it A.
There is a Lam at the beginning of the word. We'll put a SUKOON on it. This makes it AL.
AL. This is the first word. BISMI. The next word
is A and Lam. AL. Another Lam with a FAT-HA
AL-LA. ALLAH. There is a Ha at the end of the
word. Remember? BISMI and ALLAHI
Now, when you read these two letters. Excuse me. I have to cut here. Repeat again. Take two
on this part. Now, when you look at these two words
together and this is a very simple rule that
you will see over and over again. When you read
the two words. This is BISMI and this is ALLAHI.
Together will become BISMILLAHI. BISMILLAHI. The Alif and the Lam become silent. This AL.
Alif and Lam. This is the Arabic article
the. AL. You're gonna see it in every word.
Let us look at this word here. The first letter in
it is Ba. We put a KASRAH under it to make it Bi.
The second letter is Seen and we're gonna put a
SUKOON on it to make it BIS. So, so these two letters
Bi and the Seen with a SUKOON makes it BIS. The
third letter is Ma, Meem and we'll put a KASRAH
under make it BISMI. So, there's an Arabic word
that you probably know the meaning of this word
BISMI which means in the name of. The next word
starts with an A. The second letter is AL is a
Lam with the SUKOON. AL. So, this makes it AL and by
the way, this is the Arabic article the. AL. Alif
and Lam with a SUKOON. This here
is AL, the article the. And you're
going to see it a lot. The. AL. The third
letter in this second word is another Lam
with a FAT-HA. AL LA. AL LA. And the third letter, the last letter HA. Allah. Allah. this is a
special way of writing the word that means God.
Allah. So, it's BISMI Allah. These two words. Now,
when you have two words together, the article AL
becomes silent. You do not pronounce it. There is
the first word, BISMI. You can read it. Look
it up in any book, you read it. BISMI. BISMI.
And the second word ALLAH but you have memorized
the alphabet you know what they look like in the
beginning, the middle and the end. Allah. And now a
very simple rule is that this article AL becomes
silent when you read the two words together. So,
this becomes BISMILLAH. BISMILLAH. And you have
a SHADDAH on this letter because of the... when
you cancel these two, the SHADDAH will look like that.
So, these are two word. In the name of God. BISMILLAH.
And you will always see that the article AL becomes
silent when you read... when you combine the
words together. The next word is another AL
the article the. AL. See, this is the God. AL. ALLAH. BISMILLAH. AL. the. Most Gracious. RAHMAN. AL-RA
and then the Ha with the SUKOON. AL-RAH.And then the Ma. AL-RAHMAN
There it is. BISMILLAH. Now, because
we are not stopping on Allah, again
we have to put a KASRAH here, becomes BISMILLAHI
And this word is AL-RAHMAN. Just make it
connect because there's one more word to
make this AL-RAHMANI. If you stop, then you put
a SUKOON. Cause SUKOON mean stop. AL-RAHMANI
And again if you read this letter, combine
this world combine with the other words
the article AL becomes silent and you add a
SHADDAH on this letter. So, it becomes BISMILLAH-E
RAHMANI. The article AL becomes
silent. Same with the last word AL
RA HI and the long HI M. And because we're going
to stop, we make... put a SUKOON AL-RAHIM. And this
AL becomes silent when you combine
it with the other words. So, when you
read the whole thing, it becomes BISMILLAH-ERAHMAN-E RAHIM. And you put a SHADDAH here.
See how easy it is? Now, as you see, you can read the
the words in any book. I'm going to prove it
to you. Let us open a Quran. BISMILLAH-E
RAHMAN-E RAHIM. And you will see that it's very
easy to read and it is very easy because you
studied the alphabet and the vowels and how
the alphabet looks inside the words. So now
let us go to the Quran and I will prove to
you that you can open the Quran and read it
Okay. So, here is a Quran, just a regular Quran in
Arabic. There is no English in it and we're going
to open it to a BISMILLAH-ERAHMAN-E RAHIM. There it is and as you see, it will look
familiar to you because you studied the Arabic
alphabet inside the words and you studied the
vowels. So, here is BISMILLAH-ERAHMAN-E RAHIM
that I wrote for you on the board. There is the Bi
with a KASRAH. There's the Seen. BIS. Now, don't
let this extension, artistic work intimidate. you.
They just... doesn't matter how long this is but
this is the Seen. Here's the Meem. BISMI.
And there is Allah. Alif Lam Lam Ha. Allah. Together,
the article AL becomes silent and becomes BISMILLAH
and there's a KASRAH here makes it ALLAHI. BISMILLAHI. And there's AL-RAHMAN.
There is the Noon. They just try to make it artistic but
there is the Noon with the dot BISMILLAH-E
RAHMAN-E RAHIM. See? There's nothing to it. It's very easy.You open any Quran and you can read it. You can
see it BISMILLAH-ERAHMAN-E RAHIM. Can you read
the rest? This Alif Lam Meem. Alif Lam Meem. This
sign here is a MADDAH, means Alif LAAM Meem.
They want it too as when you read it to extend
the Lam and the Meem. Alif LAAM Meem. Zalika. See how easy it is? You can recognize... you may
not understand what this is but you sure know
how to read and write the Quran now. ZALIKA.
AL-KITAB. AL-KITAB means this... ZALIKA means this. AL- ZA. ZALIKA AL-KITAB. ZALIKAL KITAB.
LA. This is Lam Alif. Lam and Alif. So,
it's a unique way of writing the Lam and the
Alif. Lam Ra. Ra. There is the Ya with
the SUKOON. LA RAYBA. LA RAYBA. That means
La means no. LA. RAYBA means doubt. There is no doubt in this book. ZALIKA. This. AL-KITAB. Book.
This book. La. No. RAYBA. doubt. Fihi. See the letter Fa with a KASRAH? Fi. And then the Ya.
after the Fa makes it a long FIHI. In it. There
is no doubt in it. This book no doubt in it.
So, as you see you can open the
Quran or any Arabic book and read it
only because you have memorized
the alphabet and the vowels.
Now, let us go back to the board and
study certain words, certain expressions.
Let us now look at some familiar expressions in
Arabic and I will show you how you can actually
read and write any Arabic right now. You can
write your name, for example. Let's say your
name is Kathleen. Let's write Kathleen. The
first letter is Ka and this is what it looks
at the beginning of the word, as you know.
To make it long, you put an Alif. Ka.
and the Alif cannot be connected from the
left side. Then the next letter is Tha. Kath...
The next letter is Lam. Kathli... So, you put a KASRAH
under it. KATHLI. To make it long, you put a Ya.
Kathleen. See? You can write any name right now. You
can read and write any name. There is Kathleen. Let
us say your name is Robert. Robert. The first letter
is Ra and the direction is Ru.
Rubert. To make it long, RU. And then
Ba. ROBERT. And the Ta with a SUKOON. ROBERT.
You can read and write any name. So, practice by
reading, by writing your name and you can always
write to me and write any sentences
and ask me to correct them for you.
Some familiar expressions in Arabic
like AL-SALAM-O ALAYKOM, for example.
Let us write that down AL-SALAM-O ALAYKOM. It is AL. Here's the first letter Alif. A.
AL. The article AL. The. Means peace on you. AL-SA...
And then another Lam. AL-SALA... To make it long, put another Alif and this is what it looks
like the Lam. The Lam Alif is peculiar looks like
this. AL-SALAMU. Here's the letter Meem with a
DAMMAH. AL-SALAMU. A. Here's the letter A. LA. I Here's the letter Ya with a SUKOON. ALAYKU...
KU M. And there is the Meem and the SUKOON. ALAYKUM. See how easy it is? AL-SALAMU ALAYKUM.
It's very easy. There is AL-SALAMU ALAYKUM. You
can read and write any Arabic right now and
this is what AL-SALAMU ALAYKUM looks like.Let us put ALHAMDULLILAH. Praise be to God.
When somebody asks you how are you? We're gonna
write it in Arabic. KAYFA HALUK? How are you?
KAYFA HALUK? Then, you answer ALHAMDULLILAH. Thank God
Praise be to God. So, this is what ALHAMDULLILAH
looks like. AL. The article AL again. ALHA. This is the HA. This is the Meem. ALHAM...
DU. There's the Dal with the DAMMAH. ALHAMDU. LLILAH. LI. Another Lam with a SHADDAH. LILLAH.
ALHAMDULLILAH. See how easy it is. All you need to do
is memorize the alphabet. This is ALHAMDULLILAH.
Now let us write how are
you in Arabic? KAYFA HALUK?
We will study together the grammar and you will
build up the grammar and the vocabulary as you
study Quran, for example. KAYFA HALUK? means how
are you? Here is KAYFA. The Ka. There is the Ya. KAY...
and there's the Fa. KAYFA. What's so difficult
about that? KAYFA means how. KAYFA
HALUKA means you for a male will be HALUKA. Here's Ha, make it long. HALUKA. This is the Kafat
the end of the word. Now, for a male, you say KAYFA HALUKA. For a female, you say KAYFA HALUKI.
Very easy. So, this is for a female. KAYFA HALUKI. And the answer would be ALHAMDULLILAH.
which implies I'm fine. ALHAMDULLILAH. And
you may want to add thank you. SHOKRAN. This
will teach us a new vowel. SHOKRAN. SHU. There's theletter Sheen with a DAMMAH makes it SHU and then
then the Kaf. SHOKRA and RAN. SHOKRAN is a double FAT-HA here.And you put an Alif, also. SHOKRAN.
It's a... and you will see this a lot. SHOKRAN.The sound at the end is also added.
Don't let this confuse you but you will pick
it up as you go. Sometimes the grammar makes
it SHOKREN. A double KASRAH. SHOKREN. SHOKREN. Sometimes it is SHOKRON. SHOKRON.
So
beware of this double. It is not a
very common thing but you'll be
aware of the double vowel. SHOKRAN. You can say HAMDAN, for example.
HAMDAN. In certain grammatical situations, it would be HAMDAN. If you say a lot. The word a
lot means KATHIR. KATHI... and make it
long, put a Ya. KATHIR. You put a
SUKOON for KATHIR. However, if you want
to say SHOKRAN KATHIR. This KATHIR
will have to follow the double
here, so becomes SHOKRAN KATHIRAN.
means thanks a lot. KATHIRAN. It will follow
the the grammar because this word is a description
of this. It has to follow the same kind of grammar.So, this is SHOKRAN KATHIRAN or SHOKRON KATHIRON.
with a double DAMMAH if you want. Then, you
remove this Alif, put a double FAT-HA, use the
Alif. Then, you put a double DAMMAH becomes SHOKRON KATHIRON.Now, with HAMDAN if you want to praise
God. HAMDAN KATHIRAN, then you put KATHIRAN down here. KATHIR... make it long KATHIRAN. HAMDAN
KATHIRAN means a lot of praise. You want to praise
God a lot. So, this is the double vowel that came
inadvertently. It is not very common but you will
see it in the Quran and then some other books. The
next expression I want you to study is IN SHA ALLAH.God willing. IN SHA ALLAH means God willing. IN...
There is I. Alif with a KASRAH. I. IN SHA... SHA... make
it long... SHA A... This is another Alif. You know
because there are two Alifs after each other,it's awkward to put two Alifs. So, they put a
HAMZA. IN SHA ALLAH. ALLAH. IN SHA ALLAH. Some
other expressions would be MA SHA ALLAH, for example.
MA SHA ALLAH, when you admire your own car or your
own child or your own house, the Quran teaches you
to say MA SHA ALLAH which means this is God's will.This is what God has given me. You are acknowledging
God's provision to you. So, MA SHA ALLAH will
be like this MA SHA... MA SHA ALLAH.
MA SHA ALLAH. So, these are some
of the most common expressions
in Arabic and you can read them and you
can write them very well now because you
memorized the alphabet. You can now read
and write any Arabic, book, newspaper or
anything because you now recognize the
alphabet. This is take one of the grammar.
Welcome back. Now, we are going to look at the
grammar, Arabic language grammar, a
very important lesson. The grammar
forget it... take two. This would make me smile.
BISMILLAH-E AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. And now we come to
a crucial point in our lesson, Arabic language
grammar. We're going to study the Arabic grammar
and I have a novel way of presenting it. Hopefully,
I will make it easy for you. When you look at any
Arabic word, any Arabic word, search for the root
of the word. For example, let's take the word book
KITAB. The word KITAB has a root word which
is KATABA. To write. And this... the derivation of
the word will show you that KITAB has something
to do with writing a book. For example, the word
Quran. Take the word Quran. The root word
will be Qara'a which means to read. Quran
means a book to read and so on. Any Arabic word,
look for the root of the word and this will
give you a hint as to what the meaning is. And
now for the grammar what I will do, I will take
root words and show you the different grammars
of that word and you will see by comparison.
Now, let me say at the outset that what I'm going
to show you are the general rules. There are, of
course, exceptions and those are not much. There
are only a few exceptions. So, just look at the
general rules and this will help you a lot. And
practice reading and writing. This will help you
tremendously. So, now let's take the first word, KATABA. The root word is KATABA which means to
write. It looks like this, as you know. This is KATABA.
this is KA. This is TA in the middle of the word and this
is BA. KATABA which means to write.
Now, he writes will look like this. YAKTUBU.
YAKTUBU. YAKTUBU. Let
me get a better ink here.
Now she writes will be TAKTUBU. TAKTUBU. I write will be AKTUBU. AKTUBU.
Also, you write will look like this.
TAKTUBU. It will be she writes
or you write. We'll use the same word.
Now, they write will look like this.
YAKTUBUN. An extension here. YAKTUBUN. This is... this means they write.
If it is plural, you write, it will be TAKTUBUN. It will look like this TAKTUBUN.
TAKTUBUN means you plural write. So, here's the root
word KATABA. He writes YAKTUBU. She writes
TAKTUBU or you write singular will be TAKTUBU. I write will be AKTUBU. They write will be
YAKTUBUN. You plural write will be TAKTUBUN and of
course KITAB means book. KITAB. This means book
and you can see that if you go to the root word
KATBA means to write. So, what you need to
know is that KATABA means to write and anytime
you see a word with the KA and TA and BA
you know that it has to do with writing. Now, let's
go to the next word QARA'A means to read. QARA'A.
QARA'A to read. Now, he reads will be YAQRA'U. YAQRA'U. Now, notice here KATABA
YAKTUBU. QARA'A. YAQRA'U. She reads
will be TAQRA'U. TAQRA'U means she
reads or also you singular read. TAQRA'U.I read will 'AQRA'U.
'AQRA'U. 'AQRA'U means I read. So, I want you to
notice here KATABA to write. QARA"A to read.
YAKTUBU he writes. YAQRA'U he reads. TAKTUBU she writes. TAQRA'U she reads. AKTUBU.
AQRA'U. This is I read AKTUBU I write. So,
you can see here the similarities. KATABA
YAKTUBU. QARA'A. YAQRA'U. KATABA. TAKTUBU. QARA'A. TAQRA'U. This is AKTUBU.
This is AQRA'U. Now, the plural for they write is
YAKTUBUN. For they read would be YAQRA'UN.
Can you see the similarities? It's very
easy. Don't let it scare you at first. YAQRA'UN.
You see the similarities? This means they read.Now you read, you plural would be TAQRA'UN.
TAQRA'UN.
You can see the similarities
and of course the word QURAN...
QURAN is... the root word's from QARA'A means
to read. Quran means a book to be read.
This is what Quran means. Let us take another
word, for example, to eat means a AKALA
AKALA to read. To eat, excuse me. AKALA. Now, he eats would be YA'KULU.
Do you see the trend? YA'KULU means
he eats. This is the root word AKALA or
the past tense he ate. And KATABA is the
root word and it is also the past tense
he wrote. QARA'A is the root word meaning to
read and also means the past tense he read.
AKALA the root word which means to eat and
it is also the past tense that means he ate.
Now, I want you to notice the similarities
when the root word is KATABA, he
writes would be YAKTUBU. QARA'A. YAQRA'U. AKALA. YA'KULU and so on.
So, what you need to do is look for the root
of the word and find out all you need to do
is find out the meaning of that root word and
then from the the context of the sentence you'll
be able to tell what the word is saying. So,
now let us go to the next word as far as the
root word AKALA is concerned which means
to eat. Now, she eats would be TA'KULU. TA'
excuse me this would be a SUKOON, here. TA'KULU. TA'KULU means she eats or you singular eat.
I eat would be 'AKULU and because of the A'Aof two letters, we put a MADDAH
here means 'AKULU. 'AKULU. I eat. Now, they
eat would be YA'KULUN. YA'KULUN.
YA'KULUN. Now, you eat you plural would be TA'KULUN. TA'KULUN. You see the similarities here? This is
TAKTUBUN means you plural write. TAQRA'U you
read. TA'KULUN you eat. You see the similarity?
TAKTUBUN. TAQRA'UN. TA'KULUN. YAKTUBUN. YAQRA'UN means they read. YA'KULUNmeans they
eat. YAKTUBUN. YAQRA'UN. YA'KULUN. You can see the similarities here. Now, I write is AKTUBU.
'AQRA'U I read. 'AKULU means I eat.
You see the similarity? 'AKTUBU. 'AQRA'U. 'AKULU.
How about another word? HAMADA means to praise will look like this. HAMADA. HAMADA.
Now, he praises would be YAHMADU. There's Ya. There's HA. YAHMADU means he
praises. YAHMADU. You praise or she praises
would be TAHAMADU. There's TA, HA, TAHMADU.
I praise would be AHMADU. AHMADU. They praise would be YAHMADUN. YAHMADUN.
YAHMADUN means they praise.
and you means you plural would
TAHMADUN. Excuse me
TAH... there's the HA. TAHMADUN. You can
see the trend and this is the grammar
of all these words. TAHMADUN. I am going to
close by giving you an example of using one
of these words in a sentence and you will
get the idea and I urge you to practice by
reading the Quran, writing sentences, learning
vocabulary building up your vocabulary and the
best way is to read the Quran and compare
the meanings, look at the meanings. So, this
word ALHAMDULILLAH, for example, from HAMADA. ALHAMDULILLAH. You look for the root word
HAMADA which means praise. So, this will tell
you that ALHAMDULILLAH means praise be to
God and it will look like this. AL this
is the article meaning the. ALHAMDU
or this should be a FAT-HA here. ALHAMDULILLAH.
LILL, there's the SHADDAH. LILLAH. ALHAMDULILLAH.
And you can see here the that HAMADA
is the root word from HAMADA
means praise. ALHAMDULILLAH.
can be very very easy. The next word I want you
to see is what is this LA, put a KASRAH makes
it Li. Another Lam. Now, put the SHADDAH on it. Remember the SHADDAH? The stress with a FAT-HA makes it LLLAH.
LILLAH. LILLAH. Put a Ha and the SUKOON. LILLAH. So, the two words are ALHAMDULILLAH.
ALHAMDULILLAH. You can go now to any Quran in the world, open the first SURA and
you can read, BISMILLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. ALHAMDULILLAH and so on. You can read any Arabic
now, once you have memorized the alphabet
and what looks like and the vowels. You know the
alphabet and the vowels. You can write your name. You
can write anything you hear, write the sounds.
ALHAMDULILLAH
Now, we will take a reading lesson. Now that you
know the alphabet and what it looks like what
every letter looks like at the beginning, the
middle and the end of the word, you can read
any Arabic. So, let us read the first SURA inQuran. As you see here, the first letter in the
first verse is Bi. See? This is the letter Bi. You know
it by now, with a KASRAH under it. Bi. The next letter
is Seen with this is the SUKOON as written
in this book. BIS. And then Meem. Here's Meem with a
KASRAH under it. BISMI. And then Allah there'sAlif and then Lam Lam Ha with a KASRAH. BISMI ALLAHI
BISMILLAHI. and then Alif and then Lam and then Ra. Notice that the Ra has a SHADDAH on it
See the SHADDAH? You know all these vowels by now. SHADDAH and then a FAT-HA on it. This makes stress
on the letter Ra because when you read the complete
sentence, this Alif and this Lam become silent.
So, you go BISMILLAH-E RAH... there's Ha with the SUKOON on it. Ha and then Meem with a FAT-HA on it. RAHMANI.
There is the Noon. See the Noon with the
dot with a KASRAH? Ni. AL-RAHMANI. And the last
word in this verse AL-RAHIM. There's Alif. There's Lam. There's Ra with the SHADDAH and the
FAT-HA so makes it stressed on the Ra. RAHIM. There's Hi. Ha with a KASRAH and then
the extension of the KASRAH which is the Ya with
the two dots. See the two dots? HIM. There's the last letter
Meem. Now, this happens to have a KASRAH under it.So, the whole thing pronounces BISMILLAHI AL-RAHMANI AL-RAHIMI.
But if you stop, you don't have to say
Mi. Then, you put a SUKOON on top of this letter
and becomes M. BISMILLAHI AL-RAHMANI AL-RAHIM. This is
the first verse. There's number one. We didn't study the
numbers yet, but we will do this a little later.So, this is verse number one. Now, we go to verse
number two. First word there's the Alif. There's
the Lam. There's a Ha. ALHA... See the FAT-HA for the
Ha is up there. ALHAM... then, Meem with a SUKOON on it. HAM. ALHAMDU... see? This is the Dal with
a DAMMAH on it. See the DAMMAH? ALHAMDU... and then Li. There's aKASRAH under the first Lam here. See the KASRAH?
And then this second Lam has a SHADDAH on it.
A stress. And a FAT-HA. LILLAHI. ALHAMDULILLAHI.
The next word is Ra. See the Ra? A beautiful Ra has a FAT-HA.This is what makes it Ra. The next
letter is Ba. See the Ba? Beautiful Ba with a
KASRAH under it and the SHADDAH on top of
it. This makes it RABI. RABI. The next word is
A and then Lam. AL means the. AL. 'A
See the 'A in the middle of the word? Remember what it looks
like? This is what it looks like in a book. 'A with
a FAT-HA on it. 'A. Next letter is Lam. This little
deal here means some kind of extension. LA
ALA. This is La with a FAT-HA. La. Then, there's a Meem in the middle of the word. Remember
what it looks like? Meem with a KASRAH under it and then an
extension Ya. MINA. This is NA with a FAT-HA on it.
So, let me read the whole thing for you. It say ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMINA.
ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMIN. If you stop, you don't
continue, then you put a SUKOON on the Noon
and you stop there, instead of this FAT-HA. ThisFAT-HA is in case you continue but this is the
end of a verse and there's the number two right
there. See what it looks like? This is the number
the Arabic numeral two because this is the end of
verse number two. ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMIN.
We will study the meanings a little later.
The next verse starts with the word, there's Alif
Lam. AL means the, as you know by now and thenRa. AL-RA. There's the SHADDAH and the FAT-HA. Ra.
And then Ha with a SUKOON on it RAH and then a Meem. There's the Meem with a FAT-HA on it. Ma
and then there is a Noon with a KASRAH underit. RAHMANI. The next word is there's Alif. There's La with a
SHADDAH on it. No, excuse me, the SHADDAH is on theRa. Here is a Ra with a SHADAH and a FAT-HA. RA
and there is a Ha with a KASRAH that goes with it.There's a Ya to extend the KASRAH makes it HIM
This is the Meem at the end of reading word as
you have seen before. AL-RAHMANI AL-RAHIMI. So, when
you read the whole thing together, it sounds AR-RAHMANI RAHIM because you stopped at the end. AR-RAHMANI RAHIM.
This is why you have the SHADDAH on theRa. This Ra and this Ra and this is the end of
verse number three. See the number three there? Now let
us study the meanings of what we read so far. We'll go
to the very beginning. the BISMI. This means in
the name of. You will know this at the end of the
lessons. BISMI. In the name of Allah. There's  Allah. Alif, Lam, Lam, Ha. Allah. BISMILLAHI mean in the name
of God and then AR-RAHMANI means the gracious and
then AL-RAHIM. AR-RAHIM means the merciful.
BISMILLAHI RAHMANI RAHIM. In the name of God, the gracious,
the merciful. Then the second verse
ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMIN. ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMIN.
ALHAMDU means praise. LILLAHI to God. Praise be to God. RABImeans Lord. AL-'ALAMIN the universe. ALHAMDULILLAHI RABI AL-'ALAMIN.
Praise be to God, Lord of the
universe and this is the end of verse number 2
verse number 3 AR-RAHMAN AR-RAHIM, the gracious, the
merciful. This is the same as in the first verse
AR-RAHMANI RAHIM. Now, we move on to the next verse,
verse number 4. The first word in verse number 4
is MALIKI. MALEK means king. There is Ma.
See the Meem with a FAT-HA on it? MA and then the Lam
in the middle of the word with a KASRAH under it. MALI and then the Kaf. Remember the Kaf with a
KASRAH under it? Makes it Ki. MALIKI. MALIKI. King. And then
the next word is Ya. See Ya, how Ya looks in
the beginning of the word? Ya. And then Wow witha SUKOON on it. YAW. YAWMI. There is the Mi with a
KASRAH under it. YAWMI. MALIKI. King YAWMI means day. Kingof the Day of Judgment. Here's Judgement, AD-DIN.
A. There's Alif. Lam. AL. And there is a Dal with
a KASRAH. AL-D... and then the extension. Remember
the extension of the KASRAH? Is the letter Ya with
the two dots. AL-DIN. Here's a fancy Noon with
a dot on top and the KASRAH under it makes it Ni.MALIKI YAWMI AL-DINI. So, if you say the whole
thing and stop, then it sounds MALIKI YAWMI DDIN. MALIKI YAWMI AD-DIN. MALIKI YAWMI DDIN.
The Alif and the Lam are very often silent. When you
connect, say the, all the words together and
we will notice a little later in in these lessons
and this is the end of verse number four. This is
what the number, numeral four looks like. MALIKI YAWMI DDIN. King of the Day of Judgment or Master of
the Day of Judgment. And here comes the next verse.
There's an Alif with a KASRAH on it and this
little deal here is the HAMZA. It is not necessary
but most people write it anyway. I. The next letter
is Ya with a SHADDAH on it and the FAT-HA. So, IYA. And then there's an Alif which extends
the FAT-HA makes it IYAKA. See the Kaf with a FAT-HA on it? Kaf. IYAKA. And then this is a
Noon at the beginning of the word. There's the onedot and there's a FAT-HA which makes it NA and this
is 'AYN in the middle of the word with the SUKOON. NA'A. And there is Ba with the DAMMAH on it.
See the DAMMAH, beautiful DAMMAH there. NA'ABU... NA'ABUDU. There's the Dal with a DAMMAH. NA'ABUDU. So, this says IYAKA
NA'ABUDU which means only you we worship. NA'ABUDU
means we worship. IYAKA NA'ABUDU. Only you
we worship and this Wow. There is a letter Wow with a FAT-HA on it. It means and. This one letter
here represents the word and. Wow. Again, you know
this word IYAKA and IYAKA and only you. Now, let
us go to the next word. NASTA'IN. Noon with a FAT-HA. Here's the one dot. There's the Noon with a FAT-HA. They
make it long here to distinguish it from the three
teeth of the letter Seen that comes after.
NAS. There's the Seen with a SUKOON. NAS. There is a TAwith two dots. TA with a FAT-HA. NASTA...
And there is 'AYN in the middle of the word with
a KASRAH under it. NASTA'I... and then the extension
the letter YA. NASTA'IN with a DAMMAH
makes it NU. NASTA'INU. But if you stop, then it
becomes NASTA'IN. IYAKA NA'BUDU means only you
we worship. IYAKA NA'BUDU only you we worship
Wa. And. IYAKA. only you. NASTA'IN. which means
we ask you... we ask for help. And only you we ask for
help. The next verse... this is by the way the numeralnumber, the numeral five. This is what five looks
like in Arabic. IYAKA NA'BUDU WA IYAKA NASTA'IN is the verse number five in this first
SURA of Quran. The next word... there's an Alif. I and then a Ha. Remember
the Ha? This is what it
looks like in books with a SUKOON makes it stop. IH...IHDI... there's a KASRAH under the Dal. IHDI... and there
is NA NOON with a FAT-HA and an extension makes
it IHDINA. See how beautiful this is? IHDINA
Guide us. IHDINA means guide us. IHDINA. The next word
is AL-SI... there's a Saad with a KASRAH. AL-SIRA...
there's a Ra with a FAT-HA. AL-SIRA... there's littledeal here means extend a little bit. It's not exactly
an Alif. AL-SIRATA. There's a Ta with a FAT-HA means the path.AL-SIRATA. IHDINA guide us. AS-SIRATA. Guide us in
the... the path and then this word here is AL-MOSTAQIM. Alif Lam. AL means the. There's a Meem with
a DAMMAH on it. There's a Meem with the DAMMAH. MU.And there is a Seen with a SUKOON. MUS. There is
a Ta with a FAT-HA. Ta. MUSTA. And then there's a
Qaf with a KASRAH makes it Qi and the extension
over to this Ya. MUSTAQIM. There's a Meem witha FAT-HA. MUSTAQIMA, but when you stop, it
makes it MUSTAQIM. So, the whole... this is 6. This
is the numeral six in Arabic. Looks like the English
seven, doesn't it? This is six, verse 6. Let us go to
the beginning of verse 6. It is a IHDINA guide us
AS-SIRATA mean the path. AL-MOSTAQIM means the straight.So, this is my chance to tell you that in Arabic
the adjective comes after the noun. In Arabic,
you don't say beautiful rose. You say rose
beautiful. That's the way it is in the Arabic grammar.So, this is why here you find it says IHDINA AS-SIRATA
AL-MOSTAQIM guide us in the path the straight. In
English guide us in the straight path. And this is
verse 6 and now we'll move to verse number 7. SIRATA. You know this word by now. There's a Saad
with a KASRAH makes it Si and then a Ra with
a FAT-HA or this... there's the FAT-HA with the Ra. SIRA
TA. There's a TA with a FAT-HA. SIRATA. And then it means
the path... path. ALLAZINA means those. There's Alif.
There's Lam with a SHADDAH and the FAT-HA. ALLA... The SHADDAH means stress, remember? ALLA... there's a
Zal with a KASRAH. ALLAZI... and the extension
for the KASRAH is this letter Ya with the two
dots. ALLAZINA. See the beautiful Noon with one
dot and the FAT-HA? ALLAZINA.... SIRATA ALLAZINA means
path of those. The next word is AN'AMTA means you
blessed. The path of those whom You blessed is
AN'AMTA. The letter Alif with a FAT-HA. This is the HAMZA. A. And then there is the Noon, the one
dot and the SUKOON in this book is written in
this way, an open little circle that is open on
the left side. AN'A. There 'A with a FAT-HA. There's the 'A. AN'A... there's the Meem with the SUKOON. AN'AMTA.
There's the Ta with the FAT-HA on it. In order to follow me perfectly, you have to know the Arabic
alphabet by heart. You must know it very well. If
you don't, please go back to the beginning of the
tape and study the alphabet. This is very easy
for people who had memorized the alphabet
AN'AMTA means blessed... You blessed. The next word is 'A,
see the beautiful 'A at the beginning of the word
with the FAT-HA? This is why it is 'A. There's a FAT-HA. Next, there is a Lam with a FAT-HA which makes
ALA. ALA. This is the letter Ya with the two dots for the SUKOON makes it ALAY... ALAY...
And this is the letter Ha. I showed you that this is one of
the ways of writing it and a KASRAH. ALAHIM.
There's a Meem with a SUKOON. ALAYHIM means on
them. You shower Your blessings on them You blessed
So, from the beginning, it is SIRATA the path. ALAZINA of those. AN'AMTA blessed. ALAYHIM
whom you blessed. ALAYHIM means on them. Your blessings
are on them and then the next word is Gha, remember
this funny letter? GH like the French R. GH with
a FAT-HA. GH and then there is a letter YA with
the two dots and the SUKOON. GHAY. Then, the letterRa with a KASRAH makes it Ri. GHAYRI. GHAYRI means
other than or not. AL-MAGHDHUB. MAGHDHUB means people
who have incurred anger from God or wrath, the
wrath of God. So, GHAYRI means not those. AL meansAlif Lam. The Alif Lam is AL. the. There
is a Meem with a FAT-HA. MA. And there is a GHAINagain. This is GHAIN in the beginning of... in
the middle of the word. This is the GHAIN at the
beginning of the word and this is another GHAIN
at the... in the middle with a SUKOON. So, it makes AL-MAGH... AL-MAGHDHU... there is a DHU because there's
a DAMMAH here on top of the letter DAAD. MAGHDHUB. And there's the extension. This is the extension
for the DAMMAH. GHAYRI-L MAGHDHUB makes it long. ...DHUBI... there's a B. Letter BA with KASRAH under it.
MAGHDHUBI. GHAYRI AL-MAGHDUBI. Not the ones who who
have incurred God's anger. MAGHDHUBI means they have
anger on them. MAGHDHUB. ALAYHIM on them. There's the word ALAYHIM on them. They have incurred
God's anger. ALAYHIM means on them. There's the 'A with a FAT-HA. 'A. Then Lam with a FAT-HA
means LA. 'ALA. And then there is the letter Yawith the SUKOON means 'ALAY... and then
there's the letter Ha with a KASRAH. Hi.  'ALAYHIM. There's
another, you know, I went through it before .